Learn how to build production ready multi-agent systems and automate workflows using Langchain and Lang graph.
You'll master everything from core agentic fundamentals and piedantic validation to advanced sequential, parallel, and conditional LangGraph
workflows. Along the way, you'll implement chat memory, rag, and human in the loop controls and finish by deploying your applications to AWS and render
through real-world projects like a custom Chat GPT, trip planner, and auto content agent.
Bappy created this course.
Hi guys, my name is Bappi Anywar. Welcome to my course.
In this course, you will try to master the complete Agentic AI with the help of LineGraph.
If you have seen, over the internet and everywhere, nowadays people are moving towards Agentic AI system.
Previously, we used to work on the LLM-based application, RAG-based application, but right now, agent is getting very much important and crucial for the application development.
Nowadays, AI agents are becoming very much powerful because of its automated workflows.
So right now you only need to provide a prompt, and from your prompt itself, your agents can understand your goals, and this goal should be divided into multiple tasks,
and all of the tasks could be completed by using some kinds of tools. Your AI agents can decide which tool to use to perform what kinds of tasks.
So these kinds of automated workflows your AI agents is having, and with the help of that, it can perform any kinds of tasks you will be providing to your AI agents.
So that's why this is far better than our traditional Gen AI application development.
Because right now, with the help of agents, we can automate the workflows.
So in this course, guys, I'm going to teach you each and everything you need to master the Agentic AI with the help of Langgraph. But before that, first of all, we'll try to understand my course plan.
This course I have divided into multiple phases.
So as you can see, this is my entire plan for this course agentic AI using Langgraph. So, first of all, uh in the phase one, we'll try to complete the introduction to agentic AI.
First of all, we'll try to understand what is agentic AI, okay, how AI agent works.
We'll try to see the difference between LLA maps and AI agents application, we'll try to see the agentic behaviors like reasoning, planning, memory tool, okay,
decision making. Then we'll try to see some real world use case of agentic AI, traditional AI versus generative AI versus agent TI system.
Okay, then uh we'll try to see the evaluation from chatbots to automated agents.
Okay, we'll try to see each and everything. Then some other stuff we'll try to cover as you can see, like limitations, uh, why agent why agents need memory tools, workflows, control
logic, then agent architecture, prompt and system instruction, tools, memory, planning, reflection, environment interaction, and human feedback.
Okay, then in phase two, I'll try to start with asynchronous programming and pydentic, because uh, if you are, uh, if you are already
working with AI agents, I think you know that you need this kinds of asynchronous programming, because all of the agents are using.
especially all of the agents framework are using this kinds of asynchronous programming in the back end.
Okay, so in this course I'm going to focus on the Langgraph. So Langgraph internally uses asynchronous programming, that means you can run your agents in parallel.
Okay, we'll try to understand is asynchronous programming, okay, why it is required for AI agents, how we can code inside Python. Okay, then we'll also try to see about the Pydentic.
So Pydentic is a Python library, and we use this pydentic for the data validation, okay, model validation.
Uh, and uh these things you need whenever you are implementing the AI agents. Okay, I'm going to tell you why it is required and why you have to learn this pydentic as well.
Okay, so each and everything will try to cover in the phase two.
Then in phase three, guys, I will start with our first uh orchestration framework, which is Langchin. Now you can ask me why.
We'll be learning the Langchain here because if you know Langgraph is a product of Langchen, okay, Langchen team has developed Lang Graph, right?
So that's why to master this Langch Langraph, we need some knowledge on Langchen.
First of all, we have to understand whenever we didn't have these kinds of Langgraph framework, so how people used to create the agents with the help of Langchen.
So that's why we'll try to use LangChin to build these kinds of agents and multi-agents workflows.
Okay, and still if you are using Langgraph, you need to use lang-chain because from the lang-chain you will be loading the large lang based model, you will be loading the prompt templates, okay.
All of the utility-related code you will be writing with the help of Langchain, and Langgraph you'll be using for building your agent workflows.
Okay, that's why Langchain understanding is little bit required. That's why I'm going to complete this Langchain inside this particular course.
Then we'll start with the phase four, which is uh Langgraph.
So here we'll try to understand each and every component of Langgraph. As you can see, what is Langgraph? Why Langgraph is required?
Langchain versus Langgraph, then graph-based agent workflows, state management, node and edges, okay, state nodes, edges, then conditional edges, okay,
start and end nodes, graph compilation, state graph, check pointer, message state, sequential workflows, parallel workflows, conditional workflows, iterative workflows.
Okay, then um we'll try to see basic chatbot architecture, message handling, state management, user input, and we'll try to see how we can implement
agentic chatbot with the help of line graph.
So after that, we'll start with phase five. So here we'll try to learn about the memory planning, monitoring, and autonomous system.
So here we'll just try to learn um why what is persistence memory, why it is required, agent memory, short-term memory, chat history, how we can stream the responses.
Okay, chat trading, conversation management, permanent chat persistence memory with database, okay, to integrate integration in Linegraph, okay, inside the uh um
agent t application. Then we'll try to see different, different tools, okay.
Then we'll also try to learn like how we can integrate uh REG that means rag features inside our AI agents, then vector database integration, okay.
Then uh we'll be learning another important concept which is human in the loop. Uh that means HITL. This is required nowadays.
All the agent applications are having this kind of human in the loop integration. Then we'll try to see the monitoring, our agent monitoring, agent tracing with the help of Langsmith.
Then we'll also see how we can debug the agent behavior.
Then phase six, guys, will try to start with the deployment and production grade engineering. So here we'll try to dockerize the entire agents, okay?
Then we'll try to add the fast API backend, database setup, GitHub Action CI CD, AWS deployment, render deployment, okay, environment variable, then
production folder structure, logging, monitoring, each and everything we'll try to cover.
Then uh the final phase, uh phase seven, we'll try to start with some uh end-to-end real-world AI agents project implementation.
So we'll be implementing basically three major project here in this course.
The first project I'll be implementing one end-to-end agentic chatbot with the help of Langgraph database, language, smith, tools, rag, HITL, AWS, and render.
And second project will be implementing uh uh uh our own chat GPT agent with the help of LLM, Langgraph, Fast API, LangSmith, ChromaDB, uh, SQL
Alchemy Database and AWS.
And third project uh project will be implementing called TripMate AI. This would be an end-to-end multi agent table planner agent with Grok, Langgraph, Postgres SQL, and Fast API.
Okay, so these are the three major projects we'll be implementing in this course.
Then you can ask me what would be the course requirement to start this course. What are the things I need to know?
I'm expecting you are familiar with uh advanced Python programming because all of the
Coding I'll be doing, I'll be coding in advanced Python. Then basics of generate TBI knowledge is required if you're understanding about agent AI agents, especially.
So you need some understanding about uh generate bi, at least about the large language model. Okay, these are the thing.
Then software requirement-wise, you should have anagon install in your system, VS Code, Git and GitHub, and Docker desktop and postman.
Okay, so these are the tools if you have, you can start with this course. But don't worry, I will take care of each and everything.
If you are not familiar with this concept, I'll take care, I'll uh try to teach in such a way so that you will be getting all of the concept in a clear way.
Okay, so yes, guys, uh, this is the plan, entire plan, and throughout the entire course, we'll be completing all of this concept.
And trust me, the way I'm going to complete all of the concept, you will be loving a lot. And after this, you won't be having any kinds of doubt.
Okay, so if you're already familiar with agent KI, uh, I will still tell you, just try to go through the entire course.
I think you will be learning uh some new concept here, some uh some new implementation here.
Okay, so definitely you will be enjoying the entire course, okay? So, yes, guys, this is the entire plan. Now, let's start with the course uh concept.
First of all, I'll give you the idea about the evolution of uh agentic AI, how agent AI came, okay, uh, from the traditional large
language model. Then we'll try to start with the other concept as well.
So, in this video, first of all, we'll try to understand and see the complete evolution of this Agentic AI, like how Agentic
AI came and what we used to do in our traditional generated BI application. first of all, I will give you the entire understanding how agent KI came, what are the things they have introduced.
Then uh I'm going to discuss about the detailed understanding of Agentic AI, uh, the characteristic of Agentic
AI, different component of Agentic AI, we'll try to understand with a good example.
So, guys, you can see on my screen here. I have already written the definition like what is Agentic AI.
So, if you see here, agentic AI is nothing, but it's a type of artificial intelligence that can take up a task or goal from a user
and then work towards completing it on its own with minimal
human guidance. okay? And it plans, takes at actions, adapts to change, and seeks helps only when necessary.
So, by this definition itself, I think you are getting little bit of understanding what I'm trying to say.
those who are already familiar with uh chat GPT or any other agentic AI system, if you have already used
like
VS Code, then anti gravity, cursor AI, clouded Xtop, right? So, this kinds of application if you have already used, so there you will see that whenever user gives any kinds of prompt,
right? Based on the prompt, that application decides what to do. Let's see if you are asking a very simple question. Let's say you are asking, tell me about Python. So most of the large language model
have been trained with lots of data, okay. Um, especially whatever data we are having on the internet, so they have used those data and they have trained those are the model.
and every model is having a knowledge cutoff, okay. Every model is having a knowledge cutoff, knowledge cutoff means a specific date uh till they have trained the model.
Let's say if I'm talking about uh chat GPT or let's say GPT uh 3.5 turbo or let's say GPT 4, you will see that those model
uh probably they have trained uh uh on the year 2022 or 2023 around, okay. Uh till the date they have taken all of the data from the internet and they have trained those are the model.
So uh whenever I'm asking about the Python, so definitely in 2022 or 2023, this information was available on the internet,
and definitely our large language having these kinds of knowledge, right? So it will be able to give you the answer in short or directly.
But whenever I'm asking anything which is latest, let's say I'm asking um I'm asking a latest information, I'm asking like
tell me about
Like the latest news of Iran and USA okay were in 2026.
So that time definitely uh if you are using a single large language model, okay, this kinds of large language model won't be able to give you the response.
Okay, it will tell I don't have enough context okay after 2022 or 2003. So I I can't answer your questions, okay. This kinds of I think you will uh get the answer.
If you have used the older chat GPT, I think you are getting what I'm trying to say. So, but if I'm talking about nowadays, whatever application we are using, like Clouded desktop, then anti-gravity
cursor ID. If I'm giving any kinds of prompt, let's say I'm telling
just try to implement uh application for me. Let's say implement a Python game for me.
So, what it will do, it will try to take that prompt as a command and it will automatically let's say plan for a task like what to do,
okay. How it can implement the entire game for you. So, to implement a game, first of all, it has to create the environment, it has to add the requirements, it has to create the user interface,
it has to make the character. Okay, so one by one, all of the plan would be sorted.
Then once all the plan is ready, okay, it will execute the plan one by one and it will complete the entire system, and definitely
in between it will try to test that particular let's say application. Okay, if it doesn't get any kinds of bugs, it will continue and it will complete that particular work for you.
Okay, so that means everything is happening automatically, and sometimes you will see that in between it will ask a human interaction, it will ask for a human input.
Let's say whenever it will try to implement a game, that time it might ask you what kinds of color you want for this particular environment,
how many character you want in this particular game, what would be the let's say car color, what would be the car speed.
Okay, so sometimes it will ask some kinds of questions to the human, okay, for the guidance, and once uh we'll try to provide the feedback or let's say
our input, it will take that input again, it will try to continue the workflow. Okay, so that's why here you can see it is telling with minimal human guidance, okay.
Not not complete human guidance, we give like very minimal human guidance here, and it try to take uh uh plans, takes action, okay. add up to changes.
Let's say it has to let's say it has to do one particular changes in the environment or let's say color or let's say any character, it will automatically do that,
okay. And it seeks help only when necessary. So, guys, before I, uh, give you the entire discussion on this agentic AI.
first of all, I want to walk you through the fundamental concept of generative AI application, like so far, whatever application, we usually
create. okay, and how this agentic AI, or let's say AI agents came in the market. then we'll try to understand this agentic AI concept.
So, for this guy, I'm going to take you on my whiteboard and there we'll try to discuss each and everything. So, guys, I'm inside my board, so here I'm going to write down each and everything.
So, see whenever I'm talking about
uh AI agents, right?
AI
agent,
so this is the application of generative AI,
okay. This falls into generative BI domain, and those who are already working with generate BI, so I am having a dedicated course on my channel,
the complete generate BI course. So, there I have already discussed the foundation of generative AI.
So, in that course, I have already taught you all the concept regarding generative i, large language model, okay, retrieval augmented generations. so each and everything I have already covered there.
So, if you are not familiar with generative AI, first of all, try to complete that particular course, then it would be easy for you to understand.
Okay, so in generative AI, the main component we usually work with large language model, okay. Large language model. So there are different different large language models nowadays. I think you know
there are some organization, there are some company they have launched different different models. If I'm talking about meta, okay, meta, AI. so they have launched something called Lama.
Then if I'm talking about OpenAI, they have launched GPT.
Okay, then we are having Mistral.
We are having
Gemini.
Okay, this is from Google.
So that's how we are having different different large languages model nowadays. We usually use so previously whenever we started generate BI, that time
we used to only use a fine-tune fine-tune based or let's say pretend based large language model. Let's say here I'm having a large language model, so we used to provide a prompt,
okay, prompt, and it used to give a response.
Okay, response. So basically, we used to use this large language model for text generation. okay, for very, uh, good quality text generation, or uh, for, for some other task.
also, we used to use, like for language translation.
okay.
Then for text summarization,
then
definitely for chat operation.
we used to ask different kinds of question, and we used to get the response, then definitely for
like some other NLP tasks like NER
and so on.
Okay, so initially those who have already used this chat GPT, I think you are trying to relate the concept.
What I am trying to say, it was like a very basic application, okay, we used to use for these kinds of text generation tasks.
But slowly, what they did they actually introduced also image generation, okay. Image
generation.
So image generation happens whenever they introduce something called multi-model system. So in the multi-model you not only generate the text, there you can also generate the image, okay.
But what was the problem with this kinds of application? As I already told you, let's say if I'm talking about any kinds of large language model, it is having a knowledge cutoff, okay.
This is having a
knowledge
cutoff.
So, what is knowledge cutoff? Let's try to understand. So, for this, let's go to the Google, and here if I am searching for any kinds of model, let's say I'm searching for open AI models.
Let's open up the models
now. Let's pick any kinds of model from this open AI. So, let's say if I'm talking about the GPT 4
mini, or let's see if I'm taking any older model, older model, yeah. So, I think
here some models are available. Let's see if I'm talking about this um
Vall.
Let's see if I'm talking about the GPT 4.1. So if I click on this model, you will see that this model having a configuration.
Configuration means the context window, like how much context it can take, then maximum output tokens, how how much token
it can generate, and there is a section called knowledge cutoff. Okay, so here the knowledge cutoff you can see January 1, 2024.
That means this model has been trained till January 1, 2024. internet data. Okay, so if you're asking anything after that, let's say we are asking February 1, 2024.
Definitely this model is not going to give you the response because this model doesn't have the knowledge after January
1, 2024. Okay, whatever let's say recent update we are having on the internet. This this model doesn't know about that. So the main problem I think you can understand.
Let's say if my prompt is uh before okay, before this particular knowledge cutoff, the information I am looking for on from my large language
model, definitely this model uh can give you the response, but if it is after the knowledge cutoff, that time it will not able to give you the response, okay?
It will tell I don't have the um context, I don't have the information okay after this particular knowledge cutoff. So I am extremely sorry for that.
So that that is the things actually uh uh happened uh whenever chat gpt came okay uh initially in the market, and I think you remember okay,
uh chat gpt used to give this kind of response. Then uh what they have introduced, they have introduced a concept called RAG, okay.
Why they have introduced the concept called RAG because now let's say if I want to add some other information, let's say this is 2026.
So now I have to I want to add some more information okay inside my large language model. So what I have to do, I have to fine-tune this model, right? I have to
fine tune this model, and fine-tuning means we are taking the pre-turn model, okay, and on top of that, we are adding some new data,
adding new latest data, and we are training few parameters here, okay. And whenever I'm talking about the LLM parameters, it will count like from million, right? Million to billion.
Okay, this is the issue. So fine-tuning is not an easy task. For this, you need a good resources, then good budget, okay. Then you you should have also time.
If you're having these kinds of things, then you can easily fine-tune one large language model, okay. There is no issue with that.
So, for the company, this fine-tuning task was easy because they are having a good resources, they're having like very heavy investment, okay. They're having lots of time, so they can do that.
But what about for the developers? Let's say if I'm creating an application, okay, for my client, and if any new data is coming, and I want my application to be aware
on top of this new data, so for me, for for me as a developer, this is this is going to be like very hectic task, right?
For fine-tuning a model, because I don't have this kind of supercomputer with me, I don't have this much of budget, okay, so that I can purchase a good cloud for the training.
I don't have that much of time, time so that my client will wait for me because they have to also do the business, right?
If I'm running my business, also this should be continuously running, and I should have handled all of the client with the latest information and everything.
Okay, so that time researcher introduced something called rag concept. Okay, this is called retrieval,
okay. Retrieval augmented
generation,
okay. reg rag component in the rag component uh concept. What we used to do, let's say we are having a large language model. This is completely fine.
Let's say we are having a large language model,
okay,
so it will be connected to a knowledge base.
So knowledge base is basically a database,
it's a vector database.
So this is called knowledge base, so it is having all the latest information,
latest data, I can say
okay. So this data you have to store in the knowledge base, and you have to connect with your large language model,
okay. And for this kind connection, we use the orchestration framework, some orchestration framework. I think you know inside general TBI we are having Langchain, we are having Lama index.
Okay, so this is called orchestration framework. So we use this kind of orchestration framework to make the connection with our LLM.
Okay, now if user is asking anything, okay. Let's say user is giving input. Okay, first of all, this input would be verified in the uh pre-tend model, that means the large language model itself.
First of all, it will try to check whether this information he is asking, what kinds of question they are asking, it is available in the LLM itself or not.
It is available in this knowledge cutoff or not. If it is having okay, in this knowledge cutoff, this will give you the response. Directly, this will give you the response.
Okay, this will give you the response directly. But what about this information is not available? that Time it will go to the knowledge base, it will go to the knowledge base.
Okay, it will do something called semantic search, similarity search. This will get the relevant result about the questions user is asking.
Then this particular relevant answer again, your large language model will take, it will try to analyze, it will try to
it will try to clean up, it will try to rearrange the uh response, then you will try to send it to the user again. Okay, that's how the entire RG system works. Okay, RG system works.
So basically, the major component, we have added this knowledge base, and adding data in the knowledge base.
it is super easy because only you just need to fetch the latest informations and add in the knowledge base, and your LLM is already connected to the knowledge base.
so anytime if you're asking any kinds of question, it will bring that particular latest information, and it will do the refining operation. then it will pass to the human.
Okay, so this will work like that. Okay, and this was the like very famous technique that time, even nowadays also use the same technique.
We we create the RAG application, and this actually helps us from this fine-tuning operation because here we are not doing the fine-tuning okay on our LLM,
only we're just working on the knowledge base. We are adding the data in our vector database. This is the things, right? But there are some problem with this vector database or this RG system.
What is the problem? Whenever I'm talking about the real-time data, real-time data means the data is continuously changing.
Let's say if I'm talking about weather informations, if I'm talking about temperature, if I'm talking about the latest news, okay, it is continuously changing.
That time it is not possible for me to sit down the whole day and take all of the latest informations and like add in my knowledge base, okay. That that kinds of things we can't ever do.
That so that that is why this rack system fails. Let's see if we're asking uh questions to the rack system that's a tell me about latest news, okay. Right now in the morning.
So definitely this information is not available in the knowledge base, okay. That's a morning news you have added, but what about the afternoon news? What about after one hour news?
Okay, so these kinds of things you don't have, okay. So that time your application won't be able to give you the response. So, what you have to do that time, you have to
you have to think about a different approach. So that's why researcher thought why not we can create an agent, okay? Why not we can create an agent? So that agent will be connected with some tool.
Okay, tool means we can use different different tool here.
let's say we can use any kinds of search tool, we can use any kinds of storage tool, we can use any kinds of calendar tool, Google Drive tool,
whatever we can use, but there should be some kinds of tool. So, with the help of that particular tool, my AI agents will try to fetch the information and it will give to the user.
Okay, so what they introduce that time they introduce a
agent system. Let's say this is your agent,
okay. Agent, internally, it is using a large language model only. Okay, whenever user is giving any kinds of input, it is connected with some kinds of tool.
Okay, so let's say if I'm asking for any latest informations, that time it is connected with a source tool, okay. Internet search tool.
So mostly this will search on the Google, and Google is continuously updating okay with latest informations.
So if you're asking any real-time question, first of all, what it will do, it will use this search tool, it will search over the internet, it will get the informations, okay.
Latest informations, and your agent LLM is trying to refining that and it is giving you the response again, okay.
And why I'm calling this particular system as an agent because your application is smart enough to understand what it needs to call this to
call this tool, when it doesn't need to call this tool, okay. This kinds of reasoning capacity your application will be having, okay. That's why we call it as a agentic agentic system.
Okay, here we are not deciding when to call this particular tool. You just give the prompt, okay, to the application.
Applicant application will decide whether I have I have to call this tool to get uh uh give the response, or I have this information with me
so I can give you the response. Okay, so this kinds of capacity it was having. So this was the first agent they have introduced with some real time tool.
So if I uh take you to the chat GPT, so let me give you the example.
So I'll open the chat GPT
and here let's say
I'm asking a question. Let's say I'm asking, tell me
about
okay,
Python.
Now see what will happen.
Uh, this is directly giving you the answer. Okay, it is not referring any kinds of tools, search tool. it is not searching on the internet.
Okay, instead of that, what it is doing, it is giving you the direct answer, okay. Because this information is already available in the knowledge bit itself, okay.
Knowledge uh knowledge uh LLM knowledge itself, okay, because it is already having before the knowledge cut off.
Get it. but whenever I'm searching for any other question, let's say I'm telling, "Tell me,
the
latest
news,
news of
India election.
Now, if I search that
now, see it is searching for web.
okay. It is searching for web, it is using an internal search tool, and with the help of that, it is searching over the internet and it is referring some
trusted uh let's say sources like Al Jajira, AVC News. Okay, that's how it is searching on different different websites.
Okay, now if I open this website, you can see that this is a website, this is another website, okay. And this website has already this kinds of latest news.
It is bringing that particular information, it is passing it to the LLM. LLM is trying to refining, LLM is trying to summarizing all of this, let's say
all of this content of these kinds of sources, and this is refining and giving you the answer, okay. Refined version of answer. Okay, so this is called actually
agent system, okay. It is utilizing some kinds of tools in the back end, and this application is automatically deciding when it needs to call that tool,
when it doesn't need to call that tool, okay. Not only that, this is a simple example I have shown. If you have already used
like anti-gravity let's say if I open up my anti-gravity, so this is my anti-gravity. So here I can give the prompt to the agent. So let's say here I am telling
create
car racing again using Python.
Okay, Python. Now here you can select different different model because internally I told you agent uses a large language model, okay? Because this is the brain, okay.
It is having the reasoning power and it decides actually when to use the tool, when it doesn't need to use the tool. Okay, so here you can select different different model.
So anti-creapity supports these are the model you can select any of them. Now, if you give this prompt, you will see that automatically, first of all, it will try to make the plan, okay. What to do?
Now see it is telling generating. Let's wait now. See, it is thinking, okay, it is thinking now it is trying to making the entire plan for you.
Okay, how it is going to create that particular racing game with the help of Python. What are the resources it need? What are the tools it needs? It will try to make the entire plan.
See, this is the plan you can see. This is the plan, okay. Proposed plan.
Now, what it will do in the plan, first of all, it will do the initialization, set up the pie game display, front, and clock, then player
car, obstacle, uh, collistone detection, score system, give over screen. Okay, then what are the requirement it needs? Verification plan. So, this is the agent plan, guys. That's how one agent works.
First of all, it has to make a plan, and based on the plan, it will start working on that. Okay, now I told you in the definition itself, uh, it will seek for help when it necessary.
That means little bit of human interaction is also needed. Now, this plan is proposed to me. Now I can review the plan. Okay, I can make some changes.
Okay, so let's see if you want to change anything, let's say you don't need this particular step, you can change anything. Okay, you can change anything, you can edit anything.
Okay, then you can review it. You can like tell okay, this plan is completely fine for me. You can continue now. Let's see if I do
the plan
is fine.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Now if I give the prompt,
I think prompt you can't see because this is just beside my image, but I think you can see okay,
the prompt I have given
now. See now it has started working on the plan. Okay, one by one, it will work on all of the plan, okay, and it will try to implement the entire game for you.
Okay, so this is called AI agents nowadays. So AI agent is like this is not
I mean restricted to the tools only. Okay, now it can automate the workflow. This is called automation, right? Here I'm not writing the code.
See, my agent is writing all of the code and it is asking for the approved. Okay, if I show you, if I let's say show you, so here you can see it is telling do you want to run this pip install command?
So it is asking for human interaction. Now, if I give the human interaction, if I give if I tell yes, just do it. If I tell okay, I accept the code now.
The rest of the task it will automatically do that for me. Okay, so this is called AI agents. Now I think you have understood this particular definition.
Now let me show you the definition once more time.
So this is the definition, guys.
Okay, so here you can see agentic AI is a type of AI that can take up a task or goal from a user. So the here the task and goal I have given just create a car racing game with the help of Python.
So then what it will do, it will work towards completing this particular task is own with minimal human guidance. First of all, it will try to plan, okay, then it will take action, adapt the changes.
Okay, let's say whenever it requires any kinds of changes, it will automatically do that and seek help when it necessary. That means it will ask for my help.
Okay, if I want to change anything, so it will ask for that particular help for me, it will ask for ask uh for my feedback. Okay, if I give the feedback, it will start working on that.
Okay, so I think guys, you have understood the entire
evaluation of this agentic AI, how this agentic AI came okay, right now in the market. Now, in the next video, guys, what I'm going to do, I'm going to
discuss this agentic AI in detail, okay. The application working mechanism. Okay, I'm going to show you one example like how one agent TKI application works whenever we give any kinds of command.
Okay, we give any kinds of prompt. I think you have seen all the antigravity we given a prompt and it creates the plan. After creating the plan, what it will do, okay.
Each and everything I'm going to give you. I'm going to
tell you the characteristic of this agent KI, what are the characteristic it follows, what are the component it is having.
Okay, so with a good example, we'll try to understand the entire concept in the next video.
So, yeah, this was uh uh this was only the understanding uh like about this agent tki evaluation, like how this agent
tki came in the market, and whatever traditional application we used to create in the GNEI. nowadays people are actually
people are moving to the agentic protocol, people are moving to the workflow automation instead of creating the simple uh actually text generation-based application
because right now everything can be automated, all the workflow can be automated.
Okay, instead of working on manually, we can create uh agents, and that agents will try to complete that particular task for me.
That's how you can also scale up your business, you can uh you can actually uh uh create some agents for your business so it will run automatically.
It's a customer support agents you can create okay, automatically uh email sender agents you can create.
So that's how you can minimize the employee in your company and you can save your budgets, okay.
But let's say if you don't have this kinds of agent TKI system, that time what you have to do, you have to hire someone to do that particular task.
Okay, that's why companies are adapting these AI agents in their application development, in their workflow automations.
Okay, they're replacing some low level employee which they feel like okay, I don't need this kinds of employee, and I can do this kinds of work
automated way, okay.
People are thinking in that way, okay. You have to also be smarter. Now, people ask like whether we'll have the job or not.
Okay, definitely we'll have the job, but you have to learn these kinds of technology. If you know these kinds of technology, then tell me who will replace you.
But if you don't know this technology, let's say still you do the Excel uh uh let's say uh data collection automation, uh data collection, let's say uh
strategy.
Now tell me, I can easily create an agents and I can do the Excel data collection.
Okay, I can easily handle the customer automation. I don't need someone to handle my customer. Let's say whatever customer are coming to my website, okay.
I don't need to like hire someone to sit and reply for that.
So, what I will do, I'll just create an agents, I will give all of the information about my website, all of my services, my agents will take care of everything.
Okay, this is the things nowadays people are moving. Okay, so yeah, trust me, guys, this particular skill is having high demand in the market.
So if you can master this one, definitely you can you can get lots of opportunity, okay.
And I will try to complete this agentic AI in such a way so that after completing it, you can create any kinds of agentic AI applications.
So, in this video, I'm going to discuss about the detailed discussion about agentic AI, how one AI agent works,
how one agentic AI application works.
We'll try to understand each and everything with a good example.
Apart from that, I am going to also discuss about the key characteristics and key component of an agentic AI system.
So, this is going to be one amazing discussion, guys. Make sure you watch till the end.
And if you have any kinds of doubt, feel free to comment in the comment section.
So instead of talking too much, guys, let's start with our discussion.
So, guys, on my screen, I think you have seen the definition of agentic AI. So, this definition is already familiar with you.
Uh, in my previous video, I have already given you the walkthrough.
Let me uh again give you the walkthrough of the definition.
As you can see, Agentic AI is a type of AI that can take up a task or goal from a user and then
work towards completing it on its own with minimal human guidance;
it plans, takes action, adapt to changes,
and seeks helps when necessary.
So, in my previous video, guys, I have given you the demo of a AI agents application. I think I showed you the anti-gravity example. So, there what happens?
Let's say whenever I used to give a prompt, there I give a prompt like just create a game for me, color racing game for me with the help of
Python.
So, what it was doing, it was creating a complete plan.
Okay, I think you remember it was creating a complete plan like what to do, what are the environment it should use, what are the package it should use.
Okay, then what should be the color, what should be the let's say
environment. So it has each and everything it was like making the plan.
Okay, after making the plan, guys, what it started, it was looking for my confirmation, whether if everything is fine or not.
So it was looking for a minimal human interaction, okay, minimal human guidance.
so whenever I approved everything, it started uh taking the actions that means one by one, all of the plan it was starting executing,
right? And it was uh creating that particular games for me, okay.
So that's why uh this definition is uh I think pretty clear, like how one agentic system works. But if I'm talking about a simple chatbot, okay, so in simple chatbot, what happens?
You just try to do some question answer, okay. It will give you the answer with respect to that, but it doesn't have any kinds of let's say tool integration, it doesn't have any kinds of let's say.
Reasoning capacity so that it can automatically think like okay, now I have to use the tool, and now I don't have to use the tool.
Okay, but in agent TKI application, it has the capabilities
for selecting any kinds of tools it's required. Okay, let's say you are uh you are uh doing some automatic coding or let's say you are creating a game, right?
That time what kinds of tools it is required, it will automatically call that tool and it will start creating that particular application for you.
So let me give you one example, guys, how this agentic system works.
So, as you can see, guys, this is the example I have taken.
So, let's say uh this is our agentic agentic system. Okay, this is an agentic AI application.
So let's say uh DSP Bappi uh wants to hire some back-end engineer or let's say some other kinds of engineer.
So, what I have done, I have created this Agentic AI system okay for my platform.
Now, let's say if I'm not using this kinds of platform, so what I have to do, maybe I have to hire someone, okay.
So he will try to or she will try to
prepare everything, okay, for this particular job role. That means the job description, then once the job description is ready, he or she will be posting over different different job platform then
they will continuously monitoring that how many applications are coming.
Once uh application are getting submitted, again they will try to review that.
If application is coming very less, again they will try to update that particular job description with a different job role.
Again, try to upload that.
Okay, that's how they will be continuously monitoring, and once application got submitted, we'll try to review that.
And once reviewed, everything is fine. Okay, let's say we got some amazing candidate, we'll start uh scheduling the interview. will take the interview after uh taking the interview.
What I have to do, I have to
uh I have to actually uh uh prepare uh offer letter for him, then we'll be sending the offer letter, and once the offer letter is approved, then we'll try to
do the onboarding operation. So this is a like very long and time-taking process, and here I have to definitely uh pay for that particular work, right?
let's say the person I'm hiring for this one, so definitely I have to pay for that right, but let's say I don't want to pay because nowadays people are using
agent ki system. So, what I'm going to do, let's say I have created this agent for me.
So, what this agent does, so this agent is already connected with my platform DS with Bhappi. So it is having all the data okay about my uh about my let's say platform,
and I have already told uh this particular agents like what kinds of candidate I want, what kinds of job requirement they are having, what is the salary,
okay. Each and everything I have given uh uh okay uh to this particular agent. Now, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to simply give a prompt.
I want to hire a back-end engineer, and uh they should have two to four years of experience. Okay, let's say this is my prompt.
So, first of all, I think you remember what an agent will do, right?
A agent will first of all try to make a plan.
Okay, an agent will try to make a plan, but how it is going to make the plan, first of all, the command, the prompt you are giving, this command and prompt would be taken as a goal.
So, as you can see, my agent goal is hire a remote backend engineer, okay.
their experience should be two to four years of experience, and this is the plan actually, it has automatically created.
Now, just try to see the plan, okay.
The way actually a manual human will do that, it has done the same thing, okay, but with a revised version.
Now you can see it is giving me a plan.
First of all, it will try to make a draft job description and post on best platform. Okay, let's say LinkedIn it can post, NoCree it can post, okay.
Then some other job platforms are also available.
Okay, so there it will try to post that particular job description.
So once posted, it will continuously monitor the pipeline.
Okay, monitor the pipeline means let's say I have posted a job description. It it uh it doesn't mean that I will just try to disappear, right? Automatically, application will come.
It's it's not like that. You have to continuously monitor that particular application uh job description, like how many applications are coming, uh what are the candidates are applying for?
is there any issue or not? Right, we have to continuously monitor that particular pipeline.
So, what we are going to do, guys,
we'll be continuously monitoring that pipeline. So, agent is also telling we'll monitor the pipeline and adjust strategy if needed.
Okay, so it will automatically adjust okay, this particular strategy if needed.
Let's say you are getting very less application, let's say your expectation is let's say 50 application, but you are receiving four to five application.
That time, definitely this is not meets your expectation, right?
Definitely there should be some problem with the job description, that's why candidate are not preferring that you preferring your job description.
So, what agent will do maybe agent will try to change the job description. Let's say instead of back end engineer, maybe it will tell like fully stack engineer or let's say
fully stack AI engineer, okay, or let's say web developer. This kinds of job role again, it will try to set and again it will prepare the job description, again it will post on the platform, okay.
Then again, it will continuously monitor that particular pipeline. Then let's say now this particular pipeline is working fine.
so people are applying for that particular job role. We are getting lots of candidate.
So, from the all of the candidate guys, we'll try to filter out like what would be the best fit for this job for this particular job rule.
We'll try to select that particular candidate. So agent will try to select that candidate, and maybe let's say it will take two to three candidate and it will schedule uh interviews for them, right?
So once interviews is scheduled, then uh it will uh we'll be taking the interview.
Then after that, uh let's say we selected a candidate, agent will try to draft the say offer letter.
So offer letter would be created and it will be sending to the candidate.
Once candidate is approved, then it will start the onboarding process. Okay, so this is the entire plan it has proposed.
Okay, it has the entire plan it is proposed.
Okay, now after preparing this particular plan, I think you remember it will first of all
okay, it will first of all ask me should I continue with that?
So definitely you have to give a permission.
Yes, continue.
Okay, then what it will do, it will first of all see what is the first plan. First plan is drafting the job job description.
Okay, so it will tell now I will first start with the drafting the job description, taking help from the company documents. Like let's say I have already given my platform access, okay.
DS with Bappi platform access, so it is having all the documents, all the data. Okay, what are the things I am having the requirement?
It will try to take all of the data and it will try to prepare a job description for that. And now it is telling, do you want me to make some changes?
I'll try to review the entire let's say job description if completely fine with me. So I'll just try to tell no, this is absolutely fine, you can continue with that.
Now let's say my agent has prepared one job description for the back end engineer.
Let's say we are looking for a remote backend engineer with two to four years of experience in backend development, blah blah blah. Okay, so once this particular job description is ready.
Now the second plant was posting the job description in a different platform.
Okay, now it will tell all right shall I go ahead and post this job description on the following platforms like LinkedIn, Nokri, etc.
Uh so I will try to review again and again I'll tell to the yes, you can do that.
Then what it will do? It will try to post that particular job description.
Um uh then it will tell I will continuously monitor the application and keep you posted.
And for uh posting this particular job description on a different platform, we have to connect with the API of the platform. Okay, so this particular API we can call it as a tool, okay.
So LinkedIn having a tool, Nocri is having a tool, okay. That's how there are uh thousands of like uh uh I mean job posting platform they're having the tool,
so you just need to give the tool access to the agent.
So agents will try to decide when to call what kinds of tool, okay. Maybe you can't see now. I think it is visible.
So just right hand side you can see uh it is calling the API okay as a tool, and it is trying to access over the LinkedIn and NOCRI,
and it is posting that particular job description in that particular platform.
Okay, so that's how this kind of agent works.
Now, what should be the
next plan?
Let me show you what should be the next plan.
Next plan would be revising the job description. Okay, let's say it was continuously monitoring, okay. It was continuously monitoring the pipeline, then it just received.
you can see the job posted uh posting has received only two applications so far, much below our expectation. Let's say my expectation was 20 application but I'm getting only two applications.
So definitely there would be some problem with my job description. So my agent has suggested me some kinds of
feedback. Okay, you can see it is suggested some action.
so it is telling broaden job description to include fully stack. that means, instead of giving the back end engineer, maybe we can make it to fully stack engineer because fully stack engineer
might have demand in the market. and people are looking for this kinds of job and promote job on LinkedIn, or let's say Nocry.
Okay, so what it is trying to say, it is trying to say, like, why not we can promote that particular
job on the LinkedIn by doing the advertisement?
Okay, maybe by doing the advertisement, uh, it will go to that particular candidate and he or she might be interested and they can apply.
Now it is telling, shall I proceed with that?
So if I'm fine with this particular suggestion, I'll do
yes, please. Okay, you just continue. So this is called actually
what I think you can see the definition.
Let me show you.
See, adapt to changes, okay. Adapt to changes and seeks health when necessary.
Okay, my agent itself is trying to
planning, taking action, and it is doing the changes if it is required, and it is also seeking the help when it necessary.
It is trying to wait for my confirmation and it is doing all of the work for me.
Okay, now what it will do again, it will try to change that particular job description, revised version of job description would be posted, and also
promotion marketing would be activated, then again it will start monitoring the entire process. Okay, so here now
um what it will do, guys, it will try to continuously monitor.
Now, let's say uh here
we are getting our expectation right now. Let's say uh revised job description posted, promotion activated, and it is continuously monitoring.
Now, let's say eight applications received. Okay, this is completely fine.
so what I can do, I can screen them using our checklist strong candidate partial matches and weak matches. Okay, that means it will try to divide all of the candidate in three categories.
The first category would be strong candidate.
Let's say from eight application two are strong, three are partial matches, and three uh weak matches. Okay, so what it will do, it will try to
only select the strong candidate, okay, with respect to my let's say company's requirement.
Now it is telling, shall I schedule the interviews with the top two?
See if everything is goes fine, I'll tell okay, you can continue with that.
Okay, so what it will do, it will try to schedule the interview. But before scheduling, what it will tell, it will first of all try to check my availability.
So, for the availability, what I can do, maybe I can give my calendar access to my agent.
Okay, I think you know that we can integrate any kinds of tools, okay, any kinds of applications to the agents nowadays.
You can connect your Slack, you can connect your calendar, you can connect your Google Drive, anything you can give the access.
Even if you have used already clouded desktop, you will see that clouded desktop, you can also provide your computer access, entire computer access, okay, and you can control your entire computer.
This is also possible, right?
So, what I will do, I will give my calendar access.
So, my agents will try to check my availability.
Okay, now it is telling. Let's say, sure, let me check your ability for this week. You are free on Friday. Let's say I'm free on Friday.
do you want me to schedule the interview on Friday?
So here I will tell.
Yes, go ahead. Okay, I don't have any kinds of issue. I'm completely free on Friday.
Now, what it will do? It will try to draft an uh invitation email
for the candidate. Let's say this is the inter uh email it has prepared.
Hi, candidate, we would like to schedule a 45 minutes of interview uh for the backend engineer role. Please share your availability.
Okay, so this email would be send it, now.
Sixth step, it will try to do the interview process. Okay, so fifth step it was doing the scheduling, then fourth step, it was doing the short listing, okay, and third step.
I think you know it is doing the revision of the job description. Step by step, it is running the plan, okay, not randomly.
Now, once let's say
candidate
accepted the invitation of this interview scheduling, so what will happen? It will try to remind me.
so it will tell quick reminder you have two interviews line up for Friday.
So I'll tell okay, thanks for reminding.
Now it will tell I have mailed you a doc documents containing a list of interview questions asked in previous interview for the same role.
Now it is not only schedule the interview for me, it is also
preparing the interview questions okay for that particular job role and it is giving to me.
Okay, so I'll tell okay, I'll check that.
Now let's say these are my interview question. it has prepared.
Okay, now what I'm going to do, I'm going to
take the interview of the candidate.
Okay. Manually, I'm going to take the interview for the candidate. Let's say 30 to 35 minutes.
I'll take the interview. I will ask all of the questions my agent has suggested.
And if he or she is completely fine with that question, he is able to give me all of the answers. So definitely I'm going to select okay, one of the candidates.
Now let's say I told I have finalized one candidate. Can you draft an offer letter?
My agent will tell sure here is the offer letter. Please review.
I will tell okay, yes, it works. Then offer letter would be send it and tracking the acceptance. Okay, that means this let's say this is my uh offer letter.
Okay, my agent has prepared, it will send to the candidate. Okay, let's say we are pleased to offer you the position of backend engineer. Please let us know.
Um
please let us know if you accept. Okay, so once the candidate has accepted, now what it will do? It will do the onboarding process.
Okay, after sending the offer later it will do the onboarding process.
So here, candidate has accepted the offer. I have initiated the onboarding, welcome email sent it. Access requested submitted, laptop has been provisioned.
Okay, shall I schedule a introduction meeting with him?
I'll tell yes.
So the introduction meeting would be scheduled. Okay, so that's how guys our agent system works with a very minimal human interaction here.
So you just only give to uh you just only need to give a task, you just only need to give a prompt.
Let's say I want that, or you have to do that particular work, it will automatically make the plan, take the actions, and
it will ask for the help when it necessary.
Okay, so this is not possible with a simple chatbot or the simple REG-based application, whatever we used to create previously.
This is only possible in the agentic AI system, okay. And this is called actually AI agents, and every AI agents works in that way.
Okay, first of all, it will try to make a plan, and step by step all of the plan would be executed.
This is called take actions, then adapt the changes. That means whenever it necessary, it will do the changes.
Whenever let's say uh it feels like okay, it needs to ask to the human for the confirmation, it will do that because I can't give full access to my agents to do everything,
because definitely there should be some uh manual human observation, okay. Otherwise, uh some other things might be happen right? So that's why some minimal human interaction is required.
If you take any kinds of agent KI application, whether it's CloudDextop, whether it's your anti-gravity
cursor AI, it works in that way.
Okay, I think I showed you the example of anti-gravity there I was doing the automatic coding, right?
I was implementing a game, so there I give the prompt, it was taking that particular prompt as a goal.
After that, it was creating the plan.
Okay, in the plan itself, step by step, all of the things it has suggested me.
Then I approved everything, it was creating step by step, it was also executing in between.
If any changes required, it was doing that and it is asking for my confirmation.
And once I confirm, it is doing each and everything for me.
Okay, so I think now the agentic system is clear what this agentic system is, how it works. Okay,
now we'll try to understand the key characteristic of a agent KI application.
So, for this, let's go to the next uh actually diagram. As you can see, these are some key characteristic of AI uh AI agents or agent KI applications.
So the first characteristic you can see it should be autonomous.
So definitely the example I have showed you this is completely autonomous agent. So there I only told I I need to hire a back end engineer with two to four years of experience.
So, what is started? it was started creating the plan, taking the actions. Okay, everything was auto auto automatically doing there, right?
It was posting the job description, it was continuously monitoring that, it was uh
asking the help uh yeah uh to me, if I confirm that it will again recontinue the work, so it was completely autonomous,
okay.
Then it should be goal-oriented.
So, definitely the task you are giving it should be taking that particular task as a goal, okay. Without goal, how it will achieve that particular work, right?
So, in in our life, also, whenever we get any kinds of work, whenever we get any kinds of task, definitely we have to take it as a goal.
Okay, if we take it as a goal, then we can complete that particular goal by planning something, right?
We'll do the different different planning, we'll execute those plan and we'll try to achieve that particular goal.
Okay, that's why the next characteristics the planning. So to achieve this goal, we have to make the plan.
That means for this particular example, you saw that it was creating the plan. Like, first of all, job description would be created, posting in the different platform, continuously monitoring.
After that, it will change if it is required, then scheduling the interview,
sending the offer later. It was complete plan, right?
Then reasoning.
So, this is the most important characteristic of an AI agent, the reasoning, and here your LLM comes, right?
Because LLM is the only brain your agentic AI system is having.
With the help of this particular LLM, it performs the reasoning operation and it automatically decides uh whether it needs to call any kinds of tool or not,
because your agents will have connected with different different tools, right?
Different different application sources, and it will automatically decide when it needs to call what kinds of tool.
Let's say whenever it was posting the job description, it needs to call the LinkedIn on Ocry API, right? This is the tool.
Definitely, it will not call the calendar API, right?
So it is automatically thinking in that way.
This is called reasoning, right?
Then adaptability.
Okay, adaptability
it should have it, it will automatically decide uh when to change something.
Okay, what should be the suggestion for that?
Okay, then the context awareness. Context awareness means it should remember the previous context. Let's say I given let's say
I want to hire a back-end engineer.
Let's say today I have given this particular prompt, and for some reason, uh I just uh I went out.
Okay, let's say for two days I went out, then again I came to my agents and I told just tell me the progress about the backend engineer.
Now it is if it doesn't have the context awareness that means the memory integration, that time your agent will tell what kinds of back-end engineering you are uh
telling me, right?
what is the task you are telling me? I don't know about that, but if it is having the context awareness that means the memory, it can tell okay.
So this is the progress I have already posted the job description, continuously monitoring, and let's say eight to nine application I got so far.
So this is called context awareness, and every agent application should have this particular context awareness.
Okay, so guys, now let's try to see the detailed discussion of each and every characteristic.
so here I have already listed down each and everything.
So, first of all, let's try to understand this uh autonomy.
Okay, this autonomy means the autonomous, the first characteristic.
So, as you can see, autonomy refers uh to the AI system's ability to make decisions and take actions on its own to achieve a given goal without needing step-by-step human interaction.
That means if you have already seen the example of our AI recruiter, so there it was kinds of autonomous,
okay. It was uh it was autonomous agent, and it will it doesn't need any kinds of step-by-step human interaction.
So, there I was not giving step-by-step human interaction, I was not giving step-by-step prompt what to do, right?
So, the things is that I have only given my requirement, my goal.
So, it took that particular prompt as a goal, it was creating the plan, it was executing step by step.
That's why you can see it is proactive, that means continuously it is working on that particular goal.
Then autonomy in multiple facts like execution, it was executing the plan step by step, it was doing the decision making.
Okay, uh, by the decision itself, it was uh thinking like what to do when it needs to post it on different different platform when it needs to make the changes,
then tool uses okay. Let's say when to use what kinds of tool.
Let's say whenever I want to post the job description, what kinds of tool I need to call? Definitely to call the LinkedIn
and Knockri,
right? So, this kinds of ability my autonomous agents will be having. That's why the first characteristic, the autonomy.
We can also call it as a autonomous, right?
Now, the thing is that autonomy can be controlled, permission scopes.
That means you can limit what uh what uh tools or actions the agents can perform independent uh independently, can screen
candidate but needs approval before rejecting anyone.
Okay, that means it's not like that. I am given the full autonomous permission to my agents, so definitely you can set the limit, you can set the permission.
So let's say once uh one interviewer.
having the screening round, uh, so before approval or rejecting, so definitely I have to see that manually, then I will approve that. Then my agents will do that for me.
Then human in loop, we can also call it as a HITL.
So insert checkpoints where human input is required before continuing.
That means in this case, let's say my agent was telling can I post this particular job description or not? Okay, this is called human in loop, and every agents are having this kinds of functionality.
Okay, going forward, we'll be implementing the agents, right? with different different uh
framework. So there also you are having this kinds of functionality with the help of that.
You can uh you can actually create this kinds of system whenever your agent is needed your human approval, it will ask for that, then you can continue and it will start working on that.
Then override controls allow users to stop, pause, or change the agent's behavior at any time.
Pause screening command to
halt resume process. Okay, so what happens? Let's say in my agents, okay, whatever I am doing, it's completely fine, but it should have
it should have my control. Okay, my control means let's say I can stop this particular agents anytime, I can pause anytime. Let's say my
screening round is going on in between. If I feel like okay, I have to stop the screening route.
I if I give the command, it should stop that.
Okay, it should stop the process that time.
Okay, so this is called actually override controls, then guardrails and policies.
So definitely your agent should have guardrails and policies nowadays. You will see that agent integrates different different guardrails, okay.
And for this, one framework came in the market called guardrails AI.
With the help of that, you can define hard rules or ethical boundaries to the agent must follow.
That means, let's see if I give one example,
it will tell never schedule
interview on weekends. Let's say weekends I'm completely occupied, I'm not available. So I can give the restriction, I can give the rules, never schedule interviews on weekends.
So my agent will never do that.
And if you see now it is all the agent AKI application is having these kinds of guardrails and policies.
Let's see if you are asking any kinds of violating content, if you're asking any kinds of sexual content, if you're asking any kinds of let's say
adult content, definitely it will not give you the response with respect to that because it has a guardrails and policies restriction in the agent itself.
Okay, and for this, we are having some library where having some framework definitely will also see in our playlist itself.
Okay, then
autonomy can be dangerous. The application uh auton autonomously sent uh sends out job offers with incorrect salaries or terms.
So if you completely make it automated, so what we'll do, there is a possibility your agents will send a job later with incorrect salaries.
Let's say your budget is one lakh, but your agent is sending the expected salary 10 lakhs, right? So definitely this is going to be an issue.
So that time the applications shortlisted candidate by age or nationality violating anti-discrimination laws. Okay, this is another uh Trump's, then the application spending extra
on LinkedIn ads. Let's say sometimes what will happen if it is running autonomously, although you are getting a good let's say application
from your job description, but still your agent will feel like okay, I need more and it is spending more money on LinkedIn ads.
Okay, so these kinds of things definitely you have to uh overcamp okay by actually doing the human in loop
HITL okay functionality inside your agent. Now the next things we are having, which is
this goal oriented.
Okay, goal-oriented. Now you can see what is goal-oriented.
Being a goal-oriented means that the AI system operates with a persistent objective in mind and continuously directs its actions to achieve that object
rather than just responding to the isolated prompts.
Okay, that means if you read here, you will see that
goal acts as a compass for an autonomy. Okay, so to make your agent autonomous, definitely there should be a goal.
In this case, our goal was hire a back-end engineer.
Okay, this was the goal and will act as a compass for the autonomy.
That means your autonomous agent should follow this particular goal, and to achieve this goal, it needs to execute different different plan.
Okay, now goal can be a goal can come with constraint. Definitely, you can set some constraint.
In this case, let's say my constraint was for two uh two to four years of experience candidate. I only once okay, then goals are stored in the core memory.
That means goal should be stored in the core memory, that means in the context awareness memory, otherwise, your agent will forget that. What to do, right?
Let's say if I give you a basic uh actually template, the common template for all the agents, it stores the data in the memory.
So this is a JSON format. Let's say you can store any kinds of database here.
internally, agent uses a specific database or storage services and it stores these kinds of metadata so that it can remember.
So, in this case, let's say the goal was hire a back-end engineer, the constraint was two to four years of experience, remote is true,
stack Python, Django, cloud. Okay, these are the skills I'm looking for.
Status is active, my agent is always active.
When I
posted the job description, this particular date would be also saved.
Progress job description is created, true.
If not created, it should be false. Okay, posted on different platform like LinkedIn and Angel list or NOCRI.
Yeah, it has posted, and this is the list.
How many application received so far?
Only eight applications, interview schedules with two applications. Okay, so this is the storing uh I mean strategy for every agents.
So let's say each and every framework is having different way they stores the data, but this is the common.
If I tell uh one common let's say structure, so this is the common structure, that's how the goal should be stored in the core memory.
Okay, all the uh running instance metadata would be saved in the core memory, that's how it usually saves, and it will take that particular data from the memory itself to
continue the plan to continue the goal.
Okay, that's how one agent remembers it and everything.
Now I think you are getting now. Goals can be altered as well. Let's say once you have set one goal, you can also change that particular goal to another one.
This is also possible here, okay. Now the next characteristic it is the planning.
Okay, planning.
So you can see planning is is the agent's ability to break down a high-level goal into structured sequence of actions or sub-goals and decide the best path to achieve the desired outcome.
Okay, that means let's say I have given a prompt, I have to hire a back-end engineer.
Now, to achieve this particular goal, what this agent has to do, agent has to create a
different different okay.
Agent has to create a different different plan.
I think you saw that what was the plan.
So for that particular example, it was preparing the job description, posting on different different platform.
Okay, then it was continuously monitoring that this was the plan.
Now, whenever it is planning, you'll see that generating multiple candidate plans. It will only not let's say proposed one plan, it might give you multiple plan.
Okay, let's say plan A, post the job description on LinkedIn, GitHub, jobs, or Angel list.
Okay, plan B is that use internal referrals, okay, and hiring agencies.
So it has suggested you two plans now.
It is asking for your feedback, okay.
Now, based on your choice, you can select which plan you want to go ahead with.
So whenever your agent
agents are working, it has the reasoning capacity that means it should also minimize my cost, right?
And if it is suggesting me to plan.
So definitely if I'm taking the plan A, so there I will I will uh let's say spend less less amount because here I
directly post on LinkedIn, GitHub Jobs, and handle list. Okay, but if I'm taking the plan B, if I'm taking some hiring agency, so definitely I have to take their subscription plan, right?
So there I have to pay more money.
So get it.
So that's why it is giving you different different
Okay, then evaluate its plan. As I all told you, agents will itself evaluate the plan. Let's say plan A is perfect or plan B is perfect for this particular work.
Based on that, it will give you the suggestion.
Then the efficiency, which is faster. So if I'm going with plan A or plan B, which is faster. So definitely plan
A is a little bit faster because I can directly
post the jobs on the platform itself and get the applications.
Okay, then which one is having less cost? Definitely plan A is having less cost, then risk.
Will it fail if we get no applications?
Okay, then alignment with constraints, remote jobs only budget.
Okay, so these are my
steps inside the plan.
So, based on this particular evaluation steps, it will select the plan.
Okay, now third step select the best plan with the help of human in loop.
That means it will definitely ask to the human for the best plan which one you would like to go ahead. So, which of this option do you prefer?
A pre-programming policy, uh favor low cost channel first. Okay, so definitely whenever I will take any kinds of plan, I will try to check this particular low-cost
okay, uh, option in my mind.
So, yes, uh, this was the uh I mean characteristic which is planning. Now, the next characteristic the reasoning.
Now, let's try to understand this reasoning, guys.
So, what is reasoning? First of all, let's try to understand. As you can see, reasoning is the cognitive process through which an agent KI system interprets information, draws conclusions,
and makes decisions both while planning ahead and while executing the actions in real time.
Reasoning during planning goals, decompositions, breakdown, abstract goals into cons uh concrete steps, tool selection decide
which tool will be needed for which step, resource estimation, estimated time, dependencies, and risk. Okay, as I already told you, whenever a agentic system is working,
it will be working with respect to the reasoning because behind the reasoning one LLM works, right?
And LLM has the actually intelligence capacity so that it can understand and it can automatically make the decision,
it can automatically let's say break down the goals, okay.
It can automatically tell you what kinds of tools should be selected. You can also uh like work on the resources estimations like estimated time, dependencies, and risk.
Okay, so with the help of this reasoning, guys, these agents would be more powerful, more efficient.
Why? Because I told you
if one agent is one agent doesn't have the reasoning capacity, that means this should be the simple chatbot only.
Okay, this should be the simple chatbot only.
Why a chatbot is different from uh AI agent?
Okay, why AI agent is powerful because of this reasoning, okay.
Let's say if I'm having an agent, if I'm giving any kinds of input and it is connected with different different tools, right?
Some kinds of tools it is connected now.
Whenever I'm giving an input, now this will perform this reasoning operation, it will decide the question human is asking whether I have to directly give the answer,
I have to refer the tool for that.
Okay, so this is called actually reasoning. So reasoning is super important here, okay.
Now, here you can see
reasoning, duration, execution, decision making, choosing between option, uh, three candidate matches, schedule uh for two
uh two
uh best candidate and reject one. So this kind of decision making is taking your
agent, okay, with the help of this reasoning with the help of this LLM.
Now HITL handling.
Knowing when to pause and ask for help, unsure about the salary range.
Okay, for an example, let's say with the help of this reasoning, it is automatically decide when it should ask for the help to the human when it needs to ask for the confirmation from the human.
Okay, in this case, let's say my my recruiter agent is asking what should be the salary range, just try to tell me, then error handling,
interpreting tools, API failure, and
recovering. Okay, let's say sometimes some of the tool might be down, right? That time, how this particular agent will handle that particular error.
Let's say if my tool A is not working, so definitely it will try to move to tool B.
Okay, so this kinds of ability, this reasoning will be having.
Now, the next one adaptability.
So, what is adaptability? You can see adaptability is the agent's ability to modify its plan, strategies, or action, responses to unexpected conditions, all while staying aligned with the goal.
Okay, so that means I told you, let's say in that particular case, I think you remember,
uh, we got very less application, right?
And my agent was automatically give you the suggestion, and it was it was telling, like, I need to change the job description to back end engineering to
full stack engineer. So, this is called adaptability. Your agent is automatically modifying the plans, modifying the strategy, then again it is working with respect to that.
Okay, you can see failures in uh then external feedbacks and changing the goals.
Okay, now what is the next next uh
characteristic is the context awareness.
I already told you what is context awareness, context awareness is the agent's ability to understand, retain, and utilize relevant information from uh
from the ongoing task, past introduction, user preferences, and environmental uh cues to make better decisions through the multiple steps.
Okay, and if I'm talking about content context awareness, this is nothing but it's a memory.
Okay, you can see context awareness is implemented through memory.
Here we create two kinds of memory: one is short memory, one is long long-term memory, short-term memory and long-term memory. So, as you can see,
uh, if my uh agent doesn't have the context of my previous, let's say, uh goals or plan, so then how it will progress
the current one. So, definitely to run the current progress, it should have the previous context, right?
So, let's say in this case, I have given I want to have a back end engineer with two to four years of experience,
so it should have this kinds of information in the context memory based on that, it will make the decision. Okay, this is what actually it is explaining, and what are the tool responses it is getting?
Definitely, it will also try to
uh store that particular responses to the context memory so that it can give you the better response with respect to that.
Now, at the end, this context awareness implemented through memory. So here we create short-term memory and long-term memory. Short-term memory we create for the current state.
Let's say if one current state is running, if it is creating some metadata, we will be storing in the short-term memory, and long-term memory means the whole conversation, the whole
user introduction it is doing, it should have the
present in the long-term memory. Okay, so this is the idea.
So, yes, guys, these are some characteristic we usually have inside any kinds of AI agents, and how you will understand this particular application is a AI agents
application or agent TKI application.
If this application is having these kinds of characteristic definitely you can think about this is a agent KI application.
Okay, definitely in the architecture itself, these kinds of characteristics uh characteristics should be mentioned.
So, guys, now we'll try to see the components of agent KI application. What are the component one AI agent is having?
Uh, using uh you can see the first component is the brain.
Okay, whenever I'm talking about the brain, so here LLM would be utilized.
You can use any kinds of LLM here.
So LLM has the reasoning capacity.
with the help of that, it will make the decisions, it will try to do the HITL operation, it will do the tool selections.
Okay, all the operations will be happening with respect to this particular brain, and the second is the orchestrator.
So, what is orchestrator to build an entire agent TKI system?
Okay,
we need some orchestrator.
Orchestrator means this is the framework,
okay. Framework, let's say it will do the connection with the LLM that means brain, it will make the connection with tool,
then whenever it is required for the tool calling, it will perform the tool calling operation. Whenever it is required, let's say it will uh uh call the uh
ITL that means human in loop, right? It will ask for the uh approval from the human.
So these kinds of things. If I want to create a complete agent KI application, I need to use some framework.
I can't create with the help of simple Python or I can't create with the help of simple TensorFlow, right?
Or lang chain. This is not possible, so I have to use some end-to-end framework for that.
Okay, so in the market, there is some famous framework like we are having crew AI,
okay. We are having
Langgraph,
we are having Autogen,
Some some no code platform is also available, like N8N.
Okay, so apart apart from that, some other like framework are also available, but these are framework actually very uh common and very popular and very powerful in the market nowadays,
and people use that developer use that to create agent DKI applications.
Okay, so throughout the entire um this course, guys, we'll try to master these are the frameworks we'll see the entire crew AI framework, we'll try to develop uh AI agents with the help of crew
AI, okay. Into a multi-agent system, we'll try to create then Langgraph. We'll try to explore, we'll try to create end to end application with Lang Graph.
We'll try to see the autogen, we'll try to understand the entire auto gen autogen component.
We'll create the AI agents with autogen, we'll try to see some no-code platform as well, like n8n.
We'll see how we can create the AI agents without writing any kinds of code by doing some drag and drop operation.
Each and everything will be learning, okay. So that's why orchestrator is also required, and this is one other component of a AI agent.
An orchestrator means AI agent building framework.
Okay, always remember.
Langchain can be also utilized with the help of Langchain. Also, you can create some of the simple agents, but
later on Langchain published actually Langgraph, so people are moving to the Langgraph for building these kinds of AI agents. Okay, now the next one is the tool.
So definitely
tool should be available as a component.
Here we can utilize any kinds of tool, whether it's any kinds of search tool, whether it is any kinds of calendar tool or any kinds of application tool.
Okay, if you just open the internet and if you search like agentic AI tool list, okay, you will see that there are thousands of tool listers available, okay.
Whether it is search, whether it is any kinds of application with your Google Drive, with your calendar. So let me show you some of the list.
So, guys, as you can see, there is a GitHub called AI Agent Tools catalog, and there is some other website as well you will be getting over the internet. So if you open it, open this up.
So this this is having all kinds of tool, tools and toolkit as you can see.
so we are having archive so tools to read archive papers.
So I think you know if we read any kinds of research paper, we go to the archive website, okay.
archive.org. So this is also a tool.
Uh, this tool is available in the framework itself. You can use this tool for reading any kinds of research paper.
You can connect your AI agents with the research paper, uh, actually, wild. Okay, then uh by do search is there, Bing search is there, Brave search is there. These are my search tool.
Okay, then code doc search is there, CSV search is there.
That's how you can see Google search is there.
We are having different different tools, okay. So, this is for the code interpreter, okay. These are the code interpreter. If you want to interpret any kinds of code, these tools you can use.
If you want to do the productivity, these tools you can use.
Okay, you can connect with your calendar, email, zoom.
Okay, this is for regular automation.
Now, this is for web browsing. If you want to browse the web, this tool you can use.
If you want to connect with the database, these are the database tools are available.
If you want to do the file operation, these are the tools are available. Okay, so that's how whatever tool you want, everything is available.
Okay, in the orchestrator framework, in the AI agents, you can connect with anyone, okay.
Now, next we are having the memory.
Memory is another component.
So I told you context awareness is required. So here we use something called memory.
Okay, so memory should be also integrated, and for memory development, uh we use orchestrator framework. In the orchestrator framework itself, we are having different different memory functions.
Either you can also use different different database for the memory, you can do anything here.
Then the supervisor.
So this is the
H I T L that means human in loop.
Okay, human in the loop.
So with the help of the supervisor, what it does it try uh it's try to interact with the human when any help is required, it will try to help uh ask for the help, it will
ask for the human guidance or feedback, and it will continue the agents.
Okay, so these six actually components uh sorry, five components are available in any kinds of AI agents, and this is the high level actually diagram I have shown you.
Some other component might be available as low level, but this is the main one, okay. So if you find these are the components are available inside AI agents, yeah, you can I mean
select that particular application as an agent application, and whenever you are creating, you have to take care of these are the components okay inside your application.
Now, let me
show you the component explanation. As I already told you, the brain-wise here, what we do, we use a large language model, and what is the use of large language model, the goal interpretation,
planning, reasoning, tool selections. Okay, everything is uh everything we do with the help of this particular brain or large language model. The orchestrator orchestrator is a framework,
uh, AI agents implementation framework with the help of uh we can do task sequencing, conditional routing, retiring logic, looping iterations, and delegations. Okay, then tools we are having.
So tools with the help of tools we can connect our AI agents with external sources, okay.
and to knowledge base as well. let's see if you're creating a rack-based agents at time, our knowledge base should be external sources. Okay, this is this would be perform as a tool that time.
Now, the next component I told you the memory. So, what memory does so memory actually basically
stores all of the context of the conversation, and we create actually two kinds of memory short-term memory and long-term memory, and it will
do the straight uh tracking, okay.
Um, restrict tracking is required. I already told you, I already showed you previously, right? Uh, it was uh storing the data in the JSON format, so this is also required.
Then the supervisor, so approval uh requests for HITL, that means human in the loop, then guardrils uh enforcement,
then edge case uh escalation. Okay, so let's say if you want to block some unsafe uh non uh compliant behavior, you can use the guardrails evaluation.
I will also show you how to perform the guardrails evaluation and uh age uh case uh escalation that means alert human when uncertainty
conflict arises. Okay, and you already understood about this uh HTIL okay, human in loop, uh human in the loop format.
So, yes, guys, these are some components are available uh of AI agents, and whenever we are developing our own AI agents, we have to take care these are the part.
and every AI agents are having these kinds of
component idea uh nowadays. Okay, so apart from that, I think uh uh there is nothing uh inside AI agents.
If you feel like okay, if there is any new things, you can just do let me know in the comment section. Definitely I'll try to cover that as well.
Okay, but so far my understanding, I think these are some uh we have to follow whenever we are creating or whenever we are working on agentic AI system.
So, yes, guys, uh, this is all about uh from this video.
I hope you have understood and this was helpful for you.
I think I already told you uh in my previous uh video, uh, like there are uh some components are available, especially whenever I'm talking about uh the agentic AI.
Uh, one of the component is the orchestrator, right?
Orchestrator means there we use some kinds of framework. Okay, with the help of these are the framework we create we implement the AI agents, whether it's a single agent, whether it's a multi
AI agent system, we try to create these kinds of things, right.
So there is a concept, guys. you have to understand before I start with this kinds of orchestrator framework.
The concept name is asynchronous programming. Okay, so why this asynchronous programming is required?
because if you see,
going forward, we'll be creating the multi-agent system, and to create the multi-agent system, guys, we'll be using this kinds of orchestrator framework,
and internally, this orchestrator framework uses asynchronous programming.
Okay, that means it will run your agents in parallel.
Let's say you have created 20 agents.
So, what it will do instead of running agents as a sequentially, it will run all of the agents in parallel so that your execution would be more fast.
So, this concept I'm going to discuss in detail, guys. No need to worry.
first of all, let me show you one thing actually.
I have just figured out.
Let's say if I go to the Google, so here if I search like is Langgraph uses asynchronous in the back end for multi-agents.
So I think you know Langgraph is one of the orchestrator framework.
With the help of Langgraph, we create agentic AI applications, right? And we'll be also mastering this Langgraph inside our codes.
So as you can see, the response was yes, Langgraph is uh designed with first class asynchronous supports in the back end for multi-agent
system.
That means it is utilizing the asynchronous programming, asynchronous concept in the backend.
Okay.
Now, if I just go below, let's say I have asked for about the autogen because autogen also will be covering inside our course.
So, as you can see, autogen also utilizes asynchronous programming at its core, but it is uh
architecture fundamentally different from the Langgraph state uh Langraph's state machine approach, but internally it is uses asynchronous programming concept.
Now, again, I asked like
what about crew AI?
Okay, so you can see crew AI also supports asynchronous execution, but it approaches orchestration differently than Langgraph and Autogen, while uh Langraph uses
a state machine and autogen uses an actor model, crew AI is built around role-based collaboration and process-driven execution model.
Okay, but the main fund is that all of the orchestrator framework we are using for developing these kinds of multi-agents application
internally, it is uses asynchronous, okay. Asynchronous programming.
Now, before I start with these are the orchestrator framework, first of all, I want to clarify what is asynchronous programming, why it is required, how asynchronous works, okay,
what is parallelism, what is
let's say sequential execution, each and everything I'm going to clarify.
Then we'll start with the orchestrator framework understanding.
But after that, there is one more topic we have to cover, which is nothing but piedentic
validation. This is also important because you will see that whatever large language model we are having, it will generate the unstructured output, and to make it structured, even
whenever we are giving any kinds of prompt to make our prompt more structured, we use this piedentic validation.
Okay, so this piedentic validation will be understanding in the next video, but in this video, I will only focus on the asynchronous understanding.
Okay, so here I'm going to give you the detailed understanding of asynchronous with a theoretical understanding as well as the practical understanding as well.
So let me show you guys what is this asynchronous.
After that, your understanding would be more clear, and you can easily understand these are the framework whenever you will be doing the coding.
So let me give you the definition of the asynchronous programming. So here is the definition.
here is the simple definition you can see asynchronous programming in Python.
Okay, you can see asynchronous programming in Python is a programming paradigm that allows code to handle okay multiple tasks
concurrently without blocking the program's execution. It is primarily used to IO bound task, example network request, file input and output operation, database
queries, okay, allowing the program to perform other operations while waiting for slow external events to complete. That means this at in asynchronous programming will help you, okay.
Asynchronous programming will help you, okay. Asynchronous programming will help you to run your task in parallel. Okay, so you are not supposed to wait for the execution.
Let's say we know that we use synchronous programming so far, yes or no, guys. We use synchronous programming so far. In synchronous programming, what happens?
Let's say if I execute a code block, first of all, it will complete that. Okay, after the execution is complete, okay, then it will execute the second part of that particular code.
Okay, but in between, let's see if you are waiting for the execution, okay, if you are using asynchronous programming, it can run another task in parallel.
Okay, so these are the like say functionality we'll be getting here. Now you can ask me why this is required, okay. Why this asynchronous programming is required inside AI agents implementation.
Agentic AI, You can create two kinds of agent, one is the simple agent, okay, one is the simple agent. So basically, simple agents you create
only one block, okay? It can only handle one particular task, okay.
But whenever let's say you have complex problem, you have to divide the task in smaller chunks, and what you will do, you will be creating multiple agents,
okay.
Multiple agents you will be creating. Let's say this is agent one, this is agent two, this is agent three. Okay, and what will happen?
You will assign the task for all the agents, and these agents will be executing either independently, independently
or dependently.
Okay, dependently.
So it's your design philosophy. If you are making it as an independently, that time it will run as an independently.
If you are making it to dependent, okay, it will run as a dependently. So basically, what happens? Let's say if you run these are the agents, okay. These are the agents in a synchronous programming.
Okay, in a synchronous programming, what will happen? First of all, these agents need to be completed. This agents execution need to be completed.
Once this agent one this agents will be executed, then it will move to the next agents, okay?
Next code block. Then this agents will be executed. Okay, once it is completed, then it will go to this particular agents, okay? Then it will try to run this particular agent.
So let's say this agents is taking three minutes to run. Sorry, let's say here I can just tell you.
Let's say this agents is taking one minute to run. these agents is also taking let's say 1.5 minutes to run. Okay, this agency is also taking let's say one minute to run. So what is happening?
You have to wait for one minute again. You have to wait for what point five minute again, you have to wait for one minute.
Okay, so if you like add all of the time, you will see that at the end you are having okay, 3.5 minutes. 3.5 minutes you have to wait for the execution.
But if you run this task in parallel, okay, if you run this task in parallel, let's say this particular agents will do the online search operation.
So basically, if you are doing the online search operation, you will be hitting some URL, right? Rive URL, and to get the response, this will take some time.
Let's say sometimes this web server might be slow, that time it will be giving you slow response. So instead of waiting for that, you can execute your other agents.
So let's say these agents will try to collect the images, these agents will try to collect the let's say.
Any other file okay from the internet. So don't wait to execute any other agents, just try to run them in a synchronous way, okay, in a parallel way.
So each of the agents will be running in a parallel way. So let's say this if this agent is also taking one minute, okay.
So simultaneously you are running something okay in the back end, so you are not supposed to wait for 3.5 minutes.
Get it? So that is the things I just wanted to tell you.
So let's say whenever you are creating multi-agent system, and whenever you are creating let's say independent connection, okay, independent let's say policy,
that time you should use this asynchronous programming inside um inside let's say python or let's say whatever programming you're using, you have to follow that.
And if you see any kinds of agents code, you will be seeing people are using this async, okay. Uh ascens
this particular syntax, people are using that, okay. So, what is this async? Async means asynchronous, okay, asynchronous functionality.
So in Python there is a library called Asynth.io, so we'll be following the particular library to implement this particular code, okay?
So let me give you one example of asynchronous and synchronous programming. So let's say here I can write synchronous
and this side we have asynchronous programming.
So
in synchronous programming, what happens? Let's say
what I can do, I can give you one example
let's say here
let's say you are you are having a
you are having a
gas stove, okay? Gas stove
in this gas stove you only have one
one fire section, okay, one fire section. So let's say you are having uh three dishes, okay. You are having three dishes
to cook.
So what you will do, first of all, you will take the first dish and you will cook that.
Once first dish is complete, then you will take the second dish, then you have to complete, then you will be taking the third dish, then you will be completing.
Okay, that's how you can see it is taking T1, it is taking T2, it is taking T3 time.
Okay, so basically you have to wait for uh you have to wait for the previous execution or let's say previous task to be completed, then you can start the remaining task.
But in asynchronous programming, what happens?
Let's say you are having same gas stop, but here you are having let's say three fired section, you are having three fired sections, and you are having three dishes.
Okay, let's say dish one,
dish two,
and dish three. So, what you have to do? You just need to
run all of them simultaneously.
Basically, you are giving three dish to the three fired section. Okay, now at the t1 time, okay, your all of the dishes should be completed, so you are not supposed to wait for the t1, t2, and t3
to be completed. Okay, so this is the difference between synchronous programming and asynchronous programming. I hope you get it, guys.
So in Python, we usually follow the synchronous programming, that means if you are running a function, first of all, that function would be completed, then the remaining code would be executed.
Now, in programming, we we call it as a subroutine.
Let me just write here
subroutine.
And we also call it as coroutine.
I'll be discussing about what is this.
Okay, coroutine.
So, what is subroutine? So, let me write a program to explain. Let's say here I can write a function. So, I'll just write a function. Let's say def.
Okay, def. So, let's say I will
I'll give the function name
fetch.
Okay, fetch let's say data.
This is the function name. So
it is having some code inside that.
Okay, now here I am creating another function. Let's say def main.
Okay. Now what I am doing, I am calling this particular function, okay. This function inside this particular main function fetch
data.
Okay, I'm calling inside that
I'm calling inside that.
Sorry, yeah.
Now after calling, let's say in this main function also there are some code line.
So what is happening here? Let's say if you're if you're using subroutine, so that time whenever you are executing your code, first of all,
your code will come here. Okay, your code will come here and it will see you are calling a function inside that. Which function you are calling this particular function, okay.
Now what it will what will happen? First of all, it will go to this function and it will execute all of the code. It will execute all of the code. Now let's say you are running fetch data.
That means let's say you are trying to fetch some kinds of data from the internet, you are using some kinds of API, some kinds of URL.
Okay, and whenever it is hitting that particular API or URL, it is taking some kinds of time, right? So you have to wait for this particular time.
So see, once this time is over, that means this execution is over, then you will be able to execute your remaining code,
okay. Till then you have to wait for this execution, okay. So this is the idea of serve routine.
That means you are waiting for a task to be completed, then your remaining code would be executed, then your remaining code would be executed.
Although you are waiting here, although you are waiting here, you don't have any kinds of other tasks, you just need to wait for the execution, okay.
And once execution is completed, then you will be able to execute, you'll be able to see the other execution of the program. But in code routine, what happens?
So let's say here I'm having a function, here I'm having a function, and we use something called asynchronous, okay. Asynchronous syntax. So for this we use something called ascens, uh, ascense.
Okay, this is the keyword ascens. So we'll write the function as def, let's say fetch
data.
This is the function. that's inside that you are having some kinds of code.
Okay, now again you are having a main function here. So I'll just write diff
main.
So what you are doing, you are calling this particular um okay, you are calling this particular function dev sorry
okay, fetch data.
You are calling that, and inside main you are having some other code, okay. You are having some other code as well. Now, what is happening?
Just try to see whenever your Python will come here, it will see that you are executing a function. Which function?
This function you are executing, and it will see this particular keyword called essence.
Okay, that that time Python will automatically understand that this code you have written it will run in asynchronous way.
That means let's say here you are doing an API call and it is taking some time t1.
Okay, instead of waiting for this particular time, again it will come here, okay, and execute the remaining code you have, okay.
After this function, that means at the T time itself, this code would be executed and this code would be also executed. So you are not supposed to wait for the previous execution.
So this is called coroutine.
And if you're using this as since these are the things, so it internally uses this concept, and now we'll go for the practical, we'll try to see like
practically everything how it works. then I think your understanding would be more clear.
Okay, first of all, I'm going to explain the synchronous programming.
Okay,
now here I'm going to write two function. Let's say
for the first function, I'm going to write uh fitch
fitch by that.
And the second function I'm going to create
fetch news. fetch
news, okay
Now what I'm going to do, I'm going to
import the time module as well, just to see the execution time.
So import
time.
Now inside that, as of now, I'm not going to write any logic, simply I'm going to write just a print statement. I'm going to give let's say fetching weather data.
Then here I'm going to just mention a time.
Uh let's say to fetch the weather data, you have to wait for some time. Okay, so this time I'm going to assign with the help of this time module.
So here I'm going to give, let's say I will be waiting for four seconds. Okay. Four seconds. So it it is for the simulate a network delay. Let's say if you are hitting any kinds of API.
So definitely to get the response, you have to wait for some time. So let's say this time I have set four seconds here. Okay. Now once we stop for four four seconds.
Now simply I'm going to just print. Let's say weather data fetched. Okay. So this message I'm going to write.
Now, similar wise, here also I'm going to write uh I'm going to write facing facing news data, and
again I will give some time. Let's say here I have given two seconds, and once my data uh news fetching is done, so I'll tell news data fetched.
Okay, so as of now just try to consider this is a function, this will fetch the weather information and this will fetch the news. Okay.
Now if you see this function and this function doesn't have any dependency, these two functions are independent, okay. These two functions are independent.
That means if you want to fetch the weather, you don't need the news. If you want to fetch the news, you don't need the weather, so these are independent function, okay.
But once I will execute this code, okay. Let's say if if I write another function here, I'll just write another function def main.
Okay, in the main function, I'm going to call uh I'm going to call this to function.
See, first of all, I'm starting the time just to see the time, like how much time it takes to execute the two functions.
So that's why I starting the uh start, I'm taking the start time, then I'm calling this two function together, fetch weather and fetch news. You can see fetch weather and fetch news.
I'm calling, then I'm taking the end time, then I'm doing the subtract operation from end time to start time, and this will be uh this will be
my execution time of my program. But if you see here, these two functions are independent. This these two functions is not dependent. Although it's independent, okay, it's not dependent. So
whenever you will call the function, you have to wait for the you have to wait for the previous function to be completed to run the next function. This is the issue, okay?
So I can see these two functions are completely independent, but whenever I'm calling this function, first of all, this function will execute.
So let's say whenever you will execute the program, so your interpreter will come here, okay.
Your interpreter will come here, then it will go inside this particular function, then it will execute all of the code, and here it will wait for the four seconds,
okay. Four seconds it will try to wait. But see, in the four four seconds, it doesn't have any work to do, so it will be waiting.
Then once four second is over, this code would be executed, then your program will come here, okay. Then it will be executed.
That means first of all, the previous function would be executed, then the next function would be executed. So you can also check.
So let's say if I want to show you, so I'll call this particular main function here.
Okay, I'll call this main function now. If I execute, see facing weather, it is waiting for four seconds.
Now weather fetch. Now see facing news. Now it wait for two seconds, then news face, and total time taken. You can see six point something seconds.
Okay, now you can also take this code in one of the amazing website called Python Tutor, python tutor.com. Here also you can visualize this code.
Let me open the Python tutor.
Now I'll select the Python programming.
I'll paste my code here
visualize the execution.
Okay.
Now it has started. Okay, it has started. Now simply time is not defined. So okay, so the basically I need to import the time here, right? So let's edit the code.
So here I'll import the time module.
for time
Now I'll visualize the execution.
Import time. It is giving you an error. Time fo not found or supported. Only these modules can be imported. Okay, because this is a like uh website, okay. Python tutor website.
So here you can you can't import any. let's say these are the library you can you can import, but some other library you can't import. So for this, what I can do, I can remove the time as of now.
I just wanted to only just let you know that how it is executing.
Let's say I will also remove the time part.
here also remove the time part here. Also, and here also.
let's say this is my masses.
Okay, so this is my simple masses.
Let's say
executed
now. Simply do the visualization.
Okay, now see.
here I have the control. So, first of all, Python interpreter will come here.
Uh, it has seen like here I am having a function called fetch weather. then it will go to the next line that is next function.
then
it will go to the next function, which is main.
and in the main function, you can see, uh, I'm calling here. this particular main function. so it will go enter into the main function, and it will see like I'm calling fetch weather function.
Okay, so it will go inside fetch weather and it will do all of the operation.
Okay, see it is doing all of the operation now. Let's say this function is taking some time, so it will wait, okay. It will wait for two minutes, one minute, okay.
How much time it is taking, it will try to wait for that. So once execution is completed, then again it will come here, okay. Then you can see it will execute another function which is fetch news.
Now again, it will go inside fetch news and it will do all of the execution and try to come here. That means you have to wait, okay.
You have to wait for the previous execution to be complete, then you will be able to run the new code. Okay, that's how you have to wait.
Okay, you have to wait for the previous execution, and definitely it is taking lots of time.
And now just try to consider if you are running a multiple agents together and if it is running synchronously, so first of all, first agent would be completed, second agent would be completed.
So, execution time it will take more that time. We run it is an asynchronous way, so that we are not need to open, we don't need to open for we don't need to wait for the previous execution.
Okay, the time it is taking it's completely fine. I will simultaneously run for all of the function it will be executing together. Okay, so now we'll try to see that particular example as well.
How it will work. Now we'll see the synchronous programming,
sorry, asynchronous programming.
Asynchronous programming.
Now, here to
implement the asynchronous function, you need to import one library called
sorry import
okay, as since Io. Okay, as in io this particular library, and I'm going to also import time library.
Let's be import all of them.
Then here I'm going to again write the same function,
same function. I will copy the code.
And simply I'm going to mention here now instead of giving simply this definition, I'm going to write essence keyword. Okay, before that.
Now, once I have written essence keyword, okay, essence keyword at the first of this particular function now, Python will automatically understand
I need to run this function in asynchronous mode, and here it is taking the time, so maybe I can use another keyword here called avoid.
Okay, ait.
So simply I'm going to give it here.
Okay, even you can also return something if you want. Okay, you can also return like
what is the return? This function will be returning for you.
Now, similar uh same uh similar wise, I will also do it for this particular function.
So essence,
okay. Now simply here I'm going to write avit
okay, avit.
So why you are writing avit here? Because here it is taking the time, okay.
Here it is taking the time, and whenever here it is taking the time, your Python interpreter will come here, and whenever it will see the available, so it will tell, like
you don't need to wait for this particular execution, so you can execute your other code, okay. Whatever you have.
So this code will be executing, and at the same time, you can also execute your other code, okay. I'll tell you okay, how it will execute.
then simply in the main function, also I'm going to make it as essence,
okay. Essence, and here
instead of calling like that, I'm going to simply call it as await uh essenceio.gathered. Okay, there is a function, and inside that you have to give the fetch weather
fetch weather uh function and fetch news function, both you have to provide. Okay, then you can calculate the end time
and simply you can print the time taken of this particular function. Now, if you want to execute, uh what you can do, you can simply
uh you can simply call this main function.
How you can use the avit keyword main now. See if I execute
see what will happen.
Okay, um there is an error.
Oh, sorry, uh whenever you are using this avit, right? You don't need to use the time that time, uh, you can use as since
uh essenceio.sleep. Okay, so you are not supposed to use time that time, okay. You have to use as since io.sleep.
Okay, now same things I will be giving it here,
same things I will give it to here.
now I think it is fine. Now let's execute
now. See, guys, it has taken only three seconds, and if I show my previous code, it has taken six seconds. Okay, so the time reduced by half, okay. The time reduced by half, just try to consider now.
Just think like this is a big program, okay. This is a big program, this is a big agents, and it is running so many stuff. Now, if you run it, run it in asynchronous programming.
Now just try to consider how much time it should take, okay. But if you are using asynchronous programming, see it will be reducing the time half, okay, because it is running everything in parallel,
it is running everything in parallel, okay. So you are not supposed to wait for the previous execution to be complete. Okay, so all of the executions are doing simultaneously.
Okay, so that's why this asynchronous programming, okay. This accent IO is required whenever you are implementing any kinds of AI agents with any kinds of framework, whether you are using autogen,
you are using Langgraph, you are using crew AI. Try to use this particular things in your development, okay. This is good practice.
There are two concept you will be getting, which is
the first is
parallelism, okay.
And the second thing you will be getting con
q
Ren C.
So, what is parallelism running
multiple
tasks
simultaneously?
Using
multiple
process.
And what is concurrency? So let me write it here.
Yeah, I can write concurrency.
Concurrency means
managing
multiple
tasks
and
start
running
and okay, finish
with
overlapping
times.
Okay,
so let me show you
a graph. I think by seeing the graph you will be able to understand
what is the exact meaning.
So this is the graph.
So this is the concurrency. You can see
task is running, okay.
Context switching to task two, then again, task one is running, again it is doing the context switching, okay.
But in parallelism, you can see it is utilizing okay, it is utilizing multi
multi-core.
Okay, let's say uh in the first CPU core, it is running task one, and in the second CPU core it is running task two,
but here it is only utilizing the same code only, but doing
doing this concurrency operation, okay.
So, guys, I think you have seen this asynchronous concept. Uh, the main thing is that right now all of the orchestrator framework uses these kinds of asynchronous functionality in their back
end, so we don't need to manually uh use the asynchronous inside our development, inside our code.
But if you want, you can also use uh if you want, you can also design your own pipeline, design your own agents.
That time you can write the code from scratch, but whatever um let's say um orchestrator framework will be using like Langgraph,
then autogen crew AI, right? So everything uh already having these kinds of things are integrated, okay, in the back end.
So I don't need to take care of this part, but in future, whenever I will do some coding, maybe these are the terminology will come that time.
I want you to don't actually confuse with the syntax, okay. That's why I have clarified each and everything before I go ahead with the AI agents implementation.
So in this video, I'm going to discuss another very important topic, especially whenever you are creating any kinds of AI agents application. the terms is pydentic.
Okay, so first of all, I will give you the idea why this pydentic is required, and without pydentic, what would be the problem? Then we'll try to understand the entire pydentic concept.
So, this is my promise. Of, uh, if you complete the entire video, guys, I think you should not be having any kinds of doubt related, uh
pydentic, whether you are working in AI agents, whether you are working with any other, let's say, AI application development. because everywhere nowadays, we use this particular Pydentic concept.
okay, for the data validation. So I think you already know that in Python all of the variable is uh dynamic variable. basically, we use the dynamic concept here.
That means here we don't mention any
data type okay of a variable. Let's say if I'm creating a variable named
a, and inside that, if I'm storing, let's say, one integer value, which is four, you can actually
remove that for. and you can also store any other data type. let's say string, float, or boolean. any kinds of data type in the same variable itself. okay, without actually mentioning the data type.
Okay, so that's how Python works. it works actually dynamically, everything.
In short, any other programming language we use the static approach. So there we
first of all mention the data type, then we create the variable and we store the data.
But in Python actually everything works as a dynamically, so here you don't need to mention the data types or any kinds of let's say hints related
that, right?
So, guys, to make you understand what I'm going to do, I'm going to open my computer screen and there I'm going to discuss each and everything related to this pydentic.
So, guys, here you can see um I'm inside my computer screen. So, first of all, I have mentioned the pydentic definition, like what exactly the pydentic is.
So, as you can see, pydentic is the most widely used data validation and settings management library for Python, utilizing type hints to ensure data structure integrity.
As you can see, it validates parts data at runtime to match specified types, making it essential for building robust APIs and handling
external data with the uh with its core logic written in Rust for high performance. So, this is the definition of PyDentic. basically, we use this pydentic for the data validation.
I'm going to tell you about more uh more about this data validation, what is data validation, why it is required, and
I mean how it actually solves one amazing problem actually, whenever we try to create any kinds of end-to-end application, especially whenever you are working inside
AI domain. If you're working in machine learning, deep learning, uh generate bi, agent tI, anywhere whenever you are developing the application, you have to use this pyden
tick. Okay, now here I have listed down some key features and benefits of the Pydentic. As you can see, here some key features and benefit. So for data validation and parsing, we use this pydentic.
Uh so here you can see it defines how data should be structured using standard Python types automatically enforcing the uh these rules.
basically, see inside agentic AI why it is required because here we'll be working with the large language model, and you know that large language model
always will give you the output in unstructured manner.
And if I want to get a structured output, if I want to get the relevant response, only, that time, this pied identif, data validation is required.
and whenever we are also passing any kinds of input prompt, okay, we have to also make it structured so that I can get the efficient response from my large
language model. okay. instead of giving some unstructured data as an input. Then for the type hint and integration, so uses Python type annotations to define schemas reducing the needs for verbose
validation code, then definitely for the fast performance, we will be using that. basically, it is written in Rust uh actually language, that's why it is extremely fast.
Then strict and lax mode is available inside this Pyden Tick. Okay, basically, uh here you can um uh do the uh enforcing strict type and you can also perform the
um you can also performing this uh lax mode okay for converting let's say any other data type to another data type, okay.
This is also possible here, then uh clear error handling okay, provides detail errors when the data validation fails, and just on schema generation, piedentic models can easily generate just
on schema for documentations or validation is uh in other languages. Okay, now it is telling piedentic models. What is this pydentic model? I'm going to tell you. So this is nothing but a class.
Okay, we create a class and we inherit with this uh uh with this piedentic actually based uh model. Okay, so that's why we call it as a uh piedentic models.
So whenever I'm going to show you the practical, that time it would be more clear, okay. So, first of all, let's try to understand the problem, okay. Problem without this piedentic.
If I'm not using pydentic, so what will happen and what would be the issue actually we'll be having? Okay, then I'll try to use the piedentic and I'm going to show you the benefit itself.
So for this, I'm going to turn off my camera window, guys, so that you can see the entire screen. you don't miss any kinds of code snippet, okay.
Whatever I'm going to write, I think that would be good for you. So, guys, whenever we are working with any kinds of application, whether it's related ML, DL or agent KI, it doesn't matter.
we will be working with the data for sure, right? So, let's say here I'm going to take one example. I'm going to, let's say, create a function; I'm going to name it as. let's say,
let's say, add,
or let's say, uh, addition
Data.
okay?
So this is my function. So basically, this will take the name of the patient and age of the patient.
Okay.
now what I'm going to do, let's say this function add these information to the database that means the hospital database.
But as of now, uh I'm giving you the demo, so here I don't have any kinds of database. So simply what I'm going to do, I'm going to print uh those uh variables here.
Okay, so let's say I'm going to print the name and I'm also going to print the edge. Okay, so once it is done, maybe I can give you a message called
data
edit successfully.
Okay, so let's say this is my masses. Okay, once uh let's say I will call this function, it will add these informations to the database, and here I will get a message that's a database
data added successfully to the
database,
Okay, let's say this is my message.
Now let's say if I execute this code, let me take some cell. So if I want to let's say insert the data, first of all, I have to call this function add patient data.
So inside that, let's say I'm going to give the patient name, let's say I'm going to give Bappi and age is 25.
Okay, now let's say if I just execute the code, you will see that Bappi and the age has successfully added to the database. That means it's working fine.
Okay, now let's say this code is written by the senior programmer, and he has given this code to the junior programmer.
He told, like, okay, this is the function, and this function you can use for adding any kinds of let's say patient informations to the hospital database.
Okay, now what junior programmer will do definitely you will see the like
function definition. So you can see this function definition is that this function takes two argument one is the name and another is the age, and the data type is any
that means you can pass any kinds of data type here because here I haven't strictly mentioned you have to pass uh string or you have to pass integer float, okay.
This kinds of uh let's say type hinting, I haven't done so. What he will do, he will try to add any kinds of data here.
Okay, maybe let's say um he has given Bap P here patient, um, let's say name now he can also give the age like that. Let's instead of 25, like that, he will write like that 25, okay.
25 in the string. Now, if I execute this code, still see my data is added to the database. But whenever let's say senior programmer is trying to fetch this data, okay.
Let's say there is another function that function fetch the data.
So whenever let's say he is fetching the data, let's say he wants to he wants to filter out those patient, uh, the patient age is above 25. Okay.
so what he will do, he will let's say, write a condition. if patient
okay, if patient age is uh, let's say
greater than,
greater than 25.
okay, 25. then he will try to,
let's say, call those patients. Okay, he is trying to call those patients. Now just try to see here.
My junior programmer has added the patient information like that in a string format 25, but again, senior program is trying to filter out the patient information by the
integer data type. Okay, definitely these kinds of
I mean filter I can't ever perform on my database. If you are using SQL, I think you know that you can't do that because here it is a string type, here you are giving the integer type.
So definitely this patient will be missed that time, okay.
Not only this patient, I mean similar kinds of if you are doing the same thing instead of giving the integer, if you are giving the string type, that time
patient will definitely missed out, okay, for the filter operation. So this is the like problem. Now you can tell okay, then I can easily solve this problem.
So, what I can do, maybe instead of giving it like that. So, what I will do, let's say I'll try to maybe add a condition here. So, simply here I'll add a condition.
So, if
type first of all, I will check the type if type of name
is equal equal.
Okay, equal equal string str
and type of age is integer. Okay, then I'm going to,
sorry, then I'm going to
insert the information to the database. Okay, otherwise, in the else condition, I'm going to
give an error message.
Okay,
so I'm going to raise the exception, raise let's say
type error,
type error. So here I'm going to tell, uh, invalid data type for the name and edge name should be string and s should be in the integer format.
Okay, now let's say if I execute this code, and now let's say
If I am trying to add right now, uh, these kinds of uh, things, okay? So what will happen?
Okay. One more thing I have to add, which is the hinting, type hinting.
So name variable should be string and s variable should be intezer Now, if I execute now, see, if junior programmer comes here and he, if he sees,
see, the let's say function definition, he will be able to see that, okay? This function takes two argument: one is name, name should be string, and s should be integer.
Okay, so let's see, if I give integer data right now, there's a 25.
It will work perfectly. Okay, there should not be any kinds of error, but if he's trying to give like that, let's say again
25, so definitely that time one error would be coming here.
Okay, now it is working completely fine. It's not like that you won't be able to do that; you will be able to do that.
Now your senior programmer will be able to fetch the information very easily because you are following the same data type. Okay, whatever data type your Senior programmer expected.
Okay, so this is the thing,
but the problem is that let's say whenever you will be creating a big application, it's not like that you will be creating a single function; there would be lots of function.
Okay, so let's say you want to create another function. Let's say the function name is update information, okay, update patient information instead of add patients. Maybe I can add update
patient data. Okay, that time again it will take the name and age of the patient;
again, you have to check this condition, okay, and you have to check this condition whether name is a string and age type is integer. Then you will allow to update, okay? Let's say here I can tell:
"Update, update
." Let me accept this data. Updated successfully in the database. Otherwise, what I will do? I'll just try to raise the invalid, let's say, added.
But whenever we'll be creating the real application, it's not like that; we'll be working with two to three input data.
There would be lots of data, and for all the data, I have to write this particular condition. Okay? So again, this is a manual task we have to do. And how many function you will be creating?
In every function, you have to definitely check that. Okay, you have to definitely check that. Let's say another condition comes up. The condition is,
uh, condition is, let's say, um, yeah, definitely. Let's say you have given your data type, it should be name should be string and it should be integer.
It's completely fine, but let's say your junior programmer insert the data like that. Let's say instead of giving uh positive 25, he will be giving negative 25.
Now age can't cannot be never never negative, right?
Age cannot uh ne uh I mean it should not be negative, but if I let's say add this negative number again, it will be adding this particular number successfully.
Okay, but this is another issue definitely, right? Now you can tell me, okay? Then, what I can do? Maybe I can add another condition here. So, what I will do, let's say here.
maybe I will add another condition inside this in "add. patient data ". So here, I'm going to check another condition. if the age is, uh,
if age is gated, then
okay.
um, age is gated, then
equal um zero.
that time, I will allow this condition.
Okay, I will allow this condition; otherwise, I will raise another exception, it cannot be negative.
Okay, and this uh um uh this uh already I'm checking this information whether it is uh string or intezer.
Okay, so this is the else block for this particular if and this is the else block for this particular if okay now here I have written the multi uh
conditional statement. So here also you have to do the same thing, okay. Here also you have to do the same thing. Okay, so so I'll remove this part
okay. Here also you have to add the same thing. Now if I execute this code, now see now it will um check that and it will raise the value value address that means h
cannot be negative, but if I'm passing the positive, that time it will be working, there should not be any kinds of problem, okay.
But every time, whenever the condition is changing, okay, uh, because it's it is true, right?
Whenever you are creating an application, your application should handle this kinds of scenario because as a user I can pass anything, right?
I can pass anything, I can pass negative number, I can pass string number, anything I can pass in your application, but your application should
handle this this kinds of scenario. Your application should validate the data I'm passing whether it is validated or not.
Okay, so either you can do this validation by writing this kinds of manual conditional statement, either you can use the pydentic one, okay. Pydentic data validator. So, how to use pydentic?
I'm going to tell you, but I was just showing you the problem. What would be the problem if you're using this uh like traditional approach, traditional conditional approach?
So here you have to write these kinds of condition manually every time, okay.
And again, if you're creating any other function, again you have to rewrite the code, and your code size would be very big that time. Okay, so this is the problem.
Now let's try to see how to use this piedentic to solve this problem. Now, here I have already written how to use the pydentic.
So in Piedentic, first of all, we'll define a piedentic model that represents the ideal schema of a data. Now, what is model? Okay, model means model means this is a class.
Okay, here we'll try to define a class of pydentic. Basically, we'll try to inherit with the pidentic based model.
Okay, after that, we'll try to define the schema here. Okay, we'll try to define the schema. Now, what is schema? I'll tell you. then the second thing uh in uh instantiate
model with raw input, uh usually a dictionary or JSON-like structure. So once my uh let's say piedentic models is by dentic class is ready, I will prepare my data.
Okay, I will prepare my input data in a dictionary, it should be uh definitely in a dictionary or JSON-like format. Uh then uh we'll try to pass the validated uh
model object to the functions, uh functions. Um
okay, here I missed one thing. see here basically what we'll do, Pydentic will automatically validate the data, whether it is correct format or not.
The data we are passing, if does not meet the model requirement, Pydentic raises the validation error. Okay, then once let's say my data validation meets it is uh let's say validated successfully.
That time uh it will try to uh will try to pass the validated model objects to the function, the function we have created, okay, for any kinds of logic, let's say
for a database insertion or update database insertion, we can pass to that particular function, and our code will be working. Okay, now this thing we'll try to see in a practical manner.
So, for this, first of all, you have to install the pydentic inside your environment.
So, how to install pydentic, maybe in the requirement.txt you can mention the pydentic package, and definitely you just try to take pydentic like
more than one. That means it should be uh pydentic to version because in two function there are lots of Update came, but don't use one version because what one version that was older
and there you will be getting lots of issue. Okay, I'll try to suggest you use this pydentic two or more than two. Okay, you can use this one now.
Once you have added in the requirements, so simply you can open up your terminal and just write this command papinstall hypner requirement.txt.
So it will be installing this pydentic inside your environment. Okay, so for me it is already satisfied because initially I already installed this pydentic in my environment.
So once it is done, um, this is the notebook, guys. I'm also going to share you all of the source code in the description. Section from there, you can download and you can try in your system.
Now, here you definitely select the kernel, the environment you are creating. Just try to select that. So, for me, I have created this LLM demo. I'll try to select this now.
Here I'll be doing the coding example. Now, first of all, here you have to import this uh pydentic base model from Pydentic. So you have to import like that from Pydentic.
So I'm getting the code suggestion because here I'm using this Microsoft Copilot. Um, yeah, so maybe I'll take the suggestion. So from Pydentic
Piedentic input, I'm going to import the base model first of all.
Okay, so first of all, I'm going to show you the simple example, then I'm going to show you the advanced example of Pydentic as well.
Okay, first of all, let's start with the simple example. Now, once it is imported, now what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to simply write a Piedentic class.
Okay.
So let's say the class name is patient.
Okay, patient data. So let's say this is my class, and definitely you have to inherit this particular class with base model.
Okay, so this is called actually piedentic model. So this becomes actually piedentic model right now. Now inside that you have to define the schema.
So schema means like how many data you will be using.
Okay, so here I'll be using two data one is the name, another is the age because I'm replicating the same example previously I've given. So here I was considering name and age.
Okay, these two information only, and here I have mentioned the name should be in a string and age should be in intezer.
Okay,
now what I'm going to do, I'm going to again maybe copy the same uh function I created, or or let's write that.
So dev
Okay, add patient data. So this was the function
previously written,
okay. But there I passed this name and
uh name and uh a' directly, but here you don't need to give like that.
So here what you have to do, you have to
uh you have to give the uh you have to give the py identific object, okay. But before that, let me show you what to do.
So as of now, let's uh just pass it, and now the second step we have to uh in
uh instantiate the model with the raw input. So we have to prepare our raw input. So input should be in a dictionary or JSON-like structure. So let's try to prepare the input.
So input is basically my patient information,
so patient
patient data
is equal to
um it should be a dictionary.
First of all, I will add
the name
okay,
name and h. Okay, so this is a dictionary format. Now what I will do, I will just try to
I will just try to pass uh this particular data to my uh to my wire to my pydentic
object. So here what is the pydentic object? Pydentic object is nothing but my patient data.
Okay, so what I'm going to do, I'm going to pass it to the patient data. So here let's try to create
object of patient.
Okay, patient.
Let's say this is the
um
this is patient is equal to
um patient data and we'll be passing the data. And here I have given twister because this is a dictionary, and we have to unpack the value, right?
Key and value, so that's why we are given this uh to start here. Twister means you are unpacking the data, okay. Now this will become a pied identific object.
Okay, now we have created a pydentic object, okay. Now this particular object will be passing to the function.
All of the function will be creating here, whether it's uh add patient data, update patient data will be up um like passing those informations inside the function.
Now, right now, this function can't take the name and a separately instead of that, it will take what it will take the
patient, okay. Patient object
that means the piedentic object. So that means here I can
make this particular input name is that patient, and the type of the patient should be patient data.
That means this particular class, and this is your parentic model, right? This is your piedentic class. Now, why I have given patient data? Because inside that I have prepared this schema.
That means this add patient data function takes the data, okay. Take the data, and that what is the data format?
Data format should be definitely there would be a variable called name, and name name should be string, and there should be another variable called edge, it should be
integer type. Okay, so that's how we are giving the type, but initially we are giving the data like that.
We are giving the name and we are mentioning okay, this should be the stream then we are giving the age, this should be the integer. Okay, but here we are doing the manual stuff.
But here right now we just created a pidentic class and we are passing this particular class object, and it will automatically understand okay what to do, what should be the format inside that,
what should be the structure inside that. This is called actually schema. Okay, schema means the data and the data type type of the data. Okay, this is called actually schema.
Now, once it is done, now simply here I can add the patient information. So simply I can print the information. So right now, see I know I can't actually directly print the name, right?
I can't directly print the name here because we are not taking the name as a name variable, we are taking as a patient, right?
So we can call like that patient dot name because inside this particular patient data object will be having the variable name. Okay, now we'll do for the same, we'll do for the edge also.
So print patient.edge, okay. Now once it is done, I'll tell data inserted successfully to the database. So similar wise, I will create for the update.
I'll create for the update.
So let's make it as update,
okay.
Now it will again take the same patient uh uh patient data object that means the parentic object,
and once it is done, we'll try to tell data updated successfully in the database, okay, and everything will remain same.
Now let's try to see whether it is working or not. Now, simply what I will do first of all, let's say I will add the patient data,
okay. Add the patient data. So inside this add patient, you have to pass this patient information, okay.
Patient because this is my Piedentic object. We already created with the help of this pyidentic class.
now we'll try to pass it there.
Now see Bap P uh 25 data added successfully to the database. Now let's say I want to update the data. Simply I'll call the update patient data inside that I will again pass the patient object
now. See the patient information is already updated. Now let's say in updated.
Okay, so what I can do instead of patient, I can give patient one. Let's say you can create multiple patient that time
you can do that. Okay, patient one, patient two, like that you can do. So let's say this is the patient one information.
Okay, this is patient one information. This is updated.
Okay, so whenever you are doing the update operation, so make sure you are
giving any other name.
So simply what I can do
see before giving to the update function. First of all, you have to validate with the help of pydentic. So let's say now name is equal to Alex.
let's say this is patient two.
We are um we are giving this particular raw data to the pydentic, okay, pydentic object because here I already told you
instantiate the model with the raw input data. So we are initiating the model, okay.
The pidentic model with the raw data, the raw data we are passing here, okay. Raw data we are passing here, and this is uh doing the validation.
If everything is fine, it will tell okay, you can continue, then we are giving to the function.
Now, see this function is working fine, okay. It should be patient two, not patient one, it should be patient two.
Now, see, now it's become Alex.
Okay, now the things I want to show you the benefit actually uh using this pydentic, which is that let's say by mistake, you have given
um let's say string 25. Okay, you have given string 25 instead of giving uh 25. So now what we'll do, let's say if I execute the code, see pydentic will not give you any kinds of exception.
Instead of that, what it will do, it will try to convert this string 25 to integer.
Okay, so you don't need to do it manually. So by default, uh actually internally this pyden tick will handle this kinds of scenario. So this will try to convert to the integer type.
Okay, you don't need to manually do that. So here also you can do the same thing. Let's say if I give string 25, your data should be updated successfully, okay.
Now let's see in future you want to add any other information so you don't need to update these at the code that time, okay?
Manually. So here let's say you want to add the weight,
uh, weight for the patient. Okay, so let's say weight.
Usually I can mention with the help of float data type We got weight should be float.
Now, simply what I can do, I can also print the weight here.
Okay, now here also I can do the same thing.
I can update the weight, and here you can give the weight information right now. Let's say weight is 70.5 kg.
Now, if I add the information,
see, still it will be working. Okay, I'm getting one error because whenever I am updating the information, here I haven't passed the weight, I have to pass the weight here.
Now, see it will work successfully.
Okay, so there should not be any kinds of problem.
Okay, but in our previous example, you will see that every time I have to handle this kinds of scenario manually, but in pydentic, we don't need to handle that, okay.
We'll try to just prepare a pydentic class, and in this particular class, we'll try to handle each and everything for me, okay?
But you have to make sure whenever you are giving your raw data, try to first of all validate, okay. Try to first of all validate with your pydentic, then try to pass to the main function.
Now I think this particular concept will be clear enough.
The strict and lax mode.
So basically, what it do, it attempts to uh co uh quote quotes the data example converting
this string one to integer one that means automatically it will try to convert for you, okay. But if you want to raise the exception, you can also do that, okay. Everything is possible here,
and one more thing I want to show you now. Let's say if you want to add
any other type data, let's say instead of giving this
let's say this is this is a number, okay. Now let's say you are not giving the number, you are giving like that 70.
Okay, say 70.
Okay, 70.
Now, see if I execute it, will throw you the error. Okay, it will tell input should be a valid number, unable to parse the string to a number because we can't convert this
this text to the number, right? This is not a number, this is a other text. This is a like uh kinds of word we are passing, okay.
But it should be a number whether you are giving as a string or intezer, doesn't matter, it should be as a number.
So if you're giving as a number, that time it will be able to convert it to the integer. Okay, but if you are giving completely text type, it will not allow that time, okay?
So, yeah, that's how the things work. But this is a very basic type example I have given. Now we'll try to move to the advance of this pyentic.
I will try to see like more depth validation how it can be done. We can add so many parameters, so many stuff here. We can add so many, let's say, verification, and we can make it like more powerful.
So, guys, so far we have seen a very easy example of the pydentic.
Now we'll try to make it uh slightly complex. Okay, so what I'm going to do maybe I can copy the same
uh same class.
So this is the class, I'll copy this,
or I can copy the entire
code
and I will paste it here.
Okay, now see here what I'm going to do instead of taking name, age, and weight, maybe I'll take some more extra variable.
Let's say here I will take
another another data called married, okay, whether this patient is married or not.
Married, so this should be a Boolean data type because either patient should be married, if married, it should be yes, either no.
So if yes and no comes into picture, so we can consider in Boolean type data type, then I can take another data,
which is allergies, okay.
Whether patient is having allergies or not.
Okay, if he or she is having allergies, so what kinds of allergies uh he or she is having?
See, allergies is is it's not a single let's say type, okay. There should be multiple types.
Someone got allergies from let's say dust, someone will be uh getting allergies from any kinds of food, right? It should be different, different, let's say, type.
So that's why we'll be taking as a list.
Now you can ask me
why I'm taking this particular things as a list, okay, because it should be list of allergies, okay.
Uh let's say one patient will have might have multiple allergies, okay. Type, or let's say one patient will have only single type, okay.
So instead of taking a single type, maybe we can take a list of the type, I mean list type so that if one patient is having multiple allergies, so I can easily store them,
right? But if you are taking list, so you don't need to directly I mean write this list, okay. If you are I mean writing in that way, it should it it won't be working.
So for this, what you have to do, you have to import this list from the typing module.
So you just need to import list from typing module. So there is a module called typing, and in this typing, we'll have we'll be having all kinds of typing, okay, inside Python.
So we are importing the list, okay. We are telling we need a list now. It should be a list, okay. So here we'll be
telling this should be a list type.
Okay, now I can't actually write list like that because
see what will happen if I open up my blackboard.
See,
patient is having allergies. Okay, allergies is nothing but it's a list, okay.
It's a list.
Now the thing is that inside that we have to write write the allergies type.
Let's say this is dust type, and what is dust?
Dust is a string, right? Now let's say food.
Okay, food is also a string.
Okay, so type cannot be any kinds of number.
Okay, it should be a definitely string type. That's why I'm telling uh the list we are creating of the allergies inside the list will be storing
string type data, okay? Because allergies type should be always a string, so that's how whenever we are creating any application, we have to think about the data type. What should be the data type?
Okay, uh, the data we are getting, what should be the type?
Okay, you have to think about in that way. So, allergies should be list, and inside list the data will be storing, it should be string, okay.
That's why we can write this particular syntax, and this is called schema. Okay, we are creating this schema right now, and we are extending this particular pydentic model.
I think you get it right now.
I'll add another let's say data which is
contact.
Okay, contact information.
So, contact information, let's say I want to keep it as a dictionary.
let's say someone will pass, let's say contact information like that.
Uh, let's say
um he or she will be writing in that way.
Let me tell you
so, contact we want to take it in that way. Let's say contact info
is equal to it should be a dictionary.
So, inside that, first of all, user will pass the email address,
okay.
So, let's say this is the email address,
And this is my phone number.
Okay, phone number. Let's say this is my phone number
like that. Okay, I think you are getting and this should be also string type data.
Okay, so that's why I'll be taking this contact info as a dictionary now. Inside this dictionary,
I'm going to mention okay. I'm going to mention what kinds of data I want to take.
dictionary should be
string type.
Okay, key should be also string, value should be also string.
Okay, that's why we're mentioning the data type, and this is a dict, and again, I can't use the Python default dictionary function.
I have to import from this typing, so simply I'm going to import this dict, and now
I'll mention it here.
Okay, that's it. Now let's try to um execute, but before executing, I think you have to know we have to prepare the raw data. Now let's try to prepare the raw data.
So we are already getting the suggestion, we'll accept that. So here you can see we have added
uh we have added uh this one
married,
yeah. Married,
so this is we have added
this is true.
Uh, you can also give it as a string, you can also give it as a boolean, it doesn't matter, it will work.
Then you can see we are giving the allergies, so allergies we are giving as a list, as you can see.
We are having an allergies from peanuts and selfish.
Okay, then we are giving the contact info.
Let's say this is my email address and this is the phone number.
Okay, now let's try to execute whether it is able to work or not. See, I'm not going to update these are the function.
You can if you want, you can also update with all of these variables, you can print all of them, but let's do it quickly.
So, here I'm going to do I'm going to simply execute. Okay, now see uh information is added successfully.
That means it's working fine right now.
But in some case, let's say if I am giving instead of let's say uh this uh allergies instead of giving this string, if I'm giving any kinds of
integer number, let's say 23, okay, it will give you that.
okay. It will tell one validation error from this patient data that means the piedentic model.
So allergies, it is coming from the allergies, okay.
Allergi's field input should be a valid string, not the integer.
Okay, so that's how you can specify this one.
So I'll come here again. I'll change it.
Execute.
See, it will work perfectly.
Okay, so that's how any okay, any kinds of type you can mention inside your pidenc model.
Okay, any kinds of speak schema you can mention inside your pidentic model, everything is possible here, okay. So, guys, we have seen another example.
now I'm going to talk about this required and optional fields. Okay, what is this required and optional fields? Let's try to understand. See, whenever we are creating this schema, right?
We are creating this piedentic model.
Uh that time, uh, whatever data we are taking, right? Whatever data we are uh let's whatever schema we are um writing, we have to give all of this field, right?
We have to give all of this field whenever we are preparing the raw data.
So if you skip any of them, okay. So if you skip any of them, what will happen?
So let me show you the example. I'll copy this code, I'll add it here.
Let's say these are my schema, right? Let's say I will let's say I will let's say
not provide these allergies. So, what will happen?
So if I remove the allergies from here.
Let's say I will completely delete this allergy field.
Okay, I will delete this. Now if I execute, it will throw you an error. Okay, it will tell one validation error from patient data allergies field required.
Okay, but you haven't given this particular data. So this is the issue. Okay, now let's say I want to make it as optional. Let's say if user is not also giving this allergies, it's completely fine.
It should be completely optional. That means my code will still execute. So for this, what I can do,
I can make it optional. So to make it optional, simply you have to import
optional from typing, okay. Optional from typing, and you have to pass this data type inside the optional,
okay.
Inside the optional, and one more thing you have to define, which is one default value, which is none.
Okay, so I'm getting one error. Let me check.
Okay, the error I'm getting it should not be parenthesis, it should be this square bracket.
That's why that error was coming. Now it's fine. Okay, now this allergies field should be optional. If you are also not giving it's completely fine,
I mean it will still work, and by default, this allergies field will get one value which is none. I can show you by printing that.
So, what I can do, I can
print it.
So, just for simplicity, let's remove this function,
okay.
I'll only keep one function.
So, here I'll just try to print
patient
dot allergies.
Okay, now if I see show you my data there,
uh there I already removed this allergies field.
Now, if I still execute, it will work, and you can see this allergies parameter is getting none.
Okay, this is getting none because the default uh default uh value I have set as none, okay, and it is completely optional. If you give also it will work, okay. If you skip it, it will also work.
Now let's say if I give this value.
So after married, I think
I'll copy from my previous example this patient data,
and I will pass it here.
Okay, now here I have given this allergies field.
Now if I execute, still it will work, but now it will take the value because we have given the value itself, okay.
But if you don't give it,
still it will work, but it will take as a none.
Okay, now one more thing I told you about the default value. See, you can also set the default value to any kinds of field. Let's say in the married one, I can set any kinds of default value.
Okay, let's see if user is not giving any kinds of value, still it will take the default value. Let's say married is equal to by default, I will be make it as false.
Now, if I
let's say remove this married field as well,
still it will work.
So that particular okay, I can print and show you
here. I will print it
patient.merit.
Now see by default it is coming as a false. Okay, that means you can also pass any default value if you want, okay, and you can also make any kinds of field as optional.
Okay, this is also possible here.
So, guys, we have seen the optional and required field. Now I'm going to show you another example which is related data validation.
So in Pydentic, I told you we can also perform the data validation if you want.
see data validation means let's say the data you are giving, you can also validate whether it is in same format or same, let's say
it follows the same uh same structure or not.
Okay, so for an example, I'm going to let's say
take one example,
I'll copy the same code.
So this is like becoming big line. So, what I can do maybe I can
just press an enter
just to make it as a little bit shorter, okay.
So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to
take another variable.
Called email.
Okay, as of now, let's try to consider.
Um, I'm also
taking one information from the patient, uh, that means his email, and here I'm going to remove the email. Okay, so in contact information, let's uh only I'm going to take his phone number.
Okay, this is fine for us.
so email, I'm going to take it as separately.
So, what I can do, you can tell me, okay, I can make it maybe string because email usually would be any kinds of string type data, yes or no, right?
But if I'm taking as a string type data, so what will happen? Let me show you.
So let's say I'm taking as a string type data
email, and now
after name I have to pass the email.
So let's say email
should be email.
So this should be
okay.
So let's say buppy at the rate example.com or let's say buppy at the rate
uh gmail.com.
Okay, let's say this is my email, it's completely fine. Okay, now let's see if I execute it will work.
See, it is working fine, there is no error, okay. But let's say if I
not giving this at the right sign now, if I still let's execute my code,
it will be working, okay. Although this email format is not good, okay.
Although this email format is not correct, but still my code is working, okay. Then what is the use of that?
So here actually data validation comes into picture.
So basically, see if I am doing manually with the help of Python, so you can tell me okay, I can use regular expression library and I can validate whether this email
it is correct or not.
Okay, I think you know with the help of regular expression, also we can handle this scenario, but we are using the pydentic. okay, and definitely we are using it for my benefit, right?
So in pydentic, instead of giving this email as a string, you can also give this particular format
to the email format. Okay, so inside this pyden tick, we're having another function called
email string.
Email str okay. So, what this email s tier does, it does the data validation. That means it will automatically check whether you are what kinds of email you are giving, it is in correct format or not.
If it is not correct format, that time it will throw you the error.
Okay, now instead of giving this string, maybe I can give this email STR.
Now, what will happen?
Now see if I execute this code,
if I execute this code, it will throw you error.
The error should be uh this email, okay. Hello is not valid email address.
Now, unless and until I'm not giving the valid email address, let's say if I give this at the red sign right now,
now it will work perfectly. Okay, there should not be any kinds of issue. So that's how you can perform the data validation.
Before giving the data, you can validate whether the data we are passing, it is well it is in correct format or not. It is validated or not.
Okay, I think you get.
Now, similar
similar things you can do with another let's say data validator.
the name of the data validator is like any URL.
Okay, any URL actually validates any kinds of uh um let's say web URL, the web URL you are passing, whether it is uh in correct format or not.
So let's say I'm also giving the patient uh LinkedIn information. Okay, so let's say this is uh this is a it uh it patient hospital. We are only
taking the it patients, okay. IT it background related patients, and we are also taking their LinkedIn profile okay to our database. What I'm going to do, maybe I can create another field here.
I'm going to name it as LinkedIn.
Uh LinkedIn.
Okay.
LinkedIn URL.
Yeah, and the type should be an URL because this should be a URL format, right? Anywhere.
Now, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to pass a
URL, LinkedIn URL.
So I'm already getting a suggestion.
So maybe I can create another enter.
Okay.
So here we are taking the URL as you can see HTTPS
slash www um dot
or let's say I will copy my LinkedIn profile.
So this is my LinkedIn profile.
I will add it here.
Okay.
Now see if I execute this this thing will work fine. Okay, there should not be any error.
But let's say if I'm not giving this https, okay.
If I'm only giving this ww
or let's say I'm also removing this WW. okay. Now if I execute,
see it will give you the error.
It is telling input should be a valid URL.
Okay, otherwise it should not be working. So this is the work of data validator.
Okay, that's how in Python Pydentic there are some default validator um validator uh are present.
you can simply see the documentation and you can do the validation.
Okay, if you want, this is possible here.
Now, one more thing I will show you, which is uh let's say uh here we used some of the um I mean already available uh data validator,
um validator like email uh email string, then any URL.
Okay, but let's in some cases uh there should be some of the data uh and for those data, this kinds of validator won't be available,
okay.
That time how you can actually validate those data. Let's say uh here what I can do, I can show you one example. Let's say here the name we are passing.
Um, I want to make a restriction.
Um,
the maximum length of a name should not be more than uh 50 characters.
Okay, that time how I'm going to do this kinds of validation.
Okay, so for this, we can use the custom custom validator, and we can write this custom validator with the help of one of one
amazing actually function called field. So, what you can do,
uh you can simply import this field from Pydentic.
So you have to import this field from Pydentic.
Just a minute.
Yeah, you have to import this field from Pydentic.
Now, here simply you just need to define this, okay?
Let's say name that should be string, and here I'm going to write the field
okay.
Inside the field, I'm going to tell the maximum length of a name should uh should be only 50 character. Okay, it should not be above 50 character.
Okay, now let's say if I execute my code,
it will work fine completely because right now the name I'm using it is less than 50 character, but if you increase it, let's say I will add
something big.
Okay, now if I execute, you will see that it will throw an error.
The string should be have most um 50 character.
Okay, so that's how you can do the data validation uh in your custom data if you want.
So, like that, I can also let's say set to any another field.
Let's say I want to restrict the age uh age field here. I want uh whatever age uh user is passing, it should be
it should be greater than zero and uh lesser than actually let's say 100.
Okay, so for this, what I can do, I can add another field here.
Uh I'm going to write is equal to field.
So there is a parameter called Gt.
Okay, GT means greater than greater than zero, and there is another parameter called uh Lt. Okay, Lt means lesser than so here I'm going to tell let's say 100.
Okay.
Now if let's say user is giving the age let's say minus 25, so this is definitely lesser than zero, so that time it will give you the error
because input should be greater than zero, but we are giving lesser than zero, okay.
Now, if we are giving the correct information, it is working fine, okay. Like that, we can also let's say
add these kinds of validator inside our allergies. Okay, let's say this is the list of the allergies we are taking, and all of the value should be string.
we can also define the field here.
So I'm going to write the field
okay, field.
Uh so here let's say the allergies uh we are taking uh from the user, so only
uh user can pass actually let's say maximum five five allergies, okay. Five allergy list.
So that time I can define the max length,
should be
Five.
Okay.
Now let's say if user is giving more than that,
okay. Allergies, I make it as an optional.
So what I can do, I can maybe add the data here.
Previously I had the allergies. Maybe I can copy.
So from here I can copy.
Okay, so here I can add it after
married. I can add the allergies.
Married also I removed right previously.
Okay, because this was optional. So here I can add the allergies.
it should be a comma.
Now if you are giving more value here,
okay, that time it will throw you error.
Okay, because it should be
five item but we are giving more than five.
Okay, so this is another issue.
So let me
yeah,
Now it's working fine.
Okay, so that's how guys we can uh set our custom data uh validator, okay. We can set with the help of this field now.
This field you can also use for another purpose uh to add some other metadata, okay, to add some other information about the schema about the Python tick model.
Okay, I'm going to show you.
So, guys, now let's try to understand. Um, apart from this um
um data validation, uh like custom data validation, okay, why we can use this field, okay.
So, see field we can also use for the metadata information. Let's say whenever we are creating this schema, you can also pass any kinds of metadata here, okay.
Other informations like description, okay, some other example you can provide here so that whenever this code is using any other programmer or let's say other
let's say
other person, they can easily understand what this field does, okay?
They can easily understand now. See the way we have written right now, this is completely fine, but it does it doesn't have any kinds of information about the name, let's say what name does.
But if I add some other metadata like description and all, by reading the description, I think other person will easily understand what to do, right? So for this, here I have given another demo.
I have already written this particular demo. So see, here if you want to write any kinds of metadata,
metadata inside your schema, that time you can use this particular field function, but with that you have to use another function called annotated, okay?
So you have to import this annotated from typing. So now you have to write the syntax like that. Okay, previously I was writing like that, okay.
I was directly giving the string field and all, but right now, if you want to write the metadata, first of all, you have to give the annotated object,
then inside that you have to define the data type, okay. The type int. Let's say this is a string, then you will be giving the field.
So here my field was like maximum length 50. Now, here I can pass some other metadata like name or like the title. Okay, so name of the patient.
So the uh that means this particular name field is nothing but it's a name of the patient, and you can also give the description, okay.
What this does, this give the name of the patient in less than 50 character.
Then you can also provide some example, okay, so that by seeing this particular example, your programmer can understand okay. This actually works like that.
So here I've given example like Buffy and Alex.
So this is less than 50 characters, okay. So similar wise, you can use this for all the field you are having. Let's say I have given some other example, I have added this inside the weight, okay.
The same.
see, here we mentioned like this is float.
Here we here we have given the field, okay.
Right now I'm going to remove this stick parameter. I'm going to tell you why this is required.
Now, here you can also provide the description, okay.
Uh description and all
everything can be done.
Okay, so this should be mentioned inside field variable.
So here you can mention like description, okay, weight of the patient in kg, then married. Also, I have given the same thing annotated. Then this is boolean type field.
I have given the default value. So see if you want to give the default value. So previously, how I was giving, I was giving like that.
Let's say I was just giving an equal sign and giving the value. But right now, you're using this field.
So inside field itself, you can give the default value. Let's say in default is equal to none. So by default, it will take as a none.
Let's see if you're giving any other, let's say true, false, it will take as true false. Okay, now here I have given the description.
Okay, now for allergies also, you can do the same thing. You can mention, like, okay, this is optional because previously this allergies was optional, and the data type is
list, and inside that we are taking the string type data.
Field is default value you are setting as a none. You can also give the default value if you want, and maximum length should be five.
Okay, so for contact details, also you can do the same thing, but I left this part, okay. Now, see if I execute
this is giving you an error.
There is
uh field required
contact details.
Okay, so the error is that here I have written contact details, but here I have given contact information, so here you have to give the same name, same name.
Now, if I execute it will be working fine, okay. Now, one more thing I wanted to show you, which is this streak parameter.
Let's say I told you um in my previous demo, I think you remember.
Uh, whenever let's say we are giving let's say weight is equal to a string number, okay. But here, what is the type I have mentioned?
Weight is equal to it should be a float number. So by default, my uh pydentic is converting this particular string to a float because this is the number, okay.
But always it is not necessary to convert it, okay. Automatically convert it. Let's say you are creating an application there, you only want to take this kinds of let's say number as a string.
That time you should not be convert to the float data type. That time you can write one parameter.
so here you can write a parameter, the parameter name is strict,
okay. Strict, so you have to make it as true.
Okay, so if you make it as true, so what will happen?
You have given float type, but if you are trying to give this uh string type, it will throw you error.
See, it is throwing you error, it is telling weight should be uh input uh um it should be a valid number, float type number, but we are giving
string type, okay. That's why it's not working. So now if I make it as float,
okay, so it will be working right now.
So if you're giving integer also, again it will throw an error because here I've made it as a strict okay, strict parameter. So that's how you have all kinds of
customizable options inside Python tick.
Whatever you want, you can do everything here, okay. This is possible.
So, guys, we have seen some data validator uh validation actually strategy how we can do that. Now I'm going to discuss about this
validator in advanced level.
we call it as a field validator, okay.
So, see so far the validation we have done.
this was like the simple validation.
so we used some of the predefined validator and we also like given some some of the like
Custom constraint there, okay. But let's say you have some complex scenario there you have to do a complete field verification, okay.
So for an example, let me uh let me tell you like the problem statement. The problem statement is that let's say
the application we have created.
let's say this is a hospital application.
So basically, this stores the patient information, okay.
Then it performs the diagnosis to the patients. Okay, now just try to consider this hospital has also connect connection with some of the bank. Let's say
some of the bank it has the connection, let's say HDFC bank, it has the connection, ICICI bank, it has the connection.
Okay, now what happens if it is having the connection with the banks? Let's say whatever patients are coming from, these are the banks, so they will be getting 50% discount.
Okay, they will be getting 50% discount from this particular hospital, and if the patient is not from these are the banks, so they have to pay 100% about
the money. So this kinds of let's say validation I want to add inside this application.
Now, how to do that? So, definitely this is a little bit complicated.
So, for this, I have already created the code as you can see.
I just copy-pasted the same code, but what I have done, I just reduced uh reduced the I mean some extra coded so that you can
understand easily see what I have done.
the previous validation I showed you with the help of annotated, I removed each and everything. I just taken my previous example, okay. Previous this clean example.
So here you can see this is the cleaned example.
Okay, I have taken the name, email, age, weight, married, allergies, contract. Okay, these are the things I have taken. Now let's say I want to check the email here.
Okay, I want to check the email here because only I will understand whether this patient uh he is from any bank or not.
How I'm going to understand because patient will give their email address, right?
So if I'm a like a very uh I mean uh common person, so I'll give my common email address like at the regmail.com and all
right. But if anyone is working in the bank, so definitely they will be having their bank domain email address, okay. Let's say hdafc.com or icici.com, okay, like that.
So email is the best field I can do this kinds of validator. So for this, what you have to do? You have to write a custom function, okay. So the function name is I have given email validator, okay.
You can give any name, but I have given email validator, and whenever you are creating this function, make sure you have to give two decorator. one is the field validator.
So field validator you have to import from PyDentic.
So you can see I have imported from Pydentic uh field validator, and inside that you have to mention which field you want to validate. So here I will tell I want to validate this email.
Make sure the spelling should be same.
Okay, email field should be validated, and another decorator you have to get called class method because this is the method of this particular class, that's why this class method.
Now, this is my function.
So this function takes two arguments one is the class, class object itself, okay, and this is the value.
Value means
uh let's say user is giving the email, right?
Email address, let's say abcd.gmail.com or sdfc.com. Okay, so this is called actually value. So this particular value will come and I have to validate this particular value.
Okay, so for this, what I have done, I created a list.
I named it as valid domains. So here I just listed all of the bank let's say a domain, let's say sdfc.com icici.com. You can also give any other bank domain if you want.
Then what I'm doing, first of all, the value I'm getting from the user, let's say whatever email user is passing, okay. I'm just trying to extract this last part, okay.
As you can see, let's say if this is the email address, I'm extracting this particular part. So this code is doing that.
So I'm splitting with the help of this add direct, then I'm taking the last value, that means this particular part.
Then what I'm checking if domain name not in our valid domain, that means if particular this domain name is it is not available inside our valid domains, that means this is not a
uh uh this is not a patient from the bank. Okay, this is a common people, okay. So that time I'm raising an exception, not a valid domain.
Okay, otherwise we are returning the value.
Simple. Now let's try whether it's working or not. See, here I have given simple email address bub at there is gmail.com. So definitely it will throw error because uh I'm not from the bank.
okay, still it is working.
Okay, the issue is that this should be patient data object, okay?
Not patient.
Uh, this should be patient data object, uh patient data class.
Now, if I execute, now see it is giving you error, it's telling value error not a valid domain. Okay, that means uh this particular person it is not from the bank.
Now, see if I give the bank domain, let's say I'll give sdfc
com.
now it should be working.
Still married.
Married.
Okay, so here I haven't passed the married, right?
Uh
so let's give the married as well.
Married
is equal to true.
Now if I execute, see it's working fine.
Okay, because this particular person uh he's from the bank itself.
Okay, so that's how you can do advanced level uh uh validation.
Okay, this is called field validator.
Now you can also do some transformation with the validation as well. That now let's say I will be working on another example.
So one more thing you can do with the help of this field validator, you can you can definitely validate, but if you want, you can also do
the transformation. Let's say the name you are getting from the user.
you want to store this particular name in a uppercase format, always okay. If user is also not giving, it's completely fine, but you want to make it uppercase and you want to save inside the database.
So for this, again you can write another validator,
So see, this is the function I have created called transform name, and I told you you have to use two decorators, one is field validator.
Now you have to specify which field I'll tell name field and the class method decorator.
Now it will take class object and the value. Now, whatever value user is giving, that means the name. I'm just doing the upper operation, okay, and I'm returning it now.
See here I am giving let's say lowercase buffy, but if I execute this code, still you will see that in the database all of the character would be in uppercase.
Okay, so this is called transformation with the help of this field validator that is also we can do here.
So, guys, now we'll understand one another important concept which is model validator.
So previously I told you about this field validator. So in field validator, what I was performing.
So let's say if I want to do a single field validation, that time I was using this field validator, okay. But let's say there is a condition you have to verify multiple field.
Okay, multiple field means let's say the system you have created, you want to add another functionality which is let's say if patient age is greater than 60, okay.
That time in the contact details there should be an emergency number.
So this kinds of validation I want to do.
Okay, so that time with the help of only field validator, I can't do that because I can't I can't actually mention two field together in the field validator, okay. Only one field can be mentioned.
So we solve this particular problem with the help of this model validator. So for this, this is a very simple concept.
So let me show you how to add this.
So here you have to add this at this code.
So here I will just try to define the indentation, and you have to import this model validator from PyDenti.
Okay, there is another validator called model validator you have to import, and inside that you have to uh give this parameter as after mode is equal to after,
and here you will be creating the function.
The function name is uh validate emergency contract. This will take the class, okay, and this will take the model. Model means the entire schema.
Okay, so if you give the model, that means you can access all of the schema, okay, from inside this particular function.
So here you can see here I'm checking if model.age that means I'm extracting the age. If it is um greater than 60 and uh emergency not in model.contract, okay.
That means if emergency phone number is not available, that time we are er raising one exception, value error patient older than six uh sixty
must have an emergency contact. okay? Then we're returning the model.
Now let's try to check this whether it's working or not. So let's say right now my age is 25. That means this kinds of uh this condition uh will not match, so it will work fine.
So if I execute, see it is working fine.
There is no error,
but if I let's say make my age uh to more than 60, let's say 70, now this will throw you error. It is telling uh value error patient older than 60 must have emergency contact number.
Now, here I have to add the emergency contact number, so maybe after the phone number I can add an emergency number. Now, if I execute, it's working fine.
Okay, so this is called actually model validator. So that means if you have multiple field verification, that time you can use this model validator okay inside your application.
Now, let's try to understand another concept, which is computed fields.
Now, with computed fields, what we can do? Let's try to understand. Let's say, in the same example, um, I want to do another thing. Let's say
um here I have added another information, another data called height. Okay. Now, um, see what computed field does, it does a computation itself.
Okay, let's say if user is giving any kinds of information and it has to recreate or let's say generate a completely new information by utilizing the same information.
That time we'll be using computed fields. Let's say in this case, my patient has given me weight and height, but I want to calculate inside my pydentic uh the BMI, okay. B I'm BMI of the patient.
I'm not taking the BMI from the patient itself.
Instead of that, what I want with the help of weight and height, I want to calculate the BMI. So that time I'll be using this computed field.
So you have to first of all import this computed field from Pydentic. We have already imported now.
You have to again use this as a decorator and you have to write a function here. So my function name is BMI, and again you have to use another um
another actually um
uh another uh decorator which is property.
Okay, you have to use this property.
Uh so the property I think this is already available.
this property is already available inside Python. This is default one, so you don't need to import from anywhere.
Then this is the function we are writing BMI, and we are giving the self parameter, and this returns the float value, okay? Because BMI should be float, and here we are calculating the BMI.
We you can see here we are taking the weight, okay.
Uh then we are dividing with the help of this height and we are squaring it, okay. Then we are taking the BMI.
Okay, we are calculating this BMI, we are taking the result, and with this result, we are trying to return it. Now, if I want to print this, so I have to just simply write patient.bmi right now.
See BMI I haven't written here, okay. Inside my schema, instead of that, I'm calculating it and I'm returning it, so that's why I have to call with the help of this particular function.
Let's say if this function name is BMI test, you have to also give BMI test here. Okay, this is required. Now, simply let me show you whether it works or not.
So here I have already given the height, height, let's say I'm considering in meter and weight I'm considering in kg. Okay, now if I execute, now see it is also giving you the BMI.
Okay, so this is called actually computed field.
So if you want to compute anything with uh with the existing schema you are having, existing data you are having, you can use this computed field at time.
So, guys, now we'll discuss about another important concept inside Piedentic, which is nested model.
so sometimes what happens whenever we create the fields, so field might be complex field as well. So let me give you one example.
Let's say here I have this particular um pydentic model that means the class patient data.
So here I'm having the patient information like name, gender, age, and another information I have which is address.
Okay, now address field might be complex field because address I can't write in a single uh let's say word.
So inside an address, there should be three kinds of entity one is city, pin, and state.
Okay, now
here I'm not going to write uh these kinds of syntax, okay, because this is not possible here.
So instead of that, what we can do, we can create another actually pydentic um class, okay, piedentic model, and we can make it as
a nested, okay.
So, how it can be done? So, let's say here I've created my patient data.
This is my model, and here I've created another model which is address. Okay, and again I inherited with the help of this base model. Okay, now here I've given three entities ct, state, and pin.
Now, first of all, I've created the address as you can see, address dict.
So ct is equal to I have given Gurgao, state is equal to Hadiana, pin is equal to this is the pin.
Okay, now this particular address you have to pass wire to this address model. Okay, so we are passing it to the address model, we are unpacking that.
Okay, now this will uh this will return me one Pidentic object. Okay, now I'm going to create my patient information right now.
So you can see name, gender, age, and now right now address is equal to C.
What I have done, I have given this particular object, this class. Okay, address should be this class. So I'm passing this particular object right now.
Okay, address is equal to this address. Then this patient information I'm passing inside my patient model.
Okay, now this is giving you the patient information. Now, inside this patient information, you are having all of the information, whether it is related patient data, whether it is related address.
Now let me show you. So here I'm putting first of all all of the patient uh you can see data. So inside patient, I am having name, age, okay, and the address. Okay, add this object is also available.
Now, if I want to uh let's say access the name, I can do that. If I want to access the address, I can also do that. Now let's see if I want to
only access the patient ct. Okay, so you just need to write patient address dot ct. So this will give you the ct. Okay, so that's how you can write this nested models.
This is also possible inside pydentic.
Okay, I hope you get it.
So, guys, uh, one more last thing I'm going to discuss about this pydentic, which is uh serialization.
That means you can also um export your uh pydentic object um as a dictionary or a G JSON for this. We use serialization.
So I have taken the same example, so only the last part of what I have done. So here you can see let's say this is my final object of my uh nested uh nested model.
So what I'm doing, I'm just doing model.dump. If you do model.dump, so what will happen? It will return you as a dictionary.
See you are exporting your object as a dictionary. Okay, you can see this is a Python dictionary, okay.
But if you're using this JSON dump, okay, this should be uh string, that means it's a JSON format. Now you can use uh JSON library to export.
I mean you can also export it, you can also dump it, and you can also load it let's say later on. Okay, this is required. Let's say whenever let's say you have created a pydentic object, okay.
You have done some data validation and all, and you want to uh take it as a
take it as a let's say file and let's say you want to load it later on, you can do do this kinds of serialization. Okay, this is also possible.
It's like a like uh mission in machine learning we train model, right? After training the model, we save the model, right? We serialize the model, so it's kinds of that.
Okay, now guys. Uh with that our discussion has been end and we have understood all of the concept uh concept related pidentic, okay. And I think now you are pretty much comfortable with pydentic.
You should not be having any kinds of issue with the pydentic, whether you are working in agentic AI whether you are working in machine learning, deep learning,
anywhere you will see these kinds of concept will be available.
Okay, now one thing I want to show you.
So if I go to Google and if I search like why Pydentic is important for AI agent, as you can see, uh Pydentic is crucial for AI agent because it brings the structure reliability
and type safety for software engineering to be traditionally unstructured and unpredictable word of large language models.
Okay, by leveraging the Python typhins and runtime data validation, Pydentic ensures that AI agents interact uh uh reliably with external docs, APIs and databases.
Okay, so here are some of the uh you can see.
Uh concept they have given. You can go through that.
you will see that at the end, this particular concept is very much required whenever we're working with agent KI application.
Okay, so yes, guys, I think you have understood the whole of the concept. If you have liked it, please try to subscribe to my channel and share this video with your friends and family.
So in this video, I'm going to show you how you can implement uh AI agents with the help of this Langchen.
Okay. But if you're completely new to the Lang Chin, if you don't know about anything about the Langchen, so definitely there would be a prerequisite for this session, uh,
which is the Langchin.
And this Langchen video is already available on my YouTube channel.
As you can see, I am having a complete langchain crash course on my YouTube channel. The
video name is Ultimate langchain Crash Course for Developers.
Okay, so I'm going to
add this video link in the description.
If you are completely new to the Lang Chin, guys, first of all, go ahead with this particular video, then you will be able to understand each and everything about the Langchen.
Then it would be easy for you to understand this Langchen agent's creation, okay.
But if you are already familiar with this Langchen, um you don't need to go through this recording, it's completely fine. You can continue with this particular lecture.
But those who are completely new, I'm telling you guys, please try to complete the Langchain, then you can start with the phase three.
So, in this video, I'm going to implement a single agent system application with the help of langchain.
there I'm going to teach you like what are the things you need to implement these kinds of single agents let's say
workflow and how you can utilize LangChin okay for uh for this particular task.
So, guys, in this video, we are not only going to implement our AI agents after implementing it. I will also show you how we can deploy these kinds of agents over the cloud platform.
So this is going to be very interesting video, and this is going to be our first agent, okay. The first agent application will be creating with the above Langchain.
Uh so this is going to be a single agent system, guys. Don't worry, I'm also going to show you the multi-agent system as well in the next video.
so each and everything I'm going to clarify.
So make sure you watch this video till the end.
So, guys, before implementing this AI agents, first of all, let me give you the idea about AI agents.
Although I have given you the detailed introduction of AI agents, but let's do some quick revision.
As you can see, an AI agent is an intelligence system that receives a high-level goal from a user and autonomously.
plans, decides, and executes a sequence of action by using external tools, APIs, or knowledge sources, all while maintaining the context,
reasoning over multiple steps, adapting to new informations and optimizing for the indented outcome.
Okay, that means agentic AI application or AI agents is having a kinds of power.
Uh basically, it uh it has lots of connection with uh external like tools, APIs or knowledges.
So whenever we are giving any kinds of prompt, okay, it is taking it as a goal, okay.
And with respect to the goal, it is planning all of the let's say task one by one, okay.
And once all of the let's say task is ready, it will try to execute those tasks okay as sequence, and whenever it required any kinds of external tools or APIs, it will try to use that.
Okay, that means if I give you a brief idea about the traditional LLM and uh uh and the current AI agents, what would be the difference between them?
So let's say I think you know previously we use only large language model, right?
Large language model, and here we pass a prompt.
Okay, prompt.
So what will happen? This large language model uh model will take that prompt and it will give you a kinds of answer or response.
Okay, but this large language model doesn't have any external connection with any kinds of tool APIs or knowledge sources.
Okay, so whenever you are asking something, it should be available in the knowledge base itself of the LLM. That means this information should be available when they train this particular LLM.
Okay, but the difference of this AI agent is that whenever you are giving a prompt to the AI agents, so definitely internally AI agents is utilizing the large language
model as a brain, right?
It is utilizing large language model as a brain so that it can perform the reasoning operation, okay? Reasoning operation,
and I I think you know why reasoning is required because with the help of this reasoning, it will decide when to utilize what kinds of tool or what kinds of external sources,
APIs or knowledge sources, whatever, right? So, whenever we are giving a prompt to the AI agents, so basically, what it is doing, it is trying to utilize the large language model;
it is performing the reasoning operation, okay.
And when it is required any kinds of external tools for getting the information, it will try to use that particular tools or any kinds of API,
any kinds of let's say external knowledge sources it will try to utilize, then this will give you the response, okay.
with respect to the prompt you were asking, okay. But whenever it is doing these kinds of operation, so basically it is running some of the plan, right?
Internally, it is running some of the plan, it is making the decision, okay. Then it is executing these are the workflow one by one.
Okay, so this is called actually AI agents.
I think you already know that.
And to make this particular agent okay, to utilize these LLM tools and everything, we need the orchestration framework, okay.
We need the orchestration framework, so with the help of that particular framework, we can uh integrate like large language model, we can integrate like external tools, APIs,
knowledge base.
Okay, then uh we'll try to integrate the reasoning ability so it happens with the help of one orchestration framework. So in this video, we'll be using
Langchen orchestration framework, okay.
Apart from Langchen,
actually uh other orchestration frameworks are also available, which is only designed for AI agents like Langgraph, crew AI, autogen.
Okay, we'll try to discuss definitely, but I want you to first of all show you the first
orchestration uh orchestration framework, actually uh LangChain uh developed okay for the AI agents.
So we not only use LangChain for agent uh generative AI application development, still you can use Langchain to implement these kinds of AI agents,
but Langchain is having some like uh uh limitation. I'll tell you about the limitation in the next video. What is the limitation we are having, why we have to use Langgraph, uh crew AI.
Okay, these are the things definitely I'm going to television everything.
So now let's try to see how we can implement these kinds of AI agents with the help of this lang gen. So for this, I'm going to open up my
local
directory, and then I'm going to launch my VS Code and all of this setup we'll be doing, and we'll start the development.
So, guys, I'm inside my local directory. So, here what I'm going to do uh I'm going to open up my Visual Code Studio here.
So let's open up my Visual Studio Code.
So this is my
Visual Studio Code. Let me zoom.
And I also need to open up my terminal here.
So I'll open up my terminal.
Okay.
So the first step here will be creating a virtual environment and we'll do the requirement installation for this agent.
So let's try to create a file here. I'm going to name it as
readme.md
and inside that I'm going to mention all of the command you need to execute.
So to create an environment, you have to execute this command. So conduct create hypen n.
I'll name it as lang
agent that means lang chain agent. You can give any name, it's up to you.
Then you can specify the Python version.
So Python is equal to I'll be taking
3.11
and hyphen wipe. That means I want to give the yes permission.
Once it is done, you have to activate the environment and you have to install the requirements.
Okay, now you can copy this command one by one and you can execute inside your terminal.
So for me, this uh environment is already available. So what I'm going to do, I'm going to activate directly.
But if you don't have guys, first of all, try to execute the first command, then execute the second command.
So see, guys, this lang agent is already available. This environment is already available.
Now I'm going to add the requirements.
So let's create another file here.
I'm going to name it as requirement.txt.
Inside that, you have to mention all of the requirements for this particular agent.
So I have already listed down all of the requirements you need, guys.
So these are the requirements you need. So I need Langchin, I need Langchain community, I need Langchain code, I need LangChin OpenAI,
I need um uh these things I don't need. I need request, then tably Python and Python.
I'm going to tell you why this uh uh this thing are required. Actually, let me tell you, see Langchen.
I think you know this is the main framework, this is the main orchestration framework, and to uh run this Langchain, you need some other dependency package like Langchain Community and Langchain
Core.
And here we'll be using a large language model because I think so internally agent uses a large language model for the reasoning, and this is the main brain.
So for this large language model, I'm going to use this open AI, okay? Open AI provider.
So from open AI, I'm going to use a particular model, and here you can change with any kinds of model if you want.
Let's say you can also use any free provider like open router, you can also use Grok API, okay.
You can also use Gemini API, you can use anything, but I have the open AI, that's why I'm going to use the open AI.
But whenever you are using this kinds of free model, so there are some limitations definitely. So you won't be getting any kinds of good response from this kinds of free model.
That's why I'm using my open AI model so that I can show you the best response I'll be getting from my agent itself. Okay, but this code C uh this model is changeable, guys.
This provider provider is changeable anytime you can change with any model, any provider.
So simply you just need to copy that
model initialization code. And if you give to the chat GPT, and if you ask, like let's say I want to use open router, this free model, so definitely you will be getting that.
So let me first of all write the code, then I think you will be able to understand.
Then request I need let's say if I want to hit some of the URL external URL or external website, external API that time. I need this request module.
I will tell you why this request module I'm I'll be using here.
Then tabily Python. So tabily is a tool, okay. Search tool. So with the help of tabily, what you can do, you can perform the internet search operation.
Okay, so the agents will be implementing, we'll try to add this tool so that my agents will be able to search any kinds of content over the internet
and python.enb I need for the environment management. I'll be using open api key. I need tabily API key. All of the API key I'm going to mention inside my.enb.
Okay, so let me create a file called env.
So inside that I'm going to mention all of the API key.
But first of all, you have to install this requirement.txt. So let's copy this command, open up the terminal, and simply execute that.
So for me, it is already installed.
it will tell like requirement is already satisfied, but for you it will take some time.
Okay, so see, it has executed.
Um,
I think everything is fine.
Okay, so here another package you need which is
language in.
Langchen hub,
okay. Langchen hub is also required. I'll tell you why Langchen Hub is required.
So let me install again.
Done.
Okay, Langchen
... okay, spelling is not correct, so let's copy the spelling
now. I think,
yeah, everything is fine.
So for me, it is already satisfied; for for you, it might take some time. So once installation is completed, guys, what I can do?
I can simply create a folder.
I can, let's say,
give the folder name as research,
and inside that, I'm going to create a Jupyter notebook file. I'm going to name it as agent
uh
demo
dot ipynb
okay
yeah
Perfect, so one more thing I have to do which is this.enb file. I will copy this one and I will paste it inside research as well,
okay? Because, uh, if I want to execute this notebook file, definitely I need this dot .enb, so that's why I have done that.
Yeah.
Now guys, what I'm going to do, I'm going to first of all import some necessary library. But before that, let's select our environment, so python environment which is lang agent.
Okay, I'm going to select that.
So simply, I'm going to import some required library, so I need operating system, then I need
Certify,
okay.
Why I need certify? I will tell you. Then I need request
import,
request. Then I need
env.
So let me copy all of the input I need here.
Yeah, so I need env.
So I will import load env because with the help of this load_env, we will try to load the environment variable and whatever key we are having inside that we can load.
Then from Langchain OpenAI, we are importing chat openEI So this is the class we can use to load any kinds of large language model
from OpenAI provider.
Then we are also importing these tools.
Okay, why this tool is required? I'll tell you. But as of now, let me delete this option and also delete this, uh, delete this library, because these two things I want to show you later on.
First of all, let's create a simple agents. Then I'm going to show you how we can improve this particular agent. Okay? Then from Langchain community, I'm importing this tabily search result.
Okay, that means this tabily search tool as I already told you. We are also installing this, uh, tabily python.
So tabily is one of the search tool with the help of that you can perform the internet search operation.
So we can import. This, uh, Tably from the tool and it is available in Langchain community. Okay, that's why you are also installing Langchain community.
We are importing tools tabily search and Tably search result. Okay, so once it is done, so simply
I'm going to, uh, okay, another package I need which is,
uh, lang chain hub.
Okay, so from Langchain
import
hub.
So now let me import all of them. So it is asking, it will install some required ipy kernel package, so let's install.
So, if you are doing it for the first time, um, let's say in waste code first time means, you know, like, uh, if you are creating a fast jupyter notebook file
and if you're executing, so initially it will install some dependency, uh, ipy related, uh, package. Okay, so it is installing.
Let's wait. Once this installation is complete, then we can execute again.
Okay, it has executed successfully. There is no issue.
Okay.
Now, here guys, what I'm going to do simply I'm going to um import uh some agent related functionality from Langchin. Okay, so first of all, I need
two things.
So from Langchin create
dot agent.
Okay, it is available inside agent module.
I'm going to import
agent uh create react agent. Okay, so there is a function we are having called create
Okay, so this thing I'm going to tell you what is this create react agent. The full form of this uh react agent is reasoning, uh reasoning and action.
Okay, so the full form of this react is reasoning and action.
Okay, we can we can call it as a react agent.
I'll tell you how this react agent works, uh what is the mechanism behind it.
But as of now, just try to think this is the agent uh we mostly use from the lang chain.
Apart from that, some other let's say agent function we are having in the lang chain,
but this is the most popular one people use this.
Okay,
React sorry, reasoning and action agent.
Now, once it is done, I'm going to import another
functionality which is agent executor. Okay, I'm also going to tell you why this agent executor is required and how this works with the React agent.
Okay, so these two libraries I need.
Now let's try to import them.
Yeah.
So once we have imported, now simply
uh what we have to do, guys, we have to uh we have to load the environment variable.
Okay, we have to load the environment variable because in the environment variable itself we'll be mentioning all of our API key.
So, first of all, first of all, I need my open API key because I already told you for the large language model uh we'll be using open AI, right? So let's try to mention the open API key.
So, how we can get the open API key, guys. I think you know simply you just need to go to open AI uh API provider.
So here you can go to the API platform and uh left hand side you will see the option called uh API key.
Okay, simply create our API key here, and you just need to copy the API key.
Okay, so for me, I already have the API key. Let me show you.
I'll just copy.
Copy this API key.
So this is my API key, guys. Don't use my API key. I'm going to reboot after this recording, just try to create your own API key.
And you don't need to necessarily use this open API key if you want, you can also use any other like LLM provider. Okay, it's completely fine.
Now, with that, I also need another API key, which is the tabily,
okay. Tabily API key because uh what happens? Let's say whenever I will be initializing the search tool, okay. Search tool of the tabily.
Uh so to use this tabily, I need an API key. So, how to get the tabily API key?
So, for this you have to visit
tabily.com, okay, or you can search like tabily API key.
So, instead of tabily, there are some other like search tools are available, like SARP API, duck duck go search, uh, and other tools are also available, but I'm going to use this tabily
one.
So, simply click on tably API key.
So, you have to create an account if you don't have account. So, I already have the account, guys. I created with the help of my Gmail.
So, once you are inside the dashboard, you will be seeing these kinds of interface. So, from here you can create an API key.
Okay, so for me, I already have created some API key, but let me show you how to create the API key.
So, let's say here I'm going to create an API key called
my key.
Okay, once it is done, just create the API
key. Okay, your key is created, and initially, whenever you are creating an account, you will be creating 1000 free credit.
I think this is enough for learning but if you want to use it for the production, that time you have to take their premium plan.
Okay, now let's copy this key and what I'm going to do, I'm going to open up my.
Inside that, I'm going to mention my
tabily API key.
So let's make let me copy.
So this is my tabily APA key.
Okay, tabily apart then now. Let's uh initialize
this thing.
But I have to load the environment first of all, load environment variable.
Let's load
Yeah, so here we are loading the environment variable, but before loading it, so here you can see I am setting this SSL
certify file. Okay.
Uh so from this certify library you can see we have already imported, and here we are calling where because what happens if you are using Windows operating system, so sometimes it
will it it might give you some path related issue, okay. Because what happens window Windows by default open some older path, okay, and that's why this issue usually raises.
So, what this code does actually it will tell your Windows that it will always try to use the trusted certificate authority,
so that whenever it is initializing the
path, it will load the updated one, okay, instead of loading the old one.
Okay, you can also search over the internet, have uh you can read about this SSL certify file. Okay, I think you will be able to understand.
But if you're using any other operating system like macOS or Linux, I think that time it is not required.
But if you are getting the path related issue, that time you can add this code, guys. Okay, uh, this is optional.
Uh for me, actually, I was having this issue, that's why I have added, but for you, if you don't have issue, if you don't have issue, you don't need to add it, okay?
It's completely fine. So once it is done, now we are getting our open API key and we are loading it here in this particular variable, and we are also loading our tably
API key.
Okay, once it is done, let's try to load them.
Now uh we'll be initializing the tabily search result uh object, so I can name it as a
search tool.
Search tool is equal to
tably
search result,
and inside that there is a parameter you can mention like max result. Okay, max result means how many results you want after doing the internet search operation.
Let's say we're searching for a topic, let's see what searching give me some latest news.
So, how many search result you want? How many reference website you want?
So, if it is let's say two, this will give me two relevant let's say
result. Okay, if you if it is five, it will give me five reference.
That's how it works, okay. Now, let me show you how this thing will work.
So, simply what I will do, I will just try to initialize it now. Let's try to test it.
Search
tool
dot invoke
inside that I'm going to let's say give what is the capital of French,
okay. Or let's say I'll tell
okay, now SARS spelling is not correct.
Now fine.
Now here I can tell
give me
the latest news on AI.
Now
I will store it in a variable called result.
Now simply I'm going to show this result.
Okay,
now see uh it is real time searching over the internet and it is referring some of the website. You can see this is the URL.
So this is the first website it is referring for the latest news on AI.
let me show you this website.
This is referring this blog google.com.
So here is the latest AI news announced in March 2026, and there is another reference you will get see uh this one.
This is another website.
from here also it is getting the information.
That means now my maximum result is two. I'm getting two actually um
internet search reference. If you if you make it as three, four, you'll be getting four references, okay, like that.
Okay, that's how you can use this tabily search for real-time internet search operation, and this is called actually search tool.
And you can use this tool with your agent because agent should be always connected with these kinds of external tool, like
this kinds of real-time tool.
Whenever it needs any kinds of latest information, it will be using this tool to get this informations, okay.
with you, and again, I'm telling you, I'm creating a single agent system here.
I'm not creating multi-agent system, I'm also going to show you how we can create the multi-agent system as well, okay.
Each and everything I'm going to cover, but in this video, we'll be only focusing on the uh single agent system, okay?
Fine.
Now, our search tool is ready.
Now, simply what I'm going to do, I'm going to initialize me my large language model.
So, let's initialize our large language model.
So, this is the large language model, guys. So, from chat openai, we are taking this GPT 3.5 turbo model. You can also use GPT 4.5, it's up to you.
Temperature, this is the creativity parameter. I'm I I just kept it with zero, and here you need to pass the open eIPI key.
Now, let's initialize the LLM.
So, once it is initialized, let me also test whether my LLM is working or not.
I'll just do the invoke operation lm.
Now, here I'm telling let's say
uh what is the year? Is it
and the result we'll be getting again will store
response.
See, this is
is it currently uh 2022?
Okay, why it is giving you it is uh currently 2022 because this GPT 3.5 Turbo uh has been trained till 2022. Okay, it doesn't have any latest information after that.
Okay, that's why this agent is required. I told you right in my introduction session why uh uh we don't use the large language model only, why agent is required, okay.
Why real time tool is required, each and everything I've already clarified.
Now, let me ask another question. Let's say
tell me
a joke about AI.
Now, see it is giving you a joke, okay. That means it's working fine perfectly. Now
I need a prompt, guys. Okay, uh, to implement the agent, I need a prompt,
and here we are using this
create react agent function, and for this create react agent function, I need a relevant prompt.
So this prompt either you can write manually, either you can download from Langshen Hub.
So that's why we have already installed this LangChann Hub, I think you remember.
So, what is Langchain Hub in the Langchin Hub itself? There are uh like so many prompt uh like predefined prompt are already available.
So there are lots of uh let's say developer they have already published their prompt, so you can use the pre-existing prompt and you can use it inside your application development.
But if you want, you can also manually write this prompt, okay? But why we are taking the pre-defined prompt because we are using this create react agent functionality, okay.
And for create for this create react agent functionality, this prompt is like very good, and this is recommended prompt to use that.
Okay, now let me show you this prompt. You can copy the name, and if you go to Google,
you can search it, you can search it here. Let's say
now you can open the first website.
Okay, so you will see this particular prompt, guys. Here, see, this is already available in the hub, and you can see the prompt, guys. Answer the following questions as best as you can.
You have access to the following tools, blah blah blah. Okay, I'm going to explain this prompt later on, but first of all, let me create the agents and then let me explain okay what it does.
Now my prompt is ready.
Now, what I have to do, guys, I have to prepare my tools.
So I only created one tools which is my tabily source tool.
So, what I will do, I'll just try to add this tool.
So let me create a list.
Okay, inside that list, I'm going to mention my search tool. Let's see if you're using multiple tool, You can add inside this particular list. Okay, I'm going to tell you how we can add also.
Now my tool is also ready.
Okay, I have to also execute the prompt.
Now see, it has uh it has get this particular prompt from that length in hub itself. Now let me show you the prompt.
Now see, guys, this is the prompt.
Okay, this is the prompt. It has already got this particular prompt.
Great.
Now you have to create the agent.
Okay, you have to create the agent.
Uh we have already got the prompt. We have already got the tool.
Let me comment here.
Okay, tool is there.
Now we'll be creating the agent.
Yeah.
So to create the agent, guys, we'll be using this function create react agent.
And this create react agent takes actually uh three things.
The first thing is the large language model.
Um, like this is the brain of that particular agent, and we are passing our large language model. The second is is that tool, okay. The tool it will be using for uh actually external uh
search operation or external reference, and the third thing it needs the prompt, okay.
That means you are telling uh your agent how it should interact, okay, how it should perform the jobs, each and everything, each and every instruction is given inside the prompt.
Okay, so whenever you are creating this uh uh React agent, that time you have to pass this three things, okay. And this will return you one agent object object. Okay, now let me execute.
So I got the agent object right now.
Now, what I have to do, I have to run this agent okay with the help of the agent executor we have already imported.
So, as you can see, we have already imported this agent executor.
So let's use this agent executor to run this agent, and don't worry, I'm going to explain you why this
I mean how this create react agent works, how this agent executor works, okay, why it is required, agent everything I'm going to clarify.
So now let me define the executor. So this is our executor.
So as you can see,
we are calling this agent executor, and agent executor takes another three argument. The first one is the agent, the agent we have created.
Let's say here we have created only one agent, okay, which is this one.
We are passing it, then we are giving the tool, okay.
Uh, the tool we have initialized, then there's another parameter called verbose.
So verbose if you make it as true, that means whatever agent will execute, let's say whatever plan step it will execute, you'll be able to see the type in the terminal.
And if you make it as false, you won't be able to see the logs, okay? So basically, if you want to see the logs of your agent, you can make it as true, otherwise, you can make it as false.
Okay, so this will give you the agent executor object. So once you got the agent executor object, now you are ready to run this agent.
So to run this agent, guys, we'll be
using this agent executor, and we'll simply do the invoke operation, and here we are giving a input. So the input wise we are giving find the capital of India and then the find its current weather.
Okay, so this thing I'm not going to pass it right now because
I want to show you another things.
Okay, now simply I'm going to tell find the capital of India. Now it will give you the response,
and this response I'm going to
print it.
Okay, this response. So from the response itself, I will print the output. Now let me execute.
Now see agent is executing, so it is telling entering new
agent executor chain.
So I should use the search engine to find the answer.
So it is using the search tool, that means the tabily search tool, and it is finding see it is action is tabily search tool it is utilising.
Then it refers a website, okay. From the website itself, it found that the capital of India is New Delhi, and once it got the result, okay, now you can see the final result, which is New
Delhi. Okay, so let me uh give another input here. So, I'm going to just write:
Tell me the
latest
news about
Iran
and USA word.
Okay, now let's execute.
So it is you can see it is using this stabilizer tool.
Okay, so as you can see, my execution is done. So it is using this stabilizers tool and it is using different different online sources, and it is extracting
the latest information.
And now let me show you the final output. So this is the final output. The latest news on Iran and USA were in uh includes Iran warning of consequences if the US launches new attacks,
okay.
Blah blah blah.
That means it is able to give you the real time, okay, the latest informations. Although we are using the GPT 3.5 toolbook,
okay, which is uh trained till 2022, but it is able to give you the latest uh latest actual informations about 2026.
Okay, now let me show you. Let's see if I'm not passing any kinds of tool to the agents, what will happen?
So here let's say
what I'm going to do.
So let's say here I'm going to create an empty
empty tool.
Okay,
so I'm not going to pass anything in this tool.
So let's execute
now. Again, I will create the React agent.
Again, I will um
execute the agent executor.
Then I will ask this question.
Now see it is continuously looking for the tool, but it is not getting right.
See, it is not getting. So execution is done. Now, if I
uh print it, the final response you will see that agent stopped due to the iteration limit or time limit.
Okay, what happens?
Because whenever you are not providing any kinds of external tools, okay, what it is happening,
uh it is not able to get any kinds of tool which it can use for searching these kinds of latest informations and it is continuously running this tool,
a loop, okay. So there are uh there are actually uh limitation of this particular loop.
So once let's say it is not able to get it, so this loop would be finished, and you are getting this agent is stopped due to the iteration limit or time limit,
okay. But if we provide this tool, okay, if we provide this tool,
that time see my agent is working, uh working perfectly fine.
Okay, see it's working perfectly fine. Now it is able to get the tool and it is able to search the content on the internet, and it is giving you the
answer.
Okay, I hope you get it.
That means what is happening? Let's say this is our agent.
This is our agent,
okay.
And here we are
giving a prompt or input,
and what it is doing. first of all, this input is coming to the agent, and it is utilizing LLM. okay, as a brain for the reasoning operation.
and LLM is deciding.
let's say, the input we are giving, whether it needs any kinds of tool or not. So the question we have given, so definitely it needs a tool because here we are using very old LLM, right?
Which is GPT 3.5 turbo.
Okay, it doesn't have the information about Iran and USA Word, right? Because this this happens actually this year, that means the current year.
Now LLM will tell okay, I don't have the information. So what we have to do, we have to use an external tool.
Okay, what we have to do we have to use external tool.
So right now, let's say I have connected with tabily search API. So what it is doing, it is going to tabily,
it is executing this tool. This tool is giving you the response, like it is referring uh to website because there is a parameter called uh um search result.
Uh big uh that parameter I have like set it to, so it will get two relevant uh let's say informations about the uh Iran
and USF wire.
So this is returning to the agent, and now agent is getting that information and it is giving you the final output.
Okay, it is giving you the final output. That's how things are working, and whenever you are not giving this tool, right? That time what is happening?
Agent agent is continuously looking for the tool, but it is not able to get it.
Any kinds of response from the tool that that's how uh it is breaking the loop, it is breaking the iteration, and it is giving you. I uh I didn't got the answer.
Okay, the loop is uh executed. Uh sorry, the loop loop is
uh stopped. Okay, I think you saw this final message here.
Uh, here is the final masses.
Uh okay. I already like uh uh replaced it. I think you saw the message, right? This loop is already closed. we are not able to execute that, okay. So that's how things are working.
Now let me explain about these two things, which is create react agent and another is agent executor. Okay, how this create create react agent works, why why we call it as a
reasoning action agent,
and why agent execute executor is required to run this particular create react agents. Okay, I'll try to discuss this part right now.
So, guys, as you can see, uh first of all, let's try to understand this uh React agent how React Agent works.
So, as you can see, React is a design pattern used in AI agents that stands for reasoning and acting.
Okay, um, it allows a language model LLM to uh enter interleave internal reasoning
thought with external actions like tool use in a structured multiple process.
Okay, that means I told you if I want to execute an agent, so I need some external tools, right?
And to select that particular external tool, definitely you need a reasoning, and that reasoning you are doing with the help of LLM, some kinds of large language model.
Large language model is deciding okay, now I have to use this particular tool, and you are using that tool to get the response, and you are you
uh and uh you are actually sending that particular tool response to the agent, and agent is giving you the structured output, okay. So the whole system is working like that, okay.
Now we are using this React React agent, okay, from the Langchain.
So the React agent is implemented in that way, okay, because internally they have written all kinds of code related, these kinds of orchestration that means it has the connection with LLM,
it has the connection with lots of tools.
Okay, so once we are giving any kinds of prompt, it is automatically deciding with the help of LLM like what tool to use, okay.
For the actions, so let's say once I executed the tool, then what will happen?
this tool will give you some kinds of response and you will be structuring this particular output and you will show show to the human.
Okay, so this is a multi-step process.
Okay, this is a multi-step process that means this is a kind of loop.
Okay, so you can see instead of generating an answer in one go, the model thinks step by step decides deciding what it needs to do next,
and optionally calling tools, apis calculator, web search, etc., to help it. Okay, that means not only um not only like tabli search tool. Okay, you can use any kinds of tool here.
Either you can use any kinds of API, either you can use any kind of calculator, web search, and anything.
Okay, now see this React actually works in three steps.
So I have already given an example.
As you can see, the first step is nothing but the thought.
Okay,
thought.
Then the second step you can see action,
okay.
And the third step is nothing but observation.
Observe
observation.
Okay, now see here is the example. So, what is thought? First of all, let's try to understand whenever we are giving any kinds of prompt. Let's say we are giving a prompt, let's say
we are giving a prompt.
what is the capital of France and tell me the
uh tell me the population for capital of France? Okay, let's say this is my prompt.
So, first of all, what will happen? We are using let's say this React agent.
So this prompt will go to the React agent, and React agent will try to make a thought first of all.
So, the what would be the first thought?
First thought is nothing but let's say I need to find the capital of France.
Okay, so first of all, this would be the thought.
Now, for this particular thought, it will perform a kinds of action.
Okay, so in this action, it will utilize external tool. So in this case, it will utilize the search tool, okay.
And with the help of search tool, what it will do, it will try to perform some action.
Okay, so let's say it has done the sourcing operation at the capital of France on the internet and it got some observation, like okay, the capital of France is nothing but Paris.
Okay, so once it got the observation, you can see the first
loop is complete.
Okay, the first loop is complete, and in the first loop, it has performed three things thought, action, and observation.
Now it will come to the second loop.
Now you can see in the second loop again the thought will apply.
Now let's say it has already got the Paris, okay, the capital of France.
Now it will tell now I need to find the population of Paris.
Okay, what it will do again, it will perform my action, again it will maybe utilize a SARS tool or any other tool it is having. With the help of this particular tool, it will perform the action.
Okay, so now it will try to figure out the population of Paris.
Now let's say observation is 2.1 million. it is the population of Paris.
Okay, now you can see this is the
second loop.
Okay, second loop is complete.
Now it will perform the third loop.
Okay, now you can see once it got the final result. Okay, once it got the final result, that time this loop would be uh this loop would be uh stopped.
Okay, now how it will understand this loop should be stopped because there we in the prompt itself we try to set whenever we we get the final answer.
Now let's say the third iteration you will say you will you'll see that now I know the final answer.
Okay, so once it knows the final answer, okay.
That time this particular iteration should be stopped.
Now you can see it will return with the final answer that time.
The Paris is uh Paris is capital of France and has a population around 2.1 million.
Okay, that means the prompt. I think you remember I showed you one prompt, okay. We are using from Langchain Hub.
In the prompt, also, these kinds of steps are available, okay. And there we strictly mention that once you got the final answer, okay.
Once you know the final answer, just try to stop this particular iteration. Now, let me show you this prompt again. I think now it would be clear to you.
So, guys, as you can see, this was the prompt. Now you can see the prompt. Answer the following questions as best you can.
You have access to the following tools.
So I think you remember in our agents we have already provided the tool access.
Okay.
All the tool access we are having.
Now we are telling use the following format.
Question. Okay. Question should be the input questions you must answer. Okay, the user input questions.
Now you can
uh you can have three things, three steps. First of all, thought you should always think about what to do. Okay, and this thought how it will think with the help of LLM.
Okay, now with respect to the thought, it should perform some action.
Okay, the action to take should be one of the tools. Okay, that means this action should be tell with the help of one of the tool.
So once let's say
we have selected the tool, now
what should be the action input? We have to provide the action input.
Now this will perform the action, and when whenever whenever it will get the response from the tool, so this this is called actually observation, the result of the action.
Okay, once you got the observation, now this particular step should be running continuously.
You can see this thought action, action input observation can repeat n times unless and until thought is I know the final answer. Okay, I know the final answer.
This particular, this particular uh let's say
iteration should be continuously running.
Okay, once you know the final answer, that time just try to provide the final answer. Let's say this is the final answer of the original questions, and what will happen?
It will try to
end that particular agent. Okay, so every agent works like that, guys.
Okay, I think you got it because the main funda is behind the agent is to run some of these steps, okay, and continuously this will run these steps
unless and until it found the final answer. Okay, once it found the final answer, then this particular loop would be break and you will be getting the final output.
Okay, now you can see the question. Um, as a as a like say um human, we have to give the question our question, and agent internally will try to take the agent uh
scrap uh scratch pad. Okay, what is agent scratch pad?
Agent scratch pad is nothing but the that three things, okay.
This thought, action, and observation because continuously it has to take that, okay. Continuously it has to take that to understand the previous question, action, and observation.
Okay, so these kinds of things will be continuously happening, unless and listening we are not going to final answer, okay. Now I think you got it.
So that's why I told you uh uh we'll be using this predefined React prompt for this React agent.
Uh, you can also write your own prompt, but if you're writing, so you may miss down, these are the option and whenever you miss down, these are the let's say context,
so definitely your agent uh might not give you the correct response. So that's why prompting is always important whenever you're creating your own agent system, guys.
Okay,
so guys, now I think you have understood what is this create react agent, okay? How it works.
now we'll try to understand what is this executor is agent executor, okay.
Why we need this agent executor to run this react agent.
Let's try to understand about this.
one more thing I want to tell you, which is that let's say after using this create react agent, it takes three parameters llm, tools, and prompt. We get the agent object, okay.
This is our final agent object, and to run this agent, we need this agent executor.
Okay, now let me show you another diagram.
So, guys, as you can see, this is the diagram of agent and agent executor.
Now we'll try to understand how this works, okay? why this agent executor is required.
So let's say we have created a React agent object, which is nothing but our agent, okay. In the code itself, I already told you.
Now to run this agent, I need the agent executor.
Okay, so why I need this agent executor?
See to run this agent, okay. I think you know internally agent uh runs actually three steps.
One is the first thing, uh first thing is like the uh this one, which is um
um let me show you,
yeah.
The first thing is the thought, okay?
Thought.
Then second thing
is action,
and the third thing is
observation.
Okay, so to run this three step guys, we need this agent executor.
Okay, to run this three step, we need this agent executor.
So without agent executor, we can't actually run these three steps.
Okay, so that's why whenever we have created our agent to execute this agent, we need an agent executor and internally
agent executor handle this three scenario.
So what will happen in the first iteration? Let's say you can see this is the steps of agent executor orchestrate the entire loop.
So, first of all, sends the input and previous message to the agent.
Okay, so what will happen?
This agent executor will try to send the input.
What is the input? Input or nothing but the user input.
Okay, user input.
Let's say user has asked.
Let's say um, I think I can give you the same example, the previous example.
Uh, what is the capital of friends? And I need the population of capital of friends. Let's say this is the input.
So, first of all, this agent executor will try to send this input to the agent, and it will also send the previous message to the agent.
Previous message means these three things thought, action, and observation.
So, initially, for the first time, whenever you are executing the agent, definitely this three uh three actually block would be completely empty.
Okay, this three block it should be completely empty. That means whatever thought, action, and observation you are sending, it should be completely empty.
So your agent will only receive the user input that time.
Okay, now once it got the user input,
now your agent will decide okay whether it has to use any kinds of tools or not.
Okay, now you can see gets the next action from the agent.
Okay, so you can see
yeah, so sends the input and previous message to the agent.
Once it is done, now uh agent will try to uh let's say perform the reasoning operation with the help of reasoning, uh,
it will decide the question we are getting whether I need to use any kinds of tools or not, because agent is already connected with the tools. I think I showed you, right?
It has already connected with tools, okay.
It has connected with tools now. Agent will decide whether it has to use any tools or not.
Let's say it has to use a tool.
What tool?
The tabula search tool.
Then again, agent will try to tell agent executor say uh
that like I have to use the tably search tool to give the answer.
Okay, now what agent executor will do?
It will go to the tool.
What tool? The tabily tool.
Okay, tabily tool, and it will hit the tabily tool with the question user is asking.
Let's say the first question was what is the capital of French?
Now, tabily will refer some internet website and it will give you the answer.
Again, agent will give this answer to the agent.
Okay, now agent got the answer. Let's say the capital of French is Paris.
Okay, now what will happen?
This is the observation. You can see execute the tool with provide an input, adds the tool observation back into the history. Now, what will happen?
Again, it will try to
add uh add uh inside this thought action and observation because it is already getting this thought,
then action
and observation. Now, this these are the parameters will be filled up. Now, what is the thought?
Thought should be let's say it already got the capital of friends, which is Paris.
Action it has already taken, it has used the tabily tool, okay.
And the input was what is the capital of friends and
sorry, thought should be it already got the
capital of friends, okay. Um and action should be it has let's say already executed the tabily tool, and observation should be the Paris. Okay, it already got the Paris.
Now it will run the second loop.
Okay, it will run the second loop because it does it didn't get the final answer yet.
Okay, it didn't get the final answer yet.
Now again, what it will do again, execute agent executor will run.
Okay, now agent exent executor will run the thought.
What is the thought? Now next thought should be this one.
Next thought should be this one.
Now I need to uh I need to find the population of Paris. Okay, this should be the next thought again. It we go to the agents.
Again, agents will decide whether it has to use a tool or not.
So again, it will tell okay, I need to use the tablice tool. Agent executor will go to a tablizer tool.
It will hit the tabliers again, get the real-time information, pass it to the agent. Now agent will again fill up this information with thought, action, and observation.
You can see thought, action, and observation.
Okay, that's it. Got 2.1 million.
Now it got the final answer. Okay. Now this agent will tell now I have the final answer. Now, once agent executor got this one, let's say now I have the final answer.
That time this agent executor will stop. That means this is running the entire loop.
Okay. That means this is running the entire loop.
So once you are getting the final answer, this particular loop would be executed, exited, and your application will stop and you will be able to see the final answer.
Okay, so that's how things are working, guys. That's how the Langchain agent and agent executor we are creating.
It is working internally like that. Okay, so whenever you are using this React agent, so definitely you have to use this agent executor. This is very much required.
Now I think, guys, you are pretty much clear about the Langchain create agent. Okay, how it works.
Sorry, Langchain React agent, how it works, why we need this agent executor along with that.
Okay, now let me show you as a code.
So you can see the code, guys.
Uh, in the code itself, we have already written this create react agent.
It takes LLM tool and prompt. Okay, with the prompt, it performs all the instruction how this react agent works. I think I already showed you the prompt.
And to run this agent, I need the agent executor. That's why we are giving this agent tool. We are also giving because I think you know that uh agent executor will uh invoke this tool.
Okay, that's why tool access also I need to give to the agent executor, and there's another one, barbos. Okay, barbos is the all the execution is happening right internally.
See, you can see the logs, but if you make it as false, let's say I will make it as false.
So, what will happens?
You won't be able to see any kinds of
execution.
Let me again create the React agent
executor. Now, if I run the agent, see you won't be able to see any kinds of logs.
See it executed, but you can't see any kinds of log, but still you will be able to see the output. Okay, output is there, but whenever you make it as true, right?
So you will be able to see the
log.
So for this again, I have to execute the agent.
Now see this particular log you will be able to see whatever decision, uh whatever thought, actions, and observation your agent is performing, you are able to see that, okay,
in life.
So that's why we make it as uh this parameter as true.
Okay, now I think you are clear enough, guys.
Okay, so yes, guys, so that's how we can uh use this Langchain to develop these kinds of single uh single actually
agent system, and this is our first agent, guys.
this is like very simple agents we have created.
so don't worry, in the next video, I'm going to also show you how we can create the multi-agent system. So here only one agent is working, right?
But if you want, we can also create multiple agent and that will be working together. Okay, this is also possible.
Now, what I'm going to show you guys, uh, I'm going to show you how we can convert it this particular notebook in in a application file, that means app.py,
and we can run that particular app.py.
Okay, because I have showed you the research right now, that means the experiment right now, but in production, definitely will you will not create the Jupyter notebook file;
instead of that, you have to create a Python file. So let's say I'm going to name it as app.py.
Okay, so simply what you can do, you can
copy whatever code you have written in the notebook
in this app.py. See, I just copy-pasted the same code.
Copy it's the same code, but before that, let me show you how we can improve this agent.
if you want to improve it, if you want to add some more tool, so how it can be done.
Let's say here I want to add another tool, and that particular tool will real time search the weather informations, okay.
weather informations given any kinds of location because right now I'm using the tabily search tool, it is completely fine, but I want my custom
custom tool. Let's say I have created a custom function, and that custom function I want to use use as a tool, okay. How it can be done? Let's try to see that.
So, for this, uh, what I'm going to do, I'm going to let's say import
this lang chain
dot
tool.
Okay,
import
there is a function called tool.
You have to import that, and I will import another library called request.
Okay, this tool library I'll import.
Once it is done, now simply here I'm going to create a function.
So after this search tool, maybe I can create my custom function. So this custom function will get the weather information.
Okay,
so I've already written a function.
So let me show you this function how it works.
So maybe I can show you test.ip
or let's say here itself I'm going to show you how this function works.
Yeah, so this is my function, guys.
So what this function does, this function takes a city name, okay, or given any kinds of location, and it it fets the current weather information of that particular city.
So for this, we are using this weather stack API, okay. Weather Stack API, I think you know this is our website weather stack.com.
So let me show you.
this is the website
weather stack.com.
so this is the website, guys. So here, first of all, you have to create an account. just sign up with free. Okay, so once you sign up, you will be able to see your dashboard.
Okay, so if you go to the dashboard,
so here you will be see this kinds of interface, okay. And we are using the free plan. So in free plan, only we can search the real-time weather information.
But if you're using the paid subscription of this weather stack, that time you can perform location search, uh astronomy data, hour by hour, okay, full historical data.
So there have been so many things you can perform here,
but I only need for the weather information. That means my free plan is completely fine. So here you have the API key, you just need to copy this API key.
Okay, so don't use my API key, I'm going to remove it after the recording.
So here you have to pass this weather API key. Now, what I can do, maybe in the.enb itself, I can mention my
API key.
so here is the.enb.
So I already collected this API key, guys. Let me show you.
So this is the API key weather stack API key, and this is the API key I have copy-pasted from the dashboard.
Okay, now simply here itself you have to load this API key as well.
So let's load it weather stack API key waste.get weather stack API key. So you are also loading this.
Okay, once it is done, now see this API key would be given here.
Now, how these things will work, let me show you. I will copy this
and I will paste it here.
Now f string, I'm going to just remove it
because this is I have given only for static variable.
F string I don't need
now.
If you give any city here, let's say I'll give
I'll give Mumbai.
Uh
okay, you have to pass the API key, right? So let's copy the API key.
Now, if I hit enter,
see you will be getting a response like that. Okay, so this is having the information about the Mumbai, uh, the current uh weather information, as you can see.
Okay, the current weather information it is having.
Okay, now I have to extract the data from this particular JSON itself.
So, what I have done, I have written a function here as you can see.
So, this function hit this URL with this API key, and you can give any kinds of city name.
I'm hitting with the help of this request library, I have already imported here as you can see request.
So, once we get the response, so what we are doing, we are just converting to the JSON.
Now we are telling if current not in data.
So I'll tell could not find the phase weather data because current parameter should be there.
Because in the current one, we are having the current weather information, okay? This temperature weather what it is having. Okay, so we are getting this current key.
Now, once we get the current key, I'm taking the city name, temperature, weather, and humidity. Okay, these are the information I'm taking.
If you want, you can also take any other information, it's completely up to you. So this is a function, custom function.
Now, if I want to use this custom function as a tool, so what I have to do, I have to write a decorator at the rate, and the tool I have imported.
Okay, so this tool I have imported. I have to just give this particular tool.
Now, what happens? This particular function becomes a custom tool.
That means this tably search result. This is a predefined tool.
This is already developed by some other organization or other company or other developer.
But right now, this gateway.data function we have created, this is our tool or custom tool.
Okay, that's how we can create our custom tool and we can use it inside our agent.
Okay, this is also possible. Now let me execute.
Now, simply what you have to do
uh here itself in the tool itself,
uh, where I have mentioned the tool, huh?
In the tool, you just need to give the tool name, which is get weather data.
Okay, that's it.
Uh get weather data
name.
Yeah, now let's execute. I mean I will execute from the beginning.
Okay,
now initialize the LLM.
Now we are also involving the LLM for some response.
Now facing the prompt.
This is the prompt.
Now initializing our tools. Okay, now see you can pass list of the tools. You can pass hundred of tools, okay? It's up to you.
Now we are creating the agent and we are passing the list of the tools right now. Now my agent is having multiple tools, okay.
One is the search tool, and this is the get away that tool.
Now I'll again execute.
now my executor is ready. Now I can give a prompt.
So now I will give this particular prompt. Let's say
this is the prompt. Find the capital of India and then find the find its current weather. Now, see if I execute, you can real time see.
See, I should first search the capital of India, uses the weather data tool, find the current weather.
See, first of all, it has used the tabily search tool to get the capital of India. So it is referring some website, uh, Indian website, and it is getting uh the capital of India, which is new Delhi.
Okay, so we got the new Delhi.
Now, once it got the new Delhi, now what it is doing, guys, it is utilizing it is utilizing my get data tool, okay. My get data tool, and it is fetching the weather informations, okay.
So that's how things are working, guys.
I think you got it.
Okay, that means now it is having multiple tools. So tably source, it is used utilizing for the search operation.
okay, for uh, finding the capital of India, and my get weather data tool. it is utilizing to get the weather informations, and how it is deciding with the help of this
React agent. okay, because it is internally using LLM and LLM is doing the reasoning, okay.
and it is deciding what tool to call, and this kinds of tool calling and everything is happening with the help of this agent executor because it is running that three step.
that means, uh, uh, I think I showed you.
Uh three step means first of all thought, actions, and observation.
Okay, that's how things are working.
Okay, I hope you get it now. If I want to convert everything in the app.py guys, so this is the final code.
So let me select my environment which is lying agent. So this is the final code. I just copy pasted the same code okay from my notebook as you can see.
The same code, nothing changed.
Okay, now I can run the app.py. Let me show you.
So I will open up my terminal and if I execute my app.py,
so python app.py.
Uh okay, so it is telling tably. Okay.
Uh, because I'm running the app.py and now app.py will refer to this.enb because previously I created inside resource folders.
What I can do, I can copy all of the key and mention inside this particular variable.
Okay, now let's execute the terminal clear. Now again execute app.py
now. See, agent is executing.
Now see, first of all, it is getting the capital of India.
Now, once it's got that, it is utilizing my custom tool get weather data, and it is giving you the temperature.
Okay, now this is the final temperature as you can see. The capital of India is New Delhi, and the current weather is 37.37 degrees Celsius with S.
Okay, perfect. That means we have implemented our first agent, guys. Congratulations with the help of Langchen.
Okay, and don't worry I'm also going to show you how we can create the multi-agent system in the next video.
Now, let's see if you want to convert uh this app to a user interface.
This is also possible.
Maybe we can add streamlit user interface.
So, what I have done, guys, I have just designed a streamlit user interface with the help of chat GPT.
Uh, you can also do that, okay? It's like very easy.
Now you just go to the chat GPT and tell I need a user interface now for this code, so it will generate for you. Okay, so what I have done, guys.
I have already generated a
so what I can do, let's say I'll rename this file. Maybe I can name it as main.py.
Now I'll create another file here.
I'm going to name it as app.py.
Okay, inside that I'm going to paste my updated code.
So this code is having the streamlit user interface.
Okay, guys, so this is the code. So nothing else. I just added the stream bit.
Uh, I think you know streamlit is a Python package with the help of we can create the user interface without writing any kind of service table and CSS code.
So, first of all, we have to install this streamlit.
so I will add this in my requirement streamlit.
So let's install
pinstall hypnot requirement.txt.
Okay, installation is complete. Now if I go to my app.py, now this error will disappear.
Yeah, now see only change uh it has done, it has set a streamlit page configuration. So there you can see
it has done a page configuration.
page title is agentic AI assistant page icon.
this is centered layout.
This is the title,
and we have given a markdown search and weather AI agents using Langchin, and everything is same.
The only thing is that at the last it has added the user query section, so there would be an input box so there I can give the query, and there would be a button if I run this button.
So my agent will be executing.
Okay, so this is a simple user interface code my uh chat GPT added okay inside my this main.py.
Now let's execute and see how this looks like.
I will clear and run streamlit
run
app.py.
I'll give the permission
now.
I'll show you this agent.
Okay, so here I'm getting an error. So let me see the error.
Okay, so this error I'm getting because I told you uh you have to add this line,
otherwise, this error might come because I'm using Windows.
I will add in the app.py
here itself. I will add that.
I have to import certify.
Okay, I'm done.
Now if I re-execute, it should work.
See, it's working now.
Here I can give my query.
So, maybe I can pass:
find the
capital
of,
let's say, French,
and
the current
weather.
Okay.
Now if I run my agent,
you can see agent is thinking.
So every agent actually thinks. Okay, if you use any kinds of agent, guys, you will see that this thinking option is there because internally it is executing
that
tools and everything.
All of these uh I mean three steps are executing, like thought of uh then action and observation.
That's why it's taking some time.
Okay, if you open any kinds of agent, uh let's say if you open VS Code agent, if you open Cloud Desktop, if you open Gemini, you will see that this um process would be there.
Okay, now see uh response generated. The final response is the capital of friends is Paris and the current weather there is 11 degrees Celsius with rain and thunderstorm.
Okay, that means our agent is perfectly working fine, okay.
Amazing.
Now, uh, what we can do if we want, we can also deploy this over the cloud because right now it is running on local host and people can't access my agent.
So I can if I if I want, I can also um I mean host this.
So if you want to host this, so what I can do?
Uh you can use uh different different cloud provider, you can use aws gcp as your but uh let me show you one amazing cloud provider that
you can deploy this agent as free.
So the cloud name is render cloud, okay.
Render.com.
So if I open render.com, so you have to first of all create an account if you don't have an account.
So I already have the account, I'll just try to click on the dashboard.
I will log in with my
Gmail.
Okay, now simply what you have to do here.
First of all, you have to um
I mean
upload this code to the GitHub.
Okay,
so what I will do is I'll simply upload,
but before uploading, I don't need to upload this.enb because if I upload my.enb, my API will be exposed.
So here I will add another file called dot
gitignore.
Okay, inside that I will mention env should be ignored and in research
env should be ignored. Okay.
Now let's
create a GitHub repo.
I'll open my GitHub.
I'll go to the repository.
I'll click on new.
I can give a name. So let's say I'll give
this name.
Search and
whether AI agents using Langchen.
Uh, I'll add a readme file,
then simply
create the repository
and make sure you keep it as public. Okay, you can also make it as private, it's up to you. Now I'll click on code, copy this link address.
I'll open up my local folder and clone this repo here.
So git clone
done.
Now what I will do, I'll just
copy this dot git and paste it here, okay?
And this folder I'm going to remove it because I only need this dot git. Okay, now from my base code itself, I can commit the changes.
issue Now if I show you, see uh this dot env is ignored. Now simply I'll commit the changes.
Now git commit
IPN M.
I'll give update it.
Now git push
origin
main.
Okay, now if I go to my GitHub
refresh,
see all of the coder available.
Okay, now let's try to deploy. So I'll go to my render
and here what I'm going to do, guys. I'm going to just create a new web service.
Okay, now I here I will click on public get repository.
Now I'll copy the link
and paste it here.
Now let's connect.
Done.
Now you can give a other name also if you want.
Uh, it has automatically taken my repository name.
Now everything just keep it as same.
Uh only here you just need to give a command. Okay, see, it will also install the requirement.
This requirement we are having. Okay, now let's give the command of running streamlit app.
So this is the command. So basically, this command will run the streamlit server.
Now, here I will take the free okay, free instance, and here you'll be by default, you'll be getting a 512 mb RAM and 0.1 CPU,
which is a little bit slow, but it is fine for the landing. If you want to let's say professionally deploy it, then you can take their plan, okay?
But I think this is fine now. Here I'll try to add my environment variable.
So here I am having
open API key, let's add it.
I have to give the value.
Copy this,
then I will add the environment variable another one.
I will add it here,
then add another one
which is
is weather stack API key
and add the value.
Done now. Simply.
Um
okay, now simply I'll just do the deployment, deploy web service.
So this is the free instance. Uh, it may take some time, guys. We'll wait once uh this particular option is live. Okay, now it is building the entire instance.
Okay, internally it will set up everything. Once this is live, we'll be able to test that.
Now see it's running.
Now see it is installing the requirements one by one.
let's wait.
So I will pause the video once this installation everything is complete. I'll come back.
So guys, as you can see, our application is live right now.
Uh everything is fine.
There is no adder. Now there is a link you can copy and you can open in your browser.
So there you will be able to see your agent.
So
guys, uh you can see this is our application. This is completely live.
if you're using free instance, it may take some time.
now we can test it.
So here I will just tell find the capital
of Nepal
and
tell me the
weather
of that.
Now I'll run the agent.
Now see, agent is working internally.
So, guys, here is the final response. The capital of Nepal is Kathmandu and current weather 20 degrees Celsius with Drizzle and 94% humidity.
Okay, amazing.
Now you can share this URL with anyone, they will be able to use your agent. So, yes, guys, I hope you understood. I hope you have seen how we can utilize uh this lang chain
to develop these kinds of AI agents, but here we have created the single agents, okay. Single agents pipeline.
Uh, in the next video, I'm going to show you how we can create the multi-agent system, okay?
So everything would be covered.
So, guys, uh, we'll be continuing with our complete agentic AI course, and I think you remember in our previous video, I have already shown you how
we can implement uh a single AI agents with the help of Langchain.
So, this was our first AI agents implementation with Langchain. Then I told you, I'm also going to show you how we can create multi-agent system with the help of Langchain.
So, in this video, I'm going to show you the entire implementation how we can utilize Langchain orchestration framework for implementing these kinds of multi-agent AI system.
Okay, so make sure you watch this video till the end. you don't miss anything.
If you complete this video, you will be able to implement uh multi-agents AI system with a planchain.
And in this video, I'm not only going to implement these AI agents, even after implementation, I'm also going to show you how we can add the user interface and how we can deploy these kinds of
multi-agent system on the cloud platform.
I implemented weather AI agents with the upper planchain.
So there I created a single agent that has some tool connection, like I given tabily search tool and I created one of the custom tools.
Okay, uh that particular tool can access any kinds of real time weather informations given any kinds of city or
location, whatever.
Okay, that means if I show you the architecture diagram, so
yeah, if I show you the architecture diagram, so there let's say I created a single agent.
Let's say this is our agent,
okay. So this agent having some connection with tool,
let's say
it is having connection with tably.
Okay, and it is having connection with
weather
API.
Okay.
so whenever I was giving any kinds of prompt or let's see, input.
so first of all, this will.
and definitely, it was connected with, uh, LLM.
okay.
because LLM was the brain.
and with the LLM, actually, it will perform the reasoning operation.
and
whenever I was giving any kinds of input, then LLM was deciding whether I need to use a tool or not.
with respect to the question, let's say if I'm giving a prompt, just tell me the capital of India and give me the weather information of that,
right?
So, what it will do, it will first of all go to the agents and it will start with the help of tabili, like what is the capital of India, then it will get let's say the capital of India is Delhi.
Now, what it will do again, it will tell okay, now uh you just need to fetch the weather information
of the uh Delhi.
So, with the help of this weather API, it will real-time get this informations and your agent will try to refine the output
and it will show you the final output,
okay. So that's how the things were working, and the whole system actually we have orchestrated with the help of Langgin.
So, there we used actually create uh react agent, right? This functionality we used from the Langgin, and to execute this create uh React agent, we used agent executor, and the full form of
React is reasoning and action or acting, whatever you can say. So, with the help of that, we created the agent.
Okay, so this was the previous architecture.
Now, first of all, let me give you the multi-agent
we'll be implementing for this video.
first of all, I'm going to give you the idea what is the system we are going to develop.
Then I'm also going to show the architecture diagram, okay.
Like what would be the flow and how we can create the AI agents, how we can make the connection with different different tools.
That means the entire overview I'm going to give, then we'll start with the development.
So for this, this is the
this is the actually content I have prepared.
So as you can see, uh multi-agent system with the help of Langchin will be developing in this video.
So a multi-agent research assistant is a fully autonomous AI system that thinks search reads and writes on its own.
Okay, that means here we'll be creating a multi-agent research assistant.
Okay, basically, this will perform the research. So I think you have seen in chat GPT or Gemini there is a research option is available.
Uh, if you open that uh uh let's say application, so if you perform the research, what it will do, it will take some time and it will perform the research operation on the internet
uh uh in a given topic, right?
So that's how we'll be also implementing a research assistant.
So that research assistant will be having some kinds of let's say
tool access, and with the help of tool, it will perform the real-time research operation.
Okay, and here we are not going to create a single agent, instead of that, we'll be creating the multi-agent system here.
So, as you can see, multi-agent research assistant, a fully autonomous AI system that thinks, searches, reads, and writes its own.
Okay, instead of a single AI answering your question from tools, here we'll be developing a team of specialized intelligence agents.
Okay, a team of intelligence agents will be developing here uh that collaborates together to produce a professional research report on a uh topic you give them.
That means if you are giving a topic, okay, so what it will do, it will parf uh it will use all of the like specialized intelligence agents,
okay. It will work together and it will try to give you a professional okay, research report on that particular topic.
So it will not only research, okay, it will also write the report for you, okay.
And you can see the search agent goes so the first agent should be the search agent, So, with the help of search agents, will be uh doing the real-time let's say
research operation over the internet. The search agent goes out on the live internet and finds the most relevant recent sources, okay.
So it will perform the research operation of all of the internet sources it is having.
then the reader agent then dives deep into the those sources and scrap the uh scrap and extracting meaningful content. That means here I'm going to create another agent.
The agent name would be reader agent. So that region agent, what it will do, it will try to scrap and extract okay, all of the content from that sources.
Let's say the first agent will return you the recent.
recent relevant sources that means some URL.
Okay, now what I will do, we will just try to pass this URL to the reader agent.
So reader agent will take those URL and it will open that URL and whatever content it is having, it will extract scrap, then
it will gather those content.
Okay, then here we'll be creating another actually
agent, the writer agent. writer agents uh takes all that generated intelligence and craft a well-structured detailed report. That means right uh there would be another agent called writer.
So this will take all of the content and it will uh prepare a draft, okay?
Prepare a draft report, and after preparing this draft report, we'll be sending this draft report to another agent called critic agent.
You can see, and finally, the critic agent reviews the entire reports, scores it, and gives feedback just like a senior researcher reviewing a junior's work.
Okay, that means at the last, we'll be creating another agent. This agent will try to review, okay.
Whatever let's say your writer agent has written, it will review, it will give you the feedback, okay? It will do some marking.
Okay, just like let's say you are a senior researcher. Whenever your junior is giving any kinds of task, you are reviewing that and you're giving the feedback.
So every single agent is powered, uh powered by a large language model, okay, connected through Langchain's modern LCEL pipeline and orchestrated through a shared memory system that makes them
work uh as one unified brain.
Okay, so here we'll be utilizing the modern language, guys. So previous agent I created with the help of the old Langchain.
Um, but in this development, I'm going to utilize the modern language as well, uh, which is LCEL Langchain uh Langchain Expression Language.
So for this, you definitely you need the understanding about the fundamentals of Langchain.
So that's why I told you Langchain prerequisite I mean definitely should be there if you are working with this kinds of agent.
So for this Langchain on my YouTube channel, I already have one dedicated video, guys, ultimate Langchain Crash Course for Developers.
so it's around seven more than seven hours of course, seven hours of recording. So there I already covered this LCL and everything.
If you go to the timestamp section, you can see here I have already covered this uh LCEL. Okay, LCL.
Okay, the modern langchain which is langchain Expression Language.
Okay, so definitely you should have understanding on this other topic. If you don't know, please try to go ahead with my langchain lecture.
I will add the link in the description from there. You can check it out.
Okay, so the main funder is in this development we'll be using the modern langchain instead of using the old langchain.
I wanted to show you both of the langchain version because still people use old langchain okay.
and people also use like modern language.
Both I'm going to show you.
you can use any of them, okay? It's completely fine, but I will recommend you to use the modern langchain because in modern langchain the updated langchain so many functionality came
and people are moving to that, okay. So instead of relying on old langchain, maybe you can use that one.
Okay, so each and everything I'm going to clarify.
Now, I think, guys, uh, the project introduction part is clear. What to do? Now, let me show you the architecture
how we'll be building this kinds of system. So, guys, uh, this is the architecture I think uh you can see.
Um, let me show you the architecture, yeah. So, this is the architecture. So, in this architecture, guys, as you can see, uh, here we'll be implementing multiple agents.
So, that means let's say this is the first agent uh we'll be developing, and here we'll be passing uh given research topic. Let's say if I want to do a research, I will give the research topic.
So it will go to the first agent, okay?
Uh, so this agent will have some kinds of tool access. So here I'm going to give tabily API. That means tabily search tool access to this agent.
So whatever research you are giving to this agent, so what it will do, it will use this tabily API and it will uh re- uh do the real-time search operation over the internet
and it will get the relevant sources, okay. It will get the relevant website for that particular topic to this agent.
Okay, now what I will do here, this particular response I am going to save in a state memory.
Okay, so here I will try to create a state memory.
So state memory will try to save this particular response so that and your next agent can refer this particular response, okay. Your second agent can refer this kinds of response, okay.
So that's why we are using the shared memory concept. You can also improve this particular memory by utilizing some other techniques. So, this part I'm going to also discuss in my future lecture.
So, I think you saw my entire plan there. I told you will be I mean discussing this particular memory part in detail, but as of now, just try to consider we are using a state memory.
you can also replace the state memory with any other, let's say.
other
like memory database, you can use that. Okay, it's completely up to you. But here uh I'm going to use a state memory um in Python. Okay, I'll show you how we can implement that.
So now we'll be creating a second agent, guys. So the second agent name is reader agent.
So this reader reader agent will also have some kinds of tool access.
So here I'm going to use a beautiful soup uh scrapper tool. So, what this beautiful soup scrapper tool will do basically whatever URL you are getting from the first agent, okay, given topic.
So this will take all of the URL and with the beautiful soup, it will extract the content from the URL. I think you know with the beautiful soup, we can perform the web scrapping.
We can scrap the content from any kinds of given website, right? So that's why the first agent is returning the web URL web sources, and with the help of second agent,
we are extracting the content from the
URL with the upper beautiful soup.
Then what we'll do, guys, we'll try to pass this content to another state uh let's say memory uh uh called let's say scrapped content.
Okay, maybe I can create another uh another actually let's say uh object here called scrap content. Inside that I can save those informations.
Okay, now here we'll be creating um another two actually agent. You can also call it as chain inside modern langchain. instead of creating these kinds of like uh
agent in Langchain. What you can do, you can create a chain because at the end you got your final uh you got your final important content.
Okay, if you got the final important content, now it would be easy for you to generate that particular report and it would be easy for you to
review that particular report, okay. But the main thing is in that section.
So basically, here we are performing the real-time source operation on a given topic. After getting that, we are extracting the content.
Then, if we have the final content, guys, we'll be creating a writer chain, okay. In lang chain, we call it as a chain. Okay, you can also consider it's an agent, okay.
It's an agent, it's a writer agent. So, what this writer chain will do, it will take that particular content, okay. Your beautiful subhack extract it, and it will write a draft.
Okay, it will write a draft report on top of that particular
content, okay.
Because at the end it has also connection with the LLM. Okay, it has also connection with LLM, it is also having connection with LLM.
Okay, so with the help of LLM, with the help of this content you got, it will prepare a draft.
So once it has prepared a draft, what it will do, guys, it will
send this draft to the critic chain.
Now, what this critic chain will do, it will try to review this particular draft whether is there any mistake or not, is there any let's say improvement section or not?
It will try to review that once the review is complete. Okay, once the feedback is complete, then it will show you the final output.
Okay, it will show you the final output, so you will be able to see the final output.
Even you will also see the feedback, the ratings, okay, each and everything you will be able to see from this critic chain.
That means the critic agent, okay, because it is also having a connection with the large language model.
Alright, so yeah, this is the entire actually architecture of this particular multi-agent system.
So this is going to be very interesting project, guys. so make sure you watch till the end. So I think each and everything would be clear in your mind.
Okay, now here is the step, guys, will be following to develop for the entire agent. So, first of all, at the first step, guys, will be setting up the environment.
Then second step will be creating the tools, okay.
All of the tools will be creating one by one, then third step will be creating all of the agents one by one, then fourth step will be creating a pipeline. That means uh uh uh why pipeline is required.
Let's say after creating and tools, you have to
combine them, okay. You have to uh you have to add them together to work, right?
So we we can do it in the pipeline section.
So once our entire agent pipeline is ready, then we can run and test our agent. Okay, so this is the entire step we'll be following for developing this kind of system.
So, guys, now I'm going to give you the idea why we have to create mostly multi-agents AI uh AI
application.
what is the problem with the single agent?
So I think you know that this is like very
I mean easy things you can understand. Let's say
let's say if there is a company, okay. If there is a company,
company uh what they do, let's say they take a project,
okay. They take a project.
Okay, after taking this project, so what they do, they just try to assign this project to a team, right?
Team of employee,
Team of employee.
So in this team, uh what we have, we have multiple employee. Let's say employee one, employee two,
employee three,
and so on.
Okay.
So what they do actually, just try to assign these kinds of project as a task to the team, and definitely in the team itself, they will try to divide the task to different different employees.
Let's say here some of uh let's say employee one is very good at with uh front-end development,
okay. Frontend development, employee two is like really good with let's say AI development, okay, and employee
three
is good at with back-end development.
Okay, backend development.
So what they will do, so the project they are having, uh, so for the for the front-end development for this project, they will assign the task to the employee one
for API development.
Uh uh sorry, AI development for this project, they will assign the task to employ employee two.
Okay, and for backend development for this project, they will assign the tasks to the employee three.
Okay, that means all of the project will have these, are the things are common, right? And it's not like that. There would be a single guy, okay.
Single guy,
he can let's say handle each and everything.
I can't say he cannot handle, he can handle definitely.
Let's say if I am hiring a full stack developer, so definitely he will be able to handle this kinds of scenario, he will be able to, let's say,
implement the entire project.
But what would be the problem?
Okay, because if you see most of the full stack engineer, so they will have actually limited knowledge uh on this, uh, on this actually, let's say
individual topic. So for the end-to-end development, whatever things they need to know, they definitely will do that for you.
But when it comes to the deep research let's say I want to create some AI features for this project, and uh I I need a deep research, okay. I need a very
very good let's say good sources. Then after getting the good sources, I have to refer that sources and I have to build the AI features.
Okay, so if we are only depending on the single let's say employee, so he won't be able to do that because he doesn't have
actually that much of depth knowledge on this AI development.
Okay, he can only let's say uh use some of the framework library and he can implement that project for you.
But when it comes to deep deep, let's say resource, let's say deep experiment, you won't be able to do that.
That means with help of single guy, I can't perform actually multiple tasks.
Task can be performed, but the output, the quality of output will be expecting, this should not be good. Okay, this should not be good. This should be this should be kinds of average output.
But whenever we are having this kinds of project, definitely we'll expect like very good quality output from my team, right?
And if we are if we are let's say assigning this kinds of tasks to the single employee, so definitely single employee won't be able to give the quality output to me.
So that's why every company having a team, and in that particular team, there, they are hiding okay, different individuals, those who are let's say expert
uh expert in different different fields. Let's say someone is expert in front end, someone expert in AI development, someone is expert in uh back end development, okay.
And whatever project they are getting, they're dividing their tasks to them.
So let's say employee one has completed front end, employee two has completed AI development, employee three has completed the back-end development.
Now they will combine, they will combine everything and they will prepare the project for you.
Now, when it comes for research, let's say having a deep research on individual, let's say, topic, so easily these kinds of employee can perform because he is only expert in front
end. he knows about the front end.
and if you give time, okay, if you give time, if you tell this, uh, let's say employee, just try to research and add some more front-end feature with latest,
like framework, he will be able to do that.
okay. Because he don't need to worry about the I development and back-end development, he will only focus on the front-end development.
So that's how for AI developer guy also I can tell just try to explore more and add some other AI features as well.
So definitely we'll be able to do that because he doesn't uh need to worry about the front end and back end, okay. Then employee three, I'll tell just try to research more about the back end.
Let's say I don't want to use flask, you just need to use fast API, just try to explore fast API, you will be able to do that.
Okay, so that's how individual person is working on individual task and the output we are getting from here this is like very good quality
output.
Okay, good quality output we'll be getting.
Okay, that's how whenever we are creating kinds of agent application, instead of creating a single agent, okay,
instead of creating these kinds of single agent, because in single agents, if I want to perform all of this task, okay,
if I want to perform all of this task, so definitely the output should be very poor.
And if I'm using multiple agent, okay, the architecture I showed you, I think.
So this is the architecture.
If I'm using multiple agent, so here I'm assigning a different different task, Let's say first agent I have assigned your task is to only fetch the real-time data from the internet
and give the uh collect the URL.
Okay, then you will try to save the state memory. Then second agent, I have given another task. Your task is to take those URL and extract the content from that.
Okay, so after extracting content, again save to the state memory.
Then third agent I told uh um I mean let's say this agent just try to take this content and write a report on this particular research.
Okay, your task is your only task is to generate the report, so it will try to generate the report.
Then the
fourth agent I told this agent you just need to take this draft and try to
review that whether it is good or bad, or it's really it needs some feedback, just try to read
this, okay? So this particular agent only is responsible for writing this, okay, or creating this particular task.
So once everything is done, then we are getting the final output, and this final output would be very good quality.
But if I am performing the same task with a single agent, so definitely the output would be very bad quality, okay. So that's why this multi-agent things are required.
Okay, that's why you add uh we'll be developing multi-agent system most of the time, and all of the application you can see, okay.
Whatever application like cloud, desktop or you are using VS Code, anti-gravity, any anything you will see that they're using multiple agents in the back end,
they're running multiple agents, okay.
They're adding, let's say, 100 like agents in their backend and they're performing one kinds of task, okay. So, yes, that's how guys uh we will be following this multiple agent development.
And one more thing, whenever you are creating multiple agents, so make sure all of the agents will have kinds of tool access, okay.
If it is required, definitely will give the tool access, and all of the agents will have a large language model for the reasoning operation.
Okay, I think everything is clear now. We'll move on the development part, guys.
So, first of all, I'm going to create a GitHub repo for this multi-agent.
So let's try to create a GitHub repo.
So here I'm going to give a name.
Let's say
I'll give a name here.
Langchen
multi agent
research,
okay, research system.
I will make it as public repo and I will add the readme file.
I'll also add the gitignore.
So here will be coding with Python. So I'll select the Python.
After that, you can select a license. So let's take this uh
maybe Apache license.
Okay, you can take any of the license, it's up to you.
Once it is done, now let's try to create the repo.
Okay, so repo is created.
Now we have to clone this repo inside our local folder.
I'll click on this code, copy this link address. I'll open up my local folder, and here I will just try to open my terminal.
Now let's clone it. So git clone,
paste this link.
Okay, so these directories already exist because previously I already created
uh so what I can do maybe I can rename it.
Okay, I can rename it.
Okay, now just try to open your terminal in this directory and just write git clone
and paste that URL.
Okay, you have copied. Now if I hit enter,
so you will see my repo has been cloned. I will go inside that and I will also redirect my terminal inside this directory. So for this, let's write cd command cd lang chain
multi-agent
okay, research system.
Now I'm inside this particular folder.
Now here I'm going to open up my visual code studio
code studio.
Uh fine.
Okay, now the first thing, guys. Uh I told you, so let me show you the steps we'll be following.
Yeah, so this is my actually um
this is my actually note
So in this particular file, you will be getting all the nodes and architecture steps, everything. So this is the Excalidra, uh, like extension file.
If you want to open it up, so you have to install one extension from extension market called Excalidra.
So if you can source here, Excali
Excalidra.
Okay, so this particular extension you have to install. If you install that, you will be able to open this okay in your VS code itself.
Uh fine. So now if I show you my step,
um, if I show you my step, so the first step, what I have to do, I have to do the environment setup.
Okay, let's try to do the environment setup.
So for environment setup, here I'm going to write all of these tapes.
Here, let's say
the first step you have to create the environment.
So to create the environment, you can
use the same command I think you used for the previous project.
You can give the name, let's say
lang agent,
then you can specify the python.
Python is equal to you can take 3.11
and why okay. You are giving this permission after that. You have to activate that, then you have to install the requirements.
Okay, so just try to create the environment. So for me, I think I already have the environment.
Uh, so I'm going to just activate the copy
and activate the environment.
So, see, this language is already installed for me, okay. But if you don't have, just try to create the environment and try to activate. Then after that, let's install the requirement.
So, here I'm going to add the requirement.txt, and inside that I'm going to mention all of the requirement packages I need.
yeah,
so these are my
requirement guys.
Okay, so these are my requirements uh I need for this particular project. So you can see we are installing Langchen.
Um, so I think you remember in previous project we use we installed actually Langchen old version.
So let me show you, it was 0.1 point something, I think.
So this is the like first agent repository that means our single AI agent repository. So if I go to the requirement.txt, as you can see, we have installed Langshen 0.1 here, okay.
But here we're installing Langchen 0.2, that means this is the modern Langchin, the latest one.
So here actually LCL that means Langchen expression language is supported, but here this is this was not supported, okay.
So both I have showed you, uh, but try to use the latest one if you want, okay.
Uh latest one is always good uh because older one
people are not using anymore, so they are trying to um moving to the new one.
It doesn't mean older one cannot be used, still you can use old one, okay. There are some good functionality you can use, but yeah, uh whenever we have the latest one, so why not?
We can you utilize this this one, okay.
Then we are installing this Langsend code community open AI, Langsin OpenAI. So you can use any other LLM provider as well, it's completely fine.
Simply you just need to go to the chat GPT and tell that you want to use open router or Gemini.
you will be able to see that they will suggest you the code. Okay, you can replace that code here, okay.
Then Streamlit I need for creating the user interface, then tabily for the search tool, and I told you we'll be creating another
tool which is a beautiful soup extracting.
So here we'll install this beautiful to soup, and for beautiful soup, we need these are the dependency packets as well, okay. Then python.env for the environment management.
So these are the packets we have to install. So, how to install? Let's copy the command.
So, here's the command I will copy this and run in my terminal.
So for me it is already satisfied, but for you it may take some time.
Okay, once it is done, now we can create the folder structure right now.
So here what I'm going to do, I'm going to first of all create a
folder here. I'm going to name it as src.
Inside that I'm going to create a constructor file
underscore underscore init
underscore underscore dot five
and inside that I'm going to create another folder.
I'm going to name it as
tools.
I'm going to create another folder called agents.
Okay.
Then
I need
another folder
called pipeline.
Okay.
Yeah. So once it is done, then here I'm going to create an endpoint, which should be my Ambler Pi.
And I need a.env file
for environment management.
So yeah, so this is my folder structure. Uh
but uh right now I'm going to create some of the file inside these are the folder.
Like first of all, I have to create a constructor file.
So this is called modular coding. We're uh creating as a module each and every separate module.
Inside that we'll be creating a file called agent..py
Then pipeline also I'm going to create a constructor
underscore underscore init underscore underscore dot pie
and we'll be creating a file called pipeline dot pie.
So for tools also we'll be doing the same thing.
Okay everything is done.
Now let me check Let me verify everything is fine or not.
Uh yeah, I think everything is fine. So now if I show you my step again,
uh we have prepared all of the folders.
Okay, like for tools, we have created a separate tools folder inside SRC.
So inside that we'll be writing all of the tools in the tools.py for agent also we have done the same thing.
Agent and inside agents will be writing all of the agents for pipeline. We have done the same thing for pipelines, we'll be writing the pipelines, okay.
And run and test we'll be using this endpoint, which is app.py okay, so everything is fine.
Um okay, one more thing I can do for running and testing the agent.
First of all, let's say we'll try to test in the main.py then once everything is working fine, we can convert, we can add the user interface to the app.py okay,
yeah.
So now it's ready. Now let me commit the changes to my GitHub.
So simply what I will do,
I'll try to
uh commit the changes.
So, git add space, dot
git, commit
type nm,
um
"agent, setup
and
folder structure
created"
and git push
origin. main.
Done now. If I go to my GitHub
refresh,
see my folder structure is ready.
Okay.
Now, first thing let's try to work on this.
Um
I'll open up my state. Yeah, so in government setup and folder creation is done. Now here what I can do, maybe I can
write another things
folder structure structure.
Yeah
now first of all we'll be uh creating the tools, okay.
Let's try to create the tools.
So here, I will
close all of this
file,
but before creating the tools, uh, first of all, I have to collect this. uh,
uh, secret credential.
I need my open eye API key and I need tabily API key.
Okay, I already showed you in my previous implementation how to collect them.
So I already collected. Let me show you.
So this is my open eAPI key and this is my tablet API key.
So for open eye, what you have to do? You have to visit OpenEI API platform.
So there simply just try to log in with the API platform.
Once you have logged in, just try to see the API keys option
and create the new access uh secret key. Okay, so for me, I have already created now for tabily.
You can visit tabily API key, tabily.com, and see here if you don't want to use open AI, you can use Google Gemini API or OpenRoucher
or Grok API key, anything you can use.
Okay, only you just need to change that model initialization.
Simply you can go to the chat GPT and you can replace that, okay. Very easy.
But I have my open AI uh account with me, that's why I'm going to use OpenAI because I am expecting good output from my agent. Okay, that's why. Uh because in free API there is some limitation.
Um, so after certain time, actually, uh, this limit would be over.
So that's why we are using OpenAI here.
Now tably also, you have to do the same thing. Uh, here is a API creation option. You can click here, you can create a new key.
Okay, for me, I already created the key, so this is available.
Okay, now environment is ready. Now, simply let's try to create the agent.
Uh, what I'm going to do, I'm going to open this. Sorry, not agent.
I'm going to create a tool.
So I'm going to open this tools, okay? Tool folder,
tools.py.
Okay, I'm going to open it.
So the very fast tools, guys. I have to create, I think you remember, which is uh this web search tool,
which is this web search tool. If I show you my diagram, web search tool, which is tably API, okay, and we'll try to connect with our fast agent.
So let's try to create this tably search uh tabily search tool.
So for this, let's import some library first of all.
I'm going to select my environment.
So I'm going to import let's say
langgin.tools
import
tool.
Okay,
then I'm going to import
request.
I'm going to import
um
I'm going to import this uh dot env.
So from dot env
import load env.
Then
I need the operating system.
Okay, it should be import.
And
one more thing, I need to import the tably. So from
tably
import
tably client.
Yeah, you can also import tabily from LangChin.
Uh because Langchain inside tools, it is tably tools is available. You can import either you can import from tabily framework itself and you can create it as your custom tool.
So in my previous example, a tabily I initialized from Langchin.
Um I didn't create it as a custom tool, but in this implementation, I'm going to show you how we can create tabily as your custom tool. Okay, this is also possible.
both you see and whatever you like, you can prefer that because in my requirement I already installed this tabily Python. Okay, that's why we will be able to do that.
So simply first of all, load your environment variable, and after that, let's create a tably object. So tably
musical to tabily client.
Here you have to pass the API key of the tably.
So I'm going to get from my environment variable, so is.get enb tably API key, and inside this dot enb I've already mentioned my tablet api key. Okay, it will try to load from here.
So once I got it, now I'll create a function here.
So this function will try to perform the web search operation with the help of tably.
So maybe I can name this function as web search.
Okay, web search
web search. So this will take a query,
or I have already created. Let me show you.
Yeah, so this is the function, guys, as you can see.
So web search, this is the function. This takes the query, and what it does, it uh use tabily and it searches that particular query over the internet, and max result is equal to five.
That means it will give you five sources, okay? Five relevant uh sources URL from the internet, and what we are doing,
let me show you what we are doing here.
Let's say once we are getting all of the five
uh five responses. So let me just print them one by one.
Print result, all of the results
now. Let's call this function,
or we can also test inside our endpoint which is main.py.
Let's import from src
dot
tools
dot tool import search then
web search
let's say what is the capital of French. Okay, I have given this one or let's say
latest
news on AIDS
now. If I execute
python
main.py,
now, see it is giving you five response
okay, five response. But this print statement is not clear enough.
So if you want to make it clear enough, so what you can do, guys, you can install one tool which is
rich.
Let me add inside my environment
rich. Okay, so rich helps us to
uh actually um see the good print statement, and you can also use it for the logging debugging.
So let me install the rich as well.
Clear
I'll install my
requirements
once it is done. Now let's try to import the rich
in the tools. I'm going to import
from rich
Import print.
Now instead of this print, I'm going to use my rich print.
Okay.
Now if I execute, this will give you beautiful output.
Now see this is uh clean, right?
This is understandable.
Yeah, so you can see we are getting this response from tably API. So tably API, what is this doing? It is going to internet and it is searching,
it is searching over uh different different website. Okay, so this is the first website, reddit.com. So if I open it up, so here it has already discussed about this uh
uh latest AI research news.
Then again, you can see there is another website called artificialintelligence news.com.
Okay, so this is another news.
So that's how you have see uh that's how you can see one, two,
three, four, five.
Okay, total fibes uh response we are getting here, okay. Five URL we are getting here
from different different website.
Okay, now what I can do, see I don't need all of the information because here I only need this result.
Okay, in the result, I have the URL, I have the title of that particular let's say information, and I have a content. So in that content, actually, some
like one to two lines headlines are there about the content.
Okay, so if I'm able to get these, are the three things.
I think this is more than enough for my agents, because if I show you my agent,
if I show you my agent, here, so let's say first agent, what it will do: it will uh, use tably, API.
uh, for real-time data data fetching operation from different different websites, and we have to take there.
these are the information: URL, title, and content.
So this URL title and content will try to save in the state result, and my second agent will try to take that and from the URL itself, okay.
From this URL itself, it will try to extract, it will try to extract the content because this is a web, okay. This is HTML web.
So now what it can do, it can actually extract the content, and how it extract, I think you know if I perform the inspect operation.
So there is an option.
Let's say if I want to
extract any text,
easily I can do that. Let's say I can show you. Let's say I want to extract this this particular part. If I click here, so this is the content of that.
Okay, I can easily extract the content, and this operation we perform with the Alpha Beautiful soup.
Okay, so I'll try to do that as well.
So here let me show you.
I'll open it up
now. Instead of taking all of the content,
so what I will do,
I'll just try to take
these are the information.
Okay, these are the information, like I need title, I need URL, and I need content.
Okay, content I need, and content I'm only taking 300 word just to make my more uh let's say agent understand. Okay, so this is the content related that and it is available inside this URL.
You have to extract that.
Okay, now if I see after doing it, I'm just running a fold loop because this result will have a result keyword.
Okay, we are going inside that because this is a JSON response. We are taking this key inside that we have title
URL title and content.
So inside that we are extracting title, URL, and content, and we are appending to this particular empty list one by one.
That means the five uh five output should be there, five uh five links response should be there inside that. Okay, because I'm getting five response.
Now let me show you. So if I print this,
uh if I first of all I'll return it,
I'll return it.
So basically, I'm performing the joining operation.
Uh so what the join will do, it will try to join as a string, okay? So every time it will give a new line and will join all of the content.
Now let me show you how this thing will look like. So maybe now I'll try to receive it here.
Let's say
output and
print output
now. If I execute my
file.
See, I'm getting five output.
The title, and this is the URL of that content, and this is a like uh
short paragraph of that particular news.
So if I go to the reddit.com, you'll see that NAWS user started.
Okay, so this thing is available.
Yeah, sorry, from here.
Anthropic drops and uh drops a new uh new research paper today. Okay, so entropy uh drops a new research paper today, so that's how it is taking 300 word from the entire content.
Okay, entire content.
Now, this is the second one, this is the third one, this is the fourth one, this is the fifth one. That means we are getting fifth uh response from our tabily tool, okay.
Which is amazing.
Now, what I will do, guys.
Um,
my first tool is ready.
My first tool is ready, that means this particular tool is ready.
Okay, now I have to work on this tool, which is beautiful soup scrapper tool.
Now let's try to also work on that.
So for this, I again need to import some other library, like I need to import
um
beautiful soup.
So from
bs4,
I import beautiful soup;
then I have to import from
readability import documents, then I have to import
fila chart.
Okay, uh fila uh Tora. Okay, this is uh this thing I need with beautiful soup.
that's why this is a dependency package, and I also need regular expression
import RE.
So if you have ever performed web scrapping, I think you know these are the libraries useful.
So, what I've done, guys, I have already generated a function with chat GPT.
Let me show you the function.
Yeah, so this is the function I have generated from chat GPT.
Uh so basically it takes a URL, okay. It takes a URL, and what it does, uh it ex uh x scrap actually all of the content from the URL.
Okay, it performs the scrapping.
So here you can see uh we are using request package, we are hitting the URL after that. We are getting the JSON HTML response and we are extracting the content, okay.
So everything is performing with help of beautiful soup.
And once we got the content, we are returning the cleanup. And if exception is occurring, we're using the exception, okay. That's the exception handle is also important.
If you're using any third-party services, definitely you can use try except block. Okay, this is required.
So, yes, guys, uh, this is the scrapper uh function we have created. You can also test it whether it's working or not.
So, maybe let's say here what I will do, I'll try to import it as well.
Come to scrap URL.
Uh so this returns, right?
This is returns.
This returns, okay.
So, what I can do, I can
I can show you let's say
reserve
web search. So, this takes a URL.
Okay, so maybe I can provide a URL.
Let's say
I'll copy this URL.
Copy this URL and
I'll give inside there.
Okay, then I will print the result.
Now see what happens.
here
Python men.py is
still we are getting this title URL why.
Oh, okay. we're using web search. I have to use scrap or URL. Okay.
Scrap URL. This function. Sorry.
My mistake.
Now let's again execute.
Okay, now see from that HTML.
I'm getting the content.
Okay.
I'm getting the important content.
So this function is doing that.
So this function is going to that particular URL.
Okay. This function is going to that particular URL and extracting all of the content.
Okay, you can see extracting all of the content, relevant content.
Okay.
And it is giving me here.
Now this content I'll try to pass to my
next agent.
here.
Next agent. So let's say my second agent uh second agent will try to extract uh these information and it will save in the state memory.
Now I can use my writer agents to use this particular content and prepare a draft for me.
Okay, and my critic agent will try to review that.
This is the work I think you are getting. So this is called actually uh team. Okay, this is called actually team, and uh we are using
uh we are using list of agents to perform for performing actually my uh task okay, multiple tasks we are performing with the multiple agents one by one,
okay. So this is the beauty of multi-agents instead of using the single agent.
Now, one more thing I want to show you. See, as of now, I have created these are the tool as a function, okay.
And now if I want to use it as a tool, so what I have to do, I think you remember we have to give a decorator.
Yesterday also we did the same thing, so we have already imported this tool from Langchin.
So now I can give a decorator.
So here just simply give the tool decorator.
Whenever you are giving the tool decorator, now you can invoke. Okay, you can invoke this tool.
Let me show you
tool decorator.
Now let's say right now what I am doing
uh here right now. I just need to
call this function and give the input like that. But now we have converted as a tool. Now I can perform the invok operation. So, how to perform the invok operation? Let me show you.
So, let's say this is my tool web search tool.
Simply I'll do the invok operation.
Okay, invok operation.
Now, here is the question. Let's say I'll give what is the latest research on using AI for climate change migration. Now, whatever response I will get, I'll try to save inside a variable.
Let's say result,
and I'm going to print it.
Now let me show you
this will work as a tool.
See now this is working as a tool.
Okay, you can perform the inbox operation.
Alright, so similar wise, you can also perform the inbox on the scrap URL.
Okay, both it will work with the help of inbox.
So now you guys, our tool is ready.
we have created
all the tool like tabily tool as well as the beautiful Soup Scrapper tool, and it is already working.
Now the next part we can work on the
agents implementation.
Okay, now I'm going to show you how we can implement the agents, but before that, let me commit the changes. so I can also commit from my base code.
So here I can tell uh tools
uh
created for
agent.
Oh, that's a tools created.
Okay, I'll commit
and see the changes
done. If I go back,
I'll close this other tab.
So
guys, uh to implement the agent, I'm going to open this agent folder inside that I have agent.py. Let me open it up.
I can close these are the file as of now.
So first of all, here what I have to do, guys. I have to create my first agent, which is uh search agent. Okay, search agent.
So basically, this will have the connection with tablet API.
so let's try to create that.
I'm going to import some necessary library.
Um, so these are the library I need.
These are the library I need.
So one more thing I think you can observe.
Um, right now I'm importing Langchin.agent import create agent.
Okay, but previously I imported create react agent.
Okay, there are some difference between them.
see, because previously I showed you I installed actually old version of the Langchin.
So in old version Langchin, they implemented create react agent that means reasoning and action agent.
Okay, but in the latest version, in the updated version modern Langchin, they have replaced with create agent, okay.
This particular function.
So for this, I did a Google search. Let me show you the result.
See, I told is create agent and create react agent same in Langchin.
It's telling no, they are not same,
though they both serve similar purpose in recent Langchen updates.
CreateAgent has become the standard streamlined function while create react agent is older implementation.
Okay, so what they have done, they have updated their Langchen package, and what they did, they actually also worked on this
create react agent they had and they updated with this React Agent.
Sorry, create agent right now because create agent is nothing but it's the updated version of create react agents, and this is more stable, more standard.
Okay, that's why they're recommending don't use create react agent instead of use create agent only because this is more standard and streamlight function.
It is not
it's not like that you can't use create react agent, you can use
create react agent, but um, I think it's good to go with the updated one alloys.
Okay, now here are some um like difference between them. So you can see create react agent. This is the modern recommended method in core-langchain package;
it creates an agent that executes a built-in loops of tools calling using highly flexible modern middleware system, and apart from that, this create
react agent is a older implementation based on strictly on foundation react reasoning acting, okay.
A prompting
paper, it was previously able available one older version of langchain
but has been deprecated in
create agent, okay. That means the latest one, okay.
So basically, I think you remember whenever we use this create react agent function, we have to use another additional function which is agent executor, and that has to perform
three things one is the thoughts, then action, then observation. I think I showed you the detailed discussion in my previous agent implementation. If you have missed out, just try to check it out.
So there we used to run three things thought, action, and observation.
And for running this three step we used to use agent executor with this create react agent.
But right now, in create agent, you don't need to use that separately.
So they have integrated everything that means that thought, action, and observation, all of the execution process in the loop they have inbuilt with this create react agent.
So they will take care each and everything. You don't need to do these are the parts, okay? So that's why this is like more standard and optimized version of create react agent.
Okay, so that's why we'll be using this create agent right now.
Okay, I hope it's clear, guys. So that's why in my code you can see instead of importing this create react agent.
Where's the code? Yeah. Create react agent. I'm importing create agent only.
Okay. And all the code are same, like open AI, chat open AI.
Then we are also importing the prompt template. If I want to give my custom prompt, I can set my prompt with the chat prompt template.
Then output parser I need because I'm going to use the LCL language Langs and Expression language, the modern Langshen uh let's say syntax. So that's why output parser is required.
And to understand this one, definitely you have to go through my language and lecture, guys. There I have discussed each and everything. What is LCL?
Why output parser is required, each and everything I have already explained.
Then from tools, we are importing.
Uh this is not tools anymore, so this thing I can import like that. So
in my main.py I have already imported. I will copy
and I'll replace it here.
Okay, so from SRC, uh from SRC tools,
uh, we have created web search tool and scrapper tool.
Okay, both we have created and we're importing dot enb and we're initializing the dot enb.
Now the first thing we have to set up the model
so LLM is equal to
chat openai.
So I'm going to use this model
this model,
So here I can comment model
Okay, model initialization. So we are using this GPT 4.0 mini model. You can use any model GPT 5, whatever you can use, and this is the creativity parameter I have given zero.
So this will give you the llm object.
So right now I'm going to create my first agent, which is this agent called search agent.
Let's try to create it
now.
See if you're using modern line chain that means create agent function. It's like super easy, only you just need to create a function.
I'm going to name it as let's say build
search
agent,
and simply you just need to return that.
Okay, return what return your create agent.
Okay, create agent, and this will take actually
some parameter. The first parameter takes the model,
so model is equal to I'll pass my LLM.
Second parameter, it takes the tools, okay.
The tools you want to connect with this agent. So I want to connect this tool actually, web search tool, because my first agent will try to connect with my web search tool, which is tably API.
Okay, so what I'm going to do, I'm going to call this web search and pass it here.
Okay. And there is another thing you can perform, I think, which is system prompt.
Okay, system prompt you can pass, you can tell your agent what to do. But system prompt, I think it is already given in default. Uh, the same system prompt I think I showed you right uh yesterday.
Uh, I um downloaded from Langchain Hub.
So basically, it explains about the agent behavior, okay. How to work.
So I don't need to give it here because this is my um search agent.
So basically, it will take take a prompt, uh, sorry, take a topic and it will perform the live search operation over the internet, and this will return you the URL content, okay.
With respect to that, so for this, uh the manual prompting is not required. I think the default prompt is fine completely, but if you want, you can also change the system prompt, okay?
It's completely up to you.
So you can generate a system prompt uh from chat GPT and you can pass it here.
So this is my first agent.
So this is my
first
agent,
okay. Which is search agent.
Now I'm going to work on my second agent,
which is scrapping agent.
Okay, that means this one
reader agent, okay.
We can name it as reader agent.
Reader agent.
So let's create it. So, similar wise, I will create this agent as well. I'll copy this code
and here this is my reader reader agent.
Okay, and this will take the scrap URL tool because this will connect it with my beautiful soup.
That's why we're passing this
scrap URL tool in this particular agent. And if you want, you can also change the system prompt here. But I think default for prompt is fine with me.
I'm not going to change the prompt.
Okay.
So my first agent and second agent is done.
Now I'll be working with my
uh I'll be working with my
um third agent and fourth agent.
And see this third agent and fourth agent, I'm not going to create in that way. Instead of that, I can utilize the modern Langchain chain functionality. Okay, this is called LCL chain.
So I think this is enough because in Langchain we can use this LCL chain
for for these kinds of operation. Okay, this is also possible. Now let me show you how it can be initialized.
See if you haven't watched that my LCL in my Langchain, so try to watch that, otherwise, it would be little bit confusion for you.
But if you watch that session, I think it would be clear.
So I have already created. Let me show you.
This is my
writer chain.
That means my writer agent.
See,
so first of all, here you have to prepare a prompt, okay? Custom prompt. So I'm using the chat prompt template, and what I'm doing, I'm giving a system prompt.
You are expert research writer, write a clean structure and set for reports.
A human write a detailed uh research on report on the topic below.
Okay, so first of all, I will give the topic, and this topic will come from the human human input, and this will take the research.
Okay, and where it will get the research, it will get the research from this reader agent, okay, because reader agent will try to
first of all, uh first agent. What it will do, it will give the URL, okay.
URL of the relevant, uh relevant actually sources, and the second agent will try to extract the content and it will save in the state memory.
And writer agent will try to take this content and write this uh draft for you. So that's why this research we are taking it from my reader agent.
Okay, so this will automatically go to the go to the writer agent.
Okay, now here you can see structure report as I need these. Are the informations in that report introduction, key findings, minimum three word explain points, conclusion, okay, and sources.
That means whatever URL you refer, just try to also refer the URL in the research topic. You can change these kinds of prompt with respect to your requirement.
You can generate a detail report, you can generate a short report, you can generate more subpoint here, you can customize it.
Okay, now be detailed and uh factual and professional.
Okay, this is the entire prompt.
Now we are creating the chain. So writer chain is equal to writer prompt. First of all, you have to give the prompt, then you have to give the llm, then you have to give the steer output.
So, what will happen?
This prompt will go to this LLM.
LLM will try to work on that because LLM is expecting the topic and research we are already getting from the topic from the user and research from my second agent, which is uh reader agent.
Reader agents will return the content, research content, and with the help of this research content, it will refer and write that particular report.
Okay, just try to think about if I give you the recent, let's say, recent, let's say I'm searching for tell me the
latest AI tools.
So if I give you the
if I give you the let's say source content, source content means let's say in from the internet I have collected some URL and from URL I've extracted some
uh let's say
uh I've extracted the content of that particular latest information and I have given to you. So this is the content, and now just try to prepare a report on that.
So what you will do, you will just try to refer that and prepare the report for me.
Okay, the same thing we are doing here. So that's why we don't need to create an individual uh agent like that.
Okay, it can be done with the help of this LCL chain.
okay?
Very easy. Now, same we'll try to do it for my critic chain as well.
That means this one.
So this one is done. Now we'll perform for this one.
Let's do it.
So this is my critic chain.
So here also we are doing the same thing. We are creating the prompt template. First of all, so you are a sharp and constructive
research critic.
Be honest and specific, human. Review the research on below and evaluate it strictly. So we are giving the report. Report means this writer agent, whatever it will return you, will try to pass here.
Now it will respond like that. First of all, it will give you this four strength areas to improve one line uh verdict.
Okay, then uh we are preparing the chain. So critic chain is equal to critic prompt.
That means my critic prompt LM and str output. So this will become your critic chain. That means this part is also ready.
Okay, now we have to combine them all together to make all of the agent uh work together.
Okay, so these kinds of things will be performing in the pipeline. Now we'll try to create the pipeline, we'll try to combine this agents all together.
That means first of all, first agent will come.
Whatever output will be getting, we'll try to save in the state memory, then second agent will try to receive that, then we'll try to connect this tablet tool with first agent, then
this tool with the second agent. Already this is done. Okay, I have already connected this tool.
As you can see, this tool is already connected.
Then once it is done, we'll try to connect the writer agent as well as the critic chain.
Okay, critic agent or chain, whatever you can say.
Now let's try to see how we can create this pipeline.
So my agent is ready,
and my tools is ready.
Now I'll be working on the pipeline.
So, guys, our agent and tools, everything are ready. Now we can work on the pipeline.
So, in the pipeline, I told you, we'll try to connect all of the agents together and we'll also try to connect the state memory there.
So, for this, let's open up this pipeline.py file.
it's available inside pipelines.
I'll open it up.
now let me show you how it can be done.
Okay, so for this, first of all, we have to import
we have to import this agent, okay. The agent we have created that means my search agent, then reader agent, then my writer chain as well as the critic chain.
Okay, so all these things we have to import one by one.
this is the prediction.
So let's import in the pipeline. So I'm going to write from
from src
dot agents dot agent.
So I'm going to import, first of all,
build reader,
build a search agent,
then
build reader agent,
then writer chain.
then my
Okay, critic chain.
Now, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to write a function.
Um, already I prepared this function. Let me show you
what it will do.
So,
first of all, I'll try to
add this.
So,
this is the function, guys. Let me explain.
Yeah, so you can see the function name I have kept run research pipeline. So this will take the topic, whatever topic user will pass.
So first of all, what I'm doing, guys, I'm uh taking a state dictionary here.
Okay, so why I'm taking a dictionary because I told you we'll be creating a state memory.
Okay, state memory, this is a temporary memory.
once agent has executed successfully, then this particular memory would be cleared.
So that's why I told you later on if you want, you can also add the permanent memory by adding some memory database.
That thing I'm going to definitely discuss in future, but as of now, just try to consider this is our
this is our state memory we are taking as a dictionary. So every state it will try to save some data inside that particular dictionary.
So first of all, I'm just doing a print statement just to see a beautiful logs in my terminal.
Okay, so we are first of all telling sourcing agent is working, then we're giving like 50 uh this uh equal sign.
Okay, now what we're calling guys, we're calling now build source agent.
so we are getting an object of that particular agent, then we are invoking it. Okay, what we are invoking, we are invoking without prompt.
So user is giving a prompt. Find the recent, reliable and detailed information about this topic, and from where we are getting the topic, topic it will be given by the user.
Okay, from the user interface, we'll try to pass the topic.
So this topic will come here.
So this uh search agent, what it will do, it will use stability search API, it will search over the internet of that particular topic, and this will return you the result.
Okay, this will return the search result. What would be the search result? I think you remember this will return you, these are the search result.
That means the title, URL, and snippet. That means the content.
Okay, so this is the work of the first agent.
You can see, and this particular state, the first agent, whatever it is returning, I'm going to save inside state memory. So this is what we are doing.
You can see we are calling this state and I'm adding a new key which is search result, and we're storing this particular result in that particular memory.
Okay, you can see search result.
we are getting the message and we are getting the content of that, okay. Content of that, and we're string uh storing in the state memory.
And once it is done, we are also printing that particular memory. What is we have inside that particular state, okay? So this is for my fast agent. So we have completed till here.
Now we will be creating this particular option, my second agent.
So this will connect it with my previous state, it will take the data and it will run my second state, and whatever output we'll be getting, we'll try to save in the state memory again.
So let's try to work on that.
So my second step, my reader agent.
So this is my reader agent.
Yeah, reader agent.
Again, I'm doing some print statement. Now you can see I'm initializing my reader agent again.
We are doing the invoking operation of the reader agent, then we are giving the prompt user based on the following search topic. Uh so topic we are getting from here.
Okay.
Uh, pick the most relevant URL and scrap it for deeper content.
That means it will scrap that particular URL, and whatever let's say
URL we are having, we are also passing from my state. You can see we're calling the state, and I think you remember we created a key called search result.
search result, we are giving that particular um I mean content. That means
whatever URL my first agent has extracted, uh my first agent got from my tabily.
We have stored here, and my second agent is reading from that particular state.
You can see it is reading from that particular state. That means all of the URL title it will get, then it will perform the scrapping operation, and whatever scrap result will be getting again.
We are saving in the state memory.
Again, I'm creating another key called scrap content inside the state, and we are saving the content inside that.
Very simple, okay. Then we are printing that particular content.
So this part is also done.
Second agent and second agent response we are saving in the state memory. Now we have to work on the writer and critic chain.
Now let's do it.
So, first of all, I'm going to write my
So this is the writer.
You can see again I'm doing the print statement for beautiful logs.
Now
we can see
we created a variable here.
So this variable having two information was the source result.
Okay.
Source result and one is the detail scrap content.
Okay. The search result we are getting from where we are getting from this uh search result.
Okay, then what we are doing, we are also getting the scrap content.
Scrap content means nothing but my previous okay, previous agent, whatever scrap content we got, we have in the state memory, we are also getting that okay. We are getting the scrap content.
Now we are writing our chain.
You can see uh chain.invok, we are giving the topic as well as the resource combined. This means both of the example we are giving. Why we are giving the SARS result?
Because I told you, I think you remember here.
if I show you my writer agent,
writer agent. Okay, so here I uh told
uh you have to also mention the sources, okay. Sources uh list of the URL found in the resource, okay. And if I want to list down all the URL, so definitely I have to pass the URL as a reference.
So this is what we are passing here, all the URL we are passing, and whatever content we got from the URL, we are also passing that.
So it will prepare a draft for me, and this particular draft report we are again saving in the state memory, okay? We are saving in the state memory so that my critic chain can refer
and it can review that you can give the feedback, then we can get the final output.
Okay, so you can see we are storing in the state memory and we are printing that now. The last things we have to write the critic report.
so this is the critic report again. We're doing the print statement after that. Uh we are calling the critics and invoke and we are giving this report.
The last uh state was the report, we are passing the report, okay?
So this will basically take the feedback, and again, I'm storing in the state memory as a feedback, and we are printing it here, okay.
And we are returning the state.
So, yeah, this is the pipeline, guys. That means this connection we have done perfectly now. Let's test it whether it's working or not. So, what I will do? So, in the main dot, I'm going to test it.
So, simply here, let's try to import first of all this uh this function.
This is the main function run resource pipeline.
So, here I'm going to import it.
So, from src
dot pipelines
dot pipeline
import
run resource pipeline.
Okay, now simply here I'm going to take a topic is equal to
let's say the impact of AI job
market in 2026.
Let's say this is my topic.
Now I'll go pass inside my
run resource pipeline.
Okay,
So basically, what it will do, it will
give you the final
Okay, final result.
And although we are printing, so that's why we don't need to store it here, so it will print in the terminal.
Now let me show you
I'll clear
run my main..py.
Now see, first of all, the research uh search agent is working.
Now we got the uh search result okay with URL.
Now my second reader agent is working, it is scrapping all of the information from the URL
on that topic.
Now see we got the
content.
Now my writer agent is drafting the report.
Now it will prepare the report by utilizing this content as well as the URL.
Now see my
final report is ready and it has also given you the sources, whatever sources it has referred. Now critic agent is also working and it has given you the report.
It told okay, you got six out of ten, and there is some strain point. Here is the idea of improvement, and here is the one line verdict.
Okay, amazing. That means all of my agents are working perfectly, guys.
Okay, all of my agents are working perfectly. There is no error, and it is working together.
Okay, it is working together, and we are getting a very detailed report on my given topic.
Okay, but this thing I have to execute from my terminal and it's not like readable properly.
And if I give it to like non-coder guy, so definitely he won't be able to execute that agent. So, what I can do, maybe I can add a user interface here.
Uh, to add the user interface, so you can use uh any kinds of framework if you know front-end development, you can use react, next.js, okay. You can do it for you.
But if you don't know about HTML, CSS, React uh React Next.js, okay, completely fine.
There is a library inside Python called Streamlit.
With the help of Streamlit, you can create a user interface, and again, you don't need to write the code from scratch, you can use chat GPT, just simply give this pipeline code to the chat GPT until
just try to add a streamlit UI interface with that. So I have done the same thing.
So, what I did, guys, with my chat GPT,
I have generated a user interface with the help of my streamlit.
Okay, so chat GPT has given me a code. Let me show you how this code looks like.
So this is the code,
this is the code, okay. So you can see this is a streamlit development.
Okay, I have to import this one only.
instead of importing like that in the app dot I have to import like that.
Yeah, SRC agent, build agent, reader agent, writer agent, and prediction.
Fine.
So, first of all, you can see it is utilizing streamlit, and we have already installed streamlit inside our requirement as you can see.
Then we it is setting the page configuration, it is adding some custom CSS for the designing of my um UI.
Okay, some color background and images it has added, some other like markdown it has added, okay. Some HTML content has added.
See in Streamlit also you can add HTML and CSS, but again, I told you if you don't, it's completely fine.
Just open up your any kinds of assistant, Gemini or Chat GPT or Cloud A and try to give this pipeline.py and tell, like,
okay, I just need to add
streamlit UI.
It will add you whatever user interface you are getting, just try to run.
Okay, nobody's actually remember HTML, CSS nowadays, okay, because we have this kinds of flexibility.
Now, this is a simple actually
interface we have created with the help of streamlit.
Again, you don't need to understand this code. this is like
AI generated user interface, it's completely fine, but there would be definitely other guy in the company they will be working on the front-end development as per the company requirement.
Okay, but as a agentic AI engineer, we don't need to worry about the user interface.
But to run our agent, I need a user interface so that I can show to my manager, I can show to my let's say customer so that they can test my agent okay
in a user interface background, okay, instead of giving the terminal access. So now if I want to execute my app.py, what I have to do, guys, I have to run this app.py.
So simply I'm going to write streamlit
run.
App.py.
Now, if I execute, this will run my
app here.
And all of the code I'm going to share, guys, in my description. From there, you can execute. See, guys, this is the user interface. I think this is amazing, right?
My chat GPT has created this user interface for me and it has named it as research agent because in the prompt I told this should be the research research agent.
So that's why it has named like researcher agent. Okay.
Multi-agent AI system.
Uh, four specialized AI agents collaborate, searching, scrapping, writing, and creating to deliver a polished research report on a given topic.
Amazing, right?
Now, here you can see here I have the input option that means I can pass any kinds of research topic, even it has also given some suggestion like you can try with these are the example.
Okay, this is amazing. Now there is a button.
If I click on the button, my agent will be executing, and these are the pipeline I'm having inside my agent.
That means the first pipeline the search agent, second pipeline research agent, third is the writer chain, fourth is the critic chain.
And right now the starter is waiting. Okay, now let me try whether it's working or not. So maybe what I can do, maybe I can copy the same example, or you can also write some other thing if you want.
Now simply run the research pipeline.
Now, see, first of all, my first agent is working, search agent is working, it is searching with the help of tably API.
Let's see.
Done now. My research agent is scrapping, sorry, reader agent is scrapping the top resources from the URL.
Now my writer agent is drafting the entire report.
Okay, so step by step it is working amazing, right? The same things you can also perform in your anti-Kabity VS Code or uh Google Cloud or Chat GPT. You will see that it will also work step by step.
You are using the agent mode, right?
So the same thing we have developed here.
Now, see my critic agent is reviewing the report,
and that's how multi-agent system works. Now, see it's done.
Now, here you can see the status is already done. All the pipeline is completed successfully. There is no error. That means amazing, beautiful user interface it has created.
Now, just below, you can see this is the result.
Even you can see the individual uh actually
execution. Let's say my source result, my search agent has searched, right?
What it has searched, you will see see that it has got the URL, and this is the URL, it has got the content from medium, the snippet that means the introduction part.
Then this is the title, okay. Title, URL, and introduction part.
Then this is the title, URL, introduction part. Okay, that's how it is having five information.
Okay, five information now.
Second agent that scrap the content from the URL. Now you can see this is the extracted content from all the five uh URL.
Uh, this is how it has extracted, okay, and refine and this is the final resource report we got okay. On this AGI development in next five years introduction, key findings.
So it has written all of this thing, then conclusion.
Now, if you want to make it more detailed, you can change in the prompt itself. I think you remember. So here is the prompt.
Uh, here is the prompt
in the agenda.py.
So here you can increase that particular section.
Okay, if you increase it, will try to add that.
Then sources, whatever sources it has referred, it shall also give you the URL. You can see one by one, all of the URL it has given you.
Okay, let me see.
Now you can also download it as a MD file.
Okay.
my chat GPT also added another button here.
I can also download it as a MD file if I want, and I can open it up.
Then this is the critic feedback. So you can see score got six out of ten.
This is the strength that means still.
Uh uh, sorry, this is the strength that means of this particular report. Like the report provides a clear timeline for AGI development, blah blah blah.
It addresses both a technological and ethical consideration.
Still, areas to improvement are there. You can improve these are the section.
Maybe in the next um
prompt itself, you can add these are the point here.
Okay, these are the point here to improve that particular response, and this is the one verdict line it has written.
Okay, amazing.
Now let me try with another prompt. So, what I will do, so maybe I can ask like
all latest AI agent in 2026.
This example run the resource pipeline again. My agent is working.
Now, reader agent is scrapping.
Now my writer agent is drafting the report.
Critic is reviewing the report.
And my agent has executed.
Now this is my search result. This is the scrap content result. Okay, you can see here, and this is the final okay. Final research report on latest AI agent 2026.
This the report, this is the sources you can download even. This is the critic feedback.
Okay, amazing.
It's working perfectly now. If you want, you can also change the title. then you can also change this.
you can also change this okay. This content from this TMDY itself.
You can go to the code and maybe you can find out that section while it has added.
so I think there is a
so the best part is that like you can search. Okay, so let's I'll copy this
and
here I can search Ctrl F, Ctrl V.
Ah, so here, here itself you can change it here, okay.
Now
you can also change this title.
Change this title if you want. Let's say
uh here I think researcher agent.
So I can make it as
let's say research agent.
I'll save it
now if I come here, refresh now. it will become research agent. Okay, that's how you can change the title, whatever you want. Okay, everything is possible, but I will keep my researcher agent only.
So you just need to figure out why to change this UI interface, and you can also change the color, even if you want, you can also design this UI interface with respect to your requirement.
It's completely fine.
That means my agent is working fine. We have already tested. Now we'll commit the changes.
Uh
agents
working and tested.
Now we'll try to deploy this agent.
So
simply, what I can do, I can go to my GitHub refresh.
Okay, my agent is ready. Now, if you want, you can also update the readme file.
So nowadays, updating readme file is super easy.
Just open the agent inside your VSPOD, and try to mention
update the readme file for this
project,
like a open source
repo;
mention
how to
install
and
technologies
used here.
if
Architectures.
So now I will send this prompt. So automatically it will try to understand my entire code code base, now all the code, all of the agents, tool, everything, and it will prepare the README file for me.
Okay. So you don't need to write manually. After generating, you can customize.
Okay.
So let me do it quickly so that I can update in my repo.
Then I will show you the deployment.
Now see it is evaluating. See, it is also working step by step, right? First of all, it is editing the file, evaluating the file. That's how it is running multiple agents in the back end.
Okay, things are working like that.
Now see, once it needs any kinds of human permission, it will tell me I'll give the permission again. It will work.
You can also give this kinds of human in loop permission. I will also show you in future this kinds of thing.
Now in the readme file, see it has updated my readme.
Now you can uh see here, you can simply open the preview, and this is the update.
Okay, this is the update you can see.
Let me see, Right now, what I can do, maybe I can
commit the changes.
README updated.
Always try to update the readme
because with the help of readme file, user will be able I mean, some other people will be able to use your repo.
And definitely, whenever you are adding project in your resume, you have to update the readme in a proper GitHub repository. Now, see this is uh updated. Now, see this is this looks cool, right?
This looks like a like professional project, okay. Professional open source project.
You can see it has added all of the features, architectures, okay.
Then agent responsible technology used, prerequisite, installation process, okay.
Then get your own API keys, how to get the API keys, uses streamly TUI, then project folder structure, workflow, example output, contributing,
license, acknowledgement, and supports.
Amazing, right? Now let's try to deploy this project.
So to deploy this project, either you can use um paid Google uh paid actually cloud services like AWS, GCP, Azure,
or you can use any uh other platform that you can uh freely deploy this project. See, there is a platform called render cloud. I think previous project also I showed you this render.com.
So render.com also you can uh deploy any kinds of AI application, you can see first aid path to production for the workflow, you can deploy it here.
But the best part is that here you will be getting a free instance, okay. There you can deploy the project. But although this instance is like very low, but it's still I think for landing it is fine.
But if you want to uh professionally deploy that time, you have to take the subscription. But in AWS GCP, I don't free, I don't uh freely actually deploy. We can't freely deploy there, right?
So that's why we're using render.
So, first of all, you have to create an account in render. I already have the account, so I'll click on my dashboard.
Okay, so previously I already hosted another application as you can see.
Now let me create a new web service.
Okay, now I'll click on public git repository and I'll just try to give my repository link here.
Then you have to connect it.
Okay, once it is done, you can change the name by default. It has taken my repository name.
Everything would be same, no need to change anything, only you have to give a start command here.
So to run a streamlit app, you have to give this command,
okay? Streamlit run app.py server port port server address zero, and it will automatically install my requirement.txt, whatever I'm having here.
Okay, once it is done, now I'll take the free plan.
So initially it will get 512 mbram and 0.1 CPU. This is enough for I think learning, but whenever you want to professionally deploy it, you can take the subscription plan.
Now you have to set the environment variable because environment variable it's not available in my GitHub.
So I have my open AI and this tablet API, both I'll add it here.
So open AI
give the value.
Okay, now I'll add my another
environment variable which is
W.
Okay, once it is done, now simply click on deploy web service.
Now it will set up everything in that particular instance. Maybe it will take some time because we are using free instance.
we'll wait. Once this installation everything is complete, I will come back.
Now see it is installing requirement txt.
Let's wait, get once this status is live. I'll come back.
so guys as you can see my build is successful and application is live now i can copy this url Open up my browser, paste it, and hit enter.
Now this will load your application.
So initially it may take some time.
You have to wait once this has loaded, then you will be able to use that.
So, guys, as you can see, this is our application is live. Now you can share this URL with anyone, they can use it. Now let's try. Maybe I can copy this prompt
and I will test it.
See it's working.
My
search agent is working right now.
Now reader agent is working.
Now writer agent is drafting the report.
And critic agent is reviewing the report.
Okay, all of the execution is complete. Now here is the final result. You can expand and see.
This is the search result. This is the scrap content, and this is our final result we got.
Okay, yeah. So this is the sources you can download also critic feedback, everything is visible. So, yes, guys, I think uh it's working fine perfectly. There is no error.
we have successfully deployed as well.
Congratulations!
Now, let me show you if I want to let's say delete the instance so how it can be done. So, for this, you have to go to the settings,
and just below there is an option called delete web service.
Now you have to give this command
now. Delete the web service.
Okay, once you do that, you will see that your web service will be deleted.
Okay.
So, guys, I think you have seen the entire deployment, entire implementation of this uh AI agent.
We have created the complete multi-agent pipeline
uh with the help of Langchin.
Uh definitely, uh, I think this is going to be uh this is going to be actually uh interesting project uh to you if
you are creating the agent for the first time.
Uh so this was uh the first orchestration framework we have explored so far. Don't worry, uh we'll be exploring all of the orchestration framework one by one.
Now, in the next video, I'm going to tell you let's say uh why we have to use the actual agent TK orchestration framework like Langgraph, crew AI,
okay, or autogen, why we can't use uh Langchen, okay. What are the limitations Langchain is having? Each and everything I'm going to clarify.
So, guys, I think you know uh we have already uh implemented some AI agents with the help of Langchain.
Uh, this was our first orchestrator framework uh for building uh GNEI powered application, but I told you we can also use LangChain for
building these kinds of AI agents. So there I have shown you uh single agents implementation as well as the multi-agents implementation.
So if you haven't uh checked that, the link is given in the description. From there, you can check it out. So, from this video itself, guys, I'm going to start our
actual agentic AI orchestrator framework. The first framework will be starting with which is Lang Graph.
So I think you have heard of about Lang Graph, it's a very famous and mostly used framework in industry, and uh developers are using this framework okay
day by day in their life. So, before starting, actually Langgraph, first of all, I want to give you the idea behind this Lang Graph, why Langgraph came in the market.
And if you don't know, Langgraph is a product of Langchen, okay. So, LangChen developer team has implemented this Langgraph framework for building agent TKI application.
So, first of all, let's try to understand why they have created this framework for building these kinds of agent TKI application,
although they are having Langchen, okay. Um, I I think we saw we can use Langchen for building some of the agents, okay, some of the basic level agents, but why we have to use the Langchen?
Okay, what was the purpose behind to use this particular uh let's say Langgraph? Okay, first of all, we'll try to understand each and everything.
Uh, then I'm going to start with our Langgraph concept. Okay, so this video will cover the detailed discussion behind actually LangChin versus Langgraph.
Uh, I will tell you, I will show you why we can't use actually Langchen when it comes to complex actually workflow, complex
agent TKI let's say application. We can't use LangChin.
Uh instead of that, actually, we have to use Langgraph for that.
Okay, so I'm going to show you each and every example so that your understanding would be more clear. So make sure you watch this video till the end, guys.
Now let's see what are the things we're gonna cover from this video. I'm going to give you the agenda first of all, then I will start with the discussion.
So, guys, as you can see, these are the things we'll be discussing in this particular video.
first of all, I'm going to discuss about the brief overview of langchain.
So, again, the prerequisite for this video is you have to know Langchain. Okay, Langchain understanding is required, and I already told you in my YouTube channel I have created Langchain video.
again, I'm going to add the link in the description. From there, you can check it out.
So, first of all, uh we'll understand um what is Langchain, how Langchain works, uh, what are the application actually we can implement with the help of Langchain.
Then we'll be discussing about the Lang Graph. Uh, we'll understand why Langgraph is required and what is Langgraph exactly.
Then uh we'll try to understand like uh the difference between Langchain versus Langgraph. Uh, what are the benefit we'll be getting from the Langgraph?
Okay, and what are the these disadvantages we'll be getting from Langchain and when to use what kinds of framework? Definitely we'll try to understand each and everything.
So, uh guys, uh here you can see, guys, uh, here is the Langchain um.
Langchain definition. So if you see the Langchain definition uh here, Langchain is an open source library uh designed to simplify the process of building LLM-based applications.
it provides modular building blocks that let you create uh sophisticated LLM-based workflows.
Okay, with S. So I think you have already used Langchain, uh, I mean inside generate BI.
and there we work with large language model, and mostly we implement some LLM-based application like chatbots. then we create REG system, text generation system.
okay, uh, uh, retriever, system. We try to create these are the things, right?
So guys, as you can see, Langchain, uh, consists of multiple component. The first component is the model component.
So, basically, this model component gives us a unified, uh, actually interface to interact with any kinds of large language model provider.
Let's say, if you want to connect with Open AI LLM, so it is having the model component for that.
If you want to connect with Anthropic, uh, model, so it has the model component for that. Okay, if you want to connect with any open source LLM like Llama, okay, Mistral.
Okay, everything is possible. So, all kinds of provider basically it supports, and it it will give you some kinds of functionality so that you can connect with.
Okay, then it is having something called prompt component. So, what is prompt component exactly? So, this prompt component helps you to engineer the prompt.
So let's say whenever we want to give our custom prompt, okay, custom prompt, custom prompt.
Then if I want to write actually different different um prompt template, so everything is possible here and all kinds of
uh like
Prompting strategy, prompting engineer. We can perform inside this prompt component. Okay, so Langchin is having a prompt functionality; with the help of that, we can play with the prompting.
And I think, you know, especially in JNEI application, prompting is super important.
Without prompt, actually, we can't create a robust system because if you're using very poor prompt, definitely
whatever output you are getting from the application, it would be definitely poor.
But if you're using a good prompt with a detailed Instruction: That time you can get best output from the application itself. Okay, so Langchain provides all of them.
Then there is another important things we are having inside Langchain, which is this retriever component. So this basically helps you to fetch relevant documents from a vector store.
So I think, you know, we use this for the RG application, rag application.
So whenever we create the rag application, that time this uh retriever component is super important.
So there we um there we use something called vector databases, and inside vector databases we store all of the documents as a
Chunk chunk of vectors and whenever we require them, so we use retriever component for that to fetch the information, relevant information.
Okay, so yeah, I think these are the some major components, multiple components we're having inside Langchain.
Uh, but the biggest offering of Langchen is the chain.
Okay.
Uh, this, this particular things, chain. So without chain, actually it was very difficult creating this kinds of um,
this kinds of actually per uh production grade uh geni application because chain is kinds of actually workflow.
It's actually sequential workflow, so what is this chain exactly? Chain is nothing but it's a, I mean, workflow.
Basically here we create this chain in a sequential order.
So if you have already used Langchain, I think you know that. Let's say you have to create first of all multiple block, okay? Let's say I have created a prompt block, then what I will do?
I will take another block called model, okay.
Then I will take another block called let's say output parser,
Parser.
Then we'll try to connect this chain together.
Okay, this chain together. So basically, what uh will happen now?
First of all, this prompt will go to the model, and model will generate some kinds of output, and this output will try to see with the help of output parser.
So basically, it's a uh it's actually sequential workflow, and we call it as a chain.
So every block will give some kinds of output, and this output will become the input for the next next block. Okay, then again, this block will generate some kinds of output.
Again, this will be going as an input to another block, okay. That's how you can create actually as many chain as you can.
Let's say you can create thousands uh blockchain, you can create uh hundred of blockchain here, okay. So everything is possible inside Langchain.
So this is the biggest benefit we'll be getting from the Langchain.
So here you don't have any kinds of restriction, that means you have to only create uh a three blockchain or four blockchain.
Uh, you can create as much and as any uh as uh so here you can create as much as block you can, okay.
As much as like this chain you can,
okay. You have the flexibility here, so that's why this Langchain got like very popularity, and it was like
very easy for the developer for creating these kinds of Gen E powered application.
So as you can see, what you can build with Langchain. so I already told you we can implement like conversational workflow, like chatbots, text summarization app.
Okay, then apart from that, we can also create uh translation system, okay. All kinds of NLP related
I mean
problem statement we can solve with the help of this Langchain. Okay, we can implement with the help of Langchain, then multi-step workflow it supports.
So let's say whenever I want to create any kinds of
multi- multi-step workflows, that time it is also possible.
Multi-step workflow means let's say
I can give you one example. Let's say here you given a topic, okay. You given a topic, then what you have done, let's say you generated a detail,
okay. Detail report on that topic.
Okay, once this detail report a topic generated, then again you took that and you performed something called summarization
summary, okay. So basically you are running multi-step workflow here, okay. So if I break down uh as a um let's say chain here, so what you are doing, let's say first of all, you are taking a prompt
prompt uh related the topic, so you are passing it to the LLM.
Okay, let's see what telling uh I have uh um or let's say tell me about um
tell me about actually um large language model okay um you just generate a detailed report on that on the large language model in 2026.
So your uh this particular component will try to give you the output, that means the detail report. Then what you are taking again uh you are uh creating another prompt, okay.
You are creating another prompt, then you are telling now I need the summary of this particular detail report, then again you are passing to another llm.
Okay, llm, and this llm is giving you some kinds of output summary,
okay. Output summary. So basically, you are running here multi-step workflow.
So here we are not only using one large language model or one prompting, you can use multiple large language model, multiple prompting, multiple output parser.
Okay, so that's why I told you this chain can be created as many as you can, okay. And this is the best things we got inside Langchain.
Then the next thing we have, which is this REG application that means rag application.
So inside rag application, what we can do we can create an external knowledge base, okay, knowledge base for the LLM.
And we we can connect our LLM there. So basically, if you are asking any kinds of question, if the question answer is not available in the LLM itself, so what it will do,
it will refer kinds of database. Okay, we call it as a vector database, and this is the knowledge base.
Actually, we try to connect the LLM there, so LLM will fetch the information from here, and this process actually we perform with the help of this retriever component,
okay. Then we give the answer to the user, okay. So this is another things we can develop, then the last thing we can do on this basic level agents creation.
So we have already seen um how we can implement AI agents application with the help of Langchain. So there, I showed you, we can, um,
uh, create a single agents as well as the multi-agents. but, uh, here. the problem is that you can only create, uh, like very simple, um. I mean, workflow kinds of agents.
but whenever it is having complex architecture, complex workflow, that time, it would be difficult for you.
I will show you okay how what is the difficult, and if I want to implement with the help of Langchain, so what would be what would be the biggest challenge for you?
Each and everything I'm going to clarify. So basically, in the basic label agents, what we can do, maybe we can take a large language model, and here we can take some kinds of tool,
okay. Tool access.
So whenever user is giving any kinds of things, any kinds of input, so this particular LLM will have the connection with the tool,
and it it can use the tool to get the um get the answer.
Whether you can use any kinds of search tool or any kinds of tool you can use here with respect to your task, it will fetch the informations from the tool and it will show the user.
So basically, here what we have
we have some kinds of system there that system connected with some tools, okay, and that tool will provide some real-time informations to the agents so that it can perform
it can perform some automated workflow.
Okay, so this is the thing, and in multi-agents, we created multiple agents and we combined them together so that whenever I was assigning any task,
it was working together, okay, in a sequential manner. So, yeah, guys, these are the things we can actually implement from this Lang Chin uh Lang Chin actually framework.
So, guys, now we'll take an example and we'll try to understand uh why langchain
cannot be used whenever we are building any kinds of agent TKI application.
So, what would be the biggest difficulties and challenges if we are using langchain for building these kinds of agent applications? Uh, we'll try to understand in detail.
Okay, and why we have to use Langgraph, uh, we'll also try to understand in detail.
Okay, so for this, uh, I'm going to take the same example.
the example I gave you in my introduction session where I discussed about the agentic AI.
I think probably this was the second session you have to watch
on my playlist. So there I told you about a recruitment process agent.
So basically, let's say if I am having a um if I'm having a job position and if I want to uh if I want to let's say hire someone,
so how I can utilize an agent, okay. How I can utilize an agent and how this agent was working, okay. I think I give you a detailed introduction on that.
So, what I have done, that particular example I have converted in a flowchart. You can see this is a detailed flowchart. So this flowchart actually explains
each and everything about that particular application. so basically, we call it as a workflow.
So this thing we call it as a
Workflow
okay, workflow. So don't try to relate this workflow with the AI agents because there are some difference between this workflow and AI agents.
So if you want to understand this thing, so what you can do, uh you can um you can visit our website,
uh antropic.com. So they have written a blog about the building effective AI agents.
So if you just go below, so there they have discussed about the workflow and agents. Okay, so as you can see, workflow are system where LLM and tools are orchestrated through a predefined code path.
Okay, so as you can see, this workflow I showed you, so this is kinds of predefined path, and every time whenever I will run my uh let's let's say this particular block,
it will it has to follow the same things, okay.
But if I'm talking about the agents, okay, agents as you can see, agents on the other hand are the system where LLM dynamically directs their own process
and tool uses okay, maintaining control over how they accomplish a task. So I think you have seen my first example I have given you of the same requipment process uh uh applic uh uh let's say a system
there my agent was like kinds of automated, so I just need to give a prompt. Let's say I want to hire a back-end engineer. So all this step actually it was performing automatically, okay.
Sometimes it was giving you some kinds of,
let's say, human in loop that means human confirmation, but every everything it was automatically working,
so it was deciding what to do, it was automatically selecting the tools, okay, and each and everything.
But to make you understand about this uh lang chain uh lang chain actually um uh agents implementation,
or let's say if I want to implement the same that requirement application with the help of Langchin, so what would be the difficulties?
Okay, for that I created this particular workflow so that I can make you understand okay how it can be done.
so here you can see this is a workflow. so workflow means this is a predefined path, so you can see some kinds of condition looping, okay.
It is available, okay, as you can see, but on the other hand, agents are actually dynamically changes everything, dynamically take the decisions,
and it actually basically dynamically controls each and everything, okay. So I think you have understood what is workflow and agents, okay.
So, for example, guys, we'll try to consider this particular workflow
now. See, let's try to understand this workflow again. So, first of all, what we were doing here.
So, first of all, we are starting this workflow, and starting actually, we are giving our first prompt, which was let's say I want to hire a back-end engineer.
So, what will happen that time this particular request will go to this hiring request?
so this is kinds of a Python function.
You can consider this is a Python function, so this request will go to the hiring request.
so once it will go to the hiring request, so what will happen?
Uh, it will create the job description uh of that uh of that actually um um job you are asking for. Let's say we have given back end engineer. So, what will happen
for uh backend engineer? One job description would be created, okay. One job description we will be created.
Uh so let's say you are using some kinds of tool here that tool will help you to write that particular job description, then what it will do,
it will try to send to the next uh actually uh block you can see called JD approved. So this is another function.
So this function let's say has connection with another another llm.
Okay, so this llm, what it will do, it will try to let's say uh verify this job description, it will check whether this is fine or not for this job job role.
If not, fine, so it will send no.
Okay, if it is sending no, that means again you have to create the job description, okay.
I and if actually this particular job JD let's say block approved.
So, what will happen?
It will go to the next block. Okay.
It will go to the next block and it will post the job description.
So, in this case, let's say you are using some other tools like LinkedIn API, Nocry API, and with the help of this API, you are posting the job on that particular platform.
Okay, now it will go to the next block. Let's say here it will wait for seven days.
Okay, so this uh this particular block will wait for seven days. So after waiting for seven days, it will uh continuously monitor like how many application you are receiving.
Okay, so now again it is it is going through another condition.
So let's say if you got enough application, then it will perform the other step like short list, uh short listing, scheduling, conduct interview, and all.
But let's see if you're not getting enough application, let's see we are getting only two to three application. What will happen? It will send you no, and again it has to modify the job description.
Then again, let's say it will wait for 48 hours, okay.
Then again, this loop will be jumped to back, okay.
that means the previous block again. monitoring will start and again it will check whether you got enough application or not. If you got enough application, now let's say you got 20 application.
This is enough. That time short listing will be happening.
Short list listing means let's see it has some kinds of resume parser tool, so it will use that and it will uh
uh it will actually match the resume with our actual job description and uh it will short shortlist actually some of the candidate.
Let's say from 20 candidate, it will it's like four to five candidate. Then we'll try to schedule the interview, okay? then uh we'll uh take this interview, okay.
Manually take this interview, then again there is another condition block will come. So if let's say uh we selected the candidate, uh so what we'll do, we'll try to send the offer letter and all.
But if we uh let's say don't select the candidate, so what will happen? One uh regrate email will be sent to the candidate. Let's say I'm extremely 40. Sorry for that.
Um actually we are not uh uh we are not we are not actually hiring you because let's say you haven't uh performed good in uh in the interview.
Okay, this kinds of regret email we can send, otherwise, we can send the offer letter.
Okay, uh, so in offer letter also there are some condition. Let's say if this offer letter is accepted, that means definitely performing the onboarding and other task.
But if this offer letter is not accepted, then again what you will do, we'll try to perform some renegotiate.
Okay, let's say maybe I can increase the uh I can increase the package more. Let's say initially I I um let's say initially I offered uh uh 25 LPA, but let's say this person has rejected that.
So again, I will renegotiate that. Let's say I will give you 30 30 LPA.
So that time actually this person may prefer this particular package, so it will accept he will accept that, then I will perform the onboarding process and all,
then we'll uh um I mean end this particular workflow.
Okay, so that's how guys the entire workflow is working, and this was the first example we have taken to understand the AI agents, and right now we have seen as a workflow
how I mean things are working.
Okay, now let's say you want to implement this
system with the help of Langchain.
So, how you can implement this with the help of Langchain, okay, because Langchain doesn't have any kinds of conditional, uh
conditional let's say uh I mean uh workflow or conditional related functionality or looping functionality, okay. So Langchain doesn't have that.
So, first of all, let me tell you the challenges you will be facing here if you're um if you're using Langchain for this, this one.
Uh let me show you, yeah. So the see first challenge you will be getting here, which is
conditional.
Branch.
Okay. So as you can see, this particular workflow is having so many conditional branches. Okay.
So this is the first challenges we'll be facing if you're using Lang Chin because Lang Chin doesn't have any kinds of conditional branch because it works with respect to the chaining concept.
Okay, it it it kinds of sequential chaining concept it will be working, it doesn't have any kinds of conditional branch. Then the second
challenge you'll be getting the loops, okay. Loops
so as you can see, um sometimes it is performing the looping, so that means this particular things will continuously um
happening, okay. If let's say you you did you haven't received enough job uh application, so this process will again repeat, okay.
So that means you are looping the operation, okay, unless and until you this is not satisfied. So again, this looping concept is not available inside Langchain.
Okay, you can't create this looping concept inside Langchain. This is not possible. Now the third challenges you will be guessing uh getting called jump.
Okay, jump.
Now, what is jump exactly? Now you can see whenever let's say I didn't get any enough application, so this is telling no that time we are modifying the job description, waiting for 48 hours.
Then again, we are jumping back to my previous block. Okay, you can see monitor application.
Okay, so from here we are jumping again here. So this is called jump, and this kinds of jump we can't do inside Langchain. This is not possible, okay. So these are some uh biggest challenges, guys.
Uh, we will be facing whenever we will be using LangChin for developing this kinds of agent TKI system.
Okay, now let me show you um
as a code actually how it can be developed.
Uh, let's say somehow you want to develop these uh agents with the help of this Langchain.
Uh so now what would be the code is coding strategy? Okay, what would be the problem in the coding? Let's try to understand.
So here I have actually uh taken some code example, uh, and this is the Langchain implementation as you can see.
So
maybe I can open up my diagram.
Let me open the diagram, guys.
So this is the diagram, this is that workflow. Okay, now we'll try to understand now with this code. Now, as you can see, first of all, here we are preparing our prompt.
we need to hire a software engineer for the backend um back end team.
That means we are starting this recruitment process, we are sending the hiring request.
So, as you can see, um, before uh
uh before starting with, first of all, I need some, I need some let's say, um, I need some, um, um, I mean
important object. Like, first of all, I need the LLM object.
So we are taking an LLM, as you can see, Chat Open AI; we are taking, let's say, GPT4.
Then we are creating the prompt template.
Okay? So, create a job description based on the hiring request. Okay?
So whatever request we are getting, uh, so let's say this particular request we are getting, uh, we are preparing a job description for that. Okay? This is, this is a job description prompt.
Okay. So, to create this job description, we need a prompt. So, we are preparing here, then we are creating the chain here. As you can see, zd _chain is equal to job _prompt.
That means first of all, job _prompt will come, go to it, will go to the LLM.
LLM will prepare a job description, okay?
Job description, then it will uh uh it will be uh go to the output parser, and output parser will give you the job description, okay? Now, what we have to do guys?
We have to write this particular uh things as a function, uh, jd _approved. Okay, this is going to be a simple Python function, as you can see. So, we have written uh uh dev uh approved underscore jd.
So here, we'll try to pass the jd, whatever jd we have prepared, okay?
I'll try to pass in this function,
and this function will return cc. Inside that, I haven't written the whole code; I just given you the high level idea.
Let's say if this job description is approved based on some parameter, then we'll try to return approved; otherwise, we'll reject it. Okay? As you can see, we'll try to approve;
otherwise, we'll try to send no.
Okay, so here you can see:
once this particular job description is approved, then we have to pass to the post job description. See, as of now, we are considering
till here, okay. So this is the entire workflow, but I am not creating for the entire workflow, so let's try to consider uh this part, okay.
This part we we are implementing as of now with the help of language.
Okay, I'm only considering this part. So you can see,
let me show you.
Yeah, so you can see the next function I have written for post job description, that means this particular function.
So it will take the job description and let's say it has some connection with some job portal.
You have the API key, like let's say LinkedIn, NOCRE, and it will use that and it will post that particular job description.
Okay, so we have prepared all of the helper and utility related functionality. Now we have to work on the actual logic building.
So you can see sometimes we have to run the loop, sometimes we have to go through the condition. So these are the things we have to do, but in Langchain, this kinds of functionality is not available.
In Langchain, I think I told you this kinds of conditional branching, looping, jumping is not available. So, for this, what we have to do, we have to write some manual code.
So let's say here we have written the manual code. So, first of all, we have taken two variables approved and job description output.
Okay, by default, I have created it as a false, and this is this one is none.
Okay,
now here you can see in step five, we are running a loop until job description is approved. That means this particular things, okay. This particular loop will be writing.
So for writing this loop, I have taken a while loop, okay. While loop, and I told uh while not approved, okay.
That means unless and until this particular approved parameter is true, this loop will be running.
Then continuously, what we are doing, we are creating the job description, okay. Job description with the help of this particular prompt user is giving, and we are sending to approved job description.
That means this particular function, and unless and until we are not getting approved from this function, this particular loop will be continuously running.
Okay, you can see if not approved, job description uh job not approved, regenerating again. It will come here, again it will generate another one, again it will send to the this particular function.
This loop will be continuously running, okay. Let's say this particular job description is fine, we got approved.
Then what we'll do in the final step, if it is approved, then we'll try to post this job description with the help of this post JD function.
Okay, so that's how we can implement this system. Okay, we can implement this system, and yeah, we are able to do that.
Okay, somehow we are able to do that, but to implement this system, I think one more thing you have observed, which is this uh extra code, okay, which is this manual coding.
So let's say this manual function we have created again. Um
this manual code we have created,
okay. This manual code we have created.
So this is called actually
okay, glue code. So to implement this project, we have to write okay, so many line of glue code. Now, let's say you are creating the entire workflow right now.
Let's say you are creating the entire workflow right now. Just try to think about to complete the entire recruitment process how much glue code you have you have to write here, okay.
And it's recommended whenever you are creating any kinds of production grade application, so you have to avoid writing these kinds of glue code,
okay. You have to avoid to write these kinds of glue code, this kinds of manual coding.
Okay, so that's why in the market uh they published different different framework for different different kinds of tasks.
Okay, for agents also, we can't use langchain because in langchain we can implement we can implement this kinds of system,
it's completely fine, but for this, we have to write so many manual coding, so many glue code.
And this glue code is not good for our application, okay. And again, just try to think about as a developer.
Uh, definitely uh it would be very hectic task for you to write that that much of glue code, okay, inside your um uh code base,
and just try to think about how much your uh your code base would be. It would be huge code base, right? To manage this code base, like you have to, I mean, uh you have to uh
I mean take care of everything.
And we only do that right. So that's why, guys, we won't be using this Langchain for building these kinds of uh agenc workflow.
Because if you see this agentic workflow is not a linear one, it's a complex workflow, right? It's a complex workflow. When it comes linear workflow, that time it's completely fine.
Let's say there is no condition, there is no looping. That time easily we can use the training concept and we can implement these things with the help of Langchain.
Okay, but when it comes this kinds of conditional uh
conditional branch looping jump that time, this Langchain is not recommended for that.
Okay, so for this, we have to use some kinds of agentic framework, okay.
Agentic framework, it is only for design for building this kinds of complex workflow, complex block, okay, and it has support with this kinds of conditional branching,
looping, jumping, all the functionalities it is having.
Okay, that's why LangChain team has implemented another amazing framework called Langgraph.
Okay, so they have created one amazing framework called Lang Graph. So Langgraph is an agentic AI framework, okay. With the help of that, you can create agents application.
Okay, so how much complex it doesn't matter, you can implement all kinds of agents application, and why this kind of framework is
really good for building agentic application because it works uh works uh I mean with respect to the nodes, okay. I think you know graph is all about nodes, okay.
You can create as much as nodes you can, then you can connect those nodes all together, then you can also add the conditional statement, you can add the looping in the nodes.
Okay, that means graph data structure is a complex data structure, it's not a linear data structure.
If you have already studied about this DSA concept, I think you know that. So, graph data structure is a complex data structure, it's a non-linear data structure. So, here we can do anything, okay.
So, that's why
this lang graph is got. I mean, this is like very uh very powerful and popular framework when it comes for building any kinds of agent DKI application, and that's why
uh LangChen team has developed this kinds of system, and internally they are using uh Lang Chin only, okay.
Internally they are using Langchain only, they have written some robust code for that, and with the help of that, actually, they have built this Langgraph for us
so that we can use this Lang graph for building
AI agents application.
Okay,
I hope you understood. So, as I told you, this Langgraph works uh with the help of nodes because it has to create a graph, and to create a graph, we have to create a nodes.
So, if I now open the workflow, you can see I can clear, yeah. So, if I open the workflow, as you can see, here each and every block is kinds of nodes, okay.
Lang graph will consider each and every block as a node. So, let's say this hiding request, it it would be a node.
So, I can write here
so let's say this hiding request it's a it's a node.
So, this is going to be another. node.
This is going to be another node.
Then
we have
um
job approved. Okay, that means this checking function.
So I can make it as job approved.
Now
there is another node
called this post job description.
Post.
I can make it as a post.
Okay, so that's how it will create the nodes.
Just a minute, guys. Let me fix it. Yeah, notes. Okay. Now, after creating the nodes, guys, what it will do, it will draw the edges.
Okay, edges means the flow. Let's say this hiring request will go to the job description, that means
from here to here.
Okay, this is called edges.
Okay, in Langraph we call it as an edges.
Okay, you can see in the code also. I'll explain this code as well.
but I know that uh you you haven't written any kinds of code in Langgraph, but it's completely fine.
I'm going to teach you how to write the code, but as a high level, I'm going to make you understand okay how things are working. Now this job description will go to the job approved, okay.
This block that means this note.
So again, we'll create another edge.
Okay, now this job approved will go to the next uh next edge, uh, next actually notes, which is post job description.
Post job description, okay. So we have drawn the edges, okay. Now we'll be working on the conditional and looping.
Okay, now we we have to work on the conditional and looping. Now to uh I mean for better understanding, maybe we can see the code, guys, here.
so this is the code implementation
Let's say the same workflow we can implement with with help of Lang Graph. So you can see the Langgraph implementation.
So first of all, we are adding the nodes, okay. All of the nodes one by one. First of all, we are adding hiring request.
This this nodes, we are creating these nodes, okay. And you can see we are giving the name as well as we are giving a hiring request object. Now you can ask what is this hiring request object?
This is nothing but this is a simple Python function, as you can see, hiring request. Okay, so we are
creating a simple Python function. Um we are using LLM or we are using some kinds of API here in that, and we are preparing a function.
And once this function is ready, we are giving the object of that particular function in the inside the nodes. That means this particular function will be created as a node, okay.
Node inside line graph. Then the next node we are adding create job description.
Job description again. Create job description is another function, okay. We are giving the object here, okay. Then we are creating next node, which is check approval.
That means this function, okay.
So this is the function check approval. Then next we are doing this post job description that means this node, this node, again again, this is the
post approval. What is post approval uh post right post job description? Okay, this one, this particular Python function.
Okay, so with the help of that, we are preparing all of this node one by one. Now, once node is created, now I have to draw the edges. Okay, now we'll be drawing the edges.
So, as you can see, we are drawing the edges.
Uh so now see the workflow. First of all, uh hiding uh request will go to the
Uh create job description. So you can see uh graph.add edge
uh hiding request will be connected with create job description.
That means here to here.
so the first one then the second one. Okay, you want to connect this particular edge. Now next edge would be create job description to check approval.
Create job description to check approval.
Okay, so here we have to draw the edges.
Okay, but in between you can see
create job description to uh job approval. Here we have a
we have a condition.
Okay, if job is not approved, then it will again create a job description.
If it is approved, then it will post the job description.
Okay, so now we have to create this conditional statement, and it would be very easy for me to create a conditional statement because we are using this graph structure, okay. Inline graph.
Now you can see in graph itself there is a function called add conditional edges. Okay, now what would be the condition?
Uh condition would be dependent on this check approval function. That means this check approval we have created, that means this one, okay.
So if this check approval returns no, okay, if it is returns, no, okay, not accepted, again it will create the job job description.
You can see if it is not approved, then create the job job description. It's a loopback, right? But if it is approved, then it will go to the directly post ID.
Now you can see in next graph we are again adding another edges post ID that means from here to here, from here to here, okay.
So that's how guys we can easily implement this kinds of system with the pipeline graph.
Okay, I hope you got it and see, like very easy it is, right?
But in my previous implementation, it was very hard for me, and we have to write so many line of glue code here, but here it is not required,
okay. So I hope guys you have understood.
So this is the easiest example I can give.
like uh
regarding this Langchen versus Langgraph, and why people are using Lang Graph, why it is recommended to use Lang Graph like
instead of using LangChin for building this kinds of agentic workflow. Now I think everything is clear in your mind.
So that's why in this lang-graph implementation, you can either use looping, okay, looping concept, either use branching concept,
this conditional statement concept, okay, without writing any kinds of glue code. that's why it is
super powerful and recommended.
And easily you can implement any kinds of complex application, complex agent t application with the help of this lang graph,
okay? Because internally it is using this noding concept, graphing concept.
I hope it is clear, guys.
So, guys, now I'll be discussing about the second challenges you will be getting whenever you are using uh lang chain um
for this agentic AI application. So the challenge name is handling state. So let's try to understand what is state exactly.
So, see state a kinds of metadata
we use whenever we execute the entire workflow. So if I open the workflow, I think you have seen these are some important blocks we are having.
safety blocks will generate some kinds of output, and based on this output, actually we are deciding for the next block.
Let's say hiring request will go to the job description, job description will generate job description. Okay, then job approved will try to check whether the job description is fine or not.
If it is fine, if this job description sends yes, then job post will be happening. Otherwise, if it sends no, that means again it will create a job description.
So, in in every step, guys, you can see we are generating some kinds of state data, okay? State data. So if you just go through this block, I think you will understand
why this block are important and why the generated uh data are important because based on the data we are making the decision for the next block.
So, as you can see, if I show you this state, so let's say if this is our goal, hire a back-end software engineer. So, first of all, uh what will happen?
These are the information will be stored in the state memory. That means the job
description text would be available, then job approved or not, this particular status would be true or false, job posted or not, this would be true or false.
How many applications you got, number of applications you have, okay? Shortlisted candidates' name is offered letter sent or not, interview question is prepared or not.
Okay, so these kinds of data you need to run the entire workflow because these uh your agents will try to refer the state, okay, state data,
and it will decide okay what to do next. Let's say you have run till here. Let's say you have run till here,
you have executed till here till monitoring. So now right now your agent is having this kinds of state data, let's say.
It know actually how many applications uh you you you have currently, okay. It it it received currently and how it will understand because this information is available inside state, right?
So it will solve let's say five application came so far.
So what it again it will do again, it will tell this is not enough. Just try to modify the job description and again try to monitor everything, okay.
Based on that particular data, it is deciding, right? So this is super important. So this is called actually state, and Langtion is stateless, okay.
Langshen doesn't have any kinds of state-related functionality because you can see this particular state would be stored as a key value pair,
like a dictionary, okay. But Lang Shen uh Langtion doesn't give you any kinds of um dictionary or key value pair
storing concept, okay. That means Langshen is completely state less here, okay. You can't do it with the help of Langtion. You can do it for this.
Maybe what you have to do, you have to let's say whenever you are starting the code at the very first time you have to take a dictionary about uh name let's say state, okay.
You are taking a dictionary, and you have to manually like define these are the key here, manually define these are the key, and every after every execution you have to manually update these
are the value here, okay. So that means you are again writing the glue code here, and this is very hectic task for you to manage all of the state, right?
So if I show you all of the state, because it's not a like a very short state we are handling if you are creating the entire workflow, just try to think about how many state
that is how many metadata will come, and every time you have to update that inside lang chain, okay. So this would be hatric for you, but inside this lang graph, okay.
If I am using lang graph, so inside lang graph guys, this concept is available. So lang graph is like stateful, okay. Stateful.
If you are using lang graph, it is stateful because in lang graph we create a nodes, right? We create a nodes,
and nodes will be having this kinds of
this kinds of actually state connection. State connection means see
state connection means we can create a state object. Okay, we can create a state object inside line graph. So state object. So this state object can be created with the help of pydentic.
So I think I already taught you pydentic in my playlist. This same playlist, you can check that. Either you can create with the help of type dict. There is another concept you can use it, type dict.
Okay, so basically, what you will do, you will just try to define this kinds of structure at the very beginning of your application, and in every nodes you will try to provide this state access,
okay. So, what the node will do, so after every node execution, automatically these kinds of data would be updated. Okay, this kinds of data would be updated inside the state.
Okay, so let me show you, maybe you'll be clear enough. So I think I showed you an example, right?
I showed you one example related this
yeah, node concept. Yeah, you can see we are creating the node, okay.
We are creating a node.
So whenever you are creating a node, it will have the access to the state object, okay? So let's say whenever it is doing any kinds of execution, let's say it is generating the job description.
That time in the state, there would be a section called job description in a key, right? It will try to update the job description again.
It will run to the next node job approved.
So whether the job is approved or not, whether it is true or false, again it will try to update that particular parameter because we are defining this particular state with the help of this
pydentic, pydentic or this state dict. Okay, we are doing that this kinds of structure.
So that's why in the code itself, if you see the Langgraph implementation, so every time in the function itself, we are giving this kinds of
state. Okay, you can see we are giving this kinds of state, okay, and output it will also return you some kinds of state, okay, because it is updating in that particular
state object.
Okay, so that's how this language handles this kinds of scenario, this kinds of stating scenario, okay. Yeah, but you now you can ask me in in Langchain.
Uh we have the memory concept, definitely, right? In Langchain, we have the memory.
We can use the memory, but memory you can use for what for the conversational workflow.
Okay, you can store the conversation. The conversation you are doing with your chat bot or whatever. You can state the you can store the conversation. Okay, conversation story.
But it doesn't support any kinds of key value pair storing. This kind of stating concept is the it doesn't support.
You can store the conversation, you can use conversation buffer memory for that, but this kinds of thing is not possible, okay. I hope it is clear, guys.
Now, guys, let's talk about the third challenges uh we'll be facing, um, uh, which is event-driven execution.
Okay, so what is this event-driven execution? See, let's try to understand this one.
So, the workflow we have uh seen here. So, this workflow can be executed in two ways. Um, money is
let's say this is the workflow,
okay. So, this can be executed through sequential manner,
okay, and even driven.
Event driven.
Okay, so let's try to understand the sequential.
So let's say um sequential means let's say uh you are implementing through the languchain, and I think you know languchain works in a uh in a chain order, that means in a sequential order.
So, what I can do maybe
just a minute,
or let's clear.
So, see in Langchain
in Langchain
you have created in a sequential order.
So let's say first of all, you have given a prompt,
then you are passing this prompt to LLM.
LLM is giving a uh kinds of output again. You are preparing another prompt, again this output and prompt you are giving to another llm.
Okay, LLM, then you are getting some kinds of response here,
response here, right? So this is called actually sequential left to right. You can see left to right, it is happening. So this is a sequential order,
sequential order it is following.
Okay, so sequential order means this will start and this will complete the execution, then it will be completed. Okay, in between it is not pausing anywhere, okay.
In between it is not pausing anywhere, but if you see the workflow, inside workflow, sometimes we have to pause the execution, okay? So let's say if I give you example,
let's say if I come here, you can see. So, whenever this workflow is running, right?
It is running the workflow, it's completely fine, but here you can see it is waiting for some manual trigger, right? Let's say it will wait for seven days.
After waiting for seven days, then what it will do after posting the job description, it will wait for seven days, then your monitoring application will be started.
Okay, so here it is waiting for some kinds of trigger.
Okay, so this triggering concept is not available inside that sequential execution, okay. It is not available inside Langchin.
Langshen doesn't have any kinds of uh uh this uh pausing option, triggering option.
Okay, you can't do that,
okay. But you can implement inside Langshen. So for this, what you have to do, let's say maybe you will be creating this part separately, then you will wait for seven days.
Okay, let's say in some uh in Python code you will be writing a function that that function will try to wait for seven days, then again you will run this particular uh
this particular let's say workflow.
Okay, so that means you have to do it manually again. You have to write the glue code for that, but inside lang graph, okay. Inside Lang Graph, this kinds of concept is available.
This event-driven concept is available. So, Langchain, what it will do? So, automatically, because it has this state connection, right?
It has the state connection, and the state itself, this uh metadata would be available. You have to wait for three days.
So, in Lang-graph automatically, this particular event-driven option should be available, so it will wait for the trigger.
So, once this trigger is complete, then it will run the remaining workflow for you.
Okay, so this is another challenges you will be getting if you're using Lang Chin for building these kinds of agentic workflow. Okay, I hope you clear, guys.
So, guys, uh next challenges uh you will be getting called fault tolerance. So, what is this fault tolerance?
Fault tolerance means let's say whenever we are running these kinds of big workflow, so definitely there would be some kinds of fault in your application, okay.
Fault in your application, fault means let's say sometimes what uh what happens, let's say you are executing the workflow, let's say here.
You are executing the workflow. Uh, this particular workflow is getting executed. This particular block is executed. That time, let's say you are posting the job description to the LinkedIn.
Let's say uh that time LinkedIn API is not working, so definitely your application will stop that time.
Okay, so this is called fault.
Uh, there is another fault. Um, let's say you have deployed this workflow in a server, let's say AWS, and AWS got down. So, this is another fault.
So, that means this fault can be two types one is small type,
small type, and one is big type.
Okay, in small type, uh, what is happening? You are getting
the fault in between. Let's say in between the block, let's say you are not able to post the job in the LinkedIn because LinkedIn API is down, okay.
Our big fault means let's say you are you have hosted this workflow in AWS and AWS got down, that time your application will crash. So, what happens inside uh this uh
Langchain, Langchain doesn't have any kinds of fault or a nice functionality integrated with it. That means if you're creating a chain, let's say you have created this kinds of chain,
okay. This kinds of chain.
Okay, so how chain executed? It executed in a sequential order. Let's say here you you break the chain, okay. So let's say for a region, let's say this is the post job description.
Let's say API is not working, so that time it will break here, and all of the application will be break, okay.
Break then whenever you will be re-executing again, it will re-execute from the beginning, okay. From here it will execute, okay.
But already you have done so many stuff before posting the job description. Let's say your JDS paypad, everything is ready.
But if you're running from beginning, again it will do everything, then again it will post the job description over the LinkedIn.
That means it is not able to resume from here, okay. It is not able to resume from here, it is executing the entire workflow again.
Okay, inside the Line chain this is the problem, okay. Uh and let's see if your server is getting down, AWC is getting down also.
Again, you have to execute from the beginning, but inside lang graph, uh, this fault tolerance functionality is available. So basically, what happens?
Let's say whenever you are creating this kinds of workflow, let's say this is your workflow, okay. This is your workflow.
So let's say you are coming here and your you got you got some kinds of error, let's say your LinkedIn API is not working, that time it will give you um
one option called retry.
Okay, retry.
So if you do the retry operation, that means from after some times from here only your execution will start. That means it will go to the this node and this node.
Okay, it doesn't have uh has to come here from beginning and run the entire workflow.
Okay, and let's say you have hosted over the AWS, AWS got shut down, and let's say you run till here. There is some other workflow also available. Let's say you run till here, okay.
So, whenever you again let's say your AWS server fixed, okay, and it is running again, so again it will
continue from here, again it will continue from here, again it doesn't need to run from the beginning.
So, these kinds of fault tolerance option is available, and again, this fault tolerance how it is I mean handling with the help of the state concept,
state concept because we are having the state informations, okay. All of the state informations every time Langgraph will take the snapshot of the state and it will stored in a memory.
Okay, you can also use a physical memory here if you want some memory database you can use, and this state you can save inside a memory.
So every time it will take a snapshot of the state, let's say what is the current execution? Current execution, let's say post job description. Post job description. Let's say here your
let's say you got the fault. Okay, so this kind of state already saved. Let's say before this post job description, everything is ready, but during post job description, this is filled.
So, what it will do again, retry from here. Again, retry from here, it will not run from the beginning. Okay, I hope you got it. So that's why fault tolerance is another challenges inside Langchen.
So, guys, the next challenges and the very important challenges you will be facing if you are using Langchain called human in the loop or HLTL. Uh HITL.
Uh, I think you know what is human in loop, uh human in the loop and why it is required because I have given you the same example and let's try to understand from this workflow itself.
So, human in the loop actually it depends upon the human input.
So basically you are not giving the full access to the agent, instead of that, some of the restriction you are setting, let's say whenever it will create the job description,
before posting the job description, it will ask for the approved to the human. Let's say it is asking for the approved to you. If you approve that, then it will post this job description, okay.
Or let's say here, before sending this, uh conducting the interview, it will ask you uh whether uh you are free or not. Can I schedule the interview?
So if you give the access, then it will like um schedule the interview for you.
Okay, so this is called human in the loop, and this human in the loop functionality is not available um default inside Langchain.
Um, I mean you can't take the human in I mean human input in between the chain. So let's say if you create a chain here, let's say this is your chain,
this is your chain, right?
And in between, let's see you have to take an input from the human.
Okay, you have to take the input from the human
that time.
you can't actually I mean use any kinds of default functionality for that.
So maybe what you can do in between, maybe you can take an input function and you can take the input from the human, but again, this will stop the chain here, okay.
Unless and until you are not giving the input, this chain won't be executed or it will take unnecessary computation, and whenever it is long term, right?
Long term means this kinds of agent tick system is long term, so user can give the input after two days as well, right?
So that time I don't want to necessarily compute, I don't want to necessarily use my computation, right? So this is another problem.
So maybe you can create this chain separately, this chain separately in between you can ask the input, and whenever user will give the input, then you can recontinue this chain from here, okay.
But again, you have to take all of this state uh, I mean state data manually, and you have to copy here again. So again, you have to write some glue code there for that, right?
But inside this uh langu, this human is loop already implemented, okay. This is already the first class citizen, okay.
First class citizen inside this language, it is already already available, okay. Already available, even if you go to the documentation of Lang Graph. there is a separate section for that.
Let me show you. So, this is the Lang Graph documentation. So you can see human in the loop is available. So the human in the loop is s hitl me middle wire lets you and human oversight
to agents to call when model responds an action that might requires a review. For example, writing to a file or execution SQL. the um middle wire can pause execution and wait uh decision.
Okay, so you can see this particular option is available and they have already integrated in their functionality. Okay, here in the loop. Okay, this is already available.
We'll definitely learn this in detail whenever we'll uh learn the lang chain component. sorry, Lang graph component. I will try to learn each and everything. Okay, I I hope this part is clear.
That means this is another challenges you will be getting uh if you're using Langchen, okay. And this is super important, guys.
If you're you is creating this kinds of workflow, so this uh human in loop is required there, okay. I hope you clear.
Now let's talk about the next one, which is nested workflow.
Uh, nested workflow means see inside uh lang graph you can run the nested workflow. So, whenever I'm talking about Langgraph, I think you know we can create actually
complex
nodes here, right? It works as a node.
Okay, you can create this kinds of node.
Okay. Now let's say a nested workflow means the nodes you are creating
inside these nodes you can create another graph.
Let's say this node represents this kinds of graph.
Okay, that means this node itself it's a graph object.
This is called nested workflow.
Okay, I you I think you get it. We call it as a sub node. So there is a concept inside the documentation. Let me show you.
Um
this is the documentation. Uh you can see if you see there is a concept called sub sub node.
So let's say this is your node, this node itself should be another graph, and you can use this particular graph.
Okay, so this is called actually sub uh sub node concept, and we call it as a nested workflow. And this nested workflow is very much required whenever you are creating this kinds of system.
So let's say if I'm talking about uh use case, so let's say if I'm talking about this conduct interview, okay.
So instead conduct interview, uh, this thing is not like uh very easy to implement because just try to think about if I want to conduct the interview.
First of all, I have to prepare a set of questions for each and every candidate, then I have to also
take the interview, let's say round one, round two, round three. Okay, I have to track those informations. So instead of creating a single uh nodes here, maybe I can create it as a sub node.
So this will be connected with another nodes, and that uh sorry, this will connect it with another workflow, another graph, and this graph will try to let's say
prepare the interview questions for the candidate or uh taken taken care by the round one, round two, round three, okay, and so on.
So these kinds of complex nodes whenever it is coming, you can simply handle with the help of this nested workflow, and this is very much important whenever you are building any kinds of multi-agent
system, okay. In multi-agent system, this nested workflow is required that time, but this uh nested workflow functionality is not available inside Langchin.
Inside Langchin, actually, we can't create these kinds of sub nodes and all. This is not possible, okay? So that's why uh you can call it uh this is as a feature inside line Graph as
well. Now, guys, the last uh challenges will be understanding which is observable uh observability. So basically, uh what is observability? Actually, let's try to understand.
Observability refers to how easily you can monitor debugs and understand what your workflow is doing at the runtime.
So, whenever we are running these kinds of runtime, so definitely we have to uh continuously do the observation, otherwise, what will happen?
Uh, sometimes it will do some um let's say unexpected task, right? Let's say you have run your agents
for the LinkedIn ads, okay? So let's say it is running the LinkedIn ads continuously, and you will end up with lots of cost that time, right?
let's say it's not necessary to run that much of LinkedIn ads or that much of budget, right? So that time if you are not doing observation, so definitely you will end up with lots of cost.
so that that that's why observability is required, but it's not like that we'll sit there manually observe all of the execution, it's not like that.
So, definitely we have to use some automated things that will continuously do the observation, continuous to do the monitoring, and it will give me the report. Okay, so fortunately in Langchain.
If I'm talking about Langchen, Langchen
has
um observability tool, which is Langsmith.
Okay, I think you heard about Lang Smith. So Lang Smith is a like observation tool with the help of Lang Langsmith. We can continuously track the Lang Lang Chin actually pipeline Lang Chin chain.
So whatever Lang Chin um chain will be executed, all of the uh all of the actually let's say parameter we can uh uh we can actually monitor here in the langsmith Lang
Smith will automatically monitor. So by default, lang langsmith um can support this Langchain uh monitoring, okay.
And don't worry, we'll try to understand Lang Smith as well continuously. sorry, going forward. But what is the problem with the Lang Chin?
Uh, if you're using LangSpeith with that, see if you are implementing this workflow with the help of Langchen, so definitely you have to write lots of glue code.
I already told you, right? You have to write lots of glue code, but glue code cannot be monitored with the help of Lang Smith.
Lang Smith only can monitor your Langchain chain, okay, chain code or whatever you are writing inside that.
But if you're writing extra glue code, you can't actually uh you can't actually uh track with the Lang Smith. This is not possible.
But if I'm talking about Lang Graph, if I'm talking about Langgraph, okay, Langgraph is having very strong connection, okay. It is having very strong connection with Lang Smith.
Okay, so that means whatever node execution you are doing one by one, all of the node would be tracked in the Lang Smith,
Lang Smith, and you can see each and everything, okay. So that's why this Lang Smith uh as the observ uh observability tool will be learning in this playlist as well.
In detail, I'll tell you how to use the langsmith and all, and how we can perform the monitoring operation of our agent. Each and everything will we'll also try to understand here, okay.
This is super important, and uh uh yeah, I think this is a good practice to add the observability uh whenever you are creating the application because there you will get
enough understanding about your workflow execution, okay, at runtime.
This is super important.
So, yes, guys, we are done with uh all of the challenges. We have understood each and everything in detail.
Now we'll try to conclude uh this video.
Uh, so before concluding, let me tell you few things.
So, guys, so far we have understood uh about the Langgraph and difference between Lang Chin and Lang Graph. Um, and I also
showed you the challenges actually we will be facing. Okay, if you are using only Langchen, okay, if you are not using Langgraph, what will be the challenges?
Now you have pretty much uh good understanding about the Langgraph, what exactly the Lang Graph is, but again, I have given you a definition.
You can see Langgraph is an orchestration framework that enables you to build straightful, multi-step, and event-driven workflow using large language
model. It uh it's deals uh ide ideal for uh designing both single agents and multi-agent t applications. Think of a Lang Graph as a flow chart engine for LLM. You define the steps nodes, okay.
We call it as a nodes, how they are connected edges, um, and uh and the logic that governs the transitions.
Line graph takes care of state management, conditional branching, looping, pausing, resuming, fault recovery, feature as uh feature essential for building robust production grade
AI system. Okay, so I think you have seen I have introduced so many um so many actually strong terms here, like this uh edges branching, looping, pausing, okay,
fault recovery. So now I think this uh these are the traps are clear because I have already clarified these are the traums, then I give you the introduction.
So at the very beginning, I could have given you the introduction to this line graph, okay. Uh this kinds of uh definition I can show you.
This uh this uh actually page I can show you, but uh you won't be able to understand okay what the languag is, and you that time actually were not familiar with these are the concept.
So, what I have done actually, I have clarified all the concept. Now I have given you the introduction. Okay, I have given you I have told you what is Langgraph exactly.
Okay, now I think you are pretty much clear with. Now let's try to understand when to use what kinds of framework.
So use lang-chain when you are building simple linear workflow like prompt chaining, summarization, or basic retriever system, chatbots. Okay.
These are the things, and use Langgraph when you use case uh involves complex non-linear workflow that needs conditional paths,
loops, okay, human in the loops concept, then multi-agents coordination and asynchronous revenue-driven execution.
Okay, so now I think, guys, uh, you have the understanding uh about uh this concept like when to use what kinds of framework.
Uh so based on the problem statement, you can decide whether you will be using the Lang Chin, whether you will be using the Lang Graph for that.
Okay, so now I think you have the enough understanding on that. Now, one more very important things will be understanding at the last.
Uh so see, people uh still uh people will uh I mean uh tell you like don't use uh lang chain, lang chain is
like deprecated and all. Okay, so should we still use Lang Chen or not?
Because this kinds of questions will definitely come, and through the entire video, actually, I have given the appreciation to the Langgraph instead of giving to the Lang Chin.
Okay, but things is not like that. See, still we have to use this Lang Chin, okay. Lang Chin is required why because Langgraph is built on top of Langchen,
okay. Internally they're using Langchen only, okay.
then they have created this Langgraph framework, so it is basically handling the complex workflow, okay.
The complex workflow by adding the noding concept, but internally it is using Langchen because if you see still you need LangChen components,
like if you want to load any kinds of LLM, you have to use chat open AI or any other open let's say llm provider functionality.
If you want to create a prompt, so you have to use the prompt template, if you want to create a retriever system, you have to use the retriever, documents loader, tools, etc.
Okay, these are the things you will be only loading from the Langchin, not from the Lang Graph.
Okay, I think you get it, and Langgraph handles workflow orchestration while Langshin provides the building block for each step in the workflow. That means LangChin is very important, okay.
But we can't use LangChin to build the entire complex workflow orchestration.
Okay, we create this orchestration, we create this workflow orchestration with Lang Graph, but internally Langgraph uses some lang chain building blocks, like these are the building blocks
to uh work on that. Okay, I hope this part is clear, guys. Okay, so guys, uh I think uh you have uh now clear and uh I mean enough amount understanding on this
Lang Chin. Uh you have got the detailed introduction to the Lang Graph.
Uh, and uh don't worry, I'm going to uh teach you the uh teach you all of the component of the Langgraph, we'll be also building the agents with that, okay.
Each and everything will be covering in this course itself, okay. Now in this video, I'm going to discuss some important core component of Lang Graph because what I feel like
before starting the actual Lang Graph concept, first of all, let's try to understand the Langgraph core component.
So once we have understood the Lang Graph core component, it would be easy for us to learn all of this component one by one,
then we can combine all of them together and we can build any kinds of agentic AI application.
So, guys, as you can see, uh what is Langgraph? Langgraph is an orchestration framework for building intelligence stateful, and multi-step LLM workflows.
Uh, it enables advanced features like parallelism, loops, branching, memory, and resumability, making it ideal for
agentic and production grade AI applications. And Langchain models your logic as a graph of nodes. Basically, we call it as a task and edges.
Okay, I think you saw there are some edges we are drawing in my previous class, right? So we call it as edges, we also call it as a routing instead of a linear chain.
Okay, so in LangChain we used to create a linear chain, but here we don't create the linear chain instead of that we try to make everything as a graph.
and to make this graph we use nodes and edges, okay, inside Langgraph. So let's say you are having a LLM workflow. So let's say this is our LLM workflow.
okay. This is our LLM workflow and this is called actually edges. Okay, this is called actually edges.
So let's say this is our LLM workflow. Okay. I'll tell you more about this LLM workflow. What is LLM workflow is? LLM workflow is nothing but I told you about the workflow, right?
Workflow is nothing but it's a it's a process of executing an entire let's say application, entire problem statement. So basically we try to represent as a workflow, and inside that we use LLM, right?
So that's why you call it as LLM workflows. So you can see this is the LM workflows. So here we pass any kinds of input, okay. And all of this uh you can see node. Okay, this is called actually node.
This is called actually node. This node can be called as a task, okay. Task basically, let's say you are having you are having an entire goal, okay. Entire goal.
So to achieve this goal, what you have to do? We have to break down this goal as a task, okay? Different different sub task. and each of the sub tasks can be represented as a node, okay, in Langgraph.
So we try to represent as a node. So this node will perform all of the task.
Let's say some of the let's say the first node is responsible for taking the input, second node is responsible, let's say preparing the prompt.
Okay, then third node is responsible for calling the LLM. Okay, that's how another node will be responsible for calling a tool. That's how it is defining a separate separate task as a node.
Okay, I hope you get it. Now we also call it as a flow chart. We also call it as a flow chart. As if you see this particular graph, this is kinds of flow chart.
Okay, now you can see inside lang graph we can perform this parallelism, looping, branching, memory, reasonability,
each and everything. So if I'm talking about the parallelism, so lang graph can be also executed in a parallel. Okay, let's say here you are having
a node, here also you are having a node, so both node can be executed parallelly. Okay, both node can be executed parallelly.
Let's say you are preparing a prompt template and here you are calling the LLM. Okay, so it's not like that after preparing the prompt template, you will call the LLM.
Both you can execute in parallel, right? That's how there are so many problem statement you can I mean um consider here. Okay, now it can also supports this looping concept.
Looping concept means let's say sometimes let's say you are you are here in this particular node. Let's say after completing this node, again you have to go back.
Okay, you again you have to go back and again you will re-execute and again you will try to send to the another nodes.
I think you remembered our previous uh uh previous actually um example I have given you that uh interview uh
interview agent TKI. Uh I think uh huh. So interview uh interview system. Okay, that interview system what happens? Let's say whenever uh uh sorry, not interview, that was actually recruitment agent.
So there actually what happened? Let's say if uh if let's say your job description is not generated properly, so what it will do again, it will go back and again it will regenerate.
So this is called actually looping, right? This is called actually looping. you are performing the looping here. Then you can also perform the branching operation. Branching means the condition.
Let's say if this condition is not true, okay, that means if it is not yes, then it will go here. Okay, that's how you are creating branch here. So this is called branching.
Let's say if you didn't get 20 applications, again what you will do, again you will try to like change the job description and wait for the application submission.
So this is called actually branching. So this branching also can be supported, then memory.
Memory means let's say each and every nodes, whatever it is generating the output, it would be stored inside a memory. Okay, it will remember that particular output and input as well.
This is called memory, okay. Then re uh resumability. Reasonability means let's say I told you about the um about the actually problem.
Okay, problem is let's say somehow your one of the application got let's say Got trouble, that means it got stopped. Let's say it got stopped here only in this particular node.
Okay, in this particular node, it has stopped. So, whenever you will reinitialize the instance, so instead of running from the beginning, it can resume from here only, it can continue from here only.
This is called resumability. Okay, so that's why we call it as a like a very powerful I mean framework, this particular land graph, because
the way it is handling all of the let's say task, all of the system, this is completely amazing, right?
And that's why we can't use the simple lang chain here, the linear chain here to solve this kinds of complex workflow.
That's why lang graph is required, and this is what actually your lang graph is, okay.
So basically, here we will be working with the nodes and edges, okay, to make a graph, okay, instead of a linear chain. I hope you understood, guys.
Okay, now let's try to understand about the LLM workflow in more detail. so you can see what is LLM workflow. First of all, let's try to understand.
So LLM workflows are step-by-step process using which we can build a complex LLM applications.
Each step in a workflow performs a distinct task such as prompting, reasoning, tool calling, memory access, or decision making.
Workflows can be linear, parallel, branched, or looped, allowing for a complex behavior like uh retries, multi-agents communication or tool
augmented reasoning. And we'll be discussing about some common workflows as well. So the first workflow, as you can see, this is the linear sequential workflow.
We can also call it as a prompt chaining. So here, what happens?
Let's say whenever we are giving any kinds of input, it will first of all go to uh LLM, okay, LLM call, because I'm calling it as a LLM workflow,
and definitely inside the workflow, definitely LLM call should be there. Okay, LLM should be there. That time we can call it as a LLM workflows, okay.
If it doesn't have any kinds of LLM, that time you can't call it as a LLM workflow, and now inside a workflow there can be one or multiple LLM call,
okay. One or multiple LLM call. It's not like that you have to only use one LLM call or let's say five llm call or 100 lm call.
You can use as many as llm you can inside a workflow, but make sure LLM call should be there, otherwise, we can't call it as a LLM workflow. Okay, so let's say this is a workflow.
So, first of all, this input will get this particular LLM, then here we are let's say doing as kinds of verification whatever output we are getting, whether it is good or not.
Okay, if it is good, then we are passing it to the LLM another LLM okay for another task, then it will send an again to another LLM for another task, then it will
give you some kinds of output, okay. Otherwise, if this particular response is not good, then it will exit the application. Okay, so this is called actually linear workflow.
you can understand okay from this particular.
So here you can understand this particular concept from this workflow itself. Okay, I hope you clear.
Now let's take an example to understand this prompt training workflow. So let's say you are building uh you are building an agent, that agent will take a topic, okay. Topic name as an input.
Okay, so this input should be a topic name, topic name, and what it does it generates a complete report on that particular topics.
Okay, so I think previously you saw I created these kinds of agents with the help of Langchain. So there I passed a topic and it was preparing a detail
detail actually scientifically put on top of that. Okay, so first of all, what you are doing, you are giving this particular topic name to the first llm call, and that means the first llm,
and this LLM will try to
we will try to generate something, okay. We'll try to generate something.
Let's say this particular llm has generate a draft from this particular topic, okay. So let's say it has generated draft. Okay, draft now. Here you are doing a verification.
Let's say you are writing a condition. If this particular draft is more than 5000 word, okay, it is more than 5000 word. That time you are not going to take you simply exit the application.
Okay, you only take less than 5000 word. So if it is less than 5000 word, then again what you will do again you will pass to the alalar llm. Let's say this llm does the
review operation, okay. Review operation that means it will perform the review operation. The draft you have prepared. If review is completely fine, if it pass okay, then it will go to the next llm.
This llm will try to write this particular draft in a file, okay.
write.
Okay, write this particular draft in a file, then you will get the output. Okay, so this is the example you can consider about the prompt training.
Okay, so inside prompt training, what you are doing, you are trying to break down a task, okay. Um, and you are trying to solve it, okay, step by step. This is called prompt chaining.
Now let's try to understand about the another llm workflow, which is routing.
Okay, so this is another kinds of LLM workflow.
this is called routing. Routing means here you are getting an input and you are using a lm um uh definitely llm call, but this llm call we are considering as a router.
Router means it will basically route uh route the uh route the task, okay. Route the task to different different llm. Okay, as you can see, let's say this is llm1, this is LLM2, this is llm3.
Okay, and here we are getting the output. So let's say you are building a customer support application, let's say for the tech company.
So there you are getting different different let's say customer questions. Let's say you are getting related.
let's say you are running an ad tech company, you are let's say getting the question related about your service, okay. The service you usually provide. let's say whatever course you provide, okay.
Whatever let's say
content you are providing, these kinds of service people are asking about.
So let's say the fast uh lm uh we uh we just uh let's say uh defined this service task to the fast llm that means the prompt we have written here.
So this particular lm will try to only handle about our service, okay. Service limited query. So let's say this is the service
service llm.
Okay. now, the next, let's say
next, let's say, um, uh, I mean, um task, which is uh about our
about our, let's say what I can say,
or let's try to consider about a technical query,
technical query,
query, technical query.
Okay, technical query means let's say people are having a doubt related python or machine learning, deep learning, whatever.
So this particular LLM will try to handle that, let's say this is the tech LLM. Okay, now there is another LLM; this LLM will try to give you the interview related help.
Okay, interview preparation related help. Let's say you want to prepare for the interview, so
this particular LLM will try to handle the interview related task. Now, whenever any kind of student is giving the input, let's see: student asking about the services.
Okay, the service we usually provide in the DS with Bub P, okay? DS with Bub P, whatever service we provide, he is asking for now. What this LM router? Okay, LLM call router will do it;
will automatically understand about your questions and it will decide when to send this, but Uh, why to send your question whether it has to send to the LM call,
sorry, service service LLM, whether it has to send to the take LLM or whether it has to send to the interview LLM? So, definitely this is a kinds of service related query.
It has, it will send to the service LLM here, okay? And service LM will try to give you the response and you will see the output.
Now let's say someone is asking about the Technical query, let's say he is getting a python function error, so that time LM router will understand. Okay, now I have to send to the take LLM.
Take lm will give you the output and you will be able to see the output. Now there is another, let's say question, you are getting related interview;
your LM router will send to the interview LLM and he will be getting the output. Okay, so this is called actually routing workflow, routing LLM workflow.
This kinds of workflow we can easily create inside the line graph. Okay, so definitely we'll try to also discuss about that.
Now, let's try to understand about the next workflow, which is, uh, parallel, um, parallel, uh, parallelization. Inside parallelization, actually, uh, what we can do?
We can execute, uh, the task in parallel. So, let's try to understand, uh, this particular concept as well.
As you can see, let's say here we are getting the input and some multiple LM call is happening. Okay? Let's say LM2, LM1, LM, uh, uh, two and LM3.
Then we are performing the aggregator operation, then we are getting the output. Okay? So, if I'm giving you a real -time example, let's say I'm a YouTuber, definitely.
I just try to upload my content to the YouTube and by default, YouTube also,
YouTube also use internally this uh um, I mean, AI related uh functionality.
Okay, so with the help of AI, actually it uh what it do it, it it tried to let's say, uh, do the verification check of your content. Let's say the content we are uploading to the YouTube.
Okay, let's say I have recorded a video. Okay, I have recorded a video.
So, first of all, you will upload that video, and it's not like that YouTube will directly take that video and uh it will allow you to publish. First of all, it will do some verification.
Okay, verification. Verification means let's say it can be multiple layer verification. The first is, let's say, whether it is any uh unappropriate content or not;
unappropriate content or not, then it will check whether it is sexual content or not, then it will check whether this content is uh having any kinds of uh
any kinds of let's say
abusive or not.
Okay, so this kinds of let's say multiple layer verification it will do.
Now here what we can do for each of the verification, maybe we can use different different tasks, different, different let's say lm call for that.
Let's say the first one is responsible for checking unappropriate okay, unappropriate verification.
Second one, let's say it is responsible for sexual verification, and third one is responsible for let's say
abusive verification. Now it's not like that after checking this unappropriate verification, you have to do the sexual verification, or after checking the sexual
sexual verification, you have to check for abusive verification. It's not like that. All of the checks are independent here, okay. So instead of running sequentially, you can run in parallel.
So parallelly, all of the check will done. Okay, once you will get all of the let's say check, check let's say ratings and answer, then we'll try to aggregate them together, okay.
Let's say it will give you some kinds of rating. Let's see if it has given you 9.5 out of 10. Okay, that means this video is good. It has also given you let's say 9.6 around 10.
Okay, it has also given you 9.5 around 10. Then you are combining all of them together, you are making the average, and let's say there is a condition, there is a average threshold.
Let's see if this threshold is matching. That time you will try to accept this video, otherwise, you will try to reject the video, then you are getting the output here, okay.
So that's how this parallelization will be working, and this kinds of workflow also we can easily create inside our line graph as well.
Okay, now the next workflow let's try to understand, which is this orchestrator workflow. Okay, so this is this is the same kinds of I mean parallelization actually workflow.
As you can see, we are also taking all of the result and we are also doing the aggregator operation and we are getting the output. But the only difference is uh let's uh let's try to discuss about
so in this workflow uh as you can see um before this uh
before this particular section, there is another section we have which is orchestrator. Okay, orchestrator is another you can say lm um lm uh call.
So basically, this is the main okay, lead lead actually
lead nodes. This particular nodes will decide a particular task it is getting. so what to assign whether it will assign to the LLM1, LLM two, and lm3. Okay, it will basically decide.
But if you see the previous one, the parallelization one, so basically here we are uh uh setting the task. Let's say here we are assigning the task.
Let's say lm uh one will get the task related unappropriate content, LLM will get the task related uh let's say sexual content and lm3
will try to get the task related abusive content. We are defining the task, but here there is no task nature, okay. So basically, your orchestrator will decide what to you set this particular task.
Okay, so based on the orchestrator, it will define let's say it can define to LLM1, LLM2, and LM3.
Okay, it doesn't matter, but it will decide okay which one would be appropriate for this particular task.
Then once we are getting this, we are again doing the synthesizer that means aggregating and we are getting the output, okay.
So your orchestrator can also define this particular task to only lm1, okay? Or let's say it can define the task to lm1 and lm3. It doesn't matter, okay. Based on the task, it will decide.
It can either give to the let's say multiple lm, either it can give it to the one lm. Okay, so this is called actually orchestrator workflow. I hope you get it.
Okay, so this is the Similar kinds of your parallelization. Now the next workflow you are having this evaluator optimizer. Okay, so what is evaluator optimizer?
So I think by the workflow itself you can understand the actual example, okay, how this will work. So basically, it has one LM call generator, okay.
LM call generator, this particular section, and it is having another one called LM call evaluator.
Okay, so basically, whatever input you are getting, giving first of all lm this lm call is generating this particular output, then you are sending to the lm call evaluator and it is checking, okay.
It is checking whether it is good or not, okay, whether it is good or not, and if it is not good, it will reject,
and with the reject, it will also give some kinds of feedback like what to update next.
Okay, so this will get again this particular LM call generator, the rejection parameter as well as the feedback based on the feedback again.
It will try to based on the feedback again it will try to generate, okay. Again, it will try to send to the LM call evaluator. Okay, then if it is good, then it will accept and we'll see the output.
Okay, and this particular loop will be continuously happening unless and until this will LLM call evaluator will accept your content, okay. So I think you know that in our that
recruitment agent I told you about the job description, right? So let's say one of the LLM will generate the job description here.
Let's say this is this is generating the job description, and another LLM you're using for verifying the job description whether it is perfect or not.
If not perfect, it will give you some kinds of rejection and the feedback again.
It will try to generate the job description, again it will send, and if job description is fine, then it will accept it. that particular job description. Okay, I hope you get it, guys.
So, guys, I have shown you I think five workflows here: one, two, three, four, and five.
Okay, so five different LLM workflows I have explained here, and don't worry, I'm going to I'm going to cover these are the workflow in this particular playlist itself.
Okay, we'll try to see all of the workflow one by one. Now, the very important concept we'll try to understand about the
Line Graph components. Okay, we'll try to understand Line Graph core components, which is graph nodes and edges.
Okay, although I have given you the high-level overview in my previous video, what is graph nodes and edges, but still we'll try to understand this particular concept in detail.
So for this, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to take an example.
I'm going to take a problem statement, and this problem statement will try to define as a graph, okay, define as a workflow, then we'll try to understand these are the concept.
So, guys, as you can see here, I have taken an example.
so let's say here we want to create a system uh that generate a SE topic. Okay, I think you know about SE.
Uh so whenever you are let's say going for any big uh universities, uh
so basically you have to submit uh SE there, okay, uh based on the topic. So let's say what it does, it uh collects the student uh SE submissions and it evaluates in parallel on
depth of analysis, language quality, and clarity of thoughts based on the combined score. It either gives the feedback for the improvement or approves the SE.
Okay, so to build this particular system, first of all, we have to break down the task, okay. Let's say this is the entire goal. Okay, this is the entire goal of our system.
Now, to achieve this goal, we have to define a set of tasks. Okay, the let's say first task, what it would be so let's say this particular system will first of all generate a SE, right?
The first of all, we have to generate a SC topic. So system generate a relevant uh UPSC style as a topic and uh present in a
present it to us to the student. Let's say uh you are giving UPSC exam that time. Let's say the this particular SC topic you have to prepare, okay. Then you have to collect the SE from the student.
So student write and submits the SE based on the generated topics.
Okay, you will try to collect that after collecting uh your system will evaluate the SE.
Okay, parallel evaluation block because here we will be evaluating based on the analysis, language quality, clarity of thought.
So, all of the checks we are doing, all of the evaluation checks we are doing based on the language, based on the um.
Language quality, then analysis, okay. Clarity of thought, we are checking each and everything.
Okay, so after getting the evaluation report, we are aggregating the results. Let's say the combine the three scores and generate the total scores.
let's say we got the three scores all together, then we combined them and we got one average score and we match with the threshold. Now, here there is another task you can see conditional routing.
So, based on the total score, either you will accept that particular SC, otherwise, you will give the feedback. Let's say again you have to update this particular SE.
Okay, so then you can see we are uh our next task is the give feedback based on the uh conditional routing that means aggregating results.
We are giving the feedback, and there is another option we have kept. Let's see if user wants to uh give the revision version of that particular SE, they will be able to do that.
Then at the last, we'll try to show the success uh message to the um student. Okay, if your if their SE is good, then we'll try to congratulate them. Okay, so this is the entire let's say problem.
Now, if I want to if I want to represent uh with the help of language, so first of all, we have to make it as a graph, okay.
I think you know language um make every let's say problem statement as a graph as a workflow, okay. So basically it will represent as a graph.
After representing as a graph, then what it will do, it will try to uh take all of this task as a node, okay. All of the task as a node, then it will connect the edges.
Let's say after uh which node another node would be executed. Okay, this particular connection will be do doing with the help of edges. So for this, I have already prepared a graph. Let me show you.
Let's say this is our line graph graph we have prepared. Okay, so you can see whatever problem statement I have showed you here. So I have just represent as a graph.
First of all, it will generate a topic. So this is the first you can see. This is the first
first task, right? Let me just right here. This is the first task,
okay. Because we broken down our entire goal as a task and generate topic was one of the task and this task we represented as a node,
okay. This is called actually node, each and every block is a node here, okay. Now, this is another task as you can see.
Write as write as it means you can also let's say take the S from the student, okay. User will upload that, student will upload that, then after uploading, you are doing the evaluation here, okay.
So this this evaluation is also another task, another node. So this is also node, this is this is also node, this is another node, this another node, this another node.
So here we are let's say evaluating with the with respect to the clarity of thought, depth of analysis, language. Then we are getting some kinds of score here, okay.
Let's say we are getting some kinds of score. Let's say this this one is giving you 9.5, this one is given you 9.8, this one is given you 8.5.
Okay, based on that, we are doing the final evaluation, we are aggregating the results. Let's say our threshold is 9.5 and after combining all of these, we are getting uh 9.5 or greater than 9.5.
Then that time, what I will do, I'll just try to simply give the success message to these students. Okay, let's say I will congratulate them, otherwise, I will give the feedback.
Let's say this is another
another node. In this particular node, I'll give the feedback. So, in the feedback itself, I'll tell what to update, otherwise, they can also resubmit that particular essay to me.
Okay, so this is the entire representation, and in the representation itself you can see this is the entire graph. Okay, this is the entire line graph graph, and each of the tasks is a node.
Okay, each of the tasks is a node, and the connection you can see this particular connection. This is called edge. Okay, this edge is represents after generate topics.
Write as you will execute after write as a this evaluation. let's say nodes will execute after evaluation. This final evaluator node will execute.
Okay, then either it will go to this access nodes, either it will go to the feedback nodes. Okay, this is called edges, this is called connection.
Okay, so if you understand this thing, guys, it would be very easy for you to create any kinds of line graph graph for you, okay? And you can represent any kinds of problem statement in a graph.
Okay, I hope you're clear, guys.
So, guys, now we'll be discussing about the next line Graph component, which is state. So, I think you know already about this state.
I have given you the state overview in my previous video, but let's try to understand. So, as you can see in line graph state, it is the shared memory that follows through your workflows, it holds all
the data being passed between nodes as you graph runs, okay. As your graph runs, so as you can see, this is how your state looks like so this is a kinds of
like python object, okay. Python are kinds of dictionary object, it is having the key value key and value pair.
Either you can create this with the help of Pydentic, okay, Pydentic uh library with uh inside Python, either you can also create it as a type dict,
okay. Type dict, both you can use to define this particular state memory.
So I think you know that to run a lm workflow, let's say this is our complete lm workflow, we need this kinds of state that means some metadata informations
because each of the nodes will generate some kinds of output, and that particular output will take uh taken by another nodes.
Okay, let's say this generate topic will generate some kinds of topic, okay. Topic name.
So this topic name will go to the next node, which is this write assay because on top of that your um essay will be written, right?
So that means whatever topic this particular node is generating, this should be stored in the state memory,
and the next node, let's say this write assay, uh will take that particular topic and it will write that content as well.
So after writing this content, this content would be also saved in the state memory. So you can see there is another section called AC text topic, okay.
Then we are evaluating the scores, and all of these uh scores would be saved in this uh this uh uh state memory. You can see they have the score language score clarity score.
So after this score, you will perform the final evaluation, okay? So total score would be also saved, then you will be giving the feedback.
This feedback would be also saved, then evaluation round it will also save.
Okay, so that means to execute the entire nodes to execute the entire workflow, you need this particular state, and this state is a shared, okay. It's a shared memory, as you can see.
It's a shared memory. Shared memory means each of the nodes will take this particular state as an input. Okay, each each of the node will take this particular state as an input, all of the node, okay.
All of the node will take this particular state, and after taking it, once it will generate some output, this output will be instantly updated in that particular state.
Okay, that's why this state is mutable as well. Okay, mutable mutable means you can change it anytime, and after
every execution, this state would be saved, okay? Because this is completely dynamic, and this is required, guys.
Okay, without that, actually, you can't create any kinds of agent application inside line graph. Okay, this state is required.
So, yes, I think you have understood, and whenever we'll try to create these kinds of
application, definite will define this state at the very beginning. Either we can use Pydentic, either we can use type dict for that, okay, and we'll try to define this state.
And for your problem statement, you have to define the state like what are the variables you will be keeping here, but data you you uh feel like okay, this should be updated to run your
intelligence. Okay, this thing we'll try to define at the very beginning.
Now let's try to understand the next component of line Graph, which is reducer. So, what is reducer exactly?
so reducer in the line Graph defines how updates from nodes are applied to the shared state.
Each key in the state can have its own reducer, which determines whether new data replaces, merges, or adds to the existing value.
So if you see this reducer is very close to your state, okay, this is very close to the state. That means whenever you are defining the state, that time reducer will come to the picture.
Okay, so let me give you one example. see, as of now, what we are doing let's say whatever we are getting the data from each and every nodes we are directly updating in the state memory.
Okay, you know that and this state is a shared uh shared uh actually memory, and it is accessible to all of the nodes here.
Let's say these nodes will also take this state, these nodes will also take this state. Okay, all of the nodes will take this state and it will update in real time.
That means every time the value you are changing here, it is replacing. Okay, let's say previously you you generated a topic, let's say topic A.
So again, whenever you will second time execute that, this topic will replace. That means the previous topic will be removed. Okay, that that means we are replacing the value.
That's how depth is code, language score, clarity score, as it as it takes. Okay, so all of the parameter you are changing every time and your previous information you are losing.
But let's say sometimes let me give you first of all one example. Let's say you are creating an application, okay. You are uh you are building an application.
That application, let's say takes two number. So let me just give you the workflow, let's say
takes two numbers A and B. After that, it performs the sum operation, okay. Then whatever sum you get, okay, it performs the multiply operation with three. Okay, then it shows the result
result. Let's say this is your application. Now, in this application, what would be the state if you consider state? So state would be first of all the first number,
first number
okay. First number should be state, then second number,
then the result.
Okay, so this this is this is your state. So what will happen?
Let's say you are giving two numbers, first number is five, second number is six, and if you do the sum operation, what would be the result? It would be eleven. Okay, eleven.
But if you see you are multiplying by three, okay. If you multiply by three, so what will happen? This result will be replaced. That means previously it was
previously it was 11. Now I'll rub this 11. Initially, after summing the result is 11. Now you have to multiply by 3. So if you multiply by 3, that means this 11 will be replaced by 33.
Okay, that means this 11 is not there anymore. Okay, this is change completely, but in some application, let's say uh let me give you another example. I will
rub this now. Let's see, you are creating a chat bot. You are creating a chat bot.
In the chat bot, what you are doing, you are doing the conversation to the AI, your conversation to the application. Let's say this is your app,
okay. This is your app, and you are doing the conversation. So in this application, what would be the state?
State it would be the let's say message, the message we are sending or message we are getting from the
application. So initially, let's say you have given I.
I am bhappe.
Okay, let's say this is your message. So this message would be saved here. Let's say hi.
Okay, now let's say second time you have given
I like
football.
Okay, now this message will be replaced. Okay, let's say this this will be removed and it will replace by I like.
Okay, football.
Now, if you ask what is my name, so that time
let's say your nodes won't be able to uh get get your name because this this name is already removed okay from the state memory. Now you only have I like football. Okay, this is the problem.
So in this case, if you are using only state without reducer, that time it will replace that. But if you are using reducer, okay, inside reducer you can define whether you have to
okay, you have to replace the data or merge the data or add the data. So in this case, maybe we can add the data. So that means my previous message would be also there. Let's say I am Bappi.
Okay, after giving a comma, maybe I can add the second message. That's how continuously all of the masses would be saved here.
Either you can merge, either you can replace everything can be defined with the help of this reducer.
Okay, so that means the reducer in line graph defines how updates from nodes are applied to the shared state.
Okay, that means whenever you are creating the state, that time you can define all of the state data you are preparing, right?
Whether it should be addable, it should be mergeable or it should be replaceable. Okay, so in this case, let's say we have defined this particular state.
So in the feedback section, you can see we have given add. Add means instead of let's say replacing the feedback, it will continuously add. Let's say this is our example I showed you.
So in this example, let's say the feedback we are getting. So this feedback should be definitely saved in the state memory.
So next time, whenever it is executing, okay, it will see that particular feedback, the previous feedback, then it will give the new feedback. Otherwise, what will happen?
The same feedback continuously it might give, right? So that's why it should be addable. Okay, it should be addable inside state memory.
So this is the work of reducer, and definitely we'll also learn by a project, okay.
in this particular playlist, there I'll try to use this reducer concept as well with the state, so there this part would be more clear. So I think, guys, now you got it. What is the reducer?
So, reducer only can be used whenever you are using this state concept inside the line graph, okay? Now I think it is clear.
So, guys, now we'll be understanding the last concept of this line graph, which is line graph execution model. So, what is this line graph execution model means?
model means that means the way it is executing the graph because I think you know line graph internally defines your problem statement as a graph,
it creates the nodes, then it creates the edges. Okay, that's how basically it executes everything. So, what is the execution process of this particular graph?
Okay, this is called actually execution model. So, line graph internally follows one amazing execution model strategy, which is let me show you,
which is actually Google uh Pragel. Okay, Pragel. So, what is Google Pragel? Google Pragel is a system for large scale graph processing. so basically they have published this particular research long
long ago. That time actually they showed if you are having a large scale graph, okay. That time, how it can be processed.
Okay, so internally Langgraph uses the same technique for executing these kinds of graph
because if you see the lang graph uh actually graph, whenever you are creating very big workflow, that time this graph would be also big, and to process this,
to execute this, you have to follow that Pragel uh strategy. Okay, now this is the strategy, guys. As you can see, here I have already defined all of the execution process.
So, first of all, what happens? if you see here, first of all, it defines the graph. Okay, so whenever you are giving any problem statement, it will define the graph.
So, whenever it will define the graph, first of all, it will define the state schema that I uh I showed you uh showed you about the schema, right?
state schema, either you can do it with the help of uh pydentic, either with the type dict.
Okay, you can you you just need to define the state schema after that you have to prepare the node and edges, okay. So this node and this edge connection, okay. So fun and what is node actually?
This node is nothing but it's a simple Python function, okay? It's a Python function only.
If you can write a Python function, if you can write a Python code, you can just define any kinds of node, okay?
Because each of the nodes is responsible for a specific task, and this task you are solving inside this Python function only. Okay, that's it. And what is edges? Which node connects to which okay?
That means this particular edges will be connecting to another nodes okay. Like the execution flow, like after this node, which node would be executed.
So once you have defined this particular graph, then next step you will do the compilation. So here we'll do the compile compile operation. Compile means let's say you have created a graph.
Let's say this is your graph, okay. This is your graph, and this is the edge connection. And let's say you created another node, but this node doesn't have any kinds of connection.
Okay, so after doing the compilation, you will be able to understand okay, this node doesn't have any kinds of connection, that means there's some problem with the graph, okay.
Otherwise, what will happen? Our entire agentic system will be okay, terminated.
So that's why after defining the graph, we have to the compilation to check the graph structure and prepared prepares for the execution.
Okay, then this uh third thing we'll be doing invocation operation.
So, invocation operation that means whatever first node we have prepared, we'll try to do the invoke operation with our initial state.
The state we are preparing will try to pass to this uh pass to this initial actually nodes, and this initial nodes, what it will do, it will take this
state and it will execute and it will generate some kinds of output, and this output would be also updated in the state.
Okay, so once it has updated to the state, then this state will go to the another function, okay. Another another nodes, and this node would be also initialized that that is activated.
Okay, so after giving this initial state, this node would be activated, and once you get some kinds of output from this node, then it will pass to the next one,
the next one would be activated. Okay, so this is called actually invocation. Okay, you can see Langgraph sends the initial state as a message to the entity of nodes, okay.
Then once it gets this particular let's say
output and whenever it activates, okay, we call it as a super step begins.
Okay, execution process uh in rounds that means uh it's not like that manually you have to uh I mean initiate uh and invoke all of the nodes one by one.
So once you invoke the first one, okay, the remaining one will be automatically executed because it is getting the output, and after getting the output,
this will go to the input to the next node, and next note would be uh activated. Okay, this is called actually super begins, super step begins. Okay, like Langgraph called it as a super step begins.
That means all of the nodes would be activated that time. That means you can see message spacing and node activation.
The messages are passed to the downstream nodes via edges, so that means whatever output you are getting from the first node, it will go via this edges to the second node,
then it will be activating one by one. Okay, so this is called super step begins.
Okay, and with the help of that, it apart from the message parsing and node activation, and the last step, which is nothing but uh nothing but the halting conditions,
so execution stop when all no nodes are activate and no messages are in transit.
That means if all of the node has been activated and no messages are uh let's say in transit that time, this particular condition would be stop and your graph would be also
stop, yeah. So this is called actually the spray a system for large scale graph execution process and language follow the same strategy whenever they execute their graph.
Okay, so yes, guys, I think you have understood all of the concept about the uh langu graph, all of the component about the languagh.
Now it would be easy for you to code in language whenever we'll write try to write the code whenever we'll create the agents.
That time you won't be having any kinds of confusion, you won't be having any kinds of problem related each of the components we have discussed.
So, guys, so far we have discussed about the theoretical aspect of agentic AI, as well as I have already given you the in-depth understanding about the
uh Langgraph components and all. Now it's time to start the practical exploration. So, from this video onward, guys, will be working on the practical part of the line graph.
So, first of all, we'll be starting with the very basic workflow inside line graph which is sequential workflow. I think I have already told you about that.
First, actually, workflow the workflow name is sequential workflow. Okay, sequential means this will run
in a step-by-step let's say manner, okay. This is called sequential sequential workflow, so it doesn't have any kinds of looping, it doesn't have any kinds of conditional branching, okay?
It doesn't have anything, only uh it will be uh working as a sequence manner. Uh so we call it as a sequential workflow, okay.
So for this guys, uh, first of all, uh we'll be installing the Langgraph okay in the inside our system. So to install the Lang Graph, guys, you can visit this Lang Graph documentation.
So there uh you will be getting uh all kinds of actually tutorial how to install, okay, how to create your fast agent, so each and everything they have already given.
So, see if you want to install this line graph, you can use the pip command, either you can use UV, okay. So let's use uh peep as of now.
Maybe in future I will also show you how to use the UV package manager as well. So you just need to run pip install line graph. So this line graph would be installed inside your system.
So for this, let's open up our local folder, and here I'm going to just open up my Visual Code Studio
and I will also open up my terminal here.
Okay, so the first thing, guys, uh here I'm going to create a file called
readme.md.
Inside that I'm going to mention all of the command you need to execute to install this line graph to create your virtual environment and everything.
So if you want to create the virtual environment, you have to execute this command called conduct create
hype n.
Okay, then you can give the name of the environment. I will give let's say lang
graph
test, okay.
Python
you can specify the python version, python is equal to 3.11 and hyphen y.
Okay, so this is the command. First of all, you have to execute this command to create a virtual environment, then you will be installing this language.
Okay, now you have to activate this environment after that. You will be installing the
requirements.txt.
Okay, so these are the command guys. You have to follow first of all. So let's create this requirement.txt here.
So inside that let's mention our line graph
package,
okay. line graph. So apart from language, uh, you need to install some other library as well, like you need this Langchain Open AI.
Okay, so we are using this Langchain OpenAI because uh I'll be using my open AI large language model, but if you want, you can also use any other model
from any other provider. Let's say you can use open router, you can use uh grok API, okay. You can use Gemini API, anything you can use, it's completely up to you.
now it's a very easy things you just need to change this model provide at that time, okay? So with me, I am having my open API key, that's why I'll be using this one.
Okay, and if you want to use OpenAI API, so that time you have to install this Langchin OpenAI because I told you Langgraph uh doesn't work actually independently
internally, it is uses Langchen, okay, and for all the model uh let's say loading, creating the prompt template, we need the Langchen, okay.
Still Langchen is required, then uh I also need python dot enb for the environment management.
Okay, now guys, uh, you have to install this requirement.txt file, but before that, I told you you have to create the environment.
So try to copy the first command and execute from your terminal. So this will create the environment okay for you. But for me, this environment is already available. I will activate the environment.
So conta activate line graph test.
Yeah, so you can see this is already available. But if you don't have just try to create it first of all, then just execute this requirement command, it will install everything.
So for me, it is already satisfied because I installed previously.
Okay, now once it is done, now what I'm going to do, guys, let me just tell you about the sequential workflow.
Okay, what is the workflow I will be creating here? See, here I'm going to create a very simple workflow without using any kinds of LLM.
I'll also show you how to use LLM how to create the LLM workflow as well, don't worry.
But this is our first workflow we are creating inside Langgraph, and we don't know how to code inside Langgraph, right?
So to understand the workflow, first of all, we'll be creating a very simple workflow without using any kinds of LLM. Then I'm also going to show you how to use the LLM as well.
Okay, so guys, uh now let's see uh what workflow we'll be creating first of all.
So here you can see we'll be creating a sequential workflow, and the workflow is temperature conversion workflow.
Okay, so here it doesn't have any kinds of LLM as you can see. This is a simple workflow we have created without using any kinds of LLM.
So basically, this workflow, what it will do, it will
convert actually Celsius temperature to Fahrenheit. Okay, this is the only work this workflow will do, and if we convert this workflow in a graph, so this will look like that.
So, as you can see, we have taken the start node, then convert temperature node and the end node.
So start and end would be common for all the workflow you'll be creating with the help of this Langgraph.
This is a dummy nodes you can say because Langgraph understands okay, workflow starts from here and it it uh ends actually here, okay,
and basically it takes the input
to the like other nodes as well. And this will also have a state, right? State is a shared memory, and this is a mutable uh let's say object.
You can create this state with the help of uh pyden tick, either you can use type dict, okay. Anything you can use it.
So basically, this state I have to share to all of the node so that it can take the data and it can update the data as well in real time.
So you can see in this particular workflow, the only function I have to write this conversion function, temperature conversion function.
So user will give Celsius temperature and I'll try to convert it to the Fahrenheit, then this this Fahrenheit output would be shows uh shows as a so
shows as an output. Okay, so you can see for this we have create we have taken a node convert temperature, and this node would be a simple Python function.
In that particular Python function, what I will do, I'll just try to I'll just try to write
the code related conversion, temperature conversion, and whatever output we'll try to get, we'll try to update in this particular state. So here in this particular variable we'll try to update that.
Let's say whatever temperature user will give. This is in Celsius, so this will save inside this particular state uh let's object, and whatever I'll try to convert, right?
Uh in the Fahrenheit, this one I'll try to save it here, okay. Then whenever I'll try to show the output, so from here I'll try to read and I'll show the output here.
So this is a simple workflow, guys.
we have to create, and this state is a shared memory, so this will go to the all of the uh all of the nodes, okay, one by one, and the complete you can see this diagram,
this workflow. This is called actually graph. Okay, I hope you cleared. Now let's try to code inside line graph. So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to open up my
so let's create a file here.
I'm going to create a file.
I'm going to name it as
One temperature conversion workflow dot ipynb.
Okay, so here I have taken the Jupyter notebook file, guys, because here I'm not creating any kinds of end-to-end project, I'm just explaining the concept.
Uh, that's why I think this notebook uh format would be uh great fit for that because I will also show you the uh workflow in a diagram, okay.
And this diagram I can't uh I can't actually show you inside py file, that's why I have taken this dot ipynv file notebook file. So let's select our environment line graph test, yeah.
So, first of all, what you have to do, guys, you have to import some library.
So, here let me comment.
First of all, you have to import
some library, okay? So you have to import uh this line graph.
So from line graph
dot graph,
You have to import state graph, okay. You have to import state graph if you check the documentation as well.
So here also they are doing the same thing from line graph, they're importing state graph, then start and end. Okay, this is a dummy nodes I already told you.
This will be common for all the workflow you'll be creating with the help of this line graph.
Okay, so let's try to import them.
So state graph, then I need start,
I need start,
then I need
end.
So here state graph is the function with the help of that. We create the graph, okay. Entire graph it will be creating basically.
Uh this helps to create the graph as well as uh to add the state uh inside our graph, okay. Now let me import them.
Yeah, so import is successful. Uh that means we have already installed this line graph and we are able to import uh everything, okay. Then I also need to import this type dict from typing.
So from typing.
So
first of all, I'm going to show you how we can create the state with the help of this type dict, uh, type dict actually module from Python.
Then later on, I'm also going to show you how we can create this state with the help of Pydentic.
Okay, Pydentic is another Python framework with the help of that. You can also create the state.
So let's import
type dict.
This one.
Now let me import all of them.
Now, the first thing, guys, I have to uh initialize the state uh state object. Okay, state is important. Uh without state, actually, we can't create the graph.
Then after creating the state, uh we'll be creating the entire graph. First of all, we'll be creating the nodes, all the nodes, then after that, uh we'll be uh we'll be creating the edges as well.
Okay, so this is called edges. Edges means this is the connection. Let's after uh which node uh which node would be executed.
Okay, this is the connection. So this edges should be also created, okay. And if we create all of them, uh this will be uh this will become a graph. Okay, so now let's try to define the state here.
Uh so here maybe I can comment,
define
state.
So for this problem, I told you state would be two state, okay. one is temperature Celsius and temperature Fahrenheit.
So let's try to define that.
So for this, I'll write a class
okay. I'll write a class.
I'm going to name this class as a temperature.
State
okay, and I'm going to inherit this class with this type dict uh function we have imported okay
now basically you are telling this class
like this class right now can store any kinds of data as a key value pair.
Okay, now the first key should be the temperature
temp Celsius,
okay. And you can mention the data type as well.
What should be the data type for this particular uh
variable? So basically, it uh Celsius should be in a float uh data type. I think you know that it can't be integer, it should be float, that's why I told it is a float, okay. Float data type.
Then you have to write another
variable called temperature Fahrenheit. So this should be also a float type data, okay. So this will become our state, okay.
This will become our state, and this state we'll be using inside our nodes, okay. All of the nodes will be creating, yeah.
Now this state is also ready. Now let's work on this graph.
So here, what I'm going to do,
uh, here let's say
I'm going to comment,
define
okay. Define and
graph. I think you know, after defining the graph, you have to compile. I told you the graph execution process, right?
In my previous video as well.
So to define the graph, I told you first of all, you have to use the state graph
function, you have to create an object of that.
So let's
create an object called graph, then I'm going to initialize state graph, and inside that you have to pass the state. The state you have created, this is the state temperature state.
Okay, so basically, this will take the state.
Now, see what is happening if you're using the state graph object, right?
State graph functionality, and if you're passing the state inside that, so basically this particular function will try to provide the state to all of the nodes, okay? Automatically, one by one.
You don't need to manually provide that, okay. So this is the main benefit here. So that's why we're using the state graph.
State graph basically takes this state object and it provides to all of the nodes, okay? One by one. Now
we have defined our graph here.
So this is called definition
of the graph, define your graph
define your graph. Now, next I have to
add the nodes
nodes to your graph
to the graph. So to add the nodes, guys, you just need to write graph dot add nodes,
Add nodes, then you have to provide the nodes name, okay. nodes name at the very first time you have to give the nodes name. Let's say if you see my nodes here, okay.
If you see my nodes here, so
I have only one node, which is this convert temperature, right?
I have only one node which is convert temperature. Now you can ask me start and edge ends is also a node, right? But this is a dummy node. This thing you don't need to create it separately, okay.
So whenever you are defining the edges, okay, that time you will mention that let's say after start, after start
this convert temperature node would be connected. Okay, this is called actually connection, that's why we call it as a like dummy nodes. We don't need to create separately here, okay.
We don't need to add separately here. So by default, your line graph adds that, and we just need to we just need to connect this particular nodes to our actual nodes, okay. This is the funda here.
Now let me first of all create none. I'm going to explain okay how it works. So, first of all, here I have to add our nodes. So here I only have one nodes, which is convert temperature.
So maybe I can just give a name. I will give let's say convert,
okay. Convert
temp. You can give any name, it's up to you, but make sure uh the name you are giving here, the same name you use for creating that particular function.
Okay, now this will take that convert temperature function object.
Okay, this will take this convert temperature function object, and I told you every node takes a function, and this function is nothing but it's a Python simple function.
Okay, now let's try to create this convert temperature function individually here. So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to simply
come here.
So, basically, this is our first node.
now let's write the function. So def convert temperature.
So this will take a state.
Okay. This will take a state.
What is this state? This temperature state.
And this will return also the state. I told you
every time this state would be the input, and each and every nodes will return some kinds of output. This output should be also state. Okay, the updated state. So that's why I have to
I have to give this
blueprint that this function takes uh state of uh state as an input and it also returns the state okay, this temperature state only.
So that's how you can give the blueprint of a function, okay. Now inside that, first of all, I'll take the Celsius data, whatever data user will provide.
So here I'll just write Celsius
Celsius okay, is equal to this Celsius would be available inside state, okay.
So we are calling state and we are extracting the Celsius only because this is a dictionary right now, and you know how to work with the dictionary, right?
so we are working in a same, then after that, we'll try to convert. Uh we'll try to convert this to the Fahrenheit. So I've already written the code, let me show you.
So here we are converting to the Fahrenheit, okay. You can see Celsius to Fahrenheit, and if you want to see how to convert
Celsius to Fahrenheit, you can go to Google
you can search here.
So you will see the formula, okay. So this is the formula. So we are replicating the same formula here.
You can see we are replicating the same formula. We are first of all multiplying the Celsius
with 9 out of 5, then we are adding 32 with that. So once we get this Fahrenheit, we have to also
we have to also update the state memory, right? We have to also update the state memory because we have taken a variable called temperature Fahrenheit.
Now, whatever Fahrenheit we got, we have to update inside this particular state, right? So for this,
that's how we can update because this is a dictionary, right? This is dictionary.
So I'm just adding this particular new value to this variable to this key, right?
So here we're using round function because if it is a float type data, so after point there would be too many number but I'm not taking too
many number I'm only taking last two digit okay after after the point. Now, once it is done, I'm going to simply return this state.
So return this state, okay.
That's it. So this is our simple Python function we have created.
Okay, now this function can convert any kinds of Celsius data to Fahrenheit, and we are updating the state here, okay. That's it.
Now, this particular function will object will come here.
So that's how guys we have created our first node.
We have added our first node now. See this node has added okay. Now you have to create this edges, okay. You have to create it create this edges that that means the connection, the flow of execution.
So for this, let's do that.
So here I'm going to comment, add
edges
to the graph.
So, first of all, you have to
add the first edges now. See this start node will come here, okay. Now see.
So here I'll just write start and convert them.
Just try to see this graph. See now I'm telling this start node would be connected to the convert tem.
Okay, that means this is the connection we are making right now because from here it will start and it will go go to the convert temperature.
See, here we're doing start to convert temperature.
Okay, now I will add the second graph.
Sorry, second edge, add edge. Now convert them to end. Now you can see.
so basically, let me just show you. See, first of all, we connect it here, right?
That means this connection, this connection we have built.
Start to convert temperature. Now convert temperature to end.
Okay, and that means this particular edge we are getting right now.
This edge is already created. Start to convert them now. Convert them to end, okay. Particular this this edge we are getting
this edge is already created.
Now we are doing it here, so you can see convert them to end.
Okay, I hope you clear, guys. Now, once this is done, then you will be compiling the graph.
So compile the graph.
So you just need to write
uh
graph.compile
okay, and this returns you the workflow.
So maybe I can store inside a variable.
Okay, now let's compile.
So compilation is also done.
Now we'll simply execute the graph.
Execute the graph.
Now
guys, we'll try to execute the graph.
So to execute the graph, uh first of all, you have to take the initial state
that means the input, which is the
Celsius, okay, Celsius
temperature. So here what I can do, I can
create a variable. I'm going to name it as
you can also call it as input state or initial state, okay.
It's up to you, but I've named it as initial state because this this will become my initial state, okay. The first state, which is nothing but the uh temperature Celsius, right?
So initial state, so temperature Celsius, I'm giving let's say 28.5.
Now this thing will try to provide to the workflow.
So I have created my workflow
workflow dot invoke. Now you can perform the invoke operation because this is a line graph object. Inside that I'm going to pass my initial state, and this will return you the final state.
Okay, final state that means the output,
final state, and this final state I'm going to simply print it here,
okay.
Done now. Let's see whether it is working or not. Now, see if I execute now. See, initially we have given 28.5. This is the Celsius temperature.
Now the final state is
temperature finite 83.3.
Okay, you can also try with
Google.
Let's see if I am giving Celsius now. See, Celsius is 28.5 and you are getting 83.3.
You can see 83.3, that means it's working fine, right? So we are able to execute our first graph, guys.
Okay, we are able to create our first graph, and this is completely working fine.
See, there is no problem now. If you want to see this graph as a uh image, you can also do That that means you can visualize this particular graph.
This is very interesting things I found in Langgraph.
So let me just comment here, Visualize
graph.
So I found this code inside this Langgraph documentation.
Yeah, so here we are using this iPython display and we are importing this image function. Inside that, we are just giving workflow.getgraph.
Okay, basically, this will get the graph, and we are drawing this particular graph as a mermaid png. Okay, so mermaid is a kinds of you can talk about it's a flowchart okay.
Flowchart style, you can search on Google mermaid flowchart, or simply search for mermaid. You will see that okay, mermaid flowchart.
Yeah, see, so this will give you this kinds of flowchart. Okay, now let me show you.
If I execute,
see guys, you are getting the flowchart now. See this flowchart and this flowchart, just try to tell me whether you are able to see this is same or not.
Okay, this is same, right? So you can see start, then it is going to the convert temperature.
Then it is giving you the final output that means the end nodes, okay? Amazing.
So, guys, congratulations. We have created our first workflow, first line graph graph, and this is completely working fine.
So, guys, now what we'll do, we'll just try to update the workflow we have created. Let's say this is our workflow.
so here we are only converting the temperature to the Fahrenheit. Now, what I have done, I created another workflow. So, this is the similar workflow, only I have added a new node here.
You can see so the node name is label weather. So, what this label weather will do, let's say the Fahrenheit temperature we are getting, uh, we'll just try to label that.
Label means let's say if this Fahrenheit temperature is less than 50, that time weather starters is cold.
Okay, if let's say Fahrenheit temperature is it is less than equal 50 and less than equal 77, that time it is mild, okay.
If it is less than 95, then that time it is hot, and if it is not all of them, that means it is extreme heat. Okay, so this kinds of labeling I want to do.
So for this, I have created another node here. I'll I'll be writing another node here. This particular node will try to
try to figure out the weather status. Okay, it will try to figure out the weather status, whether the weather is hot, cold, mild, okay, or extreme hot, etc. Right, and to create this particular
graph, guys. I need another state called weather status because this nodes will return the label, right? Whether it is hot, cold, mild, or anything.
So this particular data I have to also save in the state that's why I have taken another variable called weather status here, but previously this was missing here. Okay, now let's try to update this.
So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to open up my code again. So, see here I'll add another nodes, okay. I'll add another nodes here.
Yeah,
let's say the node name is
uh label weather, okay, and it will take a function Python function called label weather. So now let's write this function. So after this function, maybe I can write it here.
So def label weather. So this will take this state as an input,
okay, and it will also return this state as an output.
Okay, so already I got the suggestion code from my
from my co-pilot, but let me show you the code I have written.
So this is the code. Okay, now let me also
comment here.
Let's say this is for label
weather
condition.
This is our second note.
Okay, so now what is what we are doing the Fahrenheit temperature we are getting, we're taking it from the state, okay.
We are pulling the Fahrenheit from the state instead of Celsius, because I want to check with respect to the Fahrenheit. Okay, I want to check with respect to Fahrenheit.
You can also do it with the help of Celsius as well, Celsius temperature as well. You can also label that, but I want to do it with the help of Fahrenheit.
I want to I want to only show you the output we are getting, whether we can use it inside this particular node or not. Okay, that's why I'm using this temperature
finite. Then after that, I'm checking if finite is less than 50. That time uh weather starters should be cold. We are updating this
state, okay. There should be another variable called weather starters, and right now this starter should be hot, cold, mild. So I can consider this should be a string type data.
Okay, now let me execute this one. Yeah, now you can see this weather starter should be cold if it is less than and equal 50 or less than 73 77.
That time the weather starter should be mild if it is less than 77 and less than 95, this should be hot, otherwise, it should be extreme heat. Okay, so this is our
this is our logic we have written inside this label weather function, and we are itering the state. Okay, now let me execute.
Now, what I'm going to do, just execute from the beginning one one more time just to show you the output.
So the node add is done. Now we'll try to add the edges. Okay, now we'll add the edges that means after convert temperature, this will go to the label weather. Okay, so here I'm going to write
See start start convert temperature. Okay, that means this part is done now. I have to work on this part convert temperature to level weather. So here I have to write
convert temperature to level weather. Okay, now label weather to end. Now here I just need to write right
label weather to end. Okay, now I think you have understood this particular edge connection.
Okay, so this is like very amazing, right? And if you understand this edge connection, just trust me, you can create any kinds of workflow inside Langgraph.
Okay, that's why I'm showing you this easy workflow at the very beginning. Now, once it is done, now let's try to compile the graph again. Then I will
execute
the graph. This only takes the temperature Celsius input.
So you can see temperature Celsius this 28.5, we are getting the Fahrenheit, and based on the Fahrenheit result, we are seeing that weather status is hot right now. You can check if it is 83, right?
83, that means here this condition is missing here. Okay, that means this particular condition is hot right now.
Okay, now if I visualize this graph, now see another node is added which is level weather. Now this uh this graph and this graph I think you can match.
Okay, great guys.
So yes, this was the first sequential sequential actually workflow we have created without using any kinds of large language model.
So now I'm going to show you how we can create sequential workflow with the help of large language model as well.
So guys, now we'll be creating uh LLM workflow. previously, the workflow I showed you. this workflow I have created. This is a non LLM based workflow. here I'm not using any kinds of LLM, okay.
with the help of simple Python function, simple Python logic, I was handling everything. Now let's say you want to use LLM, okay. LLM inside the workflow. So, how to create the LLM workflow for that?
Let's try to understand and see here our main goal is to learn the Langgraph uh like workflow creation. The problem statement I am taking it might be very simple.
you can think about okay, this this thing I can create with the help of simple Python function only, but why we are writing that much line of code, okay?
So, our intention is to learn the line graph workflow, okay. How we can use the line graph, how we can create the workflow, how we can create the node edges, okay, each and everything.
This idea I'm giving you. Okay, so problem statement doesn't matter, you can use any kinds of problem statement.
So, after learning this simple concept, so later on, whenever we'll be creating the actual agents or big project, so this concept will help us a lot, right?
So that's why we are um uh explaining this concept with the help of simple workflow. Now, here I'm going to take another um very simple workflow, guys. Uh, for the LM workflow.
So, here what I'm going to do uh here, this is the uh workflow, this is the graph you can see. So, basically, this will have the start and end nodes definitely because this is common.
So, the only one nodes I will be creating here the LM QA nodes. Okay, so LM QA means what it will perform.
So, basically, user will give some of the question and this LM will answer that particular question and this will return you the answer.
Only this simple operation will be doing, okay, in this particular workflow. So, for this, so what should be the state?
The state should be definitely the question, whatever question user is giving, and whatever answer we are getting from the LLM, this should be another
state, okay. So, this state should be passed to all of the nodes, and it will real-time update that and our uh uh workflow would be ended. So, this is the simple uh graph, guys.
Now let's try to implement this graph with the help of line Graph. So, for this, I have already prepared a notebook as you can see simple key way lm workflow. So, let me open it up and to run this
code, guys, you need this.enb file because in the.nb I have mentioned my open AI API key because here we are using large language model and I'm using
OpenAI large language model. But if you want to use any other large language model, you can use it completely fine for this. You can change the API key here. So, this is the code, guys.
This is the notebook I have prepared. Now, this is this looks same as per your previous notebook, only the things I have added the LLM functionality here.
Now, first of all, you have to import some necessary library. So, see, you can see we are importing the same state graph start ends from the Langgraph graph.
Then one additional package we are importing LangChen underscore PNI chat open I.
I told you if I want to use any kinds of let's say large language model or whatever, I have to still use Langchen because Langgraph doesn't have
direct functionality, so that functionality can load any kinds of LLM. Okay, so it has to use this Langchain to load the large language model.
So here one more thing you are also learning how we can use Langchen along with the Langgraph. Okay, so this is the concept.
So we are importing chat open a let's see if you are using any other other provider. If you're using rock or open router, inside LangChen it is available. You simply you can open it up.
Then we are also importing type dict just to create the state and the load env just to load our environment variable.
Now the first step we are loading the environment variable this.env for this we are calling this load env. So if it is returns to, okay, first of all, I have to import this. Now I'll execute.
Now if it if it returns to, that means this in env file is present, and inside that we have the uh key, right? It has loaded successfully. Now we'll try to define the large language model.
Okay, so here we are creating a model object and we are calling the chat open AI. So by default, I think it loads a model. Okay, uh, I think GPT 3 5 turbo model it will load.
You can also change the model parameter if you want to use any other model like GPT 5 or 4, you can easily do that. But I will take the default model, it's completely fine for me.
Okay, so I got my model object now. Here you can change with any model object. Either you are using rock, uh, either you can using open router, Gemini, anything you can use.
Now we have to create this state, okay. This state we have to create, and I told you to create this workflow. I need uh this these two state question and answer.
So this thing I will be creating right now. You can see I have written a class, I named it as llm state, and again I'm inheriting with the help of type dict.
Now we can store the data as a key value pair.
Now, the first state you can see this is the question, and the data type should be string because usually whatever question we are writing, this is kinds of string type data and answer.
Also, this is uh string type data. Okay, we are preferring the state now. Once state preparation is done, now we'll be creating the nodes.
But before showing you the nodes logic, I will show you the graph definition.
So you can see, guys, we are creating the state graph and we are passing the state, the state we have created this state, then after that, we are adding the nodes, okay.
The first node we have added the lm qay. Okay, now this llm qay we have to write. Okay, this lm qay we have to write. So this but this is this should be a simple Python function.
Inside that will perform the LLM call. So see LM QA, this is the function we are writing. This will take this state as an input and return the state as an output.
Now, whatever question user is giving, I am taking it from the state, then I'm preparing a prompt, answer the following questions.
We are giving the questions, then this particular prompt I am just giving to the model.
We are just doing model.info giving the prompt and whatever content it is giving me, I'm just extracting in the answer, and this answer I'm updating in the state memory again.
Okay, so you can see it is having the answer key. I'm updating the value there, and we are itering the state. Okay, now let's execute
now. Once our node is added, now we'll be working on the edges. We'll try to connect the edges. Now, if you see the graph, so see first of all, the start node will connect to the lm QA.
So we are connecting that start to llm QA, then LLM QA will be connected to the end. You can see, then add edges llm qa to end, okay. And I told you start and end is a default node inside line graph.
You don't need to manually add that. This is a dummy node, okay? So only we'll be calling whenever we'll be adding the edges. So once it is done, we'll try to compile the graph. Let's compile, okay.
Now everything is ready. Now we can execute the graph. So we are preparing the initial state, which is nothing but the question.
Let's say here I'm giving a question who is the creator of Python, and for the workflow we have created, we are just doing the inboxing operation, we are giving the initial state
and we are getting the final state output. Then we are just returning the answer. So I'm asking a question who is the creator of Python? Now let's see.
So, see the Python was created by Guido Van Rosem in the Late 90s 80s, okay. 1980s, so it's working fine. Okay, you can give any other question as well, it will work.
Now let's try to visualize the graph. So here I will execute this code. This code is common now. See, this is the graph you can see start LMQA and ends. Okay, amazing.
So this is the actually LLM workflow we have created. So previously, created without uh non-lm workflow. Now we have created LM-based workflow. Okay, I hope you get it.
So that's how, guys, if you want to use any kinds of large language model inside the workflow, you can define it like that. Okay, now we'll be learning another amazing concept.
I think I told you in my previous video as well called prompt chaining. Prompt chaining means you can use multiple lm calls. See here, I'm using only one lm call, right?
One lm call, but if you want to use multiple lm calls, that is also possible. So we'll be learning in the prom uh we'll be learning this concept in the prompt chaining.
Okay, so I'm going to create another notebook, there I'm going to show you how we can perform the prompt chaining operation.
That means one llm answer you are getting, you can pass this answer to another llm to get another response. Okay, this is also possible here. Let me show you that part as well.
So, guys, now I'll explain about this prompt training. this is another sequential workflow. So, in our previous workflow, we did the single LLM call.
That means user was giving any kinds of question and it was generating the answer.
But let's say you want to do multiple LLM call. that means after one LLM call, that output you want to use for another LLM okay as an input. This is called prompt chaining.
So, for an example, let me just uh tell you see here what I'm going to do, I'm going to let's say create a blog generator,
okay.
Blog generator from a topic. So here let's see user will give a topic name, okay?
So this will generate a blog, okay.
Block for that, but this blog I'm not going to generate directly. Instead of that, what I'm going to do first of all, I'm going to take this topic name, then I'm going to pass to a llm.
Okay, I'm going to pass to llm, and this llm will try to generate the outline.
Okay, outline for the block. So let's say this will generate the outline, okay.
Outline of the block from this llm, and whatever outline I will get from this llm, I will pass to another llm.
Okay, and this llm will try to
take this topic as well as this outline, and it will generate the block,
okay, and we'll be getting the final block as an output, okay. At the last, so this is the workflow, and this is called actually prompt
chaining concept.
Okay, prompt chaining concept basically whatever output we are getting from a first large language model, we are passing it to the second LLM as an input, and we are getting a final output.
That means we are calling multiple LLM call here. This is called prompt chaining concept, okay. So, this workflow will try to create right now.
Now, see, guys, I have already created this uh graph.
Okay, uh, I've already created this workflow as you can see. So, start and end would be common.
So, here I have to create two nodes. One is the create outline, that means whatever input I will be getting, that means uh the topic.
So, first of all, I'll generate outline, and this outline as well as the topic I will send to another nodes, which is create block.
This will generate the blog, and I'll be getting the final block as an output, okay. And what should be the state for this particular uh workflow?
First of all, the title that means the block title, okay.
Then whatever outline it will generate, this outline as well, and whatever content that means the blog will be getting.
This should be another state, okay. So that means three state will be available for this particular uh workflow for this particular graph. Okay, now let's try to represent in the line graph code.
So for this, I have created another notebook as you can see, prompt chaining workflow. So let's open it up.
So this is the notebook. So again, this is the same as per your previous notebook I created.
First of all, we have to import all the necessary libraries. You can see we are importing state graph, start ends, chat open i. Okay, then type d load enb.
Then we'll be loading the.enb uh.env file to load the open eIPI key. Then we'll be defining the large language model.
Then we'll be creating the state, and this state name I have uh named it as blog state, and again I'm doing the inheritance inheritance operation with the
type dict. Now we are preparing the state.
The state means the title, outline, and the content. Okay, three state we are taking.
Now, before creating the nodes, first of all, let me show you the graph.
Okay, see here we are creating the graph state graph, and we are passing the state, and first of all, we are adding the nodes, okay. So the first nodes we are adding for the create outline.
Now, let me show you this create outline function. So this is the create outline function. So this will take this state as an input and return you the state as an output.
Okay, so whatever title user is giving, first of all, I'm taking the title and here I'm preparing a prompt, generate a detail outline for the blog
for a blog on the topic. So then we are passing it to the llm. LLM is giving the outline. This outline we are saving inside the state, okay. Inside outline variable. Then we are returning the state.
Then after that, if you show if you see, I'm adding another nodes, okay, called generate blog.
Now, whatever outline I got and title I got, I will pass to this particular function.
You can see it will take from the state the title as well as the outline, then I'm preparing another prompt.
This prompt is telling write a detailed blog on the title, okay. Using the following outline, the outline we are getting as well as the title we are using here, then we are passing it to the LLM.
Okay, again, we are doing the LLM call.
Whatever LM is generating, I'm just storing in the content. That means this is the final blog.
Okay, I'm storing inside this content content state.
Okay, so it is done. Now you can see we are adding both of the nodes one by one.
So this nodes is added, create outline and create blocks. Now I have to create the edges.
Now to create the edges, guys. Here you can see I am creating the edges.
First of all, edge would be created start to create outline.
You can see start to create outline, then create outline to create block.
Create outline to create block. Okay, then create block to end,
create block to end. Okay, then we are doing the compile operation.
Then now we'll execute the graph. So here as initial state, we are giving the title, okay. We are giving uh title, let's say raise of AI in India.
Let's say this is our title, and I want to generate our outline and then block.
Now we are giving into the workflow, we are doing the invoking operation and we are getting the final state as an output.
See, it is doing multiple LLM call, that's why it's taking some time. First of all, it will invoke first llm, then the second llm, right? Now, see here we are getting the output. So this is the title.
Based on the title, we are getting the outline, and also we have the content. Final content, I think somewhere content is also there.
we can see here. So final state.
first of all, I want to see the outline.
So this is the outline.
Okay, it has prepared.
Now, if I want to show you the content, that means the blog.
So this is the blog, guys. Okay, I'm getting so this is called prompt trading concept. Now, if I want to show you the
graph, so this is the graph.
You start, create outline, then you'll go to the generate block, a create blog, then hands.
Okay, I hope you got it, guys.
Okay, so that's how guys we can create any kinds of sequential workflow.
Either you can create a non LLM based, either you can create llm based, either you can create prompt chaining based, anything you can create.
Only you just need to know how to how to define these nodes and this particular connection, okay.
Age connection. If you can understand this concept, you can just trust me, you can create any kinds of workflow, okay, inside line Graph.
Now I think by end of this video it is very much clear how we can create any kinds of sequential workflow inside Langgraph.
Okay, don't worry, I'm also going to show you like complex workflow as well, like parallel workflow. Okay, there are lots of workflow we saw, right? We'll be learning each of them.
Don't need to worry, but before starting that complex workflow, first of all, I've given you the sequential workflow.
I think now you have enough understanding how to code inside Langgraph at least, right? Now I think these are the syntax won't be confusion to you, right? Like what is a node, what is AJS?
Okay, so so far we have learned so many theoretical concepts, now we have seen the practical implementation.
And all of this code and everything would be available in the description. From there, you can download and you can try in your system. And one more exercise you can perform.
Let's say this from training we have done. Maybe you can add another node for the evaluation evaluation for this block. Let's say the blog you are generating.
Whether this is good or bad, you can take another LLM, you can take another nodes and you can evaluate that. And you can also print the evaluation result.
Let's say it needs the feedback or not, or it is completely fine. This kinds of result you can also print.
Okay, that means you have to take another state here, and whatever result you are getting, you can also show the result here.
Okay, after
you can see
content, maybe you can print another result which is evaluator result. Okay, now the best part is of this state is you you can access all of the output, okay. All of the output input anytime.
Let's say we have generated uh these three uh three things, right? title, outline, and content, and it is accessible anytime.
Okay, this is the final state.
From the final uh from the final state, you can access
any kinds of state. Let's you can access title, outline, content, or if you are adding the evaluator, you can access it anytime.
Okay, so yes, that's it, guys.
So, yes, this is all about from this video. I hope you got it. Now, in the next video, guys, will be uh we'll be learning some other workflow as well, okay.
Like parallel workflow, will be also learning conditional workflow, iterative workflow, okay. All the workflow we'll try to cover one by one.
So, guys, we are continuing with our complete agent KI course, and as you know, we started learning our first
orchestration framework, which is Langgraph, and in our previous video, I have already showed you how we can build sequential workflow inside Langgraph. So, if I open up my
previous like materials, so there I already showed you about the sequential workflow, and I think you know how sequential workflow works. Basically, it will work as a step-by-step manner.
Okay, first of all, let's say this node, then this node, then this node, okay. That's how it will execute, okay, as a sequence.
So, if I uh show you, see I created a non-lm based workflow and llm workflow, uh, then prompt chaining workflow. So, as you can see, uh, after executing this node, this node would be executed, okay.
Then you will be getting the output. So, this is a sequential order. Now we'll try to understand this parallel workflow, like how parallel workflow works, and uh we'll also try to
write the code inside Langgraph. And here is the example, guys. The first example I'm going to show you the employee analytics workflow. Okay, so this is the example I have taken.
I already told you just don't um I mean don't focus on the problem statement.
I I have taken some of the problem statement, easy problem statement so that I can make you understand these are the workflow.
So later on, we'll be building some amazing agent application completely end-to-end. So you can see, guys, here this is the parallel workflow graph, as you can see.
so you can see the difference between the sequential and the parallel. Sequential means after executing this node, this node will be executing.
That means the output you are getting from this particular node, you are passing this particular output to the next node, and this node is taking that
output as an input, then it is executing. Okay, that means you have to wait. Okay, you have to wait till this node just complete the execution, then this node will start.
But in parallel workflow, it's not like that, each of the nodes are independent, that means you can execute them independently, okay.
Simultaneously, you can execute all of the node and you can get the output. So, for this, I have taken one amazing example called employee analytics workflow.
So, basically, what we'll do here, we'll just try to take some employee data. So, here I already created the state as you can see. I have already defined the state for this particular demo.
So, as you can see, let's say this is our employee state, and you know what is state, right? State is a shared memory inside our graph, right? And it will pass to all of the nodes.
So you can see these are the data we'll be taking from the user. Okay, let's say employee name, monthly salary, working days, and completed projects.
Okay, based on that, what we will do, we'll just try to calculate the bonus of the employee, yearly salary of the employee, and the project evaluation.
Evaluation means the project is excellent, let's say project work is excellent or average. Okay, we'll try to mark that. Now you can see to do that, I don't need to wait for any of the node here.
Let's say I don't need to wait for this bonus to calculate the yearly salary, then I don't need to wait for project evaluation for this
calculate yearly salary. Okay, I don't need to wait for each and every nodes here because each and every nodes are independent. The task I have taken, you can see this is completely independent task.
So instead of running this in a sequential manner, so I can follow this parallel parallel workflow, okay, so that I can execute them in parallel and I can quickly complete my task, okay.
Otherwise, if you do if you are running in sequential order, you have to wait for the previous node to be executed, okay? But here it's not like that, this is completely independent.
Then, after getting all of this information, what we'll do, guys, we'll just try to give a summary.
summary means let's say the employee name, their salary, yearly salary, project evaluation, calculated bonus.
We'll just try to return a string, complete detail summary string, and we'll just try to end the graph. Okay, so this is a simple problem statement I have taken again.
I told you guys, don't just focus on the problem statement. just to make you understand, I have taken this problem statement. The main intention you have to learn this workflow, okay.
How we can build this workflow. So, first of all, we'll try to learn this non LLM based workflow. So, here I'm not going to use any kinds of llm.
then after learning this non LLM based workflow, the next one I'm going to take the LLM workflow. Okay, so both will be learning, no need to worry. Now, let's start the coding inside line graph.
So, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to simply
I'm going to simply create a file here. I'm going to name it as for
um employee data analytics. Okay, employee
analytics.
I'm
going to create a notebook file.
Perfect. So here I'll take the code cell and I will select the kernel.
Uh so previously I created this environment, I think remember. I will try to select that as well.
Fine.
Now, guys, the first thing what you have to do, I think you remember. The first thing you have to import all of the necessary library.
So maybe what I can do, I can refer my previous notebook and I can just import all of the necessary library I need.
Um I need this one, right?
This uh line graph, state graph, and start and end. So I'll try to import this this as well as I need this uh typing.
to create this uh state, okay. I need this particular type dict. Now let's import it.
Now the second thing, guys, you have to define the state, okay. If you uh if you see that, let's say the previous example also.
so this is LLM workflow.
But if I open my previous example, let's say this one I created, right? This is the non LLM based workflow.
then second thing you have to define the state, and for this uh example, guys, what should be the state? So this is the state I already prepared.
First of all, uh, these are the state will be taking from the um user, and these are the state will be uh we'll be just calculating. Okay, we'll be updating basically.
Let's say this calculate uh yearly salary. Uh we'll try to calculate the early salary and we'll try to update in the inside this particular state. Then bonus, okay.
We'll update inside this uh state, then project evaluation. We update inside this project status and summary, whatever summary we are getting, we'll also update here, okay.
And all of the data type I have also mentioned. You can see employee name should be string data type, monthly salary should be integer, working days. Uh, it should be also integer, completed project.
It should be integer.
That is the number of project employee has completed yearly salary. This is also integer. bonus amount also integer. project status. Okay, this status I will let's say tell excellent average.
Okay, so this should be a string and summary also should be a string. Okay, so this is the data type. Now let's try to um just write same uh uh state inside our notebook.
I'm going to just close this at the file
so.
This is the state, guys.
Okay, you can see the same state we have prepared here, and I just named it as employee state, and I inherited with type ticked because I can store my data as a key value pair.
Okay, I think I have already discussed previously. Okay, this thing, so I'm not going to repeat again.
Now my state is done. Now I'll just need to create the graph. Now let's try to create the graph.
So we'll try create the graph. You can see we are using a state graph, and inside that we are passing our state, okay. Employee state. Now we have to add the nodes, okay.
Now, how many nodes we are having?
one, two, three. Okay, and last we have another nodes called somebody and start and end. You don't need to take it because this is our default node inside lang graph. This is a dummy node.
So, first of all, let's try to create this
this one, this
calculate bonus, or you can create any of them because this is completely independent, right? you are not I mean,
you don't need to worry about the like order because this is not a sequential one. You can create any of them, any of them. Okay, so first of all, let's create this calculate yearly salary.
So here I'm going to add a node.
So
this is the node, guys, graph dot add nodes.
I named it as calculate yearly salary, and the same name I used for this particular function, okay. And this is going to be a Python function. We'll just try to write the function, okay?
Just give me some time. So, like that, I'll also define for all of these nodes one by one. the next one I'm going to create for
uh calculate bonus and project evaluation,
yeah. So calculate bonus, this one, and the project evaluation.
Project evaluation. Okay, so all of the nodes I have created, only the last node I have to create this summary.
Now let's also create the summary
summary okay. My node uh creation is done. Now I'll write these are the function one by one.
So I'll come here.
So here I will comment.
Uh this is our node one, and the function name is calculate yearly salary. Okay, now let's define a function dev
uh calculate yearly salary,
and this will take this employee state as an input because every node takes this state. I think you remember okay. Every node takes this state, okay, and also it also return a state, right?
So we are we are giving this type hint here.
So let's try to like write the logic here. so first of all, we'll try to calculate the yearly salary. So, how to calculate the yearly salary? I think you know that we have the monthly salary.
So, what I can do? I can just multiply by 12. So this will give me the yearly salary and multi salary. I have inside the state. You can see the multi-salary I have inside the state.
So once it is done, I'm going to update the early salary while in my state again. You can see we are updating this early salary in the state, then we are returning the state.
You know that every nodes return the state.
Okay, we are returning the state, it's completely fine, right? we have written the fast uh fast notes now.
Like that, we'll also write the second nodes.
state notes.dot define. We have to execute this cell now. Let's execute okay. Now it's working fine. Now the second node guys, we have to write for the calculate bonus
for this one.
let's write this function
if calculate bonus.
This will also take um
this will also take uh employee state, that means the state, and also return the state. Okay, and here we'll try to calculate the bonus.
So you can see whatever um
so what I can do, I can calculate the bonus based on the monthly salary,
monthly salary.
So I'll just try to multiply by two.
Okay, see here I'm not calculating the exact bonus here, just try to think about just I'm adding some bonus uh based on the monthly salary of that particular employee, okay?
And after that, we are adding this bonus amount inside the state, then we are returning the state, okay?
It's done.
Now we'll try to create the next one, which is uh project evaluation.
Note 3 project evaluation def project evaluation. This will also take the state as an input and return the state as an output. So here I can just write a logic.
So let's say this is the logic I can write. Simple logic.
If uh let's say the completed project amount is more than five, so that time I can just give the status excellent.
Otherwise, I'll just try to tell it's average one.
Okay, now I'll update this project status, then I will return the status. Okay, so yeah, this is our notes we have prepared.
Now once it is done. The at the last I will add this summary notes as well.
Now let's add the summary note.
So inside summary, I'm just going to return all of the summary. That's it.
So def summary.
So here I will just initialize the summary. Let's say this is the entire summary text.
I've taken the f string and I'm just joining the string all together, Employee, employee name, then has a yearly salary
of yearly salary, a bonus of bonus amount, project status is the project status. Okay, that means this is a complete string. I'm just writing and updating and returning it.
Okay, that's it. Now let me execute.
Yeah, my all of the nodes are prepared. Now what I have to do, guys.
we have already created all of the nodes. That means nodes is created. Now we have to add the edges. Okay, this is called edges. Now we have to do the edge connection.
Now let's try to do the edge connection.
So for this, I think you know that we use this
add edge uh uh add edge uh function inside Langgraph. So here I can comment.
So first of all, try to see how we are going to connect the edges.
You can see from start, it is connecting to calculate bonus,
it is connecting to calculate yearly salary, it is connected to project evaluation.
Okay, that means simultaneously you can see it is having three connections okay, with calculate bonus, calculate yearly salary
and project evaluation.
So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to do the same thing.
First of all, I'm going to add this start with calculate yearly salary.
Then I'm going to add with my calculate bonus, then I'm going to add with project evaluation.
Okay, I'm going to add with project evaluation. Now just try to relate. You can see start is connected with early salary, calculate bonus, and project evaluation.
Okay, so these are the connections I have already made.
You can see these are the connections I have already made. Now this connection is complete. Now I have to build this connection.
Okay, that means now
calculate bonus is connected to the summary, yearly salary also connected to the summary, project evaluation is also connected to the summary. Okay, that means I have to build this connection now.
Let's do that.
So, here what I'm going to do,
I'm going to write calculate yearly salary, it is connected to summary.
Calculate yearly salary, it is connected to somebody.
Okay, then calculate bonus, it is also connected to the summary, and
project evaluation.
This is also connected to the summary.
Okay, project evaluation, this is also connected to the summary, and summary is connected to the end.
Now let's add another edge.
Summary is connected to the end. Now just try to relate, okay. Just trust me, if you can understand this one, just the edge connection at the node creation.
You can build any kinds of workflow inside Langgraph.
Okay, any kinds of workflow you can create. So I hope, guys, you got it.
Okay, I hope guys you got it. How we have made this connection,
okay? And this is an independent connection.
This is an independent connection.
Nobody uh, I mean, none of the nodes is dependent on another nodes, okay.
So that's why we call it as a parallel workflow. Now let me show you.
for this, first of all, we have to compile the workflow.
Let's compile.
Okay.
Now I'll compile the workflow.
Now you can just see the workflow graph.
See if you're using this Jupyter notebook, you don't need to write this extra code for that.
I think in the recent update, they have automatically done this one in the cell itself. So previously I used this code to draw this graph, but right now you don't need to do that.
If you just print this workflow, you will automatically see this particular graph. Okay. Now see guys, this is the graph, and this is our parallel parallel workflow we have created.
Now just try to relate this graph.
Okay.
Now you can see start and it is connected with all of the nodes independently connected. Then whatever
result we are getting, we are just returning the summary and we're ending the graph.
Okay, so this is the parallel workflow. Now let's try to execute.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to initialize my initial state.
And what should be the initial state? These are the state should be the initial one because we'll be taking these are the data from the user.
So let's define that.
So this is our initial state. You can see I'm taking the employee name,
then monthly salary. So I'm going to take my name.
Let's say I'm the employee. This is the monthly salary, this is the working days, and this is the completed project. Okay, now we'll just try to run this workflow. Okay.
This workflow dot inbox. We are giving the initial state and we're getting the result.
Now execute.
Okay. Now see, guys, here we are getting one output.
The output is at key employee name can receive only one value per step.
Use an annotated key to handle multiple value.
Now you can ask me why we are getting the error. Okay, why we are getting this error because everything is fine so far, right? Everything is fine so far, but why we are getting the error? See,
the reason I showed you this error, actually, I could have fixed it previously, but I showed you this error so that you can relate the difference between the sequential workflow
this parallel workflow. Okay, if you can understand this, I think you won't be having any kinds of problem.
See what is happening.
If I show you my workflow again, so this is my workflow. See, here we created this state, right? We created this state and we are passing this state to the all of these nodes.
But if you just observe, if you just deeply observe what is happening, whenever we are passing this state to all of the nodes, what is happening to calculate the bonus?
What I'm using, okay, to calculate the bonus, what I'm using, I'm using this uh initial state. That means whatever data user is passing, I mean I'm using that.
So to calculate this, I think I was using this monthly salary only, right? I was using the monthly salary, and I was updating this value wire
in this particular section.
That means this bonus bonus amount variable would be changed, okay. After running this state, this particular variable would be changed. I'm not changing these are the variable, right?
That means the monthly salaries remain the same. I'm not changing it anywhere. That means the employee name I'm also not changing, working days also I'm not changing, completed project.
Also, I'm not changing, right? I'm only changing these are the variable here, but these are the variable remains same, common, right?
So whatever you are passing this state everywhere, it is updating here only, not here.
Okay, so that's why in parallel workflow, whenever you are giving this simultaneously to all of the nodes, okay.
So this nodes actually
conflicts each other.
Conflicts each other means there is no update, so it conflicts like whether the value we are getting here this is correct for this nodes or not, whether the value we are getting here, this is
correct for this nodes or not. Okay, that means it conflicts inside because we are returning the entire state here.
You can see we are returning the entire state, although we are not updating this at the state, but still we are returning the entire state, that means the entire state will go to the another node,
okay. That means the entire state will go to the another node, although we are not doing any kinds of update, but we are returning the state, okay.
It's not recommended, so whenever you are creating the parallel workflow, you have to make sure only the update you are doing inside the variable
that particular variable or that particular state you have to return only. Okay, let's say in this case, let me just give you one example.
Let's say in this case, we are only calculating what we are only calculating the yearly salary.
So instead of returning all the state together, what I'm going to do, only I'm going to return the yearly salary. Okay, because this is a parallel one.
I don't need to like wait for my employee name, monthly salary, these are the things, right? Whatever update I'm just doing, I'll just only try to return that.
So instead of this update, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to only return.
I'm going to only return
uh yearly salary.
See, I'm going to only return the yearly salary we have calculated. We are only returning that because at then uh this is this is a dictionary, okay. This this notes returns a dictionary.
Okay, we have to return a dictionary somehow. Now I don't need to give this time type int. Okay, this is not required because we are not returning the entire employee state.
Okay, now I'm going to just remove it.
So only it will take the state and whatever update it will do inside the state, and that state will only return, not any other state.
Okay, not any other state, only the updated one it will return. So for this, I'll update for all the nodes I have done. So let's say here
I was
updating the bonus amount, so I'll only return the bonus amount, and this thing is not required.
Okay, now for this project evaluation, also I'll do the same thing.
Return the project status. This thing is not required.
Now for summary also.
This is not required.
Okay, so let me check everything is fine or not. Yeah, everything is fine. Now let me execute from the beginning.
Now our workflow is created.
Now we'll
now we'll just try to invoke this workflow.
now see it's working. Now if I print the result,
see we are getting the final result. So this is the employee name, multi-salary working days, completed project, yearly salary. So see, we got the calculated yearly salary,
then bonus amount, project start as excellent because the completed project is seven, and our logic was if it is more than five,
right? More than and equal five, that means it is excellent. You are getting the excellent here, and here's the summary, but somebody is giving
a function.
So let me check.
now okay. So this should be summary text. I'm writing, I'm just returning the function on the right? The nodes only. So this should be a um this this variable now. I think this should work.
Now we are getting the summary.
Employee B has yearly salary of that amount, bonus uh bonus is that amount, and project status is excellent.
Okay, so this is our uh parallel workflow, guys. We have created, and I hope you understood.
Okay, I hope you understood, and this particular concept also you understood why we don't need to return the entire state
inside parallel workflow. If you're creating the sequential workflow, it's completely fine. You can return the entire state that time, okay.
You can return the entire state that time, but whenever you are creating the parallel workflow, make sure only the state you are changing, just try to
return those state only, okay? Not the entire state.
Okay, you don't need to do like that because uh internally it will do the conflict operation because we can't pass simultaneously to all of the nodes
the same state, okay. This is not possible. So in every state that should be that should uh should be updated, okay.
State should be updated, but here you can see it is not getting updated, okay. After going to the every state, every nodes it is not going to be updated.
Okay, that's why this is going to be conflicted, so we have to update it somehow. So that's why we only are returning these are the state which is getting updated.
Get it, yeah. So this is the concept, guys, and this is our first non non-lm based workflow we have created, and this is the parallel workflow, it is executing as parallel.
Okay, now we'll try to create another workflow.
we'll use the llm and we'll call as a llm parallel workflow.
Now let's try to see how we can create this llm-based parallel workflow, guys.
So, guys, so far we have created this non-LLM-based parallel workflow. we have already seen the example how it can be done. Now I'm going to show you how we can create LLM-based parallel workflow.
Now we'll try to integrate LLM with that. And for this example, I'm going to take this particular demo called assay workflow.
I think you remember uh in my introductory session, whenever I was giving you the introduction about the land graph, I used one example called
assay. Okay, assay writing example. So there I created a system, I created a workflow.
That workflow takes an assay as an input and it does the evaluation based on some parameter, like it checks the um
it uh depth analysis, then language evaluation, then
like research of thought evaluation. Okay, based on that, it returns you some kinds of feedback as well as the score and we get the final evaluation, then we conclude that right.
So, these kinds of things I think I already discussed about my this session.
Okay, this is the number seven video I have already discussed. You can go through that if you want to understand about that particular workflow, but again, I'm going to show you the workflow here.
I already created the workflow, I'm going to discuss it here, and you can also see what is assay.
Uh, essay is a like it's a short non-fictional piece of writing that presents a specific argument analysis or personal point of view on a particular subject. Okay, so basically, whenever you
attend any kinds of let's say exams or you if you are studying in a university, any kinds of university that uh so these are the essay writing you will be getting there, okay.
So this is a kinds of research topic you can talk about.
So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to take this same example here to make you understand this LLM-based workflow because here we'll be utilizing the LLM to analyze
the essay, right? And we'll also do the marking and all. So, this is the workflow. This is the graph, guys. Uh, we we uh I have created as you can see.
Start and end nodes would be common, and these are the nodes we'll be creating. Uh, evaluate analysis nodes, and that means uh whatever assay topic we'll be giving, right?
Uh assay will be giving, it will try to evaluate the analysis. Whether the analysis section is good or not, it will evaluate and it will give you two things.
Okay, this is this will give you two things.
Uh, just let me write down
what I can do. I can take a screenshot.
can take a screenshot and I will open up my board.
So now let me tell you.
Yeah. So let's say you are giving an assay here.
You are giving a
assay here.
Okay.
So this evaluate analysis will try to analyze the entire assay and it will this it will give you two things. The first one is the
uh feedback.
Okay.
Feedback, feedback of the assay, and second one is the score.
This will give you a score.
let's out of ten it will give you some kinds of score.
Then next nodes we have writing for the evaluate language. Let's say you are using English language, right? So, how is your grammatical?
Uh let's say I mean grammatical arrangement or if you are following the right grammatical structure or not,
and uh what is the words you are using. So, this kinds of language related evaluation will perform, then again this will give you a feedback,
okay, and this will also give you a score out of 10, right? Then we'll just perform another analysis.
This is the like uh uh thought analysis, thought analysis means the thought thought of on top of this assay, okay. Uh, so here this will also give you a feedback
and the score.
That means every nodes we are getting into two things feedback score, feedback score, feedback is score.
Okay, then we'll pass this feedback score, uh uh feedback and score, all of the feedback and score from all of the nodes.
Let's say this is node one, this is node two, this is node three, to another nodes called final evaluator. So that means this will evaluate based on all of the feedback.
Let's say this is feedback one, this is feedback two, this is feedback three. So it will take all of the feedback, then it will give you the final feedback, final feedback,
okay, or evaluation. Then it will take all of the score.
All of the score. and this will return you the average score of that, okay. Average final score of that.
Okay, so this is how actually we'll be implementing this particular assay.
Then once it is done, we'll try to end this particular
uh and this particular but
graph.
Okay, now if I get back to my workflow, I think now you are getting right, and to make this workflow, I need this other state. Okay, I already prepared the state as you can see.
I need this other state, I named it as assay state, and I inherited with type dict. And first of all, I need to take the assay, and assay should be string, right?
This is a variable, then language feedback that means here.
So evaluate language, this will basically do the language uh language evaluation, and whatever feedback we'll be getting, we'll try to save inside language feedback.
Then it will also give you uh this will also give you um another score, right? Uh that means the uh language score.
So instead of storing inside a single variable, so what I am doing, so here you can see I have taken another variable called individual score, okay.
And here I use this annotated list integer operator dot add. So I think you can call this uh call this concept, right? So this is called actually reducer.
I already talked about the reducer here uh in my um demo. Whenever I was explaining about the Langgraph code component, there I talked about the reducer.
So if you haven't watched that video, guys, please try to watch because this is important. Without that, actually, you won't be able to understand what is reducer exactly.
So reducer uh will help us to uh replace, add, and merge the like data inside the state. So by default it will replace everything.
I think so far, whatever state we have created, it was replacing every time, right? But as you can see, from each and every nodes, from each and every nodes we are getting some score.
Okay, let's say if I'm only taking one, let's say, score variable. So, what will happen? So, whenever I'll get this code from here, let's say I got 12.
sorry, I got let's say eight, then from this particular nodes and I get another score. From this particular node, I get another score. Let's say this is eight five. So, what I will do?
This eight point eight would be replaced by eight five. So that means I will lose my previous score of that evaluate analysis. Right, then let's say this this node has generated another one, okay?
Let's say 9.5. So again, it will replace by 9.5. So I lose my previous like score. Right, but I need all of this code to make the average.
So I need this score as well, I need this score as well, I need this score as well. That means I need to keep inside a dictionary.
Let's say the first score I'm getting eight, second score I'm getting eight five, the third score I'm getting nine five. I'll store all of the score from all of the nodes, okay, inside a list.
Then I'm going to create an average of that particular score, and this is going to be my final evaluation, okay. And for this, we are using this operator dot add here.
Okay, you can see we are using operator dot add here and we are using annotated. Okay, I think you know what is annotated. Whenever I want to use reducer, right?
I have to use this annotated, and here we are mentioning that should be a list of integer. Okay, there should be a list of integer. That means I want to
I want to let's say store store list of integer here. So here I have taken a float value, but you can consider I want to you can also like give it as float value here.
Let's say sometimes uh score should be also um float value 8.57.5, but I told I need uh only integer type
like feedback, okay. integer type score, so that's why given list of integer and operator dot add. That means I want to perform reducer, reducer, what operation?
Add operation that means instead of replacing it will every time add all of the score. So whatever is score I'm going to get from my evaluator analysis, I will store it here, okay.
Apart from the feedback, then from evaluator language, also I'm going to add the score from uh evaluate thoughts. Whatever feedback score I'm getting, I will also try to add there.
Okay, so that's how you can see for all of the nodes I have individual variable. So you can see language feedback. I have one variable, then evaluate of thought. That means uh
uh this one
clarity feedback. Okay, uh, this is uh clarity of thought. You can consider and the full name is clarity of thought. We have taken a variable called clarity feedback.
So basically, this feedback will store here.
Then we have evaluator analysis, that means the analysis feedback it will store here, okay. That means language analysis, then evaluate
thoughts, okay. Clarity of thoughts, then the overall feedback that means from final evaluation also we are getting a feedback.
From final evaluation, also we are getting a feedback. So this feedback will store inside overall feedback, okay.
And final evaluation will give you another score, which is average score, and for average score we have kept another separate variable called average score, and this should be a float value, okay.
And for individual score we are getting, we are storing inside this particular list, okay. Individual score, this should be a list, and we are performing the reducer add operation.
Okay, now I think you got it. How we created this particular state, okay. How we created this particular state. Now I think this is pretty much clear, guys.
And to understand this reducer concept, I will suggest you go through this uh recording, okay. Langgraph core component, you will try to understand okay how reducer works.
So, yeah, I think our uh uh our uh state is ready, everything is ready. Now we can start working on that, but one more issue we'll be having, which is this uh uh output uh format, okay.
That means I need a structure output from my LLM. That means every nodes will return feedback and score, feedback and score, feedback and score, and we are using llm.
And you know, llm is unstructured data generator, okay. We won't be getting these kinds of feedback score every time. Let's say if you are adding by the prompt, I need a feedback and score only.
Let's say it will run five times, maybe in six times it will give you some other parameter as well. That time your code will crash, right?
So to make our output structured, so I taught you about uh I already taught you about this pydentic, right? So you can see pydentic for AI agents.
I've already taken a class on that, so you just need to go through this pydentic because we'll be using pyden type concept to get the structured output from my LLM.
Okay, now let's try to show you how it can be done. So, what I'm going to do here, I'm going to create another um another file.
So I'm going to name it as
pipe
as a workflow.
I'm going to select my environment.
So, first of all, I will import all of the necessary library.
So I need this state graph start n okay from Langgraph.
Then
I also need
open AI model because here I'm going to use LLM and for LM I'm going to use OpenAI model. You can use any model, okay? It's up to you.
You can use Gemini Grok provider, and any kinds of model you can use, but I already have the open API key.
yesterday I already already connected uh collected. I think you remember. Okay, that's why I'm using that.
Then uh okay, I'm going to close this.
Then I need this uh load env to load my environment variable because inside environment variable I have my API key.
Then I need um
these are the import as well. From typing, I'm importing this type dict and annotated.
Why annotated? Because you know that to make this reducer, okay. I need this annotated, okay. Annotated is required and it is available inside this typing.
We are importing annotated, and we are using pyden tick. So from pydentic, we are importing base model
and field, and you have to install pydentic for this.
Uh let me install pydentic.
Okay,
I'll install this specific version of the pydentic. Now let me
activate my environment.
Then let's install the requirements again.
Okay, then now we'll come here. Now you can use this pydentic. So from py identific, I'm importing base model and field. And what this base model field does, guys. I already discussed in this session.
Please go through that. Okay, I'm not going to repeat again. So this session will give you the entire entire idea about py identification, okay?
Why it is required and operator for this add operation that means for the reducer, okay.
Operation dot add, operator dot add, we have to write it here. So once it is done, now let me import all of the packets.
Yeah, so it's working fine.
Now, first of all, we'll try to load the involvement variable.
Yeah, then we'll prepare the model.
So here I will take GPT-40 mini.
Okay, this model.
This is our LM.
Now you can perform the inbox operation if you want
directly, but if you perform the inbox operation right now, so what will happen?
Uh, this will uh give you unstructured output, but I need what I need only this uh feedback and score. Okay, I need feedback score from this model, okay.
Whatever essay I will give you, um I'll I'll give to this model, it will give me feedback and score. So I have to make the structure. So, how to make the structure for this?
We'll be using the pidentic. So here I have created one pydentic class.
So this is the pydentic class. So the name of the pydenc class is evaluation schema,
and we are inheriting with the base model. Okay, the base model we have imported here, we have inherited, and here is the pydentic syntax. Okay, this syntax I already taught you in that session.
So this should be string and this should be integer, and here I have given the field. So in the field, I am telling detail feedback for
for the assay,
and for score, I've given a description score out of 10. so this is the greater than and this is the lesser than okay, greater than zero and lesser than 10. So this should be the score.
So this that's how you can make the structured output from any kinds of given llm. Okay, now
to make the structured model. What I'm going to do simply I'm going to just add this
add this schema to the model. So for this, you have to call the model.
There is a function called with structured output, I think.
With structured output inside that you have to pass this class,
okay. This patentic class. Now this will set
into the model. That means whenever you will generate any kinds of output, this will have two things one is the feedback, one is the score.
Okay, now I'll store inside another variable called structured model. Now, this is going to be my structured model object, okay. Now, every time I'm call this, I'm going to call this model, okay.
Not this model, this model will give you unstructured output, but this model will give you the structured output.
Okay, now let me execute
and see whether everything is fine or not.
Now, if you want to test, guys, so maybe I can show you. So I'll give an assay here.
So this is one assay I generated from chat GPT.
You can see this is essay I generated from chat GPT.
You drop in the age of AI, the regulatory superpower. So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to pass this assay to the structured model with a prompt.
So, this is the prompt I have written evaluate the language quality of the following assay and provide a feedback. An ass n is score out of 10.
Okay, I'm giving the Assay text here, and right now I'm calling the structured model, not the model only. Okay, structured model dot Invoke and I'm passing the prompt.
Now this will give you the result.
Okay, result and store inside result variable.
Now let's execute.
Yeah, now if I print this result,
you'll see that it will have two parameters.
One is the feedback, okay, feedback of the assay, and another one is the
score. Okay, see I got this score. You can also extract it if you want, so you just simply need to write result.feedback.
Okay, we'll get the feedback, and if you want this code, we can call reser.score.
Okay, this is this code you got.
I hope you got it, guys. Okay, that's so without Pyden T you can um you can get the structured output from any large language model, okay. This is very much important.
Now we'll try to start writing our this workflow. Now, first of all, let's prepare this state.
So already state is given. I'm going to just replicate the same state here.
So this is our state,
as a state. So we are giving the assay language feedback, test, analysis feedback, clarity of clarity feedback, overall feedback, individual scores, and this is uh reducer, uh
reducer concept you are using. Basically, this should be a list of scores, okay? And it will add every time and the average score.
Now let's initialize that.
Now we'll write our our graph.
Let's prepare the graph.
Yeah, so we have given this state to this graph,
okay. Now we'll try to
add the nodes. So, first of all, I will add this node, this node, this node, okay, and the final evaluation node.
Total four nodes I have to add.
Let's add it.
I have already prepared all of the node
and
node.
So yeah, you can see we're adding the nodes.
First of all, we're adding the evaluation evaluate language, okay. Evaluate language this node, then we are adding evaluate analysis this node, then we are giving evaluate thoughts this node,
okay. Then last final evaluation.
Final evaluation.
Okay, my node is done. Now we have to create these are the Python function one by one.
Let's create quickly.
So here I'm going to just create it quickly. First of all, I'm going to create this function evaluate language.
So I already created, let me show you.
Yeah.
So evaluate language. This will take this state as an input, and here you can see I'm using LLM, and for this, I prepared a prompt.
So here I'm telling evaluate the language quality of the following essay and provide a feedback and assign a score out of 10. And we're giving the state sorry assay from the state.
Okay. And we are calling this structured model. That means the structured model we have prepared here.
This model, okay, instead of this model.
So structured model. So this model will give you two things: one is the feedback, one is the score.
So the feedback we're storing inside language feedback. That means this particular variable because we are evaluating the language here. That's why feedback will go to the language feedback.
And the score we are getting, we are storing inside individual score.
And this is like a reducer type that means we are adding inside a list, so that's why you can see individual score, output
score. Okay, that means the first core will save here. That means let's say
uh what I'm going to do.
See
that means um from here uh evaluate language, right? I think it is evaluate language,
uh evaluate language. So that means we are executing this node. So this node will give you two things one is the feedback,
one is the score.
Okay, so feedback I already stored inside my feedback uh
feedback uh
uh feedback state that means here language feedback now is core. Okay, score what I am doing because I created an individual feedback variable.
Okay, uh so here let me show you
maybe I can take a screenshot.
So here you remember I created this individual score variable, so basically, this is a list, okay?
This should be a list,
this should be a list, okay, and we added our first score, which is this evaluate language. Let's say it has given you eight, okay, then there would be a comma
done, okay. Now I will write for the next nodes, which is evaluate analysis, okay? Because I already executed uh I already created this node, evaluate language. This will give you feedback and score.
I already got it, and instead of returning all the state, we are returning the updated one only.
Because in my previous example, I showed you if you're creating parallel workflow, you don't need to return the entire state.
Instead of that, only you just you just need to return the updated state, okay? Otherwise, there would be a conflict problem.
Okay, yeah. So now let me
define this node.
Now, once it is done, I'll define the next node, which is the
depth of analysis, evaluate analysis.
This will take the state, and here we are giving the prompt again, evaluate the depth of analysis of the following essay and provide a feedback and
assign a score out of 10, and we are giving the essay, and this will pass to the structured model. This will give you two things: one is the feedback.
So, this feedback I'm storing inside analysis feedback, that means here
in this particular variable, and it is giving you the individual score, and we're uh
storing this uh score in the individual score, that means here.
Okay, this is a list. So, like let's say this has given you
uh again eight.
Okay, this will store here,
okay.
That's how we are storing now. This is also done.
Now we'll write for the next one, which is
clarity of thought analysis, evaluate clarity of thought. Again, this will take the state as an input.
We are defining the prompt, evaluate the clarity of the thought of the following assay and provide a feedback analysis and assign a score out of 10.
Okay, we are giving the assay,
and we are passing it to the structured model.
And this will give you two things. One is the feedback. So, feedback I'm storing inside clarity feedback in this uh variable, and the score we are getting, we're storing inside individual score.
Okay, that means here, then again, it will get give you another score. Let's say you got nine here, okay?
So that's how your individual score will form right, and now we have all of the score from all of the nodes. Now we'll try to make the average one, okay? Later on. Now it's done.
You can see we are also returning these two things clarity of uh clarity feedback and individual scores, and this will become my next node.
Now we have to work on the final node, which is final evaluation.
Now let's also write that.
This is our final evaluation nodes. Again, this will take the state as an input, and again, we are preparing a prompt based on the following feedbacks.
create a summarized feedback. Okay, now here we are passing all of the feedback one by one. That means this feedback, this feedback, this feedback. Okay, this feedback, this feedback, this feedback.
Three feedback we are giving language feedback, then depth of analysis feedback,
clarity of thought feedback, and I'm just telling the model give me an overall feedback.
And right now I only need a feedback, I know I don't need any kinds of score. Okay, so that's why I'm using the original model instead of working on the structured model.
I'm now invoking the original model because I only need the feedback, that's why I'm invoking on the original model.
I'm giving giving this prompt, and whatever content it is generating, I'm just storing inside overall feedback.
Okay, now I have to calculate the average
average score, okay. And how to calculate the average score? Because I already have the all of this score, right? All of this code as a list.
Now you can see from this state I'm extracting the individual score, okay. Individual score, because this is a list. Okay, now we are calculating the length of this
like list and how many uh let's say variable how many value we are having, we are just doing the dividing operation, okay. First of all, we are doing the sum operation.
You can see so how to calculate average. First of all, you will do the sum operation. You will do the sum operation eight plus eight plus nine.
Okay, then you will just try to divide with the number of item you have. Let's say we have three here now. Whatever output you will be getting, this is your average, okay.
So we are calculating the average like that. First of all, we are summing all the value, then we are dividing with length of the item we are having inside the list.
Then this is going to be your average score, and we are returning the overall feedback and average score.
So overall feedback we are storing inside this variable, overall feedback and the average score. We are storing this average, okay. Average score here,
and that's it.
Okay, now all of the function we have created. Now we have to add the nodes. Now let's try to refer this graph and add the nodes.
Now, see, whenever you are adding the nodes, first of all, you can see start would be connected to the evaluate analysis, evaluate language, evaluate of thoughts.
Let's add that.
Add edges.
Yeah, so you can see start is connected with evaluate language, evaluate analysis, evaluate thoughts, evaluate analysis, evaluate language, evaluate thoughts.
Okay, that means these are the connection we have built.
Now evaluate analysis is connected with final evaluation, evaluate language is connected with final evaluation, and evaluation evaluate thought is connected to final evaluation.
Now I have to make this connection.
Now let me do that.
See, evaluate language is connected to the final evaluation, evaluate analysis is connected to the final evaluation, evaluate and heart is connected to the final evaluation.
That means this connection is also done. Now final evolution is connected to the end.
Now final evolution is connected to the final end. Okay, now we have to compile the graph.
Now if you print the workflow,
so that's how your workflow looks like, and now you can verify this workflow and this workflow.
Okay, these are same. Now I need to invoke this workflow. So for this, let's prepare another essay.
So I generated another essay from my chat GPT.
So this is another essay.
I named it as essay to okay. So this is the Inverted state in the age of AI, the infrastructure and capital superpower.
So I'm going to invoke it right now with my workflow.
So let's do that.
So first of all, here I have prepared initial state and I have given my assay.
Okay, then we are invoking the workflow, and this will return you the result.
Done. Now we'll print this result.
See, here you have all of the data. So this is the essay, this is the language feedback you got, this is the analysis feedback you got.
This is the clarity feedback you got, this is the overall feedback you got, this is the individual scores for from all of the nodes, okay, and this is the average score.
I hope you get it, guys.
See, amazing, right? So that's how we can create any kinds of LLM-based parallel workflow.
now I think it is pretty much clear, and the only things is that you have to understand the connection, you have to understand this graph
and the state, okay. The state you will be using here, and when to use this
reducer, when to use the pydentic, you have to understand
by seeing the problem statement. So, here two things you have learned.
I just used in this particular practical demo one is the piedentic, how to use pydentic to get the structured output, okay.
Then another one, this reducer.
So, reducer we already saw, right?
in the concept understanding, now we practically applied this reducer as well, okay, in the language graph. So, yes, guys, this is all about that's how we can create any kinds of parallel workflow.
Now, in the next video, I'm going to teach you some other workflow like conditional, iterative.
Okay, each and everything we'll try to discuss, then we'll also implement some amazing uh practical project, okay.
In our previous video, I have already discussed about uh parallel workflows, like how parallel workflow works, and we already
did the coding as well with help of line graph.
now let's try to understand this conditional workflows, and this conditional workflows would be more interesting because if you have already uh let's say learned
programming language, you know that inside programming language we have something called AFL's condition, right? So, based on this AFL's condition, we handle any kinds of conditional based scenario.
So, the same thing you can do inside line graph as well.
Whenever you are having a workflow, this is having some kinds of condition, you can handle this kinds of scenario with the help of this conditional workflows.
Okay, so make sure you watch this video till the end, don't miss anything.
And if you found this content useful, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like.
just hit the like, guys, because like is required if you like the session, so uh it will be uh it will be reaching to all the people out there so that they can also find these kinds of content,
and please try to share this video with your friends and family.
So, first of all, let me give you the idea about conditional workflows, then I will also show you how we can code with the help of line graph,
how we can implement this conditional workflow with the help of Langgraph.
So, here also I'm going to take two kinds of examples. I'm going to take the first example, non-lm-based uh conditional workflows.
First of all, I'm going to show you the non-lm based workflows, then after that, I'm also going to show you the LLM-based workflows. Okay, both we're uh we're gonna cover here.
So if you see here, um this is the conditional uh workflows, guys.
So this is uh similar to the uh parallel workflows. I think you already studied about parallel workflows. Okay, so let me show you.
So previously I already discussed about this parallel workflows, right? So in parallel workflows, what happens if you give a task?
So basically, here we are having multiple nodes, and all of the nodes would be executed independently. That means it will execute it will be executed in parallel, okay.
All together it will be executing, then whatever result I was getting, I was just aggregating and
Showing the results, okay. But inside this conditional workflow, this is
a little bit different.
Let me show you.
So inside conditional workflow, what will happen?
See, here also we are having multiple nodes, okay.
Uh in parallel, but these are actually condition.
Okay, these are actually condition.
That means let's say uh let's say whatever content we are sending.
So, first of all, it will analyze that after doing the analyze, it will perform a conditional statement. That means if this content is good, let's say it will approve that particular post.
If it is let's say
if it is let's say needs any human review, that time it will send to the human review, okay.
And it if it is having any kinds of problem, that time it will directly reject the post. That means here you are checking the condition based on the condition, you are executing one of the notes.
Okay, you are not executing all of the nodes, you are only executing one of the nodes, okay.
Let's say
this node can be executed based on the condition, or this node can be executed based on the condition, or this node can be executed based on the condition.
Okay, based on that you are ending the entire graph, but here it's not like that. Here you are executing all the nodes together, okay.
In parallel, you are executing, then you are aggregating the results and you are showing that. But here it's not like that. This is working as a field condition, okay. So let me show you.
See, here basically we'll just write a condition, okay? Let's say here the problem statement.
First of all, I'm going to show you.
this is actually content moderation system. This is the non-LM-based workflow. First of all, I'm going to create. Then, after that, I'm also going to show you how to create the LM-based workflow.
So, here basically we'll be creating a content moderation system for a social media platform.
It processes a user text post and evaluate it for spam and conditionally allowed it to be published.
Okay, published, either flagged for the human review.
If it is uh need any kinds of human review, it will try to send to the human review or it will automatically reject that particular post.
That means here we'll be basically deciding this kinds of statement based on the condition.
Okay.
Condition. We'll first of all check the content, whatever content user will post, whatever text user will post. We'll try to check that.
Okay, before checking that, we'll try to first of all format the post.
Format the post means I will show a message. Okay, I will show a message like let's say this is the user, he has posted this uh this this particular content.
After that, we'll analyze that, right? Analyze that.
So this analyze function will try to
analyze whether this is this is this particular post I can directly post or not if it doesn't have any kinds of violation or not.
Uh either if user is completely new to my platform, okay. First of all, I have to send this post for the review.
Okay, either if it is having any kinds of violation related post, I'll just try to reject that particular post.
Okay, so this is the condition.
So basically, here you are sending uh you are handling this kinds of condition
if-else condition okay, if else condition
if this post is fine, you are approving that okay.
If it is uh uh like uh uh if it uh
or if user is completely new user, okay, new user, you are sending for the human review
or else you are rejecting the post. That means there is there is a violation problem, okay. So this is a conditional based workflow. Now I think you got it.
What is the difference between this conditional workflows and the parallel workflows?
Okay, and to implement these workflows, guys, I need a state. So I already prepared this state as you can see.
I named it as moderation state, and I inherited with the type dict, and here I have taken some of the variable.
So the first one I have taken for the post content, that means whatever text user will pass, I'll try to save it here. Post content, and this should be a string type data.
Then user reputation. This is also user will pass.
User reputation means either user is a registered user or he is the new user.
Okay, let's see if user reputation is equal to is equal to let's say.
let's say the user is the user is let's say a trusted user okay trusted user means this is this user is already
registered user okay so that time I'll not send this post for the review.
Okay, this post won't be going for the review because the review I will only learn, I mean I will only execute whenever the user is completely new to my platform.
Okay? So, this, this statement will store here and this is going to be also string type data.
Then, formatted post: so whatever content user will give, give us, first of all, we'll try to format that particular post.
Format means I will give a message. let's say
let's say user says this is the post okay that that kind of like I'm going to just give a message.
Then content flag, content flag means here is the content flag. Basically all of the condition whether this should be approved or whether this should be rejected or whether this should be uh
flag for the human review.
Okay, so this kinds of condition I'll try to save inside content flag, and this is also going to be a string because here I'm going to store either approved, either review, either reject post.
Okay, that's why it's going to uh it's going to be string.
Then result. The final result, okay. Final result means whether the post has been approved.
Uh, that me, uh, it will give a message, right?
Let's say: "post automatically approved ," or "post flag for the human review ," or "post, uh, are already rejected ." Okay, this kinds of messages I want to show at the last.
That's why I have taken another variable called result, and this is also going to be a string.
Okay, I hope you got it guys. Now let's try to code inside language how we can create this graph, how we can create this workflow.
So, I think you already get it first. Of all, I have to create some of the nodes.
Okay, this node, this node, this node, this node, this node.
Okay, then I'll try to do the edge connection, and I will show you how we can handle these kinds of conditional workflow as well with the help of this,
this line graph. Okay, this can be also
discussed in this particular video. Now let me create a file first of all here,
so I'm going to create a file.
I'm going to create a new file.
I'm going to name it as
six content moderation workflow dot ipy n b.
Okay, this is a notebook file, so I'll take a code cell and here also I'll take the kernel.
So the first thing, guys, I have to import the necessary library and the I ... I think you know that, uh, what are the library we need, right?
So let's import.
So I need this
state, graph, start, end from Langgraph graph and type date.
Let's import them.
Then after that, we have to create this state, right?
So the same state I'm going to create here.
So, this is the state.
I have taken the post content, user reputation, then formatted post content flag and result.
So, first of all, now I'm going to
create the graph, okay? Then, after creating the graph, we'll try to add all of the nodes.
Now, let's create the graph.
So, graph is equal to state _graph. Then, I have given my state _moderation _state.
Then, after that, we'll just try to add the nodes.
Add the
okay? First of all, I'm going to add my first nodes, which is this one: format _post.
Let's add that.
Format post and this function I have to write, okay?
This format post python function I have to write separately, then the next
nodes I have to write: "this analyze content
," "analyze content" - okay, I have given the same name.
Then
the next node I have to create: "approve post
." Then next node, I have to create "flag for review
Then next node, I have to create this reject post.
Okay, now let me check whether I have any node or not. No, it's completely fine. I have created all the nodes.
Now we have to create all of this node one by one. So first of all, let's create the format post.
see
inside formatted post, I'm not going to do anything. This is the non-LM based workflow.
So I'm going to just write a simple Python code here.
So basically, whatever um let's say user is passing, input user is passing, let's user is passing post content and user reputation.
So I just created a formatted V string here.
So here I told user uh reputation. Okay, that means let's say user is trusted user. So here trusted user will come. That means user trusted user says post content.
That means whatever post he is giving this particular post, it will show here. Let's say user has given uh one post. Uh check out this amazing new product and buy now.
Okay, so this will show here inside this F string.
Okay, then after that, we are just returning this particular formatted post, okay?
Formatted because we created this formatted post and whatever formatted output we are generating, right?
We'll just try to store in the formatted post string.
Okay, we are storing uh storing here and we're returning it. And why we are not returning the entire state, guys?
Because in my previous uh previous video, I already told you about right. I uh whenever I created the parallel workflow, that time I told you.
Uh, if you are having this kind of scenario, that time don't use the entire state returning concept instead of that.
whatever state you are changing, only just try to return those state.
Okay, this is a good practice, okay.
Instead of returning the whole one, because here you are not changing inside that, okay.
After the execution node execution, you are not changing inside this particular variable, you are only changing inside that, right?
That's why don't return the entire state instead of whatever state you are changing, only just try to return that.
Okay, I hope you got it. So, this is our first node we have created. Now let's create the next one called
this analyze content. Okay, now analyze content would be very simple.
see here I just written a simple condition.
So see here I am giving my state and whatever post content we are having, first of all, we're doing the lower operation, okay.
Lower operation, then after that, we are checking the condition.
So as you can see, if spam in the content or by now in the content, see here we are only considering uh this particular post would be rejected based on some like
parameter, whether it should be a spam, whether it should be by now. If user is giving this kind of word in the text itself, I'm going to directly reject that particular content, okay?
Because this is a condition, I mean non LLM based one, so that's why I I just taken like manual verification, but whenever it would be LLM based, that time it would be more robust, okay?
But just for your understanding, I kept this particular easy example, so that's why I only consider two words one is spam, one is by now.
Okay, if it is present in the content, I'm going to directly reject that particular content, so flag would be rejected.
And If the state reputation if is equal to is equal to new user, that means I told you if user reputation is equal to is equal to new user, that means he is the completely new user on my platform.
First of all, I will review this particular post.
Okay, I'll send it for the review,
or else I am going to approve the post. Let's say if it doesn't have any kinds of spam content or it doesn't need any kinds of review, that means this content is fine. I am going to approve that.
Okay, that's why in the S block the flag is equal to approved. Then whatever flag we are getting based on the condition, we are just storing inside content flag.
Okay, here we are storing that and we are returning this particular state.
Okay, I hope you got it.
Now the next one I have to create for this approved post.
Okay, approved post. So this will basically return this approved message.
result is equal to post published successfully to the timeline, and result is equal to result. So we are studying inside result.
Okay.
Now we'll do it for the same for the flag review and reject post as well.
Now here also I'm going to just return the message for flag for review.
Post sent to the human moderation queue okay for the review and we are updating the result, okay.
And here you can see we don't need to
store all of the like result here because this is not required because this is a conditional workflow, so either one of the node would be executed, it
should not be executed all of the node, right?
Like that.
Okay, so previously it was executing all of the node and I was I was collecting all of the ratings, okay, and I was storing inside a list.
That's why I I uh I used actually reducer concept here, but here reducer concept is not required because here either one of the nodes would be executed,
and I only need to save one particular result. Okay, that's why this is completely
string type. Okay, I haven't taken any kinds of reducer type here, okay.
Every time it will uh replace that.
Then the next one I have for the reject post.
Reject post.
So as you can see, uh post automatically deleted due to the policy violation, and we are updating the result.
That's it.
So let's execute this one,
and I will execute this one also execute this one, okay.
Once it is done, now uh I have to
I have to
do the edge connection, okay.
So, first of all, let's do the edge connection, then I will show you how we can handle the conditional scenario.
So, here let's try to do the edge connection,
add
the edges.
So, first of all, you can see the edge connection would be start to formatted post. Okay, let's try to do that.
Start to formatted post.
Okay, then the next one formatted post to analyze content,
formatted post to analyze content, okay.
Then after that,
what we have
uh we have
we have this connection okay, but this connection will build up based on the condition. Either
analyze content will return
this particular output to the approved post or flag review post or rejected post. Okay, now this conditional statement will come come into picture.
Okay, now this conditional statement will come into picture. So let's say, if I'm not adding the condition, if I'm directly just, let's say this, these nodes are not there.
I'm directly just adding this analyze content to the end.
analyze content to the end,
analyze content
to the
end.
Okay, now,
if I compile the graph, and if I show you the workflow,
Okay, uh, there should not be any quotation. that's why it's coming. there.
If I execute, this workflow is created. Now, if I show you the workflow, now see the workflow looks like that.
So this is the workflow right now.
Okay, but I created the nodes already, right? So if I let's say
comment is at the node, now if I execute,
see
this will look like that. So start formatted post, then analyze content and end.
Okay.
Uh let's say these are the nodes are not there.
Okay, but now I have to create this node because I have to handle the conditional statement. Now let's uncomment that.
Now here I'll just try to add the condition. Now I'll remove this one, okay.
Now here only you have to add the condition.
Now see if you want to add a condition, okay.
If you want to add a condition,
so you have to use this function
add conditional edge. Okay, there is a function inside graph called add conditional edge.
Inside that you have to
uh you have to give a function object, okay. Condition function object.
Okay, condition function object, and you have to provide from where to it will go to the conditional function.
Let's say you can see condition will start after this analyze content. Okay, so here I'll just write
analyze content, okay.
Analyze content,
yeah.
Now from analyze content, it will either go to the
it will either go to the approved post, flag for review, or rejected post. Okay, now I have to write this conditional function.
Now separately I have to create another function.
So this is the function, guys.
Okay, this is the function.
Now we have to import this literals, okay.
Literal from
this typing.
Okay, now see.
Whenever you are writing any kinds of condition, this code would be common.
See, I have named this function as check condition, and it will also take this state, okay, and it will return
it will return the nodes. Okay, you can see we are giving the nodes name, analyze content, approved, okay.
Sorry, approve post,
flag for review and reject post. That means these are the nodes appropriate post, flag for review, reject post, okay?
Because these are my node name, right?
So this function basically what happens, see this function takes this state and it returns either one of this particular node, okay, based on the condition.
Now let's try to see the condition.
See if my state flag, I already calculated the state flag, guys, here, right?
If it is if it is uh let's say approved, that means my approved post
approved post node would be written.
That means this node would be written. That means that time only this node would be executed, not these are the nodes. Okay, then
if my content flag is equal to review, that means only flag for review will be executed.
That means if my flag post is equal to is equal to let's say
review, that means this this particular node will be executed, not these two nodes.
Then
if either none of them, then rejected post post would be written.
That means if it is not approved post and flag for debut, then reject node would be executed. Okay, in exact node would be written.
So this is the logic we have written here.
That's why we are using this literal. Literal means you can return the node object here, okay. You can return the node object, that's why we have to give this particular syntax.
and this syntax uh basically recommended by Langgraph. If you check the Langgraph documentation, you will see that they have also given the same thing.
Okay, so this is the condition function you have to write whenever you want to use these kinds of conditional edges, okay.
If you want to handle this kinds of conditional scenario, that time you have to write this kinds of function. Now, this function object you have to just provide here, okay.
After this analyze content, you have to provide this
function object check condition.
That's it.
Okay, now what will happen after analyze content?
This particular connection would be either with this particular node or with this particular node or with this particular node, okay.
But you don't know which one because it will check the condition based on the condition, which condition will match, it will go to that particular node.
Okay, that's why we have written the condition.
Okay, I hope you got it. Now, this connection is also done.
This connection is also done. Now it will uh do the connection either one of them.
Okay, now you have to make this kind of connection.
That means Approved post will be connected to the end, flag for review will connect to the end, and reject post will also connect to the end. Okay, now let's do the do this connection.
So here
I will
just do the connection.
So this is the connection.
You can see Approved post is connected to the end, then flag for review, it is also connected to the end.
Okay, then reject post will be also connected to the end. Then we are compiling the graph.
Now if I execute the graph, uh okay, check condition is not defined because I have to execute this function.
literal is not defined. Okay, sorry. I have to also import it first of all.
Then I will execute,
then I will compile the graph.
After that, now let me show you the workflow.
Now, see, guys, this workflow and this workflow is same.
Okay, I hope you got it, guys.
How we are handling these kinds of conditional scenario, okay.
I know I hope you already got it, right?
Only the change is that
you have to use this can uh use this function, add conditional edges, and this add conditional edges takes the uh previous connection,
okay.
Previous connection, and it takes the condition condition function because condition function will decide after that which node should be connected,
okay. Either approved post, either flag post, either rejected post.
Okay, but it should not be executed all together, it would be only executed either one of them based on the condition.
This is what we have done, guys.
Now let me check this workflow.
So I'll invoke this workflow. First of all, let's define initial state.
So this is our initial state.
So first of all, I have given the post content.
Check out this amazing new product and buy now, and then i have given the user reputation. Let's say this is the trusted user, already registered user.
Then we're invoking the workflow, and this workflow will give me a result.
Result. Okay.
Now, if I print this result,
now see guys, this is the post user has given.
User reputation is trusted user, and we are formatting that particular
uh post. So you can see user trusted user says check this amazing product by now.
Content flag is rejected.
Okay, why it is rejected? Because it is having buy now, and we already did the condition check here.
Buy now, buy now here.
So if buy now is present in the content, it would be rejected. Okay, so that's why
you can see content flag is rejected and result is also post automatically deleted due to the policy violation.
Okay, now let's say here I'm not giving this by now.
By now, I will remove it now. If I execute the workflow again, now see uh right now it is approved because it doesn't have any kinds of violation.
Uh again, user is a trusted user, so it doesn't need any kinds of approval.
Okay, uh it doesn't need any kinds of review, that's why directly approved and post published successfully.
Okay, now let's say user is new user.
New user. Okay.
Now see, although this uh um I mean content is fine, but still it will
okay. I have to execute.
Then result, So although see, although this content is fine, but still it is waiting for the review because I have to first of all
check the user because he is not registered in my platform, that's why it is going for the review, and you can see post send to the human moderation
P.
Okay, I hope you got it, guys. That's how this conditional workflow is working,
okay. That's how this conditional uh conditional workflow is working. So, whatever message you are giving, based on that, it is first of all checking the condition.
Okay, after checking the condition, it is executing either one of this particular notes, okay? Not all the nodes altogether.
I hope you got it, guys. So, this is what our non LLM based workflow.
Now let's try to discuss the LLM-based workflow as well.
So, guys, so far we have seen the non-LLM-based workflow, conditional workflows, and I showed you how it works, right? How we can handle the conditional scenario.
Now let's try to learn the LLM-based conditional workflows. Okay, now we'll be using large language model, but previously I didn't use any kinds of large language model here, okay.
Everything I handled manually.
So, see if I
first of all explain the problem statement we are gonna create here.
So this is going to be a
review reply system. Review reply system means let's say here uh user will give a review, okay.
User will give a review, and what we have to do, we have to uh give a reply to that particular review.
Now, review can be anything, whether it should be a positive review, it should be a negative review. Let's say uh we are working, we are working in a tech company, right? We are selling a product.
Let's say we have created a software, right?
So in that software, uh uh let's say I I have uh made a subscription plan and some of the user have taken their subscription.
Okay, now definitely they will be using your product, and based on the product, actually they will give some kinds of uh like um I mean
review, right?
on your product, and uh as a let's say company owner, uh what you have to do definitely you have to take care about the um uh
user review. Okay, whatever user is giving the review, uh you have to take care. If they are giving the positive review, that means it's completely fine. Your product is amazing.
Okay, you don't need to change inside your product, but if they are getting some if they are giving some negative review, that means if they're having some of the issue,
definitely you have to handle their issue, right? So you just think in that way. So basically, user will give a review.
First of all, what we'll do is just try to check the sentiment of that review, whether this is a positive review or whether this is a negative review,
and whenever I want to do this sentiment check, right? So definitely I have to use a large language model here.
So here I'm I'll be using a large language model, and this large language model either will return the positive,
either it will return the negative.
That means this is also a structured output. And if I want to get the structured output, guys, what I have to do, I have to use the pydentic. I already uh showed you in my previous lecture as well.
Whenever I created that parallel workflow, that time I also told you uh with the help of Pydentic, uh, you can uh get the structured output.
Okay, you have to just create a schema and you have to provide the schema to the model, and model will work in uh in that way.
And for this, you have to learn the Pydentic and Pydentic video I already have in my playlist. Please try to check that.
Okay, so this particular node will return either positive or negative based on the review.
I will be using a large language model, large language model will like analyze that, analyze the sentiment, and based on that, it will give me positive either negative.
Okay, if it is positive, so see here your condition statement is working. If let's say this particular sentiment is positive, that means I'll generate a positive response, okay?
Positive reply to the Customer okay, but if it is negative, if this review is negative, sentiment is negative.
So again, I am running another node called run diagnosis.
Okay, so what this run diagnosis will do basically I want to
analyze this particular review
in little more depth because I want to understand what is the uh what is the issue they are having, okay. What is their main concern? I have to analyze that.
That's why I will be running another notes called run diagnosis. So this run diagnosis will return three things one is the issue type. First of all, it will return the issue type.
What is the issue related?
Whether the issue is coming from UI U uh UX, okay, uh, or whether it is coming from performance, or whether it is kinds of bugs or whether they need any kinds of support or any other things.
Okay, I have to understand the issue type, then I have to understand the tone, whether they're angry, frustrated, disappointed, or calm.
Okay, I have to understand the user, then I have to understand their urgency, whether this urgency is low, medium, or high.
Okay, based on that, definitely I have to uh take the actions, okay. Otherwise, I can't sell my product anymore, right?
Then once I got these are the let's see, should I based on that, okay, I will be generating a reply, negative uh uh
like reply to that particular user. Let's say I'll tell okay, you are getting this kinds of UI related problem, you you are very angry, okay, and your urgency is high.
So definitely uh we'll our team will look into that immediately, or if it is low, uh so you just wait for three to two days. I will look into that. Okay, so this kinds of reply will try to generate.
Okay, I hope you got it. This workflow.
Uh, now you can see here this is the workflow, this is a conditional workflow, but we'll be solving with the help of LLM.
Okay, so we will be LLM LLM, we'll be using the LLM uh two um uh two times here.
So in this particular nodes, and here also we'll be using the LLM to run this diagnosis. I need another LLM.
Okay, with the help of LLM, we will try to generate these at the structure, and again, this would be a structured output, okay.
So every time whenever I run this nodes, run diagnosis node, LLM will return three things issue type, tone, and urgency. Again, I have to use Pydentic for that, okay.
Pydentic for that will be creating a schema and we'll generate this structure output.
Okay, so this is what we'll be implementing, guys, right now. And for this, whatever state I need, I already created the state as you can see. I named it as review state, inherited with type dict.
So, first of all, whatever review user will give me, I will store in the review, and this should be string.
And uh, our this node will try to find the sentiment, okay. Sentiment of the review.
So either it would be a positive or negative.
you can either create it as a string, either you can create it as a literal type.
In literal type, you can mention because this is a category, right? Either it would be positive or negative, it kinds of category, so that's why we have taken this literal type.
You can also take a string type, it will also work. Okay, I have taken literal type, so positive and negative, okay. Sentiment should be positive or negative, and diagnosis.
So, diagnosis will return three things that means tone, type, tone, and angry.
Okay, so this this should this structure should be a dictionary type. You can see this is the key, this is the value. This is the key, this is the value, right?
So that's why I have taken this should be a dictionary type and the response.
Whatever response I'll try to generate, whether I should I'll generate a positive response or negative response, it will come here, and they say uh again this would be a string type.
Okay, I hope you got it. Now we can start coding inside line graph, guys.
Okay, so what I will do, guys, I will create another file here.
Let's create another file.
I'm going to name it as
uh
review workflow.
I'll take the code cell, select the kernel,
fine. So the first thing, guys, what I have to do, I have to import all the necessary library. So let's import.
And here we'll be using LLM. So again, I'm going to use my uh openEI model. I already have the API key inside my.
Okay, you can either use any other model as well, it's completely fine.
yeah.
Then after that, I need this typing
type dict and literal from typing.
Then I also need to load this.env. For this, I need this dot env load env function, and I also need to import the py identific, okay? Because I have to generate a structured output.
So py identific, I need base model and field.
So please try to see in my playlist, guys.
This tutorial is already there.
So here is the playlist, guys. Complete agent tore, and here is the py identific video. Please try to go ahead with this pydentic. You will try to understand, okay.
And previously I also uh discussed about this uh uh sequential workflow and parallel workflow. Okay, that this concept you have to also understand, okay. If you are understanding this um
uh conditional workflow, because each of the workflow is uh something is like connected with each other.
That means if you can understand uh our workflow, then you can relate with another workflow, okay.
So that's why this is required, and the way I have structured this course or course, right? Step by step, this is interconnected between.
So if you missed out the previous session, so I think it would be a little bit confusing, okay, for the current session.
So that's why I'm telling you, just try to go ahead with the previous session, yeah.
So yeah, so after that, I'll first of all load the environment variable.
Okay, now let's initialize the model LLM model.
So here I have taken GPT photo mini.
Yeah, now I told you I have to generate this I have to create this structure.
So
yeah, so I told you this fine sentiment nodes will give you two things either positive or negative.
Okay, for this I will create a structured output, and for run diagnosis node, I will create a structured output that means it will generate three things: one is issue type, tone, and
urgency, right? So for this, let's try to write this piedantic uh class.
So this is the first class I have written for this sentiment.
Okay, so basically, this will return two uh uh two things positive or negative based on the
review. Okay, so this is going to be my first actually structured output from my LLM.
Okay, so maybe I can show you.
So let's create an object
of a model.
Yeah, so let's say structured model is equal to model dot with structured output. I have given the sentiment schema. Now see if I show you the output,
let's say I've generated this uh structured model. Now, if I give any kinds of
if I give any kinds of let's say prompt here,
let's say this is the prompt. What is the sentiment of the following review?
This software is too good.
Okay, now I'll give it to my
Now, see here I'm not using the direct model, I'm giving my structured model. Okay, now I am doing the inbox operation and I am only getting the sentiment
now. See.
See positive, it will either return positive or negative. Now let's say here I've give
to bad.
Now this will return me negative.
Okay, so this is the structured output, and if you want to get these kinds of output, you have to use the piden t okay, schema for that. So the same thing I will also write for my diagnosis
So this is for my diagnosis node.
Okay, so again I'm inheriting with the base model of the piedentic, and here I have written the issue type, tone, and urgency. So this uh uh node will return this three things issue type.
Now here I have given some of the hint like I need uh issue type should be uix performance bug support and others.
Here I've given the field description, the category of the issue mentioned in the review, then tone, angry, frustrated, disappointed, calm, the emotion tone expressed by the user,
urgency, low, medium, high, how urgent to uh or critical the issue appears to be. Okay, so this thing I have discussed in my piedentic uh uh class. Okay, so I already talked about what is this
literal, what is this field, what is the description, each and everything I have already discussed.
Okay, so this is another structured output we have created.
Okay, now you can also test for this. You can create another uh
another model.
So let's say I have named this model as structured model to model
with structured output, and we are giving the diagnosis schema here, and this is going to be my another object, okay.
Okay, I'm getting an output. Okay, I have to execute this one.
Now I'll execute now. See this is working. Now you can also give a prompt, and you can
you can basically do the analysis. Let's say
now I'll call this model
okay. Uh structured model 2, Now I'm giving the same prompt.
Now I want to see the
output.
now see
uh type is other tone is disappointed, urgency is medium.
Okay, so this is returning three things.
Okay, I hope you got it.
Now what I'm going to do, I'm going to simply
create the
state. Okay, now I have to prepare the state.
So let's define the state, the same state.
so this is the state, review state, review, sentiment, diagnosis and response.
It's done now.
I'll define the notes.
Okay, I have given my state here.
Now add the nodes.
So now see the nodes,
how many nodes you are having?
Find sentiment, then you have positive response, you have run diagnosis, you have negative response. Okay, these are the nodes.
Let's add one by one.
So these are the nodes, find sentiment, positive response, run diagnosis, and negative response. Okay, now I have to create these are the functions one by one.
Okay, so let's create
first of all. I will create find sentiment.
So this is the function.
This is the note, find sentiment. It will take this state, and here I have given a prompt for the following review.
Please find out the sentiment, and here we are giving the review.
review is present inside our state, okay.
And here we are getting the sentiment from the model, and we are calling the structured model that is the first model, and first model I think returns the only the sentiment,
whether positive or negative.
Okay, we're getting the sentiment and we are updating the sentiment and we're returning this particular sentiment only, okay, instead of returning the whole state.
Then
uh I'm going to write the next notes, which is uh
positive response.
Positive response. Okay.
So again, it is taking the state and we are preparing the prompt.
Write a warm thank you message in response to this review.
So we are giving the review.
Also, kindly ask user to leave feedback on our website. Let's see. That means if the review is completely positive, at that time I want to just give us thank you message to the user.
Okay, and I will tell also just please leave a feedback to the website.
Then once it is done, we are giving to the model and see we are not using any structured model here, we are giving the main model
because why here I don't need any kinds of structured output because it will only generate some kinds of thank you masses, okay?
And I don't need any kinds of structured output, that's why I'm giving the original model and whatever content it is returning. I'm just saving inside my response.
Okay, done now.
Next thing I have to create my diagnosis,
run diagnosis.
So this is the run diagnosis again. It is taking the state, and here I preparing the prompt diagnosis. This negative review we are giving the review, return, issue type, tone, and urgency.
So we are executing this structure to model,
okay. And basically, this will return these three things,
and whenever we are getting, we are updating my
uh diagnosis. You can see we are updating the diagnosis because diagnosis type is dictionary,
and this will also have dictionary type output.
Okay, we are doing that
now.
Once it is done, I will do it for my next one negative response,
negative response.
So we are passing the state, then we are
taking the diagnosis, okay.
Then we are preparing the prompt, you are the supportive assistant, you uh the user headed issue type, then tone, then urgency.
Based on that, just write a empath uh empathetic helpful resolution message, and we are involving the
actual model, and whatever response we are getting, we are updating the response.
Okay, so that's how we are getting all of the node one by one.
Now my node is ready. Now, what I have to do, guys, I have to
make the edge connection.
Now let's do the edge connection.
So add edges with condition.
So first of all, the age connection should be start to find sentiment.
Start to find sentiment.
Okay, start to find sentiment.
Then you have to take the conditional is right now because either it will go to the positive response, either it will go to the run
diagnosis.
Okay, so here we'll just write the condition right now.
Uh
yeah,
so this is the conditional edges.
So see, it will
uh start from uh find sentiment and either it will connect to the positive, either it will connect to the negative.
So that's why we have taken the find sentiment. Now we have to write the check sentiment function.
I think previous also we have created a conditional function, right?
And this conditional function is written uh returning your nodes based on the condition. Either it will return this node, this node, or this node.
Okay, we'll write the same thing here.
So let's write this function.
Uh very simple function.
That's why I told you this code would be common everywhere whenever you are using conditional based workflow.
So, see, this is the function I have written.
Check statement uh sentiment, it will take the state and it will return the
uh notes.
Either positive response node, okay, either positive response node, either run diagnosis node.
That means this run diagnosis node, okay. Based on the condition, now where I will check the condition in the sentiment. If the sentiment is positive, I will return the positive node.
positive response node, okay. That means this node will be written, or if it is negative, I will return this run diagnosis node. That means this node would be written.
Okay, I hope you got it, guys.
So that's why we have to give this particular function here. Now, this function will decide which node should be caught.
Okay, so once it is done, now let's say this connection is done.
Okay, now this connection is done. Now I have to make the other connection.
Now, what will happen?
this positive will connect to the end, then run diagnosis will connect to the negative response, and negative response will connect to the end.
Okay, we'll try to make this connection right now.
So this is the connection.
Yeah, so you can see positive response is connected to the end,
then run diagnosis will connect it to the negative response.
Okay, if let's say diagnosis run successfully, we got the issue type tone and urgency will connect to the negative, we'll generate the negative response,
and negative response will connect it to the end. It is connected to the end.
Okay, I hope you got the connection.
Now let's define the workflow, compile the workflow.
Compile the workflow.
Now let's execute.
Done.
Now, if I show you the workflow,
so this is the workflow, guys. Now this workflow and this workflow is same.
You can check.
Find sentiment positive, run diagnosis negative, and okay, completely fine.
Now let's uh invoke this workflow.
So, what I can do,
I can give a positive
positive uh
positive review first of all.
So I will generate from ChatGPT. I will just tell, "generate a or
write a positive
review for a
tech software
in short.
Okay. now I'll copy this and
what I'm going to do. I'm going to add inside my
initial state.
So
let me define my initial state.
So in the review itself, I'll try to write my item.
Now
let's invoke the workflow.
And this will give me the result.
Now I'll print the result.
Now see,
this uh this is the review, and the sentiment is positive, and response is also positive.
Their username, thank you for your wonderful field. Uh uh here to that our software made such a positive okay.
Your kinds of word means a lot, blah blah blah, and also please give a
review in us inside our website.
Okay, now let's give a negative response as well.
Now I'll generate another one. Now uh
negative review.
what I can do, I can copy the same code.
Only I'll just change this review.
So I will invok the result uh workflow and print the result.
Okay, now we are getting the
negative. You can see this sentiment is negative, and diagnosis we got issue type is performance, tone is frustrated, urgency is high, and this is the
negative response we are writing.
We are here to help you with the performance issue by user, blah blah blah.
Okay, so amazing that means it's working fine, okay. And I think you got how we have created the entire workflow with the help of this conditional workflow.
Get it so now I think you can create any kinds of conditional workflow. Either it is non LLM based or llm based, it doesn't matter.
You can create it. Only you just need to understand this conditional connection.
Okay, if you understand this conditional connection, then you will be able to create any kinds of conditional workflow.
So, guys, in this video, I'll be discussing about the last workflows inside Langgraph, which is iterative workflows.
So far, I have discussed about sequential workflows, parallel workflows, conditional workflows.
Okay, each and everything I have already covered.
If you haven't checked those videos, it is already available inside my playlist. I have given the link in the description.
From there, you can check it out.
So, this is going to be a very important and interesting workflows, guys, inside Langgraph, because with the help of iterative workflows, you can perform the looping operation.
So, let's say whenever you are performing any task and if you feel like this task needs some more improvement,
you can continuously actually perform the looping operation with the help of this iterative workflows. So we'll try to understand this one.
So if you found my content useful, guys, and if you are really learning okay from this particular playlist, I would like to request you please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like
and please try to share this with your friends and family. So if you are supporting me, guys, if you are supporting my channel, I'll be getting more motivation to bring these kinds of content.
So if you uh see, guys, uh here is the iterative workflows we'll be discussing about. So previously I already discussed about all the workflows
I told you about inside Langgraph, like sequential workflows. You have understood the LLM non LLM based, okay.
Then I have discussed about the parallel workflows, then I discussed about the conditional workflows, okay.
Now we'll try to understand this iterative workflows. So you can see this is the iterative workflows graph. I already created this particular graph.
So, guys, to make you understand this iterative workflows, I'm going to take one amazing example.
I'm going to take Facebook post generation example.
So, what happens? Let's say I want to post anything on my Facebook. Let's say I want to post any kinds of tech related content on my Facebook.
So nowadays, actually, what will happen? I will be definitely using Chat GPT or any other large language model, let's say provider, and I'll try to generate that content,
okay.
And what I will do, I will
copy that and I will post on my Facebook, okay.
But it's not like that at the very first time you will be getting the perfect post, right? Let's say you have given a prompt and it has generated something for the first time, right?
It's not like that that should be 100% uh perfect and optimize uh for for you for your needs.
So maybe you just need to do some little bit let's say change or you need some improvement, you need some optimization.
So again, what you will do, you will you will uh send it to the LLM and you will try to tell okay, try to optimize it more.
Okay, so once you have let's say optimized another one, again you will try to review that, evaluate that if it is perfect for you, then you will try to approve and you will post it over the Facebook.
Okay, otherwise, you will again do the optimization.
Okay, so that's how let's say we usually Generate any kinds of content from the LLM, right? So why not we can create an automatic workflow?
So this workflow will automatically generate let's say Facebook content based on the topic you have provided,
then after that, it will automatically evaluate that whether this content is perfect or not.
Okay, let's say after doing the evaluation it found okay, this is useful, this is fine, then it will approve.
Then you can post over the Facebook, otherwise, it will send it to uh send it to the another, let's say, nodes, and that nodes will try to do the optimization, okay.
Optimization it will optimize
like
it will do some improvement, then after that, again it will try to send it to the evaluator.
Okay, evaluate will again evaluate that if found let's say this content is fine, then it will approve, otherwise, again it will try to send it to the optimizer,
then optimizer again it will optimize the content and it will again send it for the evaluation.
Okay, so that's how this kind uh this particular loop will continuously run unless and until this content is approved.
Okay, so this is called actually iterative workflows.
So to make iterative workflows, guys, we are using conditional workflows as well, as you can see, because here is the condition if
this content is completely fine after doing the evaluation, it will approved.
Okay, otherwise it will send it to the optimizer, and optimizer will uh like do the improvement and it will again send it to the evaluator.
Okay, so here is the looping concept, and this looping concept we call it as the iterative workflows inside line graph.
Now we'll try to implement this particular workflows okay inside line graph, and for this, whatever state I need, guys. I already prepared the state as you can see.
This is the state I named it as post state and I inherit it with the type dict.
So, first of all, I have taken a variable called topic, so user will pass a topic, okay. Uh for post generation.
Let's say I have given a topic related uh let's say agentic AI, so it will generate some kinds of post related agentic AI. Okay, so let's say uh I'll uh send it to the generate llm, right?
Here we'll be using a llm. Then this uh
this uh llm or let's say this node will generate the post, okay? Let's say this post I'm going to save inside this post variable, and this is also going to be string type data.
Then after that, we'll try to send it to the evaluator. Evaluator will also use a llm, right?
Large language model, and it will evaluate that particular result. And it will send two things one is the approved, another is the needs improvement.
Okay, if it is sending returning approved, that means this post is completely fine. We can directly approve that.
And if it is sending needs improvement, okay, that time we'll try to send it to the optimizer, okay, and it will also give you some kinds of feedback.
Okay, let's say what should be the improvement, it will also send it to the optimizer. This feedback will try to save inside this particular variable.
Then
uh we'll also try to see the iteration. Iteration means let's say it has given this content to the evaluator.
Evaluator tells okay, this needs the improvement, again it will send it to the optimizer.
Optimizer will try to again generate a new or let's say optimize that particular post and it will again send it to the evaluator. That means one iteration is done.
Then again, it uh evaluator will try to check that again. Let's say it will tell it needs the improvement, again it will try to send it to the optimizer.
Optimizer again it will improve that, again it'll send to the evaluator.
That means iteration goes to that means how many loops it is performing will try to log that particular information in this iteration variable.
Okay, and here we'll also set a maximum iteration. Let's say if you don't set this maximum iteration, what uh what is the possibility?
Let's say if you are using any very poor lar language based model, that time let's say every time whatever content it will generate, maybe your evaluator will
not evaluate that or let's say approve that that time this particular loop will continuously running, okay? We'll not get any final result.
That's why we'll set a maximum iteration, let's say four to five.
So after four or five let's say iteration, this particular loop will break, and whatever content we got after four or five iteration, that I will try to make it as
final post.
Okay, that's why this maximum iteration will also set.
Then whatever let's say post we are generating, whatever feedback we are getting, okay, from this evaluator, we'll also try to save inside this particular variable as a history.
That's why we made it as post history and feedback history. That means it will continuously add.
Okay, it will not replace, it will continuously add. So that's why we'll be using reducer concept. I think you know what is reducer inside Langgraph. You can see we are using annotated.
We are uh we have taken the list type data structure.
And we are using operation.add, that means every time it will add the post story and feedback story instead of replacing.
But here we are we haven't taken any kinds of reducer, it will continuously replace here.
Okay, I hope you got it. Then let's say once this improvement is done, evaluator will let's say found this is useful or this is completely fine.
That time this would be approved and this loop would be break.
Okay, so this is what actually iterative workflows. Now we'll try to um we'll try to code inside Langgraph, then we'll try to understand the whole concept, okay.
Now for this, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to simply open up this uh iterative workflows.ip minb file and let's select our kernel.
So, first of all, we have to import the necessary library.
So let's import.
So I'll import all of the necessary library. So you can see I'm I'm importing the state graph, start end, then from typing, I'm importing type dict, literal, and annotated.
Then uh I'm using chat openai.
That means I'll be using OpenAI large language model. You can use any kinds of large language model for this. I have one.
Then uh I'm importing the system message and human message.
Okay, where we are importing the system message and human message because I want to give the prompt for each and every LLM. So you can see here we'll be using the LLM.
Here also we'll be using the LLM for optimization. Also, we'll be using the LLM.
Okay, and every LLM I'll try to set a different different prompt. Let's say for generation one, I will set a generation related prompt for evaluator.
I'll set evaluation related prompt for optimization. I'll set optimization related prompt.
Okay, so you can directly give the prompt as well, but it is recommended to use this system message and human message function whenever you are giving the prompt. Okay, this should be more optimized.
One then operator, I need because I want to perform the reducer, I have to do the adding operation, then dot enb.
So let's import all of them.
So as you can see, execution is complete now.
We'll load our environment variable
now. Um we'll define all the large language model.
So here you can see
um, yeah.
So I need uh three large language model. one is for generation, one is for evaluator, one is for optimization.
Okay, so what I'm going to do, I'm going to make three objects for three large language models.
Uh see, I'm going to use the same model only, but I'm going to create uh three objects, okay?
Because here I told you we'll be using three no three nodes, okay, differently.
So whenever you are creating this kinds of project, let's say in real time, actual real project, that time you have to select this large language
model in such a way. So let's say whatever model is very good for generation, that time you can use that particular model.
Let's say some model is very much good for evaluation, that time you can take that particular model. Let's say some model is very much good for optimization, you can take that particular model.
Okay, so that's how we have to select in real time, but right now we are only understanding the example. That's why I have taken the same model, but I created three objects.
Okay, one is for generator, evaluator, and optimizer.
Generator, evaluator, and optimizer.
Done now. Next, uh, I'm going to
uh I'm going to define this state, but before defining this tech, I already told you here.
See this evaluator, this evaluator nodes will return you two things, okay.
One is the evaluation, okay. Evaluation uh that means it should be approved or
needs improvement.
Okay, these two things, and another one is the feedback.
Okay, what should be the feedback for the optimization, right? So it will generate two things.
I don't need anything, anything else apart from these two two things. One is the evaluation, and another one is the feedback.
So if I want to get this kind of structured output, what I have to do, I have to use the pydentic. I already told you previously also I have also taken the same example.
So, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to just create a
um pydentic class.
As you can see, I have created a pydentic class.
So here I have named it as post evaluation. I'm inheriting with the Piedentic base model, and two things I have taken evaluation and feedback.
So in evaluation, you can see this is the literal type, it should be approved or needs approved.
Okay, needs improvement, and another one is the feedback that means it will generate some kinds of feedback for Facebook post. That means if I now pass this thing to the model, that means if I
add this line uh evaluator LLM with structured output, and if I pass this class, this model will try to generate the structured output now.
So it will only give you evaluation and feedback, not anything else. Okay, now let me show you.
So let's say I have defined this one.
Now here
I'm going to just generate a Facebook post from my chat GPT.
Facebook post
about
genetic AI.
Okay, I'll copy this
and let's say here
I can take a variable post.
Now I said that I'm going to paste this post.
Okay.
Now I'm going to send it to the
structured evaluation LM.
Done. Now if I show you the result,
see this is giving you two things. One is the evaluation.
You can also extract evaluation,
approved, and the feedback.
See, this is the feedback for this particular post. Okay. So that's how every time we'll be getting this structured output from this
uh large language model.
Okay, the evaluated large language model because we have used Python
um uh data evaluation for that.
Now, what I'm going to do, guys. Next, I'm going to define the state. I'm going to define the same state I have taken here.
this is my state as you can see.
Topic post evaluation, feedback, iteration, max iteration, post history and feedback history. So here I have added the reducer concept.
So every time I will try to add this uh to information instead of replacing, and these are the things I think you already got it, right?
Yeah,
and why I have taken literal here because evaluation will only return two things approved or need needs approvement. Okay, this two categories that's why I have taken literal type instead of string.
So now I'll um I will um add my nodes,
Let's define the graph and add the nodes.
Yeah, so I have already defined the graph.
You can see state graph. I have given this post state here.
Now I'll add the node.
Add
node.
So how many nodes we are having?
One, two, three.
Okay, three nodes we are having.
We'll add this three node all together,
Yeah, so these are three nodes generate post, evaluate post, and optimize post.
Okay, generate, evaluate, and optimize.
Now we'll write this function one by one.
So, first of all, we'll just try to write this generate post function node.
So, this is the function, guys. I've already written as you can see.
generate post, it will take the state, and here is the prompt I have prepared. It's a detail prompt I created with the help of chat GPT.
And here we are using the system message and human message function, whatever I have imported from here.
Okay, so as you can see, this is the prompt.
So system message I have given you are a funny and clever Facebook influencer and human message.
Write a short original and hilarious Facebook post on the topic, whatever topic user will give.
And here I have assigned some rules do not use a question answer format max maximum uh 500 characters. Okay, and blah blah blah. These are the things I have added.
Now, after that, I am just uh invoking my generator LLM and whatever content I'm getting, I'm just updating the response inside the post and post
history. I am also updating because simultaneously update two things one is the post and it is the post history.
Both I'll update, right? So here it will replace every time, here it will add every time because here we are using reducer concept and we are returning this particular state.
Okay, instead of returning whole state, we are only returning the state we are changing.
So this is our generate post nodes we have created. That means this node is complete. Now let's try to add the evaluator one.
Generate is done. Now we'll try to create the evaluator one.
So this is the evaluator one, guys. Again, I named it as evaluate post and sending this state, and here is the prompt, guys. I have prepared again. I have given a system prompt.
So this is the system prompt I have given.
Okay, now this is the human prompt.
Evaluate the following Facebook post. we have given the post from the state, and here are some criteria I have given.
Based on that, it will try to evaluate and it will return two things: one is the evaluation approved or need improvements, and the one is the feedback.
Then we are uh invoking our structured evaluator LLM. That means this one, okay.
This one we are invoking this one instead of uh this one because here we have added the Pydentic class for the structured output.
See, and whatever evaluation result we are getting, we are sending uh saving to the evaluator state, evaluation state, and feedback also.
Uh, I'm saving inside feedback, and I'm also saving the feedback story because feedback story should be also updated.
Okay, yeah, so once it is done, uh we are also returning the state.
Now let's
execute
done now. We'll try to create the last one which is optimized post.
So this is for the optimized post again. We are passing the state, and here is the prompt. You are a punch uh a Facebook post or virality and humor based on the given feedback.
Then here is the human prompt I have given. Improve the Facebook post based on this feedback.
We are giving the feedback, we are giving the topic as well as the original post it uh my model has generated.
Okay, so based on the original post, based on the feedback, based on the topic, it will optimize that post. Okay, and it will rewrite that particular post and it will give it to you.
For this, I'm hitting this optimizer llm and getting the response, and we are updating the iteration here.
See here, we are updating the iteration, like how many iteration it has to perform to give the final or let's say optimized version of the post.
Okay, every time this loop will execute, and once let's say it found okay, now this post is completely fine.
That time it will approve, otherwise, this loop would be continuously running, and how many times it will run for this? We are just logging this iteration, we are just adding one, okay.
So, this iteration value I will give initially one, okay.
Uh, whenever I'll create the initial state, and every time it will add the one, how many time it will execute?
Okay, after that, we are just returning the response, okay. That means the final post,
then the iteration, okay.
Then we are also saving this inside the post history, and we are returning the state,
done guys.
Okay, now all of the nodes we have created successfully. Now we have to define the edge connection.
Now let's do that.
So here I'll just try to comment
add edges.
So first of all, here we have to add the edges for
this.
start to generate.
Let's define
start to generate,
then we have to define generate to evaluate.
Generate to evaluate, okay.
Now, here conditional edges will come because evaluate either it will send it to the approved, okay. It will directly uh to the approved, otherwise, it will send it to the optimizer, right?
Optimization.
So here we'll be using using the conditional edges.
So let's use the conditional edges here.
So here we are using conditional edges, so it will start from evaluate and evaluate will decide what to send now, whether it will approve or send it to the optimize.
For this, we have to write a conditional function. I think you remember for conditional statement. We write a condition for conditional function separately. So this is the conditional function.
So it will take the state, and here we are checking the condition. If my evaluation, okay, that means I already saved this evaluation inside my state, right?
You remember, right? Evaluation and what is the evaluation approved or needs improvement.
Okay, so here we are checking if this state is equal to state evaluation is equal to is equal to approved, or state iteration is greater than or equal to state max iteration.
That means if let's say it has performed maximum iteration, let's say we have given maximum iteration is equal to four.
Let's say fourth time it has done the iteration, and
whenever it is running for the five time,
that time I think our condition is matching, right?
Because my highest uh highest iteration is maximum iteration is four, but whenever it is going for five, that means this particular loop will break, right?
So that's how we are checking another condition. If this iteration is equal to uh uh it is greater greater than or equal to maximum iteration, that time just return approve, okay.
Otherwise, return needs a prune by it. So this will basically redirect this particular route, whether it will send it to the optimizer or for the approval.
Now we'll try to define this method here
route evaluation,
route evaluation. We'll
write it here, route evaluation, okay.
Now,
here we'll be adding the iteration, okay. This that means the iterative workflows right now.
Now, what will happen?
See, let's say this evaluator returns approved. That means this particular workflow will exit here because I got my final post. But if it doesn't got the approve, let's say it sends needs improvement.
That time, what will happen?
It will send it to the
optimizer.
Okay, it will send it to the optimizer node, and optimizer will optimize, then again it will send it to the evaluation.
So, these kinds of things, if you want to write, you have to give this statement inside conditional workflow only. You have to write
this, you have to write this additional line.
See,
okay, double, comma. I have given.
Yeah, now I think you can get C.
Once this route evaluation returns approved, okay. That means it will end that particular workflow.
But if it return needs improvement, that time it will execute the optimized note.
This optimized note,
okay. Optimize note.
See, it is redirecting from here.
If it needs improvement, it will hit the optimize node, otherwise, it will hit the end node.
See that that is what we are doing, and this is called actually your iterative workflows.
So here we are adding the iteration.
Okay, this is called actually iteration.
I hope you got it, guys. You don't need to take any kinds of separate function for this. Inside conditional edges only, you have to only write this statement.
Okay, that means this route evaluation. If it is returned, the approved, it will go to the end.
Otherwise, if it returns needs improvement, it will execute my optimized node.
And how many times it will perform unless and until when not getting approved, okay. Approved from my evaluator or this maximum iteration ends.
Okay, I hope you got it.
Now our edge connection is also done. Now, simply what I'm going to do, I'm going to
see this connection is done,
this connection, and this connection is done.
evaluate, So this connection is done. Now we'll try to make this connection optimize to evaluate. So let's say once it is in the optimize, so optimize will try to connect to the evaluator.
That means optimize will send this optimization result to the evaluator. So this connection will try to add.
So this is the connection.
This is the connection, okay.
Optimize to Evaluator.
Now we'll try to compile.
Okay, now we'll try we'll show you the workflow.
So, see, this is the workflow. Now, this workflow and this workflow is exactly same. You can check it here, okay.
Now we'll try to execute this workflow for this. Let's
define uh
state.
Let's say I have given the topic agentic AI.
Let's say this is our topic and iteration initially I have sent it, I have set it to the one because after that it will every time update. it will every time update one.
Okay, so whenever it needs any kinds of improvement optimization, it will add one.
Okay, that means the iteration update, and this is our maximum iteration. I want to perform this iteration maximum five time, okay.
If it is not found in five time, that means this loop will execute.
Then we are giving this initial state to my workflow and we are getting the result. Now let me execute
done now. If I show you my result,
so see, this is the result we are getting.
as you can see,
this is the topic, and this is the post it has generated.
Evaluation is uh okay, evaluation return approved. See at the first iteration it it got approved. Okay, then feedback.
This is the feedback,
and you can see iteration is one, that means it didn't update it any iteration. That means at the first time only it has approved.
This is our maximum iteration, and this is the post history, and this is the feedback history, okay. Now maybe you can change to another topic. Let's say I'll give llm.
See, here we are using open i lm, right? That's why this llm is very powerful.
Uh, at the very first time it is generating good post, okay. That's why it is getting approved. Okay, in the first iteration only.
Now let me give any other topic
or random topic and see the output.
so maybe okay.
I'll give any random topic and let's see.
Still, uh at the first time only it is uh approving.
Okay, it's completely fine. You can maybe try with different different topic okay, and you will able to see that whenever it needs any kinds of improvement, okay.
Um, it will run this iteration and it will update, okay, and again it will send it to the optimizer.
The reason it is giving you one-shot uh approval because we are using this uh OpenAI uh GPT photo mini, and this is uh like
good model.
Maybe you can use any weaker model, okay? Like more weaker model, more poor model.
That time I think this uh loop will run, okay. Iteration will run because we are using uh good model, that's why we are getting the result at the very first time.
Okay, I hope you got it now.
If you want to see the post history separately, you can also just write a loop, and from the result, you can extract the post history and you can see all of the post
history you are getting.
Okay, you can also see the feedback history. This is also possible, okay. Anything you can extract because you are getting all the object here, okay.
So, yes, guys, that's how we can write this uh iterative workflows inside Langgraph, and this is super useful.
Trust me, whenever you will be implementing uh actual AI agents, so this concept you need.
Okay, without that, you can't perform this continuous
looping operation, and you need to create a workflow. I need this kind of looping, I need this kinds of conditional statement, parallel statement. Okay, each and everything is required.
Now we have understood the last workflows inside Langgraph. Now.
in the next video onward, guys, we'll try to start working on the project.
So, guys, as you know, I have started a complete agent KI playlist on my YouTube channel, and so far we have completed so many important topic
in this playlist. So, if I show you my playlist, guys, as you can see, I started from introduction. I have already discussed about the evaluation from LLM to uh agent tki, how agent tki came.
We already understood about the entire agent tki concept, how agentic system works, then I told you about asynchronous programming, pyden tick.
Okay, we also saw how we can implement AI agents with the help of Langgen.
Okay, then we started our first orchestration framework for AI agents implementation, which is Langgraph.
Uh, even we also understood this Langgraph uh um each and every component in detail with the code implementation as well.
Now, what I am planning for, guys, I'm planning for the practical development of project. So, what I'm going to do, uh I'm going to start implementing a agentic chatbot from this video onward.
So, first of all, let's try to understand each and every component in detail.
Um, we'll try to explain the things in detail because if you want to create an agentic chatbot, so for this, you need lots of components, like you need
tools, you need memory, you need persistence, you need streaming, you need user interface.
Okay, there are so many things you have to implement independently, then you will be combining them all together, then one agentic chatbot would be ready, okay?
And if you found my content useful, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like and please try to share it with your friends and family.
So, first of all, let's try to understand in this agentic chatbot whatever component we are gonna implement.
So, guys, first of all, let's discuss our plan, like how we'll be implementing this entire agentic chatbot. So, the entire agentic chatbot I'll be implementing with the help of Lang Graph.
Okay, we'll be using Langgraph orchestration framework to implement the entire Agentic chatbot because this project is the part of our
Lang Graph uh orchestration framework in our playlist.
So, in this video, first of all, I'm going to create
a simple
simple chatbot
Okay, we'll try to create a simple chatbot workflow. then we'll try to make this Agentic chatbot like more advanced.
we'll try to add some more advanced component in this particular Agentic chatbot, and with the help of that, we'll be learning all of the Langgraph
code component.
Okay, so whenever let's say you want to implement these kinds of project, whatever component you need from the Langgraph, you will be understanding each and every component.
Okay, so that's why I made this particular implementation like a series, okay, series of video.
So, next in the next video, I'm going to show you the persistence concept.
Like what is persistence,
okay, persistence
and why it is required, why persistence we have to add inside our Agentic chatbot.
We'll try to understand so persistence in line graph,
okay.
Then we'll try to understand um
how to
add
streaming feature,
okay.
Streaming feature to our chatbot.
Then we'll try to understand the concept of
resume chat,
okay. How we can resume any kinds of chat inside our chatbot, then we'll try to see the database integration,
okay.
Integration
in our chatbot,
then
we'll try to see how we can implement
user interface,
okay.
Let's say chatbot
UI.
Okay, we'll try to also implement this. Then after that, I will also show you
how to
add the tools,
okay?
The tools in Langgraph.
Then we'll try to understand
the observability.
Okay.
Observe
observability.
So in observability, we'll try to see how we can integrate Lang Smith
Lang Smith to our agent.
So I think you have already heard of about Lang Smith. Lang Smith is a observability tool. With the help of that, we can monitor the entire application.
Okay, uh, what is the flow of the application, uh, when it is executing, uh, what component, each and everything we can track, okay, in this particular Langsmith.
We'll also try to see how we can use the Langsmith here. Then after that, we'll see the
um
RG concept, okay. How we can integrate the rag features inside our Agentic chatbot.
Because uh, if you have already used this kind of Agentic uh system, you know that it will also work with your documents.
That's you can upload your documents and you can uh do the chat operation on on top of your entire documents. Okay, this is called RG concept.
So the rag means retrieval augmented generation, so we'll also try to understand this thing, then we'll understand this uh
H I T L that means human in loop concept, then we'll also understand the short term
concept, okay. Short term
and
long-term memory concept as well.
Okay, memory.
So, yes, uh, this is the entire plan, guys. So, in this video, first of all, let's try to uh implement the simple chatbot workflow with the help of Langgraph.
Uh, then from the next video onward, I'm going to discuss these are the concepts as well.
So, guys, uh, let's try to implement our chatbot workflow.
So, if you want to implement any kinds of uh agentic chatbot, uh first of all, you have to implement the chatbot workflow.
And how chat bot uh chatbot workflow works, I think you already know that.
Um, so let's say if I want to uh implement with help of Langgraph, so how many node I have to take? I have to take only one node, which would be chat node.
So here user will uh pass some messes, okay, any kinds of message and it will go to the chat node, and chat node will try to return something, okay?
So this is a simple chat operations we'll be doing here, and to run this particular uh graph, actually, we need a state, and uh for this particular chat
bot, what would be the important state? Important state would be the message okay.
let's say the message user is passing. Let's say hi, my name is Bappi.
So this message should be saved, right?
And let's say your bot has replied, uh, welcome Bappi. Okay, and how I can help you today.
So these kinds of messages would be also saved uh inside this particular state, right?
So for this, uh, what I have done, guys, I have taken this um uh this particular state, and here we are using the reducer concept, okay.
Here we'll be using the reducer concept, otherwise, what will happen every time this state would be replaced with the new message.
So I don't want that, I want to save all of the conversation story inside this particular state, okay.
And now you can ask me why we haven't taken string type data here because messages is string type data.
because I already told you here, this is a conversational story, and in line graph actually, this is recommended whenever you are creating this kinds of uh chatbot,
you have to take this function. This is a like langu function we have to import from the languraph called add messages.
In basically, this add messages will try to handle this kinds of scenario, it will take all of the conversation story, the user message as well as the replied message, and it will
store in this particular state. Okay, and this state will go to the chat node. I hope you clear.
Okay, so once we have built this workflow, the simple chatbot workflow, then we'll try to make it more advanced. We'll try to make this particular workflow as agentic chatbot workflow.
Okay, so for this, what we'll try to add, guys.
Uh, we'll try to add see as of now in this particular workflow, you can perform the simple chat operation.
In this workflow, you can perform
simple chat operation.
Okay.
After that, we'll try to add the rag functionality. That means you can you can also upload any kinds of documents and you can perform the chat operation on top of that.
Okay, you can add extra knowledge base on this particular chat bot, right? Then we'll add the tools, okay.
Real-time tools will try to add so that if you are asking any kinds of question and if it needs any kinds of tool, it will try to use that, okay.
And that time actually it will become agenti chatbot. That means it doesn't only have the um like I mean the existing knowledge base, it has also connection with lots of tools,
okay.
So that whenever you are asking something, it will real-time fetch those informations and it will give it to you. Then I will also add the user interface
because user needs a user interface to use this particular chatbot. So definitely we try to create the UI and for UI implementation.
As of now, I'll be using streamlit package, it's a Python package, and here you don't need to write any kinds of HTML and CSS code.
But later on, I'm also going to show you how we can use HTML and CSS code, how we can use the fast API.
Okay, with the help of that, we'll try to create the entire Agentic chatbot.
But as of now, we are learning okay, this is our first project, so that's why I'll be using Streamlit so that everyone can implement with me.
Okay, then we'll also try to add the observability tool, which is Lang Smith.
Okay, Lang Smith will try to add so with the help of that, we'll try to monitor the entire chatbot, okay.
Uh like how it is performing, which particular component is triggering, each and everything we'll try to log in the LangSmith dashboard. Then we'll also learn some advanced topic as well.
Some advanced topic as well.
Okay, inside advanced topic, we'll be learning memory concept, okay.
Short-term and long-term memory concept we'll try to learn.
okay.
I missed out one thing which is
persistence. Okay, here we'll also try to learn this
persistence.
Okay, we'll also try to add the persistence in the chat bot, then we'll be learning the memory, the advanced topic. Then we'll also try to learn this H I T L human in the loop.
Okay, uh, then here also we'll try to learn the retry functionality, like how we can perform the retry functionality and all. So these are the things we'll try to cover.
That means by this particular project itself, we'll try to master okay all of this lang graph concept in detail, okay.
That's why I made this particular implementation as a series so that each of the video will cover each of this concept in a detailed way, okay. So, yes, guys, this is the plan. I think you got it now.
we already have the graph, okay.
We already have the workflow architecture. Now, based on this architecture, now let's try to implement our uh chatbot.
Okay, first of all, we'll try to create this simple chatbot workflow in this particular video.
Then from the next video onward, I'm going to discuss one by one all of this advanced component.
So, first of all, let's try to create a Jupyter notebook file.
Uh, because initially I want to show you this workflow in the Jupyter notebook, then I'm going to just uh write everything in the dot pie file, okay.
Python scripting file because Jupyter notebook file we won't be using whenever we'll be creating the project, okay. But for experiment purpose, we'll be using this Jupyter notebook.
So here let's try to create a file dot ipynb.
Yeah, so previously I had my environment, which is uh
this line graph test. I'll try to select this one, and here we'll try to import all the necessary library we need, and this import would be common, guys. I think you know that. What is this import?
Let's import everything.
So these are the imports we need. we are importing this state graph, start, and then from typing, we are importing uh type dict, annotated, then we are also importing this base
message and human message and we will be using open eye large language model. That's why from Langchain we are importing chat open eye.
You can also use any other uh large language model provider like grog.
You can also use open router, Gemini. Okay, anything you can use only. You just need to check the Langchain documentation how to import that, okay.
Even you can also copy this code, and if you give to the chat GPT, this will replace with another model. But I have my open API key, that's why I'll be using OpenAI model here.
So let's import all of the package.
okay? It's done now. The next thing, guys, what you have to do, you have to get this uh open AI API key. So quickly, I'm going to move my dot env file from my previous uh previous code.
So, guys, as you can see, this is my.
So, this is my open eip key. I already collected
now. Let's try to
write the further code.
Yeah, so now what I'm going to do guys, uh first of all, here I'm going to
um I'm going to initialize the lm.
So here I'm initializing the llm.
Okay, so we'll be taking the default large language model.
Okay, here I'm getting an error because I have to load this environment variable, right? So let's load it. So from dot env
okay.env import load env.
Then after that, we'll try to load this environment variable.
Then now this code will work.
Yeah, now we are able to load our lm.
Now, first of all, you have to define the state. Uh so let's try to define the state.
Um, this is the state, guys.
And I already told you if you are storing conversational story that time you can use this function add messages from Langgraph
GraphMesss.
Okay, so here we are using the reducer concept.
I think you know what is the reducer function, like operation dot add previously we used, but right now this is a conversational story,
so we'll be using this add message, and by default, actually, it will perform this adding operation instead of replacing.
Okay, and here I given the base message,
Base message means see inside base message what happens?
We are telling this is a like uh uh chat history. Chat history means there will be uh user message as well, and there would be like AI reply as well.
Okay, so if you combine all of them together, this will become a base message okay. So this is why we are using the base message here.
So this is going to be my state.
Now let's try to define the state.
So after that, we'll try to create the uh graph.
Now let's create the graph.
So this is our graph, guys.
Uh state graph, and we have given all the state to the graph.
Now, after that, we'll try to add the nodes.
So let's comment here
add
nodes.
So if you see we only have one nodes which is chat nodes, okay?
Let's try to add that
so graph dot add
graph dot add chat node and this function we have to write separately.
so let's try to write this function.
I'm going to create a function def chat node,
and this will take this state,
but I'm not going to return all of this state altogether.
Instead of that, simply
I'm going to only return the
update masses. Okay.
So first of all, here we'll be taking the user query
from this state.
Okay.
Take the user query from this state.
Yeah.
So user will give the masses, right? User will give the masses. So this message I will be basically this will start store as a message.
Okay.
So this message I'm extracting.
Then after that, we'll try to send it to the llm.
Okay, send it to the llm. You can see llm.inbox. We are giving the message and we are getting the response. Okay, now this response
I'm going to store in the message again.
Okay.
response stored in the state, that means in the message keyword because this is a list type, okay, and every time it will store your user message as well as the
response, okay. Altogether it will store and we are returning the state. So this is going to be my chat note.
As you can see, this is going to be my chat node.
So once this chat note is prepared, now let's try to add the edges. Okay, now if you see the edge connection, first of all, start will be connected to the chat node. So let's try to add the edges,
add edges.
So start would be connected to the chat node, and chat node would be connected to the end.
Chat node would be connected to the end. Okay, so this is the simple like edge connection. After that, we'll try to compile
Let's compile the graph.
We have come uh here will be compiled in a graph. Okay, now let's compile.
Yeah, done. Now, if you want to see the workflow,
so this is the chatbot workflow. Okay, this is the simple chatbot workflow we have created like that.
Okay, now here you can perform the simple chat operation.
So this simple chat operation you can perform as of now. Now, let me show you how we can perform the chat operation.
Now, let's give the initial state. So, this is our initial state, guys.
As you can see, we are using human message because this is a human prompt, and for this, we have already imported this human masses.
It's good to uh use this function whenever you use it, uh whenever you are implementing this kinds of chatbot.
So, as you can see, message uh this should be a dictionary.
We are giving the masses, and uh, you can see it takes um
As you can see, it takes as a list, okay. Input,
so that's why we are
giving as a list.
Now we are giving the human masses, and this is the content. What is the object-oriented programming? So this thing I will try to pass to my
Okay, so chatbot.invoke, we are giving the initial state, and this will return you. Let me show you if I don't give this line.
Yeah, so this will give you this kinds of response. So maybe I can store inside a variable response is equal to chatbot.invoke.
Now, if I show you the response,
so this is the response inside this response. You have two things.
Uh, here one you have the masses.
okay, the human masses, and another one is the AI masses.
Okay, now I have to extract this AI masses.
for this. Uh uh, this is a dictionary. First of all, I have to extract the masses, okay. Message keyword.
This mess is uh message key. I have to extract.
Once we got the extract, now this is a list, and here we have two items, okay. One is the human message and one is the AI message, and that's how this
add message stores your data right inside this list.
Now I need the last one, so for this I give minus one,
okay. The last index
AI message. Now I only need the content, so here simply I will just give dot content.
Okay, if you do it, now you will be able to get this content, guys.
Very simple, okay.
So that's how, guys, you can perform any kinds of chat operation right now with this particular workflow. Now, let's say I will ask another question what is uh let's say
object oriented programming in Python.
Now, see object-oriented programming in Python, blah blah blah.
Okay, it's working perfectly.
Okay, so guys, now what I'm going to do, I'm going to just make a loop so that user can continuously give the uh input
and uh this chatbot will be working.
Okay, it will provide the output because right now every time I have to change the message here and I have to re-execute the cell, but I don't want that, I want a loop.
Okay, so for this, what I can do, guys, I can just make a while loop.
So this is our while loop.
Okay, so here we are taking an input from the user.
I'm just telling type here some message then we are printing this uh uh user message then I'm checking if
user messes uh uh let's say if it is the uh if they write like say exit quite and buy, so that time I'm going to break the loop,
okay.
Otherwise, I'm going to simply invoke my
lm.
So let's do that.
So we'll be invoking our llm here.
That means the workflow.
So as you can see, we are doing the same thing, we are just hitting this chatbot.
Invoke, we are giving the message, human message.
Right now, the content should be is equal to the user message. Okay, because previously I hard coded this message, but right now I'm taking as a variable input variable.
Once it is done, I'm going to print this response in the terminal.
Okay, we'll be printing this message in the terminal.
That's it. Now let's execute.
Okay, now let's execute this while loop.
Now, here I can give the message.
Hi
now, see user given hi and it's telling hello, how I can assist you today.
I'll tell my name is Bappi.
Okay, hello buppy. Nice to meet you. How I can assist you.
I'll tell
what is
Python.
See, it's working fine, okay.
But one issue I want to show you in this particular chat bot. Let's say now if I ask
what is
my
name,
now it will tell you I'm sorry, I'm not able to access the personal information about the user.
But although, if you see every time we are saving this information to this state, and we are passing the state to the uh to this node. Okay, if I open my
diagram, I think you see that.
So every time what is happening, whatever message user is giving, I am storing in this uh state, and whatever response also I'm getting, I'm also storing in this particular state,
and we are passing the state to the chat node.
So, chat node should have the information okay about the older conversation because we are storing the conversation story,
but still, why it is not able to give you the answer,
okay. Still, why it is not able to give you the answer.
This is a question to you, just try to think about and please reply in the comment.
If you can you can pause the video and you can reply in the comment, okay? Why it is happening like that.
See if I tell you
see what is happening if you're using the state concept, right? If you are using the state concept, so what will happen?
First of all, let's say it will start this node, then the input will go to the chat nodes, okay?
Then chat node will return some kinds of response, then it will go to the end, okay. So once it is reaching to the end, right.
Once it is reaching to the end, that time this execution is this execution is ending.
Okay, this execution is ending.
That means whatever you have in the chat state, okay. That means in the state, this particular data would be erased.
Okay, this particular data would be erased.
So that time, whenever you are running this loop, right?
You are running this loop.
So every time what you are doing, you are invoking the chat bot, you are invoking the workflow, and whenever you are invoking the workflow, that means what is happening,
you are re-executing from from here, okay. You are re-executing from here, that means again it will go to the chat node to the end.
Again, this data would be erased. Okay, so every time this particular list will be erased, okay. It is not able to like uh let's say
uh store the older conversation it will only store in this particular session only, only one session. Let's say right now, this loop is running, right?
In this particular session, this information is available, but whenever we are again executing, this loop is again executing from here.
That time this information is getting erased.
This is the problem, okay.
Now, how we can handle this kinds of scenario? We can handle this kinds of scenario with persistence.
Okay, I think I already told you about persistence, right?
Now we'll be using persistence concept, and we can we can actually handle this kinds of scenario. That means whatever conversation story we are let's say having, okay.
So we can store somewhere this conversation story because right now this is only storing inside the variable, and once it is getting initialized again, this variable is getting cleared, okay.
This is the main problem, so that's why Langgraph uh supports actually persistence concept.
So inside persistence, either you can save this informations in the memory saber, that means inside your RAM, either you can save this particular information in the database and you can load at
load anytime.
Okay, these kinds of things you can perform. Now let's try to see how we can do this kinds of persistence operation.
So for this, I'm going to open up my code again.
Okay, so here simply I can exit my bot.
So for this, you have to give this exit message.
Sorry,
this exit message only
done now. See it has exited.
Now see persistence concept. I'm going to explain in detail in the next video. So only I'm just going to add this persistence uh let's say um uh uh implementation here, how we can add the persistence.
So inside persistence, uh
basically we just try to add a memory here, okay. We just try to add a checkpoint memory.
So what happens? Let's say the entire state we are having, right?
This entire state we are having, so this entire state we can save inside a memory. Either you can save inside your RAM, okay.
This memory you can say uh this state you can save inside your RAM, either you can save inside the database, okay. But right now, this particular state is not getting saved anywhere.
This is only storing the data in the variable, and you know, whenever code will re-execute, this variable would be clean, clear at that time, right?
We already know that. If you understand the Python concept, you already know that. So somehow we have we have to store this state inside a storage, uh, storage actually um let's say
service. Either you can use your RAM because you know that RAM would be the temporary storage, it's completely fine.
But if you want a permanent storage, that time you can use any kinds of database.
This database part I will also show you in future, but I told you I'll be going uh step by step so that I can explain each and every concept in detail.
So initially, we'll try to see how we can save this information in the RAM.
So whenever we'll save inside the RAM, so what will happen?
This uh this particular data would be saved unless and until I don't restart my kernel.
Okay, if I restart my kernel, that time this information would be cleaned up, otherwise, this information will remain same inside my RAM.
Okay, so this kinds of concept we'll try to add right now.
So here uh for this, I'm going to import a function from Lang Graph.
So inside Langgraph, there is a function called
memory server. Let me import that.
So this is the function langgraph.checkpoint.memory import memory server.
Okay. So this memory server stores your state inside the memory, inside the RAM.
You can also use any kinds of database. That part I will also show you later on. Okay. First of all, let's try to see the memory server one.
Now let me import.
Okay.
So once it is done, now simply
here,
whenever you are defining the graph.
So before the graph initialization, you have to define a checkpoint.
This checkpoint should be the memory server.
Okay. So this is going to be this is going to become your memory saber object. Okay. Checkpoint. Now, whenever you are compiling your entire graph, that time you have to mention I have a checkpointer.
Okay.
I have a checkpointer.
So this checkpointer will basically store your state in the RAM.
Okay. You can see checkpointer is equal to checkpoint.
And here we are using memory saber. Memory saber means the RAM. That means whatever state it is getting, right?
The chat is state. That means the entire state it is getting.
And every time it is updating, right, with the user message and the reply of the AI message, right?
Every time it is getting update. So this information will save in the RAM right now.
Okay, because we are using the checkpoint, uh checkpointer right now.
Okay.
Now let's try to compile the graph.
So one compilation is done, now
let me show you.
Now let's say
I don't need to execute this code, I will directly execute my while loop.
Okay, yeah, but before executing the while loop,
here I will pass one thing.
here you can specify the trade.
Okay, trade
trade means
it should be like kinds of unique uh unique ID for each of the user.
Let's say this chatbot can use
many people, right? This chatbot can use by me, then this chatbot can be used by any other person, so all of the people can chat together here,
And if they're chatting together, it's not like that. Let's say I will let the people to chat with my chat history, right?
So instead of that, what uh it should have it should have a different trade ID.
Okay, different trade ID, different trade ID means let's say if this trade ID is equal to one, I have said let's say trade is equal to one.
That means this is my trade ID. So whatever chat I will perform,
it will store all of the information in this particular trade, right? In this particular, let's say whenever it will store inside the memory, right?
Because I use the memory server. So in the memory, it will create a separate section for one, okay, and all of the information, all of the chat is story, it will save inside this particular trade.
Okay, now if I change it to two, right?
That time
another user will come and he will perform the chat operation. That means what is happening in the memory, there are different block is getting created.
Let's say this is trade one, this is trade two, okay. Whatever chat I'm performing in the trade one, uh trade two person won't be able to see that.
Okay, he won't be able to access this information, and whatever let's say uh chat trade two is doing, trade one won't be able to see or get this particular information,
okay.
Like the chat GPT, like chat GPT is having different trade,
right? Whenever let's say you uh you just create a new chat, right?
Uh in the chat GPT, whenever you create a new chat, let me show you.
So here.
So this is my chat GPT.
So let's say here you can create a new chat, right?
You can create a new chat and you can perform some chat operation here,
right? So this is this becomes a trade, right?
Then whenever you take another new chat, that means the complete new trade will be getting here, and you can perform the another chat operation here,
okay. So that means you won't be able to get the previous uh let's say
uh previous let's say trade uh information in this particular trade, but you can switch to the trade, okay.
Let's say you can switch to the trades anytime you can go to the previous trade, you can go to the current trade.
Okay, that's how we can switch.
So these kinds of things also we can perform with the help of this persistence, okay? We can make different different trades here.
Now let's try to do that. Let me show you.
I think after seeing the practical implementation, you will be able to understand. Now, let's say I'll make it as trade ID.
Initially, I'll give it as one, and whenever you are using this persistence concept, that time you have to define a configuration.
So, this is the configuration before response. Maybe I can create it.
So this is the configuration. Config is equal to configurable.
And here you have to pass this trade ID is equal to trade ID. So your trade ID. Okay, then this should be a dictionary.
Okay, dictionary object.
And this config you have to pass whenever you are invoking the workflow. So here at the last, you have to give this
You have to give this config. Config is equal to config.
Okay.
Now what will happen every time uh this uh this uh uh persistence what it will do it will try to uh load
the information load the state from the memory and it will try to pass to the um it will try to pass to the
um invok function. Invoke function means you are giving the user message as well as the older history.
Okay, user message as well as the older history that means whatever older history you are having, whatever chat state you are having, you are entirely passing the chat history
as well as the new message user is giving.
Okay, now right now it won't be replacing because we are storing in the memory,
and every time we are loading it and passing it to the invoke function. Now, see if I execute the code.
Now let's say here I'll tell my name is Bappi.
Okay, now let's say I will give another message what is Python
done now.
If I ask, let's say what is my name.
Now see your name is Bappi, it is able to remember right now, okay. It has some kinds of memory right now, and this information is saving inside my RAM
because we are using memory server here, and this is called persistence, okay. This is called persistence.
Now, if I let's say give another trait, okay. Let's see if I give another trait, let's see if I do exit right now.
Um, one thing I want to show you uh if I run it inside my while loop, so if I exit my while loop, so that time your entire session will be um like
restarted.
So instead of that, maybe I can use this code.
I'll copy this trade, ID, here,
trade ID. and, uh,
it will also copy this config.
and we'll pass this config to this
whenever we're doing the invoke operation here. I'll try to pass the config. Okay, now let's execute.
So let's say I'll say
what is
or I'll pass my name is Bappay.
Now see, uh nice to meet you, Bappi.
Now if I ask um
what is my name.
What is my name?
It's giving your name is Bappi.
Okay, now let's see if I give another trade here.
Okay, let's say trade to.
Now if I ask what is my name,
now see it is telling I'm sorry, I do not know what is your name.
Is an uh is uh as I am a AI assistant and I do not I do not have access to the personal informations, okay?
Because this is a completely new trade right now. Okay, now let's say in this particular trade I will give let's say my name is
my name is Alex.
Now it is telling nice to meet you, Alex.
Okay, now if I ask what is my name.
Now it will tell your name is Alex. Okay, now if I switch to my trade one, okay.
Now if I again ask what is my name, you will see that it will tell you your name is Bhappi.
See your name is Bhappi.
Okay. Now if I go to my trade two
trade to
that time,
your name is Alex. Okay, I hope you got it.
This concept, okay. This trading concept that means we can separate out the chat session, okay.
Chat session for each and every user.
This is possible, right?
And here you can also see the
state.
so for this, you can use this code.
So chatbot dot get state, and you have to pass the config, and you will be able to see like
how many trades you are having.
Okay, all of the history you will be able to see the entire state. That means the entire state you will be able to see. The state is saved in the memory.
So this is the snapshot object, as you can see.
Whatever question you have asked, like what is my name,
some other metadata, the AI response.
Okay, so each and everything is visible here,
the input token, output token,
and you will be able to see the trade ID as well. So, what is the trade ID?
Yeah, so this is the trade ID 2 and trade ID one is also there
somewhere, okay. So that means the entire uh state snapshot you will be able to see here.
So, this entire state snapshot you will be able to see here if you're using this persistence concept, and there is a function called get state.
Inside that, you have to only pass the configuration. The configuration you are preparing, you will be able to see the entire state, okay.
Uh, it is saved in the memory.
So, yes, uh, this is the concept uh of this persistence. Okay, we have learned this persistence concept.
So, here I already told you persistence we can add inside Langgraph.
This is also possible, and don't worry, I'm also going to take another I'm also going to record another video on top of this persistent in detail.
We'll try to understand each and every concept, okay, of this particular persistence.
Now uh this thing is working fine. Now, what I can do, I can quickly
uh I can quickly convert it to the um dot pie file.
So let's create a file here.
I'm going to name it as
agentic
chatbot.py.
and whatever code I have written here, I'll just try to copy here
or let's name it as
agentic chatbot backend backend.
Okay, now I'm going to copy here.
So, first of all, let's import all the necessary library.
Select my environment,
then I load the environment variable
and
initialize the model,
define the state.
So this is my state now.
I'll copy my node.
After node, I will copy my
intergraph.
Okay.
So this is going to be my final.
Yeah. So this is going to be my final workflow object. Okay, chatbot object. Now we can use this chatbot object anywhere to run this particular workflow.
Now what I'm going to do, guys.
I'm going to show you whether it is working or not.
So maybe I can create another file here called,
let's say, app.py.
Inside app.py, let me first of all import this chatbot object, so from
agentic
_chatbot _backend import chatbot.
Okay, chatbot now. I'll just write response
is equal to chatbot.invoke and here we have to pass the human message. Okay, and for human message we have to import this library,
this one.
So
here I'll give let's say what is
python
and whatever response I'll get I'll just try to print the response. Okay, now let's see whether it's working or not.
So I'll open up my terminal,
then I will activate my environment. So, conda activate
line graph test.
After that, we'll try to execute then app dot file so python app.py
Okay. Here,
uh okay, uh sorry, actually I have to give this, uh I have to give this um uh trade ID, right? Trade ID I haven't given because here, uh initially we passed the trade, right?
We are giving the check pointer, so you have to give this, uh pass this trade.
So here I will copy this trade. I
also copy this configuration.
then we'll pass this config.
Now I think this will work.
See, it's working. Python is a high level um widely used programming language, blah blah blah.
Okay, but here, uh, I actually, I can't left this kind of application to the user because user don't know how to code, right? And how to execute this uh app.py from the terminal.
So definitely, I have to add the user interface.
Okay, now let's try to add the user interface with the help of streamlit here.
So guys, now we'll try to add the user interface for this uh chatbot with the help of streamlit.
So streamlit is a python package and here you can Create any kinds of user interface without using any HTML and CSS code,
right?
So for this, uh, now we have to install this Streamlit. So what I'm going to do in the same requirement file —I think you know this requirement file I am using, uh, so far, okay, inside my Langgraph
um tutorial —so here I'm going to add another package. I'm going to name it as Streamlit,
okay? Streamlit. You can specify any kinds of version if you want to install.
So let's say I want to install this specific version, then I will open up my terminal and I'll just write: pip install.
I pen add
requirement.txt.
Oh, sorry, "install" spelling is not correct.
Okay, as you can see, installation is complete now.
I will come back to my app.py
close these are the file.
Now let's start implementing the UI.
See, your back end code will remain same. You don't need to change anything.
you only need this chatbot let's say,
object here, so which we have already imported, okay.
From agentic chatbot backend, we have already imported the chatbot.
Now
I'll just remove these are the code as of now.
Okay, so see, first of all, here I need a streamlit server, right? in that particular server, I'm going to just add my UI functionality, and this server should be run on my local host,
right? And if you're using streamlit, it's super easy to launch the server, only you just need to import the streamlit. So from our import
streamlit
as st okay.
If you only import that and let's say here I will give a title only
st.title.
Let's say I will give agentic chatbot with langu, I've given this title.
Now you have to execute this file only.
Okay, now if you want to execute this file, if you just let's say write python app.py, it won't be running that time.
For this, you have to use streamlit command.
Streamlit
run
app.py.
So basically you are launching the streamlit server. Okay, now if I execute
and now see streamlit server will be running.
See, this is the streamlit server, guys, and this is running on localhost port number 85.
Okay, uh port number 8501. So by default, streamlit runs on port number 8501 on the local host.
See one thing you have observed here without writing any kinds of HTML and CSS, we got this kinds of user interface.
Okay, so this is the work of streamlit, and here you you can also change the settings.
You can go to the settings, you can also
change the appearances. If I let's say active this wid mode, uh this title will be moving to the left side, and let's say if I change the color, let's say
you want a light color, I want it dark color.
Okay, everything is possible here, but here we'll try to customize in the code whatever things we need. We'll try only just try to add it. Okay, you can make it more beautiful for this.
You can go to the streamlet documentation and you can check it out. There are so many functionality you can use, but uh this front end is not like our concern, okay.
there would be other front-end developer okay. They will take care about the front end and everything. but as a agent KI engineer,
we have to know the actual concept, actual back end engineering.
I think this is more than enough. Okay, so for this particular project, uh whatever uh let's say uh UI interface we need, we'll only just try to focus on that part.
See, uh, we already launched this streamlit server and we set the title.
Now, here I need a user input box, okay. That means the chat box. So here user will be able to pass any kinds of messages. Okay, for this, we can take this
chat input.
So if you want to get the chat input,
you can write this code st.chatinput, okay, and you can give any kinds of messages because if you go to the chat GPT, right?
So here you will see by default ask anything.
So if you want to give these kinds of message, display message, you can write it here, and whatever messages you will provide, it will store in the user input variable.
Okay, so once we got the user input variable, if I show you, so if I let's refresh now, see here I got a chat chat input box.
Okay, now whatever uh input you will give here, you will try to send it here.
It would be stored here. Okay, now I can also print and show you our st.print.
St
uh dot
text
or let's say write
I think there is a function called write.
Now let me show you refresh
user return none. So if I let's say give high now see here hi will come.
Okay, that's how you can take any kinds of user input. So after taking the user input, guys, what I will check, I will check first of all user has given any input or not.
If uh user has given the input, that means if user input is equal to is equal to true, okay.
That time
I'll just try to
um.
I'll just try to give a
uh display, display, uh, actually icon.
okay of the user.
and
from this icon, I'm going to take the user masses,
user input. whatever user input will pass.
we'll try to pass it. here. Now see what will happen if I refresh.
Now, say if I pass any text here, now see uh this icon is coming because of this particular line
chat message and this is user, okay. This is the user icon and user has passed hi.
So if you see any kinds of chatbot, guys, you will be able to see people are using this kinds of icon to identify the human message as well as the AI messes.
Okay, that's why we have given this line, and by default in streamlit it is available.
So once I got the user input,
now what I have to do, guys, I have to invoke the message to my chatbot, okay. The chatbot object we have created, but before that, we have to configure the
trade, right?
So maybe what I can do
here only I can prepare my trade.
So config is equal to configurable trade ID.
So here I have given let's say trade one, okay. Trade one, you can also give one, two, three, four. It's completely up to you. Okay, even you can also write like that.
Okay, you can also write like that, it's completely fine, but in in just one line I have added like that.
Now let's try to invoke the message
yeah. So here we'll try to invoke the message yeah.
Chatbot dot invoke and message is equal to we are giving the human message, content is equal to right now the user input, and we are giving the config.
Now, whatever response I am getting, guys, I will also show this response.
So, first of all, I will extract the content
from this response.
So AI message is equal to response masses minus one content. Okay, that means we are we are doing this operation, we are only extracting the AI masses,
and this AI message I will try to
show in the console.
For this, I'm going to create another icon assistant icon, and this message would be showing the assistant icon.
Okay, now let me show you.
If I refresh,
done now. Let's see if I give hi send.
Now see assistant is giving hello. How I can assist you today. Now, this is the assistant icon, this is the user icon. Okay, that's why we have given this
chat message is uh inside that. I have mentioned assistant.
Whenever you will get give assistant, automatically it will take the assistant icon, and whenever you will give user that time, automatically it will take user icon.
Okay, so that's how streamlit works, guys. by default, internally they are handling each and every scenario.
Uh, and uh they have given some high level functionality. We can use that and we can create our chatbot.
Okay,
it's working fine. But one issue uh in this particular chatbot would be let's say if I give another message, I am Bappi.
Now, see previous message is getting replaced. Okay, previous message is getting replaced.
Now it is giving you the new one. But I can't see my previous conversation. But in chat GPT, let's say if I give I am Bappi,
so I will be able to see my previous message as well.
Okay. So this kinds of thing, uh, if you want to do it, that time you have to use something called session.
Okay, session state inside streamlit.
So streamlit also works in that way.
by default, if you're not using session state, what is happening?
So every time it is re-executing code from here, and whenever it is re-executing code from the beginning, that time this message is getting erased.
Okay, it is getting cleaned and new message is getting replaced here.
But if you're using session state, session state will store these informations
in memory, and every time, whenever it will execute from the beginning, it will not erase.
Okay, still it this information will be available inside memory, and from memory it will able to load that, okay. The same concept like uh um
uh trading, okay. We have learned before, right?
Yeah, now let's try to add this uh uh session state.
First of all, we'll create a session state here.
First of all, we'll try to create a session state. I'll check if message history is not in session state, then I'll try to create this message study.
Okay, it will create like a dictionary kinds of thing by default inside this streamlit, and this dictionary
it's a different type of dictionary. Basically, this dictionary will store the information in the memory, it will not erase okay.
If you execute the code from the beginning, still this dictionary data would be remaining same, okay.
Then after that,
we'll load the
conversation from the dictionary. So, this is the code I have written loading the conversation story.
So for message in state uh session state message story and if it founds this message so it will basically load the role and the content.
So role means
uh whether it is the masses for the user or AI.
Okay, this particular role and the content.
Now,
here you have to write some line of code. Let's say whenever user is giving any kinds of input, this input should be stored in the message story.
So this additional line you have to write here.
This is the additional line.
First, add the message to the message story. So st.session state message story, we are appending it, okay.
role user content the user input.
Okay, we are storing in this particular
list.
Once it is done, now I will also do the same thing whenever I got the AI response.
So after getting the AI response, we'll also
save this in the message story.
so you can see st.session state message story append role. Now this role should be assistant, okay? Because this is the response from the assistant.
Content is equal to AI message.
Okay, done. Now, if I come back here, refresh now. If I give the message, let's say hi.
Hello, hi. Can I assist you? My name is
Bappi.
Um, nice to meet you. How I can assist you today, okay. But this Agentic chatbot with Langgraph is coming here.
Let me see why.
Okay, because you have to assign it at the beginning, okay.
Because after load conversation story, we have assigned it, that's why it's coming here. So maybe at the top I will try to assign this one. Okay, now I think this will work fine.
Refresh now. I'll give hi.
Fine.
My name is
Now, see, nice to meet you, Bhappi.
What is Python?
Now see okay, it's working perfectly, and I am able to see my older message story as well.
Okay. so yes, guys, we are able to create our um.
uh, we are able to create our uh first. uh, chatbot workflow.
okay. with the user interface, even we have also added the uh, this persistence concept. that means the trading concept. and don't worry.
I'm going to explain this trading uh persistence concept in more detail in the next video.
But this is the first video, guys. I wanted to show you how we can create the skeleton of the Agentic chatbot. Now the chatbot skeleton is ready.
Okay, now we have to add these are the functionality one by one, okay.
We have to add these are the functionality one by one. Now, next I'm going to show you maybe
the persistence concept in detail, okay.
After next, I will discuss about the rag concept, how we can add the rag functionality, how we can add the tool functionality.
Okay, UI. I have also I have already shown you, okay. UI um I'm not going to show you again. Maybe I'm going to update continuously update the UI as per my need.
Then I'm also going to show you how we can add the observability tool like Lang Smith, memory, okay, HITL.
Okay, each and everything we'll be discussing one by one, guys.
Okay, so yeah, this is the part one for this implementation, guys, of this agentic chatbot, and we are able to build our first interface of the chatbot,
but right now it doesn't have any kinds of tool, it doesn't have any kinds of rag capacity.
Uh, we'll try to add one by one, okay.
Uh, through the entire series of the video, and I'm going to share all of this code in my video description. From there, you can get and you can execute inside your system, guys.
Okay, now I can test one more thing, which is the persistence that means whether it is able to remember my name or not. So I'll ask what is
my name.
Your name is Bhappi as you mentioned earlier. Okay, perfect. It is able to remember.
So, guys, here one more update we have to do inside this. uh chatbot, um, which is, let's say, if I, if I ask anything, um,
let's say if I tell
generate, uh
blog
um about, let's say python.
Now see, if I give this prompt to my chatbot,
it will take some time, right?
It is taking some time to generate this particular blog, and user has to wait
till the execution, right?
But if you go to the chat GPT, if you give the same prompt, right?
If you give the same prompt
and if you send this message,
so instantly you will be able to see it will start generating one by one.
So this is called streaming response.
See, it is still generating streaming response, but the chatbot we have created it is generating in one shot, okay. We have to wait for the execution.
Once execution is complete, once my generation is complete from the chatbot, then you will be able to see the content.
Okay, so let's say if you are generating a big blog or any kinds of big content from the chatbot, that time you have to wait.
And this is not a good user experience, right? But in chat GPT, this is a good experience.
if you give any kinds of prompt, whether it is a big content, it doesn't matter, it will generate this content, okay, token by token, uh,
and user will read it, okay.
Instantly, user will be able to read it. So, this is called streaming response.
So, if you want to implement this kinds of streaming response inside your chatbot as well, you can also do it because I already told you I will also show you this streaming response as well,
okay.
Uh, streaming, yeah, how to add this streaming uh inside Langgraph. In Langgraph, also you can add this streaming concept.
Now let's try to add it.
I will open up my code.
So in this app.py only
you have to add this line.
So there is a like a very minor change you have to do.
See, uh, whenever you are getting this, um
you are getting this
assistant message, right?
We we are invoking the response
and after invoking the response, we are getting the AI message.
So basically, here what is happening?
First of all, you are invoking the message and you are waiting for the response. Once you've got the response, then you are showing this response to the streamlit user interface.
So we have to replace this code with this code.
So, this is the code, guys.
You have to use. See, here instead of invoking at the very first time, first of all, what we are doing, see, we are preparing this assistant icon.
After that, there is a function inside streamlit called write stream.
Okay, we are using this write stream function. Inside that, uh, we are using the chatbot object.
Okay, now instead of invoking, we'll be using stream.
Inside that, you have to pass the uh message user input, and you have to give the configuration. Okay, we already have the configuration. I need to
pass the config only. So config is equal to config.
Yeah, and stream mode is equal to masses. You have to provide this particular configuration, and you have to run a for loop for
a message chunk and metadata.
So, whatever message chunk you will be getting, you will only take the content and this message chunk
uh continuously it will be showing in the streamlit con uh streamlit user interface because we are using write stream.
That means every time whenever using chat GPT and you are generating something, okay.
Let's see you are generating something.
Let's tell more about it.
It is giving you the response token by token, as you can see, token by token.
Okay, so this kinds of token by token output you will be getting, and you will be writing in the streamlit user interface. So this will feel like uh this is a streaming response that time, okay.
Then once everything is done, then we'll try to store this uh
AI message to the history message history.
We are appending like a same previously we did okay. As the assistant, we are appending in the session state.
Now let me show you. So if I get back, if I refresh,
fine.
Now let's say I'll give hi
streamlit has no attribute write stream.
Why this error is coming? Let me check
maybe the version we are using it doesn't have this write stream. So, what I can do, I can install the latest one.
Now if I give the message again,
okay, still the same issue. Let me check, guys.
Okay, I have given this arrow to the chat gpt and chat gpt is telling you still you need to upgrade this streamlit. So let me execute this command.
pip install upgrade streamlit.
So basically this will download the upgraded version.
Then. Now we can
try again.
Now
I'll give message hi.
Now see, we are getting the response. Now, if I ask, let's say generate
blog
about Python.
Now see it is streaming response like chat GPT right now, okay. And this is
more interesting and more
good experience to the user, okay. So that this kinds of scenario you also uh you also need to take care of whenever you are creating this kinds of agentic system, okay, or any kinds of simple chat,
but whatever you are creating, this kinds of thing you have to take care and a lang graph is having this kinds of concept integrated, okay. You can easily implement this thing in the lang graph,
okay. So, we have also seen how we can add the streaming response inside our application, okay. Now, this application looks more cool.
Now, in the next video, guys, I'm going to discuss about this persistence concept in more detail.
We'll try to see uh uh what is this persistence is all about. We have already understood in this video as a high level, but uh in detail I'll try to discuss in the next video.
So, yeah, guys, this is all about from this first part of this implementation.
So, guys, as you can see, this is the definition of persistence, and in my previous video, that means in the part one, maybe I already given you the high-level overview on top of this
persistence, like what is persistence and how we can integrate with our chatbot. I already told you about, but let's try to understand the detailed definition of persistence.
As you can see, persistence in Line Graph is a built-in layer that automatically saves and restores the state of your agent or
graph workflow over time, okay.
It works by using a checkpointer to automatically capture snapshot of the graph's state at every step, organizing them into unique and retrievable traits.
Okay, so I think by the definition itself, you can understand what I'm trying to say here because if you have already completed the part one of this
chatbot implementation, I think you know that. see persistence, why it is required. First of all, let's try to understand from the beginning.
I think you know uh inside agentic application, first of all, we'll have a goal, right? So let's say, here let me write down.
Yeah. So see, in any kinds of agentic application, first of all, definitely we'll have a goal.
Let's say you have a problem statement, right? You want to let's say here we are creating an agentic chatbot. So definitely this is our goal. Now, this goal should be divided into multiple tasks.
So, first of all, what we'll do, guys, we'll try to divide this goal to the multiple tasks. Let's say this is task one, okay, this is task two,
and so on. That's how we'll be breaking down different different tasks, and whenever we'll be using lang graph, right? Whenever we'll be using
because so far we are learning about lang graph. So, in lang graph, to define this particular task, we use something called nodes, right? Each of the tasks will become a nodes.
Let's say this is our first nodes, this is our second nodes, okay, and so on. So that means first of all, we'll be having a goal and we'll define a task from this particular goal, like step by step
task, and this particular task would be our nodes, okay, inside the graph, because this is the entire graph. As you can see, this is the entire graph,
entire graph inline graph, right?
This is the entire graph inline graph, and these are the nodes, okay. And you can see this is the edge connection.
this is the edge connection, and this start node is nothing but this is the input.
So here we pass our initial state, initial input, right? And this input will go through these edges.
This edge is nothing but it's a connection. This edge defines basically after which node, what node should be executed, okay, because of this particular arrow symbol.
As you can see, this arrow symbol defines okay. After start nodes, node one would be executed. After node one, node two would be executed, like that, right? So this is called edges.
This is called edges, and this is called nodes.
We already know about this is called nodes, right?
Okay, and then this particular task will go through all of the nodes, then at the last we use the end nodes. What this end nodes will do, it will first uh basically stop the graph execution.
Okay, let's say whenever we'll give any kinds of input and whenever it will reach to this particular end, it will stop the graph execution and you will be able to see the final
okay, final result here.
Final result here. And we have already seen this particular things in the practical implementation as well. I think this is pretty much clear to you, right?
Now, see the main things we have to understand whenever we are defining any kinds of graph, right?
Whenever we are defining any kinds of graph, and if I want to execute this graph in lang graph, we have to provide something called state, right? We have to provide something called state.
I think you know that without state, we can't execute any kinds of graph. And what is state? State is nothing but its kinds of uh its kinds of variable we are passing, right?
It's kinds of some of the data we are passing to the graph.
Okay, let's say in this particular chat bot, what is should what should be the state? State should be the masses.
Let's say the message user is giving, okay, and our AI bot is replying.
So this is the message. this is the information. So every time what will happen? This state will go to the every nodes, okay.
Every nodes, and this nodes, whatever output will return, it will basically update in this particular variable.
Okay, this is called state. But what happens if we are giving this particular state to the graph?
So let's say we are passing the state to the start node, right? Then the start node will pass to the node one, then node two, then no, then end.
So whenever it will go to the end, that means this graph execution is getting over, and whatever state, whatever state data you are having here, it will be basically erased that time.
Okay, it will be basically erased that time. Then whenever you will be running second time, you won't be able to get the previous information, whatever you got in the first execution, right?
Inside the state. So this is the main problem. Then what we introduce, we introduce something called persistence, right?
We introduce something called
persistence. So in persistence, what we usually do here, we basically save the entire state, okay, inside a storage service. Either you can use your uh RAM, okay.
We call it as a memory saber, either you can use any kinds of database.
That means two kinds of storage service you can use. Either you can use your RAM, that means
okay. Your computer memory, either you can use any kinds of database here.
Okay, database is the permanent one,
okay.
permanent one And this is the temporary one.
Temporary one, okay. Temporary means if you restart your application, that time this data would be erased.
But in database, if you restart your application, okay, it doesn't matter you if you restart if your uh uh let's say a system crashes,
it doesn't matter, your data will be permanent.
Okay, you can load anytime these kinds of data that okay.
That means uh inside persistent, whatever state snapshot we are having, okay, we try to store inside a storage service.
That's why in the definition itself, you can see persistence in line graph is a built-in layer that automatically save okay and restore.
That means you can restore this particular state anytime, okay, from the storage service. The state of your agents, okay, the state of your agents or graph workflow over time.
Okay, over time means because it is every every time it is capturing your snapshot, it is uh let's say this persistence every time
it will save the information in the uh uh storage service. Let's say after start, whatever's uh state uh update you got, right?
This particular information would be saved after no day one execution, whatever uh state would be saved, it will be basically saved in the database or your local storage.
Okay, that's how every step, okay, every step.
It will be saving the information of your state.
That's why we call it as a overtime here. And what it works by using a checkpointer to automatically capture the snapshot of the graph's state at the every step.
Okay. I already told you. And in my previous implementation, I used something called checkpointer. I think you know that. Again, I will give you the idea.
Okay, how checkpointer works and each and everything I will give you. Then one uh another thing we learned this uh organizing them into unique and retrievable trades.
Okay, we'll be also learning about the trades. Trade means you can create multiple trades.
Let's say trade one, you can do some kinds of conversation in trade two, you can do another uh kinds of conversation.
Okay, so both conversations would be different, and you can't use trade one information in trade two and trade two information in trade one.
Okay, we can also make this particular difference. Okay, I hope you got it, guys.
Now that's how your persistence comes into picture, and this is very much important whenever you are creating these kinds of agentic AI application. Otherwise, what will happen?
Your application may not get this state uh data okay over time.
Whenever you are creating this kinds of agentic chatbot or any other, let's say advanced application, which is required your older data as well.
Okay, just try to think about whenever we are creating this agentic chat bot. Definitely I need my previous response. Let's say I have given the input, my name is Bappi, right?
And second time, if I'm asking what is my name, so it definitely should remember that particular information, right? Whatever it is updated in the state, okay.
But if it is getting end, right, and if the final result is getting erased, okay, of this state, that time definitely your uh definitely
your uh agent won't be able to give you the response.
But if you're using the persistence concept and if you're capturing this state okay inside a memory, okay, if you're saving this inside a memory,
so anytime we can load this and we can pass again to the graph, and graph will be able to recall the previous information and that that will be able to give me the result.
Let's see, your name is Bappi. So this is the main funda here, okay. I hope you clear, guys.
So, guys, now let's try to understand the specialty of persistence. see, persistence is having some kinds of speciality.
see, I told you whenever we define any kinds of state, right? And
whenever we execute a graph, so this state will go to the every nodes, right?
Every nodes it will go and all the nodes will be updating something in the state, okay, and we'll be getting a final result
from here. So it doesn't mean this persistence will only capture the final updated state information. Instead of that, it will be able to store your intermediate let's say data.
Intermediate data means see what happens whenever we define any kinds of state, right?
Let's try to take example, let's say state.
So let's say here I have taken a state. Um, the state name is let's say I will take name.
I want to only save the name information here.
Okay, name. Let's say I have only taken one variable. So what will happen? This state will go to the every node.
First of all, it will go to the start node.
Okay, after going to start node, uh this uh uh
your graph would be initialized, your graph would be executed. So through these edges, it will reach to the node one.
Okay, let's see in node one we are doing some kinds of update. That means node one is updating this name.
Let's say initially it was let's say initially I have given a let me take this color initially. Let's say the name was A.
Okay. Now what we'll do this node one will try to update this particular name.
Let's say it will be
updating B.
Okay, it will update B. But whenever we pass this state, okay, initially it was name A.
Okay, but whenever we pass through this node one,
this uh was changed to the to the B, right? So the execution you can see here node start to node one.
That means through this execution, okay, this is called super.
Super step.
Okay.
This is called super step.
So what is super step basically to execute the entire nodes.
Okay. To execute the entire graph.
Uh whatever super step we perform, okay.
Let's say if I want to execute the entire graph, definitely I have to execute node one, node two, okay, then it will go to go to this end, then your entire graph would be executed.
Then you can see multiple edge connection is there, and each of the age connection is a super step here.
Okay, that means in every super step there would be some kinds of update in the state, and your persistence would be able to capture this information
in the stories, okay. That means let's say after node one, it will go to the node two, let's say node two will try to replace this uh B to this
C.
Okay, and whenever it will reach to the end, and here you will get the final name C right, but it's not like that, it is replacing all of the previous information.
Still, the previous information is available, okay.
Still the previous information is available. Okay, so this information I we call it as a intermediate
okay, intermediate state.
Okay, we call it as intermediate state, and this is called final
state, okay. Final state that means the specialty of persistence is it will capture your intermediate state state as well, and the final state as well.
Okay, it's not like that every time you will get the final state. Definitely, intermediate state would be available after each and every super step execution.
Okay, let's say in future uh your application will crash here. Let's say node one it will crash, or let's say node two, it will crash.
Okay, that time it's not necessary whenever you will restart your application, it will execute from the beginning.
Okay, it's not like that because it has the intermediate state and it has already has the information.
Okay, so what it will do, it will be able to resume, okay. It will able to resume your application from node one or node two because it has captured the intermediate state.
Okay, so this is called actually fault tolerance. I already told you about this, right?
Fault tolerance in my
introductory session.
I already told you about fault tolerance, right? That means whenever your application uh gets crashes, it not's not necessary to re-execute application from the beginning.
Okay, you can execute your application wherever your application got crashes. Let's say this is crash point, okay. Or let's say this is crash point.
Wherever your crash point happens, it will resume the application from here itself.
Okay, I hope you get it. So, this is the specialty of this persistence.
Uh, if you uh see this kinds of question in the interview, what is the specialty of persistence?
That time you can tell it can also save the information of the uh of the intermediate state along with the final state.
Okay, I hope you get it. And if you go to the uh real time let's say application, let's say if I go to the chat GPT, okay. Chat GPT also using this kinds of persistence concept.
So in chat GPT, what you can do, you can either create a new conversation, okay. New chat, either you can continue with your old chat, right? Either you can continue with your old chat.
Let's say if I want to continue some kinds of old chat, I can continue here.
Let's say this is my old chat, as you can see, right? I can continue here.
So let's say what is
the final.
See, it will basically reusing my older state,
see
and discontinuing the conversation.
Okay, and even I can also start a new conversation here.
Okay, if I start a new conversation, that means my new state would be created, and one by one, this super step will be executed,
and each and every okay, uh step, this snapshot would be captured and it will be updated in this state.
Okay, so without this state, you can't create this kinds of application.
Definitely for this kinds of advanced agentic chatbot, you need this state, and this state is already sorry, you need this kinds of persistence concept, and this persistence is already okay
integrated inside Langgraph.
Okay, and with the help of that, you can handle this kinds of fault tolerance in a very easiest manner.
Okay, I hope you got it, guys. I have given you the example with the real world example as well, like chat GPT.
So chat GPTs are also using this kinds of
persistence in the back end.
So in chat GPT, what is happening?
Whatever conversation you are doing, okay, whatever conversation you are doing, uh, this kinds of information is getting saved uh okay,
uh, in the state, and they're using persistence concept here definitely, and they're storing this kinds of information um in a database.
Okay, they are not using any kinds of local storage service, instead of that, they're using some kinds of database, and from the database itself, this information is getting
okay, fetched. Okay, whenever you are opening any kinds of old conversation, you will be able to see whatever message you have done here. So this information is coming from the database, okay.
I hope you're clear, guys.
Now, guys, this definition would be pretty much clear. like what is happening inside persistence.
now let's try to understand another concept here. As you can see, it works by using a checkpointer to automatically capture the snapshot of the graph states, okay, at every step.
Now let's try to understand what is this check pointer exactly.
So here I have taken another example, guys. As you can see, check pointer is uh in inside of persistence.
See, check pointer is nothing but uh
you can consider this checkpointer is kinds of uh it's kind of tracking uh tracking functionality.
Tracking functionality means each and every super step whenever it is executing and whatever update we are making inside the state, that time
checkpointer will be able to capture those informations in the state, right? In this state means it will be able to capture this information and it will save inside the persistence memory.
Okay, so let's try to understand this concept in detail. So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to open up my blackboard and here let me make you understand. See what I told
you. Uh, whenever we give any kinds of state to a graph, okay, uh, so what will happen? It will execute the nodes one by one.
You can see we are having lots of nodes here, and uh you can see the edge connection.
This is the edge connection, and whenever you are doing these kinds of age uh age connection and edge execution, that means after start to
sorry, um, from start to node one, here we are get doing a execution, and this execution we call it as a super step, right?
I already told you about super step,
super step, right? So whenever you are having this kinds of super step, okay, whenever you are having this kinds of super step,
after that you will basically set a checkpoint, okay. Set a checkpoint that means whenever we are passing an initial state to the start, that time one checkpoint would be available here.
Checkpoint
uh checkpoint one, okay.
Let's say this is our checkpoint one.
Then
after doing this super step execution, there would be again an update, so there would be another checkpoint.
Let's say this checkpoint two, and here here you are having multiple nodes, okay, as parallel.
So this is one execution, this is another execution, this is another execution. We combine all of the execution and we will be calling as a another super step,
another
super step.
Super step, right?
And after this super step, there would be another checkpoint.
Checkpoint three.
Okay, and at the last, uh, because here we are doing another super step execution and we're getting the final response. Okay, here also another checkpoint would be available.
Checkpoint, let's say four, okay, and every checkpoint will capture the updated state.
Let's say after you start to node one, whatever update will be happening in this state, this checkpointer will capture that information, it will save in the persistence memory.
Okay, persistence
memory it will save either. You are using local, local storage, that means your RAM, either you are using any kinds of database.
Okay,
database,
it will store there.
Okay, whenever it is storing, that means it is not replacing the value, instead of that, it is merging, that means it is adding the information,
adding the information, and we call uh call it as a reducer concept. I think you know that reducer.
That means whenever uh we are using this kinds of persistence concept, definitely we have to use the reducer.
Okay, reducer concept will be continuously adding the information instead of replacing the old one.
Okay, I hope you get it, guys.
Okay, then uh this kinds of uh checkpoint uh we have in every uh super state, and whenever any kinds of update would be happening in the state, it will capture the information
and you will be getting a final snapshot, final let's say state at the last checkpoint, and this will like store at the last, okay.
But you will be able to see the previous update as well in the state.
Okay, this is how this particular checkpointer is working.
I hope you got it right to get the like updated data in the state. We use this kinds of checkpointer, and the checkpointer work is to capture this information in the storage service.
This is the work of a checkpointer. That's why in the definition itself, I think you see the definition.
In the definition itself, it is telling it works by using a checkpointer to automatically capture snapshot of a graph state at every step, okay?
Because we are using every step execution here.
I hope you get it, guys.
Okay, now let's try to understand this checkpointer concept through an example. Let's say I'll take the same graph execution here. So let's say here I will define a state.
Let's say
I'll define a state here.
Uh, the state variable I'll take number,
Okay, number.
So this number will be a list of integer.
List of
integer, okay.
And here we are using add
operation.
Why we are using add operation? Because we are using reducer concept. I think you know that.
Okay, and uh this uh this number would be a list, list of numbers, and all of the number would be an integer, okay. So let's say initially, whenever I will pass this number,
pass this number to the graph. Initially, let's say the value is one.
Okay, the value is one.
So
I told you each and every
super step will be having a checkpointer.
Let's say I can define all of the checkpointer. Definitely uh at the first node, there would be a checkpointer, let's say CP1.
Then here also we'll be having a checkpointer CP2, here also we'll be having a checkpointer CP3,
and here we are having let's say CP4.
We are having all the checkpointer.
So what will happen?
Uh yeah, so whenever it will execute it will go to the node one, okay. Let's say node one update uh update this value, let's say this number it will update let's say two,
okay.
Two, it will return two. So it will happen now. The number will become like that.
So in this list.
List so initially the number was I'll denote with n means number.
Initially it was one, right?
One and now it has updated two. So instead of replacing the previous one, it will add the number at the last.
Okay, this is the concept of the reducer.
Okay, and this is called your intermediate state.
Now we got the intermediate state. Now it will go to the next node execution, and here also you are having a check pointer.
Now let's say this generates a single number. Let's say it will generate three, this will generate four, and this will generate five. So what will happen?
Again, the number should be like that one, two, then
this three will come, four will come, and five will come.
So three,
four, and five.
Okay, then it will save this information to the
memory. Okay, every time it will save this information to the memory because checkpointer is saving the information to the memory. Either you are using local memory or any kinds of database, okay.
It will try to save that particular state. Then it will go to the last one that means checkpointer um
checkpointer four.
Let's say this returns the final result, and here you haven't done any kinds of update, so it would be the final, okay. Final number, final number should be one, two, three, four, and five.
Then this final state would be also same, okay, in the database.
Okay, that's how we are not only getting the updated state, and instead of that, we are also getting the intermediate state.
How?
Because of the checkpointer.
Okay, now I think this part is clear to all of you guys.
So, guys, we have understood about this persistence. we have understood the persistence, then we have also understood what is checkpointer and how it works.
Okay, now let's try to understand another important concept as you can see organizing them into unique and retrievable trades. Okay, now let's try to understand what is this trade.
Okay, trades is also a concept of persistence. So, in my previous uh uh part, guys, that means in the part one, I already told you about the trades, right?
We added the trades uh with the help of trades. Actually, we can separate out each and every let's say chat.
Let's say if you are doing chat in trade one, that means in trade two, you won't be able to see that particular chat or in trade
whatever chat you are doing in trade one, you won't be able to see in inside trade two. So, this kinds of thing I think I already showed you.
If you haven't checked that, please try to check my previous part, guys.
So, here let's try to understand this trading concept as you can see. Trades in persistence.
We have already taken an example here, so I'm going to open it up.
So, see here what is happening. Let's say
here we have taken two trades. Let's say this is trade.
This is trade one, and this is trade.
Sorry, this would be trade.
Trade one, and this is
trade two.
Okay, now in trade one, as you can see, I have um I have updated some kinds of state.
Okay, so here would be one actually.
I missed out, yeah. So you you can see um let's say here we got one, then after node two execution, we got one, two, okay, and so on. Like I already showed you this example before, right?
Yeah, now I have taken the same example, but I updated let's say another state number.
Let's say here I started from six, then node after node one execution I got six, seven, then six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Okay, then six, seven, eight, nine, ten. This is the final number.
So, see what is happening here. Although I am executing this graph two time, okay, two times, but in a different trades.
So for the first time, I have given a separate number, and for the second time, I have given another number.
So it is not replacing the previous information as you can see, previous information is remaining same because it is running in a different trade,
and here trade ID is different, it is also running the same graph, but it is running in the another trade.
Okay, I hope you got this concept. So, if I give you one real-time demo, guys, if I go to the chat GPT, so in chat GPT also I think you understand. Let's say whenever we do chat operation, right?
it will basically create a traits.
Let's say this is a traits, this is another traits. Okay, that's why we are having different different traits.
Okay, let's say if I show you, let's say this is the different different hand. Let's say this is another traits,
okay.
This is another traits.
That means this information you won't be able to see
in this particular traits, right?
And whatever information you are having, you won't be able to see in this particular traits.
Right?
These two traits are completely different.
And whenever you are creating these kinds of real-time agentic chatbot or agentic AI application, definitely you have to take care of these particular traits.
Otherwise, what will happen?
It will be getting the previous context as well.
Okay. And I will be able to separate out my chat.
Whenever let's say this info this application is using by multiple person, or let's say by me only, I won't be able to
separate out my chat informations. Okay, everything will be combining in one particular trades and this is not good, right?
So that's why we create this particular trades and now we can also create another trades by clicking on new chat.
Now, if you do any kinds of conversation, see it will create another trades automatically here.
See, new chat has created, and this is another trades.
okay. So we'll also able to see how we can add these kinds of
trading, how we can add these kinds of let's say real time trading inside our chatbot also. Although I have shown you the trades, but I hard-coded the trade one and trade two, right?
in my previous demo, but I will show you okay. Whenever you are creating these kinds of chatbot in a user interface, also how we can add like chat GPT, okay.
This kinds of trading I will also able to show you.
So now I think you understood about the trades, guys. What is trades exactly? Trades is basically uh it stores the informations with a trade ID.
That's whenever you are using any kinds of database or your local storage, it doesn't matter. Let's say whenever you are using local stories, that means your RAM.
That time what is happening in the RAM only, it is creating a separate ID, trade ID.
Okay, that means it is taking a separate space inside a RAM, and for trade to it is taking another separate space in the RAM.
Although it is executing the same graph, but it is executing in a two different place. But in database, what is happening? I know you know that in database we create a table, right?
Inside a table, we can create a another column called trade ID.
Okay, trade ID. Let's see if trade ID one, all of the information would be saved about the trade ID in this particular row itself.
Let's see if trade ID is equal to two, all of this information would be saved with a trade two here. So whenever I need trade one, I will try to fetch the trade one.
Whenever I need trade two, I will fetch the trade two.
Okay, that's how the things work actually. Basically, it saves the same information but in a different different trades to separate out my each of the let's say state or each of the chats.
Okay, I hope you get it, guys.
So, guys, we have understood the theoretical concept of persistence in line graph. Now let's try to see the code example, okay. For this, I will create a simple sequential workflow here.
So this is the graph I have taken. As you can see, this is the this is our workflow. So here basically we'll try to um see um um see an example.
In this example, first of all, we'll try to generate a joke of a topic. Let's say here we'll pass a topic, let's say we'll pass any kinds of topic. Let's say I passed football.
So, first of all, what will happen?
here we'll uh create a node, and this node will try to generate a joke on top of that topic.
Let's say it will generate a joke on football, then after that, we'll pass this joke to another nodes called gen
exp.
Basically, this will generate the explanation of that particular joke.
Let's say the joke we have generated, we want to generate the explanation of that particular joke, then this workflow will be end. And to make this graph, guys, we need a state.
So I already prepared the state as you can see. We named it as joke state. We are inheriting with the type dict, and uh we have taken the state.
First of all, we need a topic, then whatever joke it will generate, joke would be there, then explanation.
Okay, that means the three variables we have taken.
I think this is pretty much clear. So I have already written the code as you can see. This is the code.
So, first of all, let's import all of the necessary library.
We are importing state graph, start end type date, chat open AI, load ENB. Only the new things I have imported this in memory server from Langgraph checkpoint dot memory in memory server.
Okay, so this is what your persistence like uh
A persistence memory that means the checkpointer, like where you want to save this state? So here we are using in memory. In memory means it will save the information inside your RAM.
You can also use any kinds of database.
We'll also see database in future, but as of now, just to show you the demo, we'll be using our RAM.
So let's import all of the necessary library.
Okay. Then we'll try to load the environment variable because there I have my open API key.
I already set my open API key here. Then after that, we'll try to define a large language model. Then we'll define the state, the same state I showed you here.
We are defining the state. Then we'll be writing the nodes. Okay.
So first of all, we have created the graph as you can see.
Then we are adding the nodes.
First node is the generate joke, second node is uh generate explanation. So generate nodes, sorry, generate jokes and generate explanation.
So these two functions I have tried separately because this is going to be my node.
So this is the generate joke uh notes as you can see. It will take this state and it will generate the joke and it will update that joke state.
And this particular nodes will try to generate the explanation.
Here we have given the prompt, so it will take the joke from the state and it will generate the explanation and it will update the explanation.
Okay, so let's try to define all of them.
So after that, we are defining the graph.
So as you can see, we are adding the nodes after that. We have to do the edge connection.
As you can see, h connection is start to gen joke, start to generate joke, then generate joke to generate explanation, generate joke to generate explanation, then
generate explanation to end, generate explanation to end. This is the S connection. Now, if you are using this persistence concept, you have to define a checkpointer.
So here we are defining the checkpointer and we are defining the in-memory server. And if you are using any kinds of database, you have to define the database class here.
This will become my check pointer. Now we'll whenever we'll try to compile the graph, we'll pass this particular checkpointer, okay.
Uh in this particular parameter. Now, basically, by this code, you are telling your line graph um
graph to use this persistence concept.
That means whatever state you are having, okay, whatever state update it will do, whether it's intermediate or final, it will try to save all of the information in this particular memory.
Okay, I hope you get it. Now let's try to compile the graph.
Done. Now let me show you how we can execute this workflow.
See to execute this workflow, you need to define a configuration.
Okay, you need to define a configuration, and in the configuration, you have to define the trades. I already told you, okay, trades is important.
Whenever you are using persistent concept, definitely you have to pass the trade, and each and every trade will store your information in a separate uh
separate space in the memory.
Okay, if you are using a memory, it will use a separate space. If you are using a database, it will use this particular trade ID to store this information.
Basically, in trade one, whatever conversation you are doing, you won't be able to see in trade two, or in trade two, whatever conversation you are doing, you won't be able to see in trade one.
Okay, that's how you can create as much as trade you can, like the chat GPT.
We saw the example, right? So we are reviewing the configuration. There is a parameter called configurable. You have to define as a dictionary, then you have to define the trade ID.
So let's say we have given one, then we are invoking the workflow. We are passing let's say topic is equal to football.
Let's say uh here the topic should be the football and it will generate a joke on top of the food ball. Okay, then we are passing the configuration here. Now let's execute
okay, guys. So here I'm getting an error, rate remit uh limit error.
I think my open AI credits is over.
so what I can do, maybe I can use other model.
So let's use another model. Maybe I can use Gemini. Gemini, maybe I can use this model freely okay for some request. So what I'm going to do, guys, quickly.
Um
you can simply go to the chat GPT.
I have already done, let me show you.
See, so I go to the chat GPT, then I given my code. Let's say this is the code I'm using, and can you change the model to Gemini?
model to Gemini, open AI credits is over.
Now it has suggested okay, that's how you have to use the Gemini model. First of all, you have to install this library, Langchain uh Google J.
So let's try to add inside our requirement.
So I've already added inside my requirement. Now let me install that.
So pip install
ipenr
requirement.txt.
Yeah, that's how you can use any model. Okay, model doesn't matter. Either you can use OpenAI model, Gemini model, open router provider, anything you can use.
Once it is done, then I'll try to simply
see the next step, I have to collect my Google API key. So and we have to add inside the environment variable. So let's try to do that.
So this is my environment variable.
So here I'll try to add my Google API key. And where we will get the API key, you have to go to the Google uh AI Studio.
Google AI Studio.
So left hand side, you will be able to see the API key option.
Now let's try to generate the API key.
I already have some API key here.
Maybe I can delete.
Okay, you want to create a new one? Click on create API key, Gemini API key.
You can select your project if you have any project. Let's I'll select my project and create the API key.
Once done, let's copy this API key and I will try to
paste it here.
Done.
Okay, now let's try to.
Yeah, now let let me check. So if you want to do that, first of all, you have to import this line.
Instead of open AI, you will import this Langchain Google Genei, import chat Google generate TBI.
Let's import
load the environment variable.
Then you have to uh replace this.
Okay, replace this uh model definition with uh uh here. I'm using Gemini 1.5 flash. I think this is the free model, free to use model, and this is the temperature parameter. Now let's define okay.
Now I think it's fine.
Now everything is good. Now I will come here or let's try to do uh execute all the
cell again,
otherwise, I think I might get some issue.
I'll define the graph now. Let's invoke this workflow.
Okay, here I'm getting a client error.
Uh okay, this model not found
during the task with name joke ID.
Okay, let me check this model not found.
I can try with this pro model.
Okay, this is also not found. Maybe I can try with this
two five flash.
I think this should work.
Yeah, one five I think it is deprecated from the
API. You have to use two five.
Now, see, we are getting the output. That means 2.5 is working. Okay, you have to use this 2.5 flash.
Okay, now see here is the topic we have given, and this is the joke I got, and this is the explanation okay. We are getting from this particular joke.
It's working fine, okay.
Now, if you want to see this state, right? If you want to see your state, because this state got saved in the memory, you have to call this function get state, and you have to pass the configuration.
That means our trade ID configuration, trade one configuration. Now, if you execute, now see this is the snapshot. This is your state.
You can see the topic, you can see the joke, you can see the explanation,
and some other metadata informations are available here.
Okay. Now, if you want to see the entire like intermediate state as well as the final state, you have to execute this function get state story, and again you have to pass the configuration that means
trade one.
Now, if I execute this, now see guys, you are getting all of the intermediate state as well as the final state.
Okay, now the last one you can see this is the last last uh like that is the final state, and the first one this is the first
state, first intermediate state. Now, if I show you this graph, guys, so how many checkpoint you have here?
See, you have one checkpoint, two, three, and four.
So that means four output we are getting. So this is the first checkpoint output. So initially, whenever we pass the topic, we didn't have any kinds of joke, then
explanation, okay.
We didn't have anything. You can see initially this was only running the start node and there is nothing, okay. Then we executed the second node that means the second checkpoint.
In second checkpoint, we passed the we only pass the topic, okay.
And that time we didn't have any kinds of joke.
You can see we didn't have any kinds of joke or this explanation.
Okay, you can see this was nothing.
Then at the third third you can see checkpoint, it was it has generated the joke, okay.
that time explanation was not available, okay. You can see uh topic was there, joke was also there, okay.
Joke was also there, but explanation was not there.
because you can see explanation is completely empty, it was not there, right? Then whenever we executed the last node, that means we got the checkpoint for that time. Explanation was available.
You can see topics is available, joke is available, explanation is also available.
Okay, that's how you will be able to see the final snapshot as well as the intermediate snapshot of this state.
Okay, this is amazing, right? And that's how your persistence is working, and this is super important, guys.
Just trust me, this is super important concept whenever you are implementing any kinds of Agentic AI application. That's why uh in my first part, the application I started, guys, Agentic chatbot.
So there I use this particular concept, this persistence concept.
So there also we created this checkpoint. I think you remember we created a checkpoint, but here I use this memory server.
I was saving everything in my RAM, but later on, I will also show you how we can add the database as well.
Okay, because I told you we'll be going step by step so that I can teach you each and everything.
Okay, I hope you clear. So now I'll get back to my code. Yeah, now let's uh let me show you one thing.
This uh uh trading concept. Let's say if I right now give this trade ID is equal to two, right?
That means uh completely one another trade would be created, another block would be created in the memory, and in that particular memory it will save all the information.
Now, see we are invoking with another topic called cricket. Now it will generate uh generate the joke on top of the cricket, but in a different trade.
Let me show you.
Okay, if you're using free model, it might take some time.
Now you can see this is the topic, and this is the joke, and this is the explanation we are getting on top of cricket.
Now, if you want to see the state, final state, final snapshot, this is the final snapshot.
And if you want to see the all the intermediate state as well as the final state, you have to execute this line. Now you can see this is for football.
Okay. Now the best part is that if I change this configuration anytime, let's say I want to get my I want to get my
football, sorry, not football. Okay, this is configuration one. I pass, sorry, I have to give configuration two.
Now if I give configuration two, now see this is for cricket.
Here also I have to pass the configuration two because this is my uh uh trade two, right? Now if I give configuration one,
so this is my trade one, that means cricket, sorry, football.
Now if I give you trade two, now this is cricket, okay. See all of the estate is different right now because it is saving inside different different trade.
Okay, I hope you get it, guys.
So from this persistence, guys, we got some benefit definitely.
So let's try to define the benefit
benefit of
persistence.
So the first benefit we got the short-term
memory.
I think you already saw the short-term memory, right?
we have implemented because it is saving the information in this state, okay, in a database.
And in my previous code example, also, the chatbot I created this was also able to remember my information. So, okay, this is called short-term memory.
We can implement okay with the help of this persistence.
Now, the second one
benefit you will be getting called this fault tolerance.
Fault
Okay, I already told you about this fault tolerance.
Fault tolerance means I think here I showed you somewhere, yeah. So let's say um if uh your application got crashes
from any any particular nodes, instead of executing your application from the beginning, you can resume the application uh from the same uh same crash point um itself.
Okay, let's say node one, your application got crashes from node one itself, you can execute your application. Okay, for this I will show you a practical demo.
I think after that you will be able to understand. Then
this persistent helps us to implement this HITL that means human in the loop concept.
Then there is another one called
Okay, time travel. We'll also see the example itself. Now we have already seen the short term memory example. even going forward, also I'll use this concept in my application.
Okay, uh, you already understood this concept. Now let's try to understand this fault tolerance, like how we can resume the application whenever it got crashes.
Okay, so let's see the fault uh tolerance uh example. Um, like I will show you a code example how it works for this. Here I have taken uh this particular workflow.
Uh it's a like very uh basic dummy workflow I have taken. I generated from this workflow from chat GPT.
So here uh what I have done, guys, I have um uh taken actually three steps step one, step two, step three. So, what is fault tolerance?
I told you fault tolerance means uh let's say uh at step two, let's say you got crash.
Okay.
Crash your application.
So
instead of running from the beginning, whenever you are resuming your application, instead of starting from beginning, so what you can do, you can start from step two
itself. Okay, because I have all of the intermediate state data.
Okay, till uh step one.
So I don't need to execute from step uh uh sorry uh stay uh from the first step again. I will execute from step two, okay. So this is called fault tolerance.
So this example we'll try to see in a code example. So here what I have done, guys, here uh manually just I have taken up uh like time.
I am using time module in Python, and here I will wait for 30 seconds, okay.
And in 30 seconds, what I'm going to do, I'm going to just do a manual keyboard interruption and I will just crash my application here, okay.
And I'll show you how we can resume your application from step two itself.
Okay, that means whatever your application will get crashed from here itself it will try to uh from here itself it will try to restart the application. Okay, this part I will show you.
But this what I've done, guys, I have written a code in Google Collab. So why I'm writing in Google Colab because in my VS Code I was not able to I was not able to interrupt this cell.
Okay, it was taking lots of time, that's why I have copied this code on my Google Colab. So I already connected the notebook and I will share this notebook with you guys.
So here what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to import all of the necessary library.
Then here for this particular
graph, I have defined all of the state I need, like I need input step one, step two, okay, and I uh inherit it with the type d
then here I have defined all of this step step one, step two, step three. You can see all of the step I have defined, step one, step two, step three.
Only in step two, guys, here I am uh just taking this time.sleep.
I will wait for 30 seconds, okay. And here I'm only just doing the print statement. I'm just doing like step one executed and return the step, okay, and update the state.
And step two, only I'm just doing this uh waiting operation 30 seconds. We'll wait, and in between, I'll just try to crash my um the cell. And step three also I'm just only doing the print statement.
Okay, this is the dummy code I generated from chat GPT.
Now let's execute this cell on also.
Now, here we are building the graph. As you can see, we're taking the graph and we are adding all of the nodes one by one, then we are doing the edge connection, okay.
Then we are taking the check pointer in memory server, then we are just compiling the graph and we're giving the check pointer
done now. Here, guys, uh, in the type set block, I am invoking my um you can see graph, and I am just doing some print statement.
Okay, so you can see I'm giving um uh input is equal to start because here I told you we are only doing uh by very basic workflow execution,
that's why I've just given some dummy value here, and here we are giving the trade also. That means the configuration.
I think you know in persistence you have to give that. Then in exception, we are also printing kernel manually interrupt crash simulated. Okay, now let's execute. Now, see it will wait for 30 seconds.
In between, I'll just try to stop the kernel. Okay, now see kernel stop that means my application got crashed.
Now, if I show you my state, as you can see,
step one done. Okay, step one executed perfectly.
perfectly, it's done. Now, whenever it was running step two, right?
There is nothing you can see. Step two didn't complete it because here it got crashed.
Now I will rerun this particular
workflow again, and you will see that instead of running from the beginning, step one, it will run from step two.
So, again, what I'm doing guys, I'm inbocking the graph, and as of now, the input I'm only giving this none. Okay, why I'm giving the none?
Because if you are doing the fault tolerance, instead of see previously I was giving my input, but right now I want I don't want to start from the beginning, I want to start where it got crashed.
That's why I have to pass the none.
Okay, then we are giving the trade again, and we are giving the same trade.
Now let's execute. Now we'll see that it is running from the step two.
As you can see, it is not running from the step one, it is running from the step two, and after waiting for 30 seconds, you will be able to see the final output.
Let me show you.
30 second you have to wait. Now see, execution is done. Now we are getting the final step. You can see step two is also done.
Now, if you want to see the state, as you can see, step one is done, step two is also done. Okay, so that's how guys fault tolerance works with the help of this persistence. I hope you get it, guys.
That's how you can resume. Okay, you can resume your any kinds of workflow whenever it got crashes in production.
Okay, I hope you clear, guys.
Now let's try to understand this H I T L that means human in the loop. like how persistent helps us to implement this human in the loop.
See, for this, let's take a simple example and try to understand this one because I'm not going to show you as a code example for this human in the loop. I'm going to create a dedicated video.
See, let's say I want to generate a LinkedIn post, okay? Or let's say Facebook post. First of all, I have to take a topic, okay.
Topic name from the user, then it will go to the next nodes, it will basically generate let's say this uh Facebook.
Facebook post okay.
Once it generated the Facebook posts then I want actually it will wait for the human verification. Let's say it will wait for the human verification. Let's say if I verify by post is completely fine.
That time I'll give the permission, just try to post this particular uh post to the
Facebook platform. For this, maybe we can use an API provider, Facebook API provider, and we can basically post this.
Uh sorry, here yeah, basically here we we we can post this particular post on the Facebook, so maybe I can draw it
perfectly.
So topic,
then
Facebook
post,
then here it will wait.
h, it
l even in the loop.
then it will post this.
post. this, uh, let's say, post to the Facebook platform.
Okay, now you can see here uh whenever we'll try to build this workflow, right?
Whenever we'll try to build this workflow, so that time user will give a topic name, it's completely fine from the topic itself.
Your Facebook post would be generated, then here itself it will wait for the human verification.
Okay, here it will wait for the human verification. So that time uh human can give this particular verification in one minute, 30 seconds, one day, two day, okay?
It doesn't matter, or after one month also, okay, based on the user, let's say, choice, user preferences. Okay, so it's not like that your entire workflow should be running.
Let's say user want to give this uh uh permission after two days. It's not like that you have to run your entire workflow two days, okay, and you have to wait for the user verification.
Otherwise, what will happen if you are continuously running?
Uh, you are ending up with like your hosting cost, right? I don't want that computation cost, I don't want that. So, what will happen?
This uh fault, uh sorry, this persistence that means
uh you have learnt about this fault tolerance, right? So, here basically fault tolerance concept would be applied. That time automatically, this particular uh execution would be interrupt.
Okay,
interrupt it. This execution would be interrupt. Interrupt would be it would be stopped.
Okay, then human will come and give the let's say feedback. Let's say he has accepted this particular post.
That time this workflow will again re-execute and instead of running from the beginning, okay, instead of running from the beginning, what it will do, it will start from here only.
That means the post is accepted. Now it will run the next workflow which is post.
Okay, the next note which is post instead of running from the beginning. Okay, and how it is remembering because it has the persistence concept, because all the intermediate data it has also saved.
Okay, so whenever it will get the new data, that time from here only it will start.
The example I showed you right now, fault tolerance, it will work in the same way.
Okay, I hope you got it, guys. That's why this persistence is also required whenever you are using whenever you are implementing this HI TL concept that is human in the loop concept.
Okay, I hope you're clear.
Now, guys, let's try to understand the last benefit which is time travel. Okay.
the concept uh looks interesting, even this is also interesting inside this
line graph inside the persistence. Let's try to understand what is time table exactly.
Okay, so see here I have already taken the code example.
I will just show you okay how things are working. So I think remember we just created this um
this um um joke generator generator actually workflow, right? We created this joke generator workflow.
So in type table, actually, what you can do uh you can actually go to the each and every nodes and you can see their execution.
Okay, so here see let's say this is our workflow we created previously, right?
Now here I showed you all of the execution, all of the snapshot, all of the like state update, right? All of the intermediate and final.
Now let's say I want to go to a particular um particular let's say checkpoint. Let's say I want to go in this particular checkpoint, okay.
Where I only pass the uh where I only pass the let's say topic is equal to cricket. So what I will do, I'll just do workflow dot get state, and here you have to pass the configure configuration.
So here this is was my trade to write that means configuration to I'm passing my configuration to that's why you're giving the trade to here because in configuration
I was giving the trade to.
Then here you have something called checkpoint ID. So here you have to give the checkpoint ID. Now you can see every snapshot is having a checkpoint ID.
So here, if you just go right side, here you can see the checkpoint ID. You just need to copy this checkpoint ID and you have to provide it here.
Okay, once you do that, now if you execute this, okay, you will be able to see that it will only return you that particular snapshot.
Uh that's the output, that particular state only.
Okay, now you can ask me why it is required and uh how it is helpful.
See, whenever you are creating any kinds of complex workflow and you want to do the debugging operation, that time this concept is required.
Okay, this thing you won't be using frequently whenever you want to perform some kinds of debugging, you want to see each and every node execution that time this time table you can use.
Okay, now you can see the exact same thing you are getting here.
Now, let's I want to see the after that uh let's say this this snapshot.
Okay, so I'll give this particular ID.
So if I go to the right side, you will have the checkpoint ID.
You just need to copy that, and here I have already passed that. Okay, now I already executed.
You can see here I'm getting topic is equal to cricket, and this is the joke, and uh here I got the explanation.
Okay, now if I show you the entire uh get is uh state story, now see initially it was four. Now two more uh snapshots is created because I did the time table. Okay, so this is the first one.
there I only got the topic, and here is the second one.
Okay,
now let's try to see another concept which is update state, okay.
like let's say here I'm having this particular node, right? And each and every node is updating some kinds of state, right? Now, if you want, you can also manually update your state.
Let's say your workflow has generated some state state, okay.
But you want to update, let's say initially I have given cricket, topic is equal to cricket, but right now I want to let's say debug with uh tennis.
Okay, so what I will do, I'll just write uh workflow.update state, and here you also need to pass the configuration that means your trade ID, and you have to give the checkpoint ID.
Now, let's say at the very first checkpoint, this was the checkpoint, right? There I give it the cricket, topic is equal to cricket. So I'll copy this uh checkpoint ID.
Okay, I'll copy the checkpoint ID and you have to provide the checkpoint ID here. Okay, after that, here you have to pass the topic, topic is equal to tennis.
I have given okay. This is a dictionary.
Now, if you execute, you will see that this particular state would be updated. Now, if you again execute the workflow, now you'll see that another state would be created.
Now, here topic is equal to tennis.
Okay, so that's how you can do the debugging operation. If you want, you can update your state, even you can do the time table through your entire state. Okay, this is also possible.
And here I already updated your fault tolerance code in the same notebook itself, okay, so that you can copy paste in the Google Cool app, guys.
So, yes, guys, this is the concept uh we have understood inside persistence, and by this video itself, you have now enough information like how much persistence
importance uh is like whenever we are creating these kinds of agent TKI application and how persistence is helping us without persistence. Actually, what will happen?
Okay, we have understood each and everything. Now I think you don't have any kinds of question.
Okay, that's why uh in my first part, guys, I added this persistence concept, I added this checkpointer concept. Okay, now I think this part is pretty much clear, guys.
Okay, so that's how guys we'll be implementing the chatbot in detail. I will try to make this particular chatbot more advanced, okay. Agentic chatbot more advanced.
I'll try to add all of the concept one by one by explaining these kinds of concept separately.
Okay, so we have created our basic skeleton, basic agentic chatbot workflow. So here you can perform any kinds of chat operation right now. So, let's see: if I give a message,
generate a
blog about,
let's say, Python.
So, if I send this prompt now, see, it is able to generate the blog.
Okay, so we have already created uh this kinds of skeleton, this kinds of workflow, like chat workflow, and everything is working fine.
Now, in this video, guys, I'm going to um Just deep dive into this streaming, like what this streaming is and why it is required.
And we'll also try to understand: if we don't use these kinds of streaming features inside our agentic chatbot or any other agentic application you are creating, so what should be the issue?
Okay, so guys, uh, we'll try to continue with our discussion of the streaming features inside uh.
Agentic chatbot, and if you are using language guys by default inside language the streaming features is available. Okay, with the help of that, you can easily create the streaming features.
So for this, you can go to the documentation of this line graph so there they have given some code example. Okay, but let me first of all show you my code example. Okay?
Then after that, you can go through the entire documentation, okay, and you can understand about the streaming.
Okay?
Yeah, so guys, see if I'm not using the streaming features, so how my chatbot will look like? First of all, let me show you.
So guys, as you can see, this is the code we have already written for this agentic chatbot, and this is our first initial workflow we have created.
Okay. This is the chatbot workflow we have created, and here, if you just go to the last part, so here I already discussed about the streaming, okay? How to add the streaming features.
But yeah, I think in the first part, you might have some kinds of confusion like how we have added this particular stream stream features here.
So, in this particular video, I'm going to clarify each and everything, then I think this would be more clear, okay?
So here, what I'm going to do guys, uh, let me show you the non-streaming, uh, like features. First of all, so I think this code is also common.
Initially, I also created this code and you remember there, I'm not using any kinds of streaming features, okay? So what I'm doing, I'm just generating the response. After that, I was um
like waiting for the entire response. Once I got the response, I was just showing on the Streamlit user interface. So if I execute this particular file, let me show you, so I'll stop my app.py.
And I will execute this nonstream.py, so I'll just write: "streamlit
okay streamlit run
non stream.py ". Now, if I hit enter,
so this will load my application.
Now here, let's see. If I give the same prompt, "generate a blog
", okay, about —let's say
I'll give
"machine learning
". Now. see if I give this prompt?
Now see, here we have to wait, right?
We have to wait, uh, till the execution. Now see, so here I think you have observed: we had to wait unless and until this output got generated here.
So let's say, if you are generating some more, let's say content here, some more big content, that time it will take some time. Maybe it can take, let's say,
30 seconds, 60 seconds. Okay, it depends upon your output or the prompt you are giving. Let's say you are running an agent and that that agent is taking time, it is using some kinds of tool.
Okay, so uh in between, actually, it will do lots of work and you have to wait for the execution. So this is not good, right? This is not good, uh, user experience. So, if I open Chat GPT, okay?
If I open Chat GPT in Chat GPT, if you give any kinds of prompt —let's say you will give the same prompt in the Chat GPT —okay,
you'll see that Chat GPT also will give you some kinds of streaming response. See, this is giving you a streaming response one by one, right? And this is more interactive, right?
This is more interactive because we don't need to wait for the entire execution to be completed, okay.
Whether it is using any kinds of tool, whether it is uh doing the reasoning operation, it doesn't matter, but I'm able to see my output token by token.
Okay, so this is good user experience here, but inside this particular application, this is not good experience. So if I uh give this kind of prompt, so what is happening?
It is taking some time, right? That's I'll give right now. Deep learning,
see, it's taking lots of time.
So this is not a good experience, okay? So that's why streaming features is required. Okay, streaming features is required.
Now let's try to understand what is streaming exactly and why it is important inside our application development.
So, guys, first of all, let's try to understand now what is streaming. So, here I have already written a definition in LLM.
Streaming means the model starts sending tokens, uh, that means word as soon as they they are generated instead of waiting for the entire response to be ready before returning it.
Okay, see what happens whenever we are using any kinds of large language model, it generates the output as token by token
or word by word.
Okay, so whenever let's say we invoke any kinds of large language model, let's say this is our LLM and we are giving some kinds of prompt here
and we get a response here, okay. So, what you can do either you can get this response in one shot, that means you have to wait for the entire output to be generated.
Okay, for this we use something called invok function, okay.
Invok function, I think you already know that we are using okay so far.
So, invok what it does it will wait for the entire output to be generated, but LLM will try to generate the output as token by token. Let's say it is generating something.
So, first of all, one token will come, then another token will come, another token will come. Okay, that's how it will complete the entire execution, okay.
That that's how it will complete the entire execution, then you will be able to see the response. But in streaming, actually, what we do, we use something called stream function.
Instead of invoke, we use dot stream function.
this is already a default inside Langgraph.
Whenever we are defining any kinds of graph object, right? And you remember we we are doing the invoking operations instead of invoking operation, we have to perform dot stream operation.
So if you do dot stream operation, so what will happen that time you will be getting this particular output as a token by token or word by word as soon as they are generated,
okay. Instead of waiting for the entire response to be ready before returning it, okay. So, this is what actually your streaming is. I think you already saw inside chat GPT.
Okay, chat GPT it was generating token by token.
Let me show you again.
So maybe I can give another prompt.
So I'll give let's say let's generate a blog about deep learning.
Now, see it will generate the output token by token. You can see token by token it is generating.
Okay, now I think this definition is pretty much clear. Now let's try to understand uh why this uh streaming is required.
Okay, you can see the first point uh faster response time and low drop off rates. Okay, I think by this uh
point itself you can understand what I'm trying to say. Uh, faster time time res uh uh response time is let's say whenever I'm using any kinds of chatbot, let's say I'm using chat GPT, okay.
I'm using chat GPT or any other thing. Uh, so there I definitely need a faster response.
so if it is not giving faster response, that time like uh I won't be getting interest right to use this particular application because
nowadays time is expensive, right? Time is expensive, and and nowadays people don't have that much of time so that they will wait for the entire execution, okay?
That is taking one minute to run, so they don't have that much of time, they will wait and they will get the let's say entire output, okay? So they need a faster response.
So definitely, faster response is required whenever you are creating any kinds of application, whether you are creating chatbot, whether you are creating AI agents, okay, anything you are creating,
faster response is required.
Otherwise, what will happen?
There would be a drop-up rate. So, drop-up rate means people will leave your application.
Okay, let's say if it is taking one minute to run.
So, definitely I'll leave your application.
Okay, I'll leave your application I will look for some other application which can give me faster response. So that's why if it is faster response time, that means low drop up rates.
Okay, low drop up rate means people will not leave your application, they will be continuously using like chat GPT. People are using Delhi, right?
Because it is having the faster response because of the streaming features.
Okay, we know that LLM takes some time to generate the entire output, but we have to handle it smartly instead of waiting for the entire let's say
output to be generated, whatever token it is generating, okay, one by one, we will show to the user so that they will see something in the screen.
Okay, this is what we have understood in the first point. Now, the second point you can understand, guys, mimics the human-like conversation, build trust, feel alive, and keep the user engaged.
Okay, see whenever you are doing any kinds of conversation with any kinds of agent or chatbot or whatever, you are doing the conversation, so
definitely uh there some kinds of engagement should be there. Let's say if this application is taking one minute to run, right? And you have to wait for the execution.
So definitely I can't tell this is like a human-like conversation. Let's say you are talking with someone, let's say this is you, okay. This is you, and this is someone.
You are talking with someone, right? And if you're asking something and let's say this person is taking one minute to give you the response, so definitely you will not feel like uh
interested, you will not feel engaged, okay?
You will you will not be able to build a trust with that particular person, okay. I can give you another example. Let's say I think you know nowadays people are using lots of
hardware assistant, right? Hardware assistant means like Amazon Alexa,
Amazon Alexa, then Google Home Mini.
Okay, Google Home Mini, people are using that, right? So this is kinds of personal assistant system, and what we do, we use this particular assistant system so that we can speak with them, right?
Speak with them and we can do lots of tasks. Now, let's see if you are talking with your personal assistant, you are talking with your let's say Google Home Mini.
Okay, you are talking with your Google Home Mini, and let's say it is giving you the response after one minute, so definitely you will not feel engaged, you will not feel alive, you will not feel
like you are not going to build a trust, okay, with that particular device. So that's why mimic human-like conversation it is required.
So whenever I will talk with my let's say bot or let's say agents, so I'll feel like okay, I'm talking with the human.
Okay, instantly I'm getting the response, and the response is engaging as well, okay. Like chat GPT. If you uh if you are using chat GPT, uh I think you know that this
engagement, then alive trust is super important, right? And we we found inside that particular chat bot, right?
That's why we are using continuously, so that's why this is super important, then important for multi-model device.
Okay, so whenever you are using multi-model and you are creating a user interface, so this is also required there, okay.
Sometimes you will be generating some kinds of image, and whenever you are generating the image, that time
you can show, like we are okay, we are generating the image, we are taking this particular, let's say, uh, color,
or there should be an image window, continuously it will tell okay, we are generating something, so that's why you have to show something.
Streaming means you have to show something on the screen, okay, instead of just keep waiting the user here. Then better ux uh uh ux for long output such as code.
So whenever you are generating any kinds of code, let's say you created an agent that generates the code, so instead of waiting for the entire code generation, you can
show the streaming.
Okay, like it is importing, it is defining the model, it is creating the architecture. So. One by one, you can show it here. Okay, so this is another user experience we get.
Then you can see uh you can cancel midway savings uh tokens. That means whenever let's say you are chatting with your agents or chatbot and you are generating a long form content, right?
And let's say you found some kinds of content useful and you don't need
like the remaining content. So, what you can do, you can stop, you can cancel the midway execution to save the token.
Because what happens whenever LLM generates the output, it generates as a token, right?
And whenever you're using any kinds of provider, let's say open AI or Gemini, it charts based on the tokens, like how much token you are giving as an input and how much token
your model is returning as an output, okay. Based on the token count, it will charge you. So let's say I don't need some unnecessary information.
So definitely I can stop the execution and I can save my tokens. Okay, this is only possible whenever you are adding these kinds of streaming features.
So if you are adding like one shot one shot output, that time this is not possible, okay. Then you can interact uh interleave UI updates, uh uh example show thinking, show tool result, okay, etc.
So whenever we'll be creating any kinds of agents, so definitely it will be using tools, right? And whenever it is using tools, that means uh that execution will take some time.
First of all, tool will be executed and this will fetch the uh informations, then it will pass to the LLM. So it's taking some time, right?
That time instead of waiting, I can show something in the user interface. Let's say it is right now using this particular tool, and this tool is facing this kinds of information.
Okay, I can just show these kinds of output to the user so that user feels like okay, now my application are using some kinds of tools
so that it will generate the final output. User will wait, but if it is if you are not showing that, so what will happen?
User will think like okay, my application got hanged, so definitely they will leave your application, okay?
So that's why this streaming is super important, and we need the streaming whenever we are creating these kinds of agentic system, guys.
Now we have already understood this streaming. Now let's try to understand through the code. Although I have showed you the code implementation before, so let me show you.
So this is the code implementation I showed you, but in this video, let me show you how things are working, okay? How we are adding these kinds of streaming features.
So for this, uh, I think you know we have already written this agentic chatbot backend. So in the back end, I already created the entire workflow.
So this is our workflow we created, and this is our chatbot object we created. Okay, this is the graph. So, what I can do maybe I can uh show you.
I will create another file.
Let's say I'm going to name it as test.py.
So inside that I'm going to first of all import my
import my chatbot from agentic backend.
So from agentic chatbot backend, we are importing chatbot. Now see if I'm not using this
if I'm not using like streaming that time I was using inbox, I think you remember. I was using inbox and we also need to import this library as well.
yeah,
Human message and base message we have to also import.
So let me check again.
Then I I need to also pass the configuration as well.
So let me copy the configuration.
Config should be also passed here.
So I'll also import the define the configuration
because we are using persistence here, okay?
We have to pass the trade and everything.
I think you know that now we'll try to replace with that.
Yeah, now this is the code, guys. So basically, we are using inbox here, and if you're using inbox, so that means you have to wait for the entire execution to be completed. Let me show you now.
Let's say if I stop the execution
test dot python.
Now see uh we have to wait for the execution. Maybe I can show you with another question
generate a blog
about
Python programming.
Now we'll be able to observe.
Now see okay, you have to wait for the entire execution. So this is not good, okay. Now we have to add the streaming features here.
So here instead of using inbox, uh we'll be using dot stream.
So
you can write like that chatbot
dot stream.
Okay.
Stream
now stream uh takes some argument. Uh first of all, you have to provide
uh the masses.
Okay, I'll try to provide the masses.
Yeah, we'll try to provide the masses. Uh now let's say I'll give the same masses and generate
uh blog
about line graph,
or let's say
machine learning.
Okay, this is the masses.
Now the second parameter you have to provide the configuration, okay, and the third
parameter you have to provide uh the stream mode. Okay, now there are multiple stream mode are available. If I go to the documentation, as you can see, we have update values, masses, okay, custom.
Uh so here I want to print the masses only, so that's why I'll be using stream mode is equal to masses, okay? Because I want to show show my masses streaming, okay.
Whatever um output I'm getting from my LLM, I want to show show this.
Okay, that's why we're using this now. Once it is done, now if I let's say um show you the result, see this stream will return two things one
is the
message chunk,
okay.
message
chunk
that means the token, okay, token output, and it will also give you some kinds of metadata,
okay. Metadata, but I don't need the metadata, I only need the masses, chunk, and metadata.
Okay, so basically, this returns a generator object. Let me show you. So I will give you
example response.
Now, if I print the response
now, if I execute this code
python test py,
so this will give you a generator object as you can see, okay.
Stream generator object, and you already studied inside Python. If we are getting the generator object, I can use any kinds of iterator to get the output. And what is the iterator?
We can use for loop here, okay. for loop will try to iterate the output one by one here, okay. Instead of getting everything in one shot, it will take one by one.
So for this, I will just write a for loop.
So now I can write like that instead of going through the response. Maybe I can
write the for loop here only.
I think that would be amazing.
So for
it will return two things I told you one is the message chunk,
and it will return the metadata
okay
in chatbot.stream.
Okay, now I'll keep this one.
Yeah, now here I'll just write a condition.
If, uh, let's say message
message chunk
dot content okay, I will extract the content only.
Okay, if there is a content sorry content
content I'll just try to print this content.
So, print
message chunk dot content Okay, and here I will give some other parameter like end is equal to this empty string, and uh,
and I will give this splash is equal to true.
Okay, these two things you have to give;
if you check the documentation, they have written the same thing.
Okay, now let me show you how this output would be generated now.
I'll again, I'll execute my test.py
now. See, it is giving you token by token as a streaming output.
Okay, I think you saw the difference and that's how we can um implement the streaming features inside Langgraph.
Okay, I hope you clear now. The same thing uh you have to also do in the user interface because in user interface uh we created this should also show as a streaming output.
And how we have done guys, I think I already written the code, let me show you. See, it is available in the app.py, so here is the code guys.
Okay, we written already. Now we are using something called
um This one write _stream here from Streamlit. We are using write _stream, so if you go to the Streamlit documentation, as you can see, Streamlit has having a chat element.
So it is having multiple chat element like chat input, chat message, status container, and there is another one called write _stream.
Okay, if you seek the write _stream, so they have already written like how to um actually write this particular use this particular write _stream.
Okay, so we are using this write _stream here.
Let me show you. We are using this write stream, so inside that, we have written the same code. We are, instead of doing the invoking operation, we're doing the streaming operation.
We are giving the input config and stream, and we are running the for loop.
It is returning two things: message chunks and metadata. We are only taking the message chunks, okay? And once we got the message chunks, what we are doing guys,
we are just writing the stream on the use. Uh, Streamlit con is Streamlit user interface, and once everything is done, we are updating inside this uh message story inside Streamlit
session state.
Okay, this is a simple code we have written now. I think this code is clear, guys. Okay, how I have written so I think many people have the confusion how these things are working.
Now, I think this is clear.
Now let me show you the final execution.
I will
clear, I'll run my app dot pie ... so, streamlit run
app dot py
So, this is our app. Now I will give
generate, let's say
code
for
image classification
in Python.
Now, see.
Okay, see streaming output we are getting?
So, yes guys, this is all about from this video. I hope you got it. Uh, what is the streaming and why it is required and why we have implemented inside our chatbot?
So, if you check my agentic chatbot, guys, so far we implemented um till here.
So here we can perform any kinds of chat operation right now.
Okay, and uh you can see it's working, and it is also giving you some kinds of streaming response like Chat GPT, right? So in Chat GPT, what happens?
Guys, in Chat GPT, you can resume your conversation with your old trades.
Let's say I did some kinds of conversation previously, I can continue anytime.
These are the conversations. So let's say this was my previous trades, right? So if I open this particular trades, I'll be able to see all of my conversation story, okay?
And I can resume my chat from here only, okay?
I can resume my chat from here only.
Right now, like that, I can go to any another trades. Let's say I will go to these uh
this threads okay. So from here only I can do my conversation.
So this is called trading. Okay, with the help of this trading, we can separate out each and every topic, let's say masses, okay.
Let's say right now I want to do a conversation related let's say deep learning, let's say I need another new session
for another topic. Let's say I want to do the conversation regarding let's say NLP, it's like that, okay.
Instead of doing all of the conversation in a single trade, in a single session, you can create multiple trades, okay, and you can do the conversation
anytime you can come here, you can see the older conversation as well with the different trades.
But this kinds of feature is not available inside our Agentic chatbot.
So, in this video, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to implement this particular features so that uh you can also get your older trades and you can also see
all of the old trades conversation as well, and anytime you can continue your conversation from there only, okay?
So, these kinds of features we'll try to add in this particular agentic chatbot in this video.
So, make sure, guys, you watch this video till the end, don't miss anything.
And if you found this content useful, please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like and please try to share it with your friends and family.
So, instead of talking too much, guys, let's start the implementation and I'm going to show you how we can add these trading features inside this Agentic chatbot.
So, guys, before starting the development, first of all, I want to show you the final result, final demo.
like what are the features we are going to add in this particular agentic chatbot? So, as you can see, we already added this trading features inside our agentic chatbot.
Previously, it was a simple chatbot only. Okay, there we didn't have any kinds of trading features, like I can't see my older trades, right?
it was not there, but in the new update, as you can see here, we have added a separate section, so from here only you can go to your previous conversation.
So, let's say here I am doing a conversation, let's say I'm asking what is Python, right?
let's say I will ask
my name
is Bappi,
and I'll tell what is Python.
Now you can see Python is a high-level programming language, and blah blah blah. Now, if I ask what is my name,
now it is telling your name is Bappi.
Okay, so this is uh conversation we have done in this particular trades, as you can see. We are using uh unique
ID right to save this particular conversation story in this particular trades.
Now, what you can do like the chat GPT, you can start a new conversation here. So I will click on new chat now. See, it will give me a completely new trades here.
Now, here if I ask what is my
name,
okay. What is my name?
You'll see that I'm sorry, I'm an assistant, I do not have access your personal information. Now, if I ask
my name is
Alex,
what is
ML
now? See it is giving you the response. Now, if I ask what is
my name,
now it will tell your name is Alex. Okay, now see this can this particular conversation is completely separate from your previous conversation.
Now I can go to the previous conversation anytime, okay, where I did like my name is Bapi, what is Python? Now, here I can continue the conversation. Let's say now I'll tell I want to see
hello world.
Program
now. See, it is giving you the hello world program because we did the conversation related Python.
Okay, and here we are doing the conversation
uh with the uh help of Bapi. Okay, so here Buppy is doing the conversation now.
Even I can go to my previous conversation as well.
So this is my previous conversation. This one, my previous conversation. Now, here you can anytime uh resume the conversation. Let's say um how it
helps in
AI.
See how machine learning helps in AI, it is uh telling you each and everything, okay. So that's how you can create different traits and you can see your older conversation as well, like chat GPT.
So chat GPT does the same thing, it also using trading concept, and every time, whenever you are doing that chatting operation,
it is continuously saving your conversation history in a one particular trade, and you can can uh start new conversation anytime, but the older conversation will remain same.
Okay, so this kinds of thing, guys, we have added inside this particular agentic chatbot. Now, throughout the entire video, I'm going to show you the implementation part.
So, guys, uh, this was our previous code we have already written.
So, as you can see, this was our previous app and it doesn't have any kinds of
trading related
code.
Although I added the trading, as you can see, I added the trading, but it was hard-coded, so only I was using trade one for all the conversation.
Okay, that's why this application was simple. Now I'm going to use the same code and we'll be writing the trading features inside this Agentic chatbot.
So, what I can do instead of giving the name to app.py, maybe I can give another name just for your reference. So let's say
whenever you want to refer this particular simple code only, that time you will be able to get this code from here. Okay, so I can also replace the code in my app.py, but
I think you won't be able to get the previous code that time, so that's why I'm going to create a new file.
So, first of all, let me rename it.
So this is let's say
simple app.
Okay, this is simple app we created.
Now I'm going to create another file.
I'm going to name name it as app underscore
uh trade.
Okay, that means the uh this uh code has the trading uh trading code, okay.
Trading related code, trading related features.
Now, what I can do, I can copy the same code as it is
here,
okay.
Yeah, and here this back end code will remain same. The backend code we have written.
This code will remain same.
Here, you don't need to change anything, the change would be applied in the front end part only, okay?
Because in the backend we are only returning the chatbot, this graph object, okay.
So, here what I'm going to do, guys. First of all, I need some more library.
So let me import.
So I need
so here I need uh U ID.
So with help of this U U ID, I'll try to generate unique ID so that I can separate out my each and every trades.
Okay, instead of doing the hard coding, so every time I will generate a unique ID and I'm going to create my trades, okay.
first I'm going to create one function that will generate unique uh unique uh ID, okay. Unique user ID because every time I need this unique user ID for this particular trading, right?
I already showed you that part.
So for this, let's create a function.
So this is the function, guys. I have already created.
Yeah, so this function what it does, it uh generates uh unique ID, uh unique user ID every time. Uh anybody will execute this function, it will give you unique user
ID.
So after getting this unique user ID, what I want to do, guys, I want to
I want to add this unique ID inside my traits.
Okay, so for this, I can create another function.
called add trades.
So, what this add trades will do basically it will add a new trades ID to the conversation list.
Okay, so basically, this will get the trade ID, and why you will get the trade ID will get from this particular function.
First of all, it will check this trade ID. It is uh available in the session state or not.
Okay, that means uh stream lead session state or not.
Uh we'll try to save uh with the help of this chat trades, um, like key.
So if it is not there, it will uh try to set my trade ID. The trade ID it will generate, okay.
So this is a simple function we have created because whenever you will try to initialize your application for the first time, there
it won't be having any kinds of
chat trades, right?
So that time one new trades would be created, completely new set trades would be created, and it will try to append there, and with that particular trades only, we'll do the conversation.
Then later on, if user once they can create the trades, okay, expect their requirement.
Now you can see this chat trades is not available, so we have to also create that.
So if you just go below, so I think you remember we created
message history previously. So here only I'll try to add another one.
So after message history, so we'll just try to write this
As you can see, if chat traits not in session state, it will create a empty chat trades, okay? And this will become a list,
and right now we'll be able to
we'll be able to append that particular trades because now this chat trades session is created, okay.
Here only I will also try to add the comments in my previous code as well, so that later on whenever you are revising this code, I think it would it will be helpful for you,
By seeing the comments only, you can understand what this code is doing. Okay, you can see this uh this code actually creates the message story when the app runs for the first time, okay.
I already created previously, I think you remember.
So once it is done, now let me add
the user interface because if you go to the chat GPT left hand side, you will be able to see all of your uh conversation, okay, all of the threads. So we'll try to create the same thing here.
So for this, let me just create a sidebar first of all.
So here I'll just try to add a sidebar
with the help of streamlit.
So I already commented out this is that sidebar trading features display the sidebar title.
So st.sidebar.title. I just name it as my conversations.
Now, if I execute my code, okay.
If I execute my code, you will be able to see that.
So streamlit run
uh app
underscore trade dot pie. Okay, this file we are executing now.
If I show you my code,
so as you can see, guys, this is our sidebar we created. So anytime you can open and close it, uh like the chat GPT. Chat GPT also has the same thing.
Okay, this is the sidebar.
Now, here only we'll be adding our trading, okay.
So, for this, uh let me just uh show you my updated code. What I have done.
Um
I can show you step by step, I think that would be
best.
So, what I can do, I can just quickly show you
so I'll just uh remove these are the code, okay. My old code, and I'm going to show you my updated code. I think that would be amazing.
I'll just try to remove all of the code.
So, first we'll be adding some utility functions.
First of all, generate uh trade ID. I already told you it will generate the trade ID every time, and other function I have written.
this will basically add the trade ID require to the session state.
Okay, but we have to create the session state.
So let's create all the session state.
I'll just try to add all of the session state.
So this is my message story session session state, and this is for my
chat uh session state. Okay, chat trades. Okay, that means this this one,
and um
um I'm going to
create a sidebar here.
Sidebar here, okay. So this is my sidebar.
Now, if I go to my application again, if I refresh,
now see it looks like that. Okay, don't worry about this chat input feature. I'm going to add it. Uh, just let me update my uh this code first of all, then I'm going to add okay.
That will remain same like we did the previously right now. What I'm going to do, guys. I'm going to add a new button here. So I think you remember chat GPT also has a button.
If you click on this new chat button, it will start a new conversation for you, and you will be able to see the old uh trades as well. So these kinds of features we'll try to add here.
So this is the code.
I'm going to tell you about this reset chat. What this reset chat will do, but let's try to understand.
Uh see, this creates a button for starting a new conversation.
So that would be a button st.sidebar.bton, new chat.
And if you click on new chat, see what will happen in chat GPT. Let's say
let's say I'm inside a trades. Let's say I'm inside this particular trades, okay? I'm inside this particular trade.
Now, once I click on new chat, you will see that one new window will come and all of the previous chat history will be clean up, right?
So for this kind of this reason, I'm also going to write a function called resent reset chat. So whenever user will take the new chat, all of the previous conversation would be removed.
So for this, let's create another function here.
I'm going to name it as
um
reset chat. So after
this function, maybe I can add
okay.
Reset chat.
So what it is doing, you can see uh first of all, it will uh basically generate a new trade ID with the help of this function
and it will store in the trade ID.
The trade ID uh we created
uh session state. I think session state trade ID is not created, so let me create it quickly.
So this is my
Okay, if trade ID not in session state, uh it will create a trade ID and it will take a trade ID from this particular function, okay. Unique trade ID.
Now it is resetting, and uh, what it is doing, it is uh
setting a new trade ID.
Then after that, all of the message study would be empty.
We you can see we are giving empty list, then after that, we are adding this particular trade ID in my session state.
Okay, you can see we are using this add trade function and we are adding this trade ID, the current trade ID in the session state, because
whenever I'm inside this particular trade, okay, I'm inside this particular trade, so all of the conversation should be saved in this particular trades only. That's why
this thing we are doing. So every time we have to track this trade trade ID, all right. Now uh let's say if I go to my
application, if I refresh, now you'll be able to the uh see this new chat. Okay, now if I click on this new chat, so it will basically
run this code, it will basically run this code and all of the recent uh uh I mean recent conversation would be removed, okay.
And uh uh we have to write this st.reton if you are doing the reset chat operation, this is recommended.
So basically, this will this will uh return the streamlit app to update uh update the interface.
Okay, so basically, what is happening uh whenever you are doing this uh new chat operation, it is resetting after getting the resetting operation, it is giving you the new window,
okay?
So whenever you are getting the new window, st dot return.
Okay, this is recommended. If you check the documentation, you'll be able to see that.
Okay, now let's try to add the chat feature.
I'll just try to add the updated chat feature.
So I already written the code, guys. Let me show you.
So this is the code.
And this is the same code, guys. only just few updates I have done. So here we are taking a chat input from the user, okay.
And whenever user is giving their input, first of all, we are appending to the message story, the same thing we did our previous code as well. So message story.
after that, we are setting this is a user conversation, and content is user input.
Okay, and why we are doing this because I want to save my conversation story, and this is the format to save the conversation story.
First of all, you have to define what is the role of this conversation, this is user, and what is the content of that?
Okay, after this, we are showing this conversation in the streamlit user interface. For this, we are taking a chat message. I think remember there would be a uh there would be a icon, okay, user icon.
So we are setting that this is the user icon and this is the user conversation, okay. And here, guys, we are defining the configuration right now, okay.
This is the persistence configuration, this is the trading configuration. Config is equal to configurable. Now, trade ID is equal to st.session state trade id.
Now we are not taking the hard-coded trade ID. Instead of that, see previously we are taking the hard coded trade ID. We are only giving trade one, but right now there would be a multiple trade.
User can create the trades, right?
So we are taking it from the session state, and already session state we have created here.
The session state it is already created.
Uh, session state.
Uh, what is that?
Yeah, session state trade ID.
Now I think trade ID it is available.
Yeah, you can see trade ID is available, and how we are getting the trade ID? It is generating by the UI ID.
Okay, from here only it is getting generated.
Okay, I hope you get it now.
Yeah, from here, actually, we are showing the user sorry, assistant message.
As you can see, we are
taking these st.uh chat message we are taking this is assistant reply.
After that, we are taking the right stream function. I told you in my previous video how
streaming works, right? How we can show the streaming response.
So inside that we are generating the responses from our chatbot object. The chatbot we have imported from the back
end, okay. As you can see, this is the same code, guys. There is no chance we are using after that.
Whatever message chunk we are getting, we are continuously uh writing with the help of write stream function, okay?
And here we are passing the configuration, and we are giving stream mode is equal to masses, okay.
And here we are getting one uh suggestion. I have to import this AI message, so let's import it quickly.
I'll just try to import these AI messes
after human message AI messes, okay? Because this streaming response should be AI messes here, okay.
That's why I'm telling if is instance message chunk, if it is uh like uh message chunk, that means we are getting aim a i reply, right?
So that's why I'm telling this should be aimasses, so this will only show the IMSs here.
Then we are saving the complete assistant response in the stream leave session state in the message story. So this code is common. I think you already know that.
Yeah, this is pretty much clear.
So after this part is done, guys. Now what I'm going to do,
I'm going to simply execute my app,
refresh
now. See, guys, you are getting this window.
Now, if I do the chat operation, let's say hi.
See, I'm getting the response.
Now I'll tell my name
is Bappi.
Now see previous uh message is getting replaced because I haven't added this code here. I do remember previously also I added this code and this uh loading the conversation story.
Okay, we have to load the conversation story every time.
So let's load that
before the user input.
So every time it will load the conversation story, message story, and it will write in the streamlit user interface as a human role
and assistant role, okay.
Because we are running a fold loop, so every time it will looping through the role, first of all, user role will come, then assistant role, then user role, then assistant role
and their content.
Now let me refresh and
again try.
So hello.
My name is
Okay, now nice to meet you, Bappi. Now see, we are able to see the previous conversation.
But right now, what I have to do, so let's say if I click on a new chat, okay, new chat will is coming. Okay, it's completely fine, but I am not able to see my older chat. That means older trades.
So now we'll be adding the code related older trades. So you can also see the older trades.
So what I can do, guys, uh I can show you my updated code I already created for this.
here I can write.
So, this is the code guys I have written display all the conversation trades in reverse order.
And why I have to show in the reverse order, see every time what is happening, if you create new trades, right?
If you get new new trades, so your
uh your uh new trades is coming,
uh new trade is coming at the last, okay.
Because by default, python will add this new trades at the last, okay.
But if you see if I click on new trades, every time this new trade should be coming at the recent chat, okay, at the first uh first uh let's say order.
So that's why we are reversing the order.
So if my new chat is getting added at the last, if I do the reverse operation, that means from the last it will come at the first.
Okay, I think you understood that's why we're doing the reverse order operation.
So this is a list, we are just doing the reverse order operation because in this session state we have this chat traits, okay.
In this session state, we have the chat traits, and this is a list, and it will continuously add at the last.
Okay, let's see if you click on the add new, so new chat will add here.
New chat will add here, right?
And this has your old chat also.
But this will show at the last, but I don't want to see at the last because whenever I'm doing the new conversation, I want to see in the recent chat operation. That means it will come at the first.
Okay, that's why we have to do the reverse operation. So if you perform the reverse operation, what will happen? This new chat will come here right now,
okay. Before the old chat, and with the help of that, I will be able to make it in the present conversation.
So, this is why we are doing this one.
Just a minute, let me
so this is why we are adding this particular quote.
So it is going through the entire uh chat trades and uh here we are giving a button because this should be also a clickable object. If I click on this particular trades, it will be able to
show my conversation.
Okay, that's why we are making it as a button. So st dot sidebar button.
So button name should be trade id only.
Even you can also uh you can also uh give any message name if you want, okay.
If you want, you can also add any message name, and the key should be trade ID.
So once, uh, button creation is done.
we are again saving this trade ID in our current trade, because this is the current trade user will do the conversation, and we'll load all of the conversation in this particular trades.
because if you click here, see, if I click here, it is loading. all of the conversation I did previously, okay, from my memory.
So I will write a function for this for load conversation.
So basically, this will load all the previous conversation here.
So after this uh
reset chat, maybe I can
write this function.
So load conversation, this will take the trade ID, and I think you remember uh from the uh line graph graph we get this state, okay?
If you call this get state function, it will give you all of the
all of the previous conversation.
If you want to understand this, guys, you have to go through this particular session because here I already explained each and everything, so that's why I'm not going to repeat it again.
So this get state function will return you all of the previous conversation.
So we are taking all of the conversation and we are only getting the messages, okay. From the value itself, we're only getting the messages.
Okay, so this particular messages will
show here.
Then we are taking an empty list here, then we are going through the messages one by one, then we are trying to separate out the user conversation as well as the assistant conversation.
Okay, so we are using is instance
function for this.
If you pass any message,
it will automatically tell you whether it is uh human message or let's say AI message. If it is human message, role should be set to the user, otherwise, role should be set to the assistant.
Then after that, we are adding inside my temporary message list all of the conversation as a role and content, then after that, we are just updating in my session state
and it is showing you in the user interface.
Okay, then again we are doing the return operation.
Now let me show you. So if I let's say come here, refresh
now. See uh if I do any kinds of conversation,
if I take a new chat now, see guys, new new chat is getting created, and I can see my previous conversation as well. Now, let's say if I do another conversation, hi
done now.
See, I can go to my previous conversation. This is the new conversation, this is previous conversation.
Okay, so we have added this particular code, and I'm also able to see my conversation history. Let's see if I've done any kinds of previous conversation, I can see the story because of this code.
Okay, this is continuously
where is that?
This function load conversation.
This load conversation is continuously fetching the information
because we are running a full uh running a full loop here, okay.
So every time uh this uh message is getting
fetched,
and one more update we have to do
every time we have to set the current trade to the conversation list, okay. For this, we'll try to add this particular code, okay.
Now I think my application is ready.
This is a simple uh code we have written, only we're just playing with the trade, okay. Trade ID, and for this, we are using UI ID.
We can also make it as a readable title like chat GPT. Chat GPT actually generates readable title uh uh title.
So if you are asking any kinds of question it will generate a title instead of giving a trade ID.
We can also do this particular update, it is also possible.
Now let me refresh my app.
Okay, so this is the app.
My name
is
Bappi.
Okay, so basically, this conversation is getting saved inside this particular trade.
Okay, in this particular trade, it is saving.
Now
I love
cricket.
Okay, now if I take new conversation, now see it is coming as a new uh new session again, and this particular session is coming at the first, and previous one
was a previous one, it is going at the last because we are doing the reverse operation.
Now, here I'll tell my
name is Alex.
I love football.
Now I go I can go to my previous conversation
and here I can resume the conversation.
What is my
uh what is my favorite
okay
you can see cricket is the favorite sport.
now I can go to my current rate and here also I can ask
what is my
name?
Your name is Alex. Okay, so that's how you can create as much as trade as you can.
What is
transformers?
So, this is uh
telling you about the movie, but I can ask: What is transformers in AI?
Okay, now it is telling you what is transformers in AI.
Okay, so that's how guys like chat gpt we created the trades. Now we can switch to different different trades and I can resume the conversation.
So, yes, guys, that's how we can add this trading features like chat gpt.
Now, if you want, you can also change this name to the actual let's say chat title.
If you want, you can also add inside this code. So I'll try to give this part as an assignment to you.
Maybe you can add this functionality in this code, okay? Simply you can go to the chat GPT and you can ask, I want this particular features? how should I add? You will be getting the suggestion.
Okay, so just try to add this update instead of showing you this uh you uh uh unique user ID.
Maybe you can show chat title like chat GPT the way chat GPT shows. Okay, you can also add these particular things. So we have already integrated this chat trading.
now we are able to continue the conversation with our previous chat as well.
That means right now I can separate out my chat trades, I can create a new conversation, I can continue with my old conversation
like chat GPT.
So, yeah, we have already added these uh trading features. So, what will happen right now? Let's say if I continue any kinds of conversation, let's say here I will give hi, my name is
Bappi.
Okay,
so as you can see, it is giving you response. Uh, nice to meet you, Bappi. How I can assist you today? Now, let's say I want to create a new chat like chat GPT.
So, what I will do, I'll just click on new chat, and you can see one new trade has created.
Okay, new um conversation has created. Now, here I will tell hi.
My name is Alex.
See, hello Alex, how I can assist you today. Now I can go to my previous conversation where I told my name is Bhappi, even I can continue with my um the current conversation I did,
right? So that's how you can create as much as session you can.
Okay, but I think you have observed one thing, which is if I refresh the application, okay. Let's say if I refresh the application, so see my previous conversation is getting erased, okay.
Previous conversation is getting removed.
So whenever you are refreshing, okay, whenever you are refreshing, that means your RAM is getting cleared, okay, and all of the conversation is getting erased.
And if you close your application as well, let's say if I disconnect from my terminal, so what will happen?
from the RAM itself, it will be removed, and again, you will be able to see the new chat here.
You won't be able to see the older conversation. This is the problem.
So, yeah, today in this particular video, guys, we'll try to understand how we can add the database features inside the Agentic chatbot so that whenever you are refreshing right your Agentic chatbot,
uh, you will be able to see the old conversation. Right now, this is the problem.
So, right now, if you perform conversation with your chatbot and if you are creating different different let's say chat threads, so if you refresh your application or if you close your application,
it will be removed from the RAM, right? So, these kinds of things we have to fix.
So, that's how guys we'll try to add new features inside this Agentic chatbot and we'll try to make this Agentic chatbot more advanced
and we'll be learning this particular project, okay? So, if you found my content useful, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel and please share it with your friends and family.
And please support me, guys. if you support me, so definitely I will be bringing these kinds of content more, okay, on my channel.
So instead of talking too much, guys, let's start with the implementation. And here in this video, guys, I'm going to show you how we can integrate database functionality in the persistence memory.
So, guys, I have already shared the source code with you, it is already available in the video description.
So, if you open up my previous code, guys, I have already written this code as you remembered.
So, there I tried to uh uh integrate this trading features inside our agentic chatbot, and this is the code we have written, right?
So, this is the entire code, and uh the change we have done in the front end uh because you can see this is the front end uh uh front
end file, and we had another file which is the backend. Okay, in the backend itself, I had my um like let's say uh agentic chatbot backend.
So here I created the chat node, then the uh graph and edges, okay, each and everything I initialized it here and I was returning as a checkpoint uh sorry,
chatbot uh graph object. So here uh if you see in this particular backend file, now here I was using this memory saver, okay, from the
uh checkpoint, check checkpointer, lang graph checkpointer.
So I was importing lang graph dot checkpoint dot memory import in memory server. So if you're using this memory server, that means what is happening?
Uh you are storing all of the conversation in the RAM, and whenever you are refreshing or closing your terminal, it is getting erased, okay? Because RAM is a temporary memory.
Now we have to make it as permanent, okay. For this, we have to use some kinds of database.
Now, if you visit this Langgraph documentation, Langgraph documentation, um, uh you will be uh you will be finding like
some database they are suggesting whenever you are creating these kinds of persistence memory.
So if you check the line graph documentation, there you will be getting some kinds of database like SQLite database they are suggesting.
So SQLite database when you can use whenever you are creating the prototype, right?
As of now, we are learning, we are trying to implement this gentic chatbot. So we are in the landing phase.
Maybe we can utilize the SQLite database because this is completely free to use, and SQLite database actually basically it will create the instance inside your local stories, okay.
But you can also utilize any production grade database like Postgres is there, then um some other database are also there, okay. You can also utilize that.
So going forward, whenever we'll try to create production grade, actually agentic chatbot, that time I'll try to use these at the database,
but right now we are in the learning phase, so we'll try to use some kinds of prototype based database.
Okay, uh, I can utilize sqlite database because this is this would be lightweight for me, and I don't need to take any kinds of subscription plan for that, right?
So that's why I will continue with the SQLite database. So if you go to the SQ Lite documentation, SQLite documentation
So, this is the SQLite documentation, guys.
So, this is uh basically a database.
Uh, this is a database actually you can utilize uh with the help of Python. And uh, if you're using this Lang Graph, guys, uh Langraph also has the connection with SQLite.
Okay, for this, you have to install one library, uh, this library, uh Langraph checkpoint SQLite.
Okay, so you have to install this particular library. If you install this library, you will be able to use this SQLite uh with your Langgraph.
You can also separately install this SQLite if you are only using Python programming. That time separately you can utilize, but here we want to utilize with the help of this Langgraph.
Okay, that's why Langgraph connection is also there. Langgraph SDK is also there.
Someone I think has created this and published on the PyPy, and we are able to use this package inside our development.
Okay, if you check the uh Langraph documentation, guys, uh here in the memory section, as you can see, add short-term memory.
That means this is the persistence memory, as you can see, short-term memory trade level persistence. Okay, so here as of now we use this memory saber uh database.
Uh sorry, memory saber actually stores uh basically this stores your uh conversation in the RAM, and uh you can see uh
they are also suggesting for the production.
So for production use, either you can use Postgres,
Postgres it is also production grade database, and you can create a Postgres server, either you can create a local server, localhost server, either you can create a cloud-based server.
Okay, so any kinds of cloud you can set up this Postgres.
Either you can use like render, either you can use AWS GCP, anywhere you can set up this Postgres server and you can connect with your line graph. Okay, this is possible.
So that's how you can also use MongoDB.
you can also connect with MongoDB, you can also connect with Redis, you can also connect with Oracle. Okay, that's how it is having different different database connection.
But whenever we are creating prototype, I think this SQLite is fine for us because we can set up inside our
local storage only. Okay, I don't need to take any kinds of separate server for that.
Okay, that's why I'm using this SQLite. so uh database doesn't matter, you can use any kinds of database, uh anything will work, but only you just need to know the um like connection, okay.
Integration, how we can integrate the database. Okay, right now I'm integrating the SQLite.
Maybe you can also integrate any other database, only you just need to get this connection string.
Okay, let's see if you're uh set up this database in the server, you just need to get this connection string.
Okay, if you get this connection string, you can check the documentation and you can copy this code and you can change it anytime.
Okay, it's up to you. So here the main change, guys, I have to do in the back end file because in the back end file I am using this memory server, and instead of memory saber, I have to use my uh
this one.
Uh I have to use my um um database. Okay, so for this, uh I have to first of all install this library.
Uh, where is that?
Uh yeah, the install this library. So I'll copy this command or I can copy the
name
and I will add inside my requirements
now. Let's install it here.
I
can add
requirement.txt. So for me it is already satisfied because I installed it previously, but for you it may take some time.
So once installation is complete, guys,
I'll open up my
backend file
and in the back end itself I'll try to change that, change that. So here what I'm going to do.
I'm going to
should I change in the same file or should I create a new file?
If I change in the same file, then you will be able to you won't be able to get the older code. So what I can do, maybe I can
um
I can
create another file, okay?
So I'll create a same file, I'll just rename it.
Agentic chatbot
backend
Here I'll just try to add
DB backend.
Okay, DB backend means uh it has the database integration.
Okay, uh that's how you will be able to see the previous code as well. Okay, yeah, I think this is fine. Now, here instead of this memory saber, we have to import uh this uh sqlite saber.
So from line graph checkpoint here you have a
class called SQLite, okay, and instead of memory saber, we have to import sqlite
okay, sqlite saber, so you have to import that.
So once it is done, now I'll just go below and here you can see I created a checkpoint object and I use this memory saber instead of memory saber.
I will use my SQLite saber SQLite saber okay, this class. Now this SQLite saber takes a connection object. Now you have to initialize the connection object database connection object.
Basically, you will be connecting with the SQLite database.
So for this, uh you have to import this SQLite library import
sqlight3,
okay.
SQLite3. So this is already available inside Python.
Then after that, here I will create a connection object.
So to create a connection object, guys, uh you just need to initialize this SQLite 3.
Then there is a function you have to call call connect.
Okay, connect, and inside that you have to give a first parameter which is database.
You have to initialize the database, okay?
So here basically this SQLite creates the database object inside your local storage only.
That means inside your project folder only it will create a database, okay?
it will create a db file, so you have to give the db file name. So here I'm going to name this file as chatbot.db.
Okay, and here you have to give another parameter which is check same trade is equal to false.
Okay, why we have to give this particular parameter because I think you remember we are using the trading concept, right?
Chat uh trading concept. So every time user is creating separate trades and they are doing the conversation, and by default, actually, SQLite doesn't support uh actually multi-trading.
That means you can't uh apply the trading, uh, you can't create a different trades in the SQLite.
Once you have created one particular session, you have to continue uh the uh the same execution in that particular session only. Okay, by default, this parameter basically it's true, right?
But if you make it as false, then SQLite will try to give you the access for the trading concept. That means you can
do the multiple trading chat, okay. That means you can store your checkpoint in a multiple trades. Okay, this will basically allow that particular option.
That's why we have given check same trades is equal to false.
Okay, I hope you clear. So this is basically here you will be getting a connection object. So I'm going to store inside a variable. Let's say this is connection object.
Now, this connection object you have to pass inside this SQLite server.
Okay, you have to pass inside this SQLite server. So once you have done that, now you will be getting the checkpoint.
Okay, now this checkpoint is not a simple checkpoint, it will not store your conversation, it will not store your checkpoint inside the RAM.
Okay, instead of that, it will save the conversation or checkpoint inside a storage service inside a database storage, which is chatbot.db.
Although this storage service will create inside your uh computer storage only, but this is not storing inside a RAM, okay.
It will store as a file, and we know that unless and until we are not uh deleting the file, this file will be available inside my computer.
If I turn off my computer as well, this file will remain same, okay. This is the main benefit here. So once we have done that, guys, uh the same code you have to write here.
Uh no need to change anything. Now let me show you whether it's working or not.
So here uh maybe I can test this file. So for this, let's do the invoke operation.
Uh so here, uh, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to just
do the invoke operation. So response is equal to yeah, so I have written like that.
So I just created a config because you know that we are using persistence memory and we have to pass the config whenever we're doing the invoke operation.
So here by default, I have taken this default trade. I have just done hard coding operation and we are invoking and we are giving the message.
Hello, how are you?
Or let's say I'll just give uh
my name is Bappi.
Okay, and we are passing the configuration, and this will give you the response. We'll try to print that as well.
Okay, now see if I execute what will happen.
Uh, you will be able to see one chatbot.db file would be created here.
So python um agent t chatbot
db backend, right?
db backend.py if I execute,
see chatbot.db has created, and we are getting the response as you can see. I given my name is Bappi and my EI message. That means my agent has replied. Hello Bappi, how i can assist you today?
And some other let's say metadata informations we are getting.
Okay, now you can see one chatbot uh DV has created. You can also visualize that. Okay, it is also possible for this. You have to install one extension called SQLite
SQLite Viewer.
Okay, I have already installed this uh extension inside my VS Code. Uh, if you don't have just try to install that and you can see this is the um this is the publisher Florian uh CLAM CLAM file.
Uh make sure you install the same version.
Okay, once you have done that, you just need to double-click on this chatbot DB and you will be able to see this
checkpoint. It has saved in the memory as you can see. Uh sorry, not memory in the database, as you can see.
Okay, now you can see it has uh stored my trade uh checkpoint, and this is the trade ID. Okay, we have given default rate as you remember.
We have given uh what is that
chatbot back and okay, not this one, yeah. This one we have given the default trade. Okay, now you can see default trade.
Now you can ask me why this uh three three time it is coming because as per our workflow, guys, the workflow we have created it has three checkpoints.
Uh uh, one checkpoint at the start, uh start position, uh second checkpoint in the chat node position, and other one is the end position. Okay, I think I already told you about this, right?
Uh in my uh this video, uh persistence video. I already told you about that, right?
So please go through the persistence video if you don't understand the checkpointer concept, like how many checkpointer uh would be available, uh, in which node it would be available,
each and everything I have discussed here. So here we are having uh three
layer, okay. Three layer inside uh this uh uh sorry, three three nodes inside our uh Agentic chatbot.
That's why three time this uh um checkpoint is getting created, and all of the checkpoint ID as well as the checkpoint
some meta information is also available, okay.
And if you want to see the checkpoint, guys, directly you can click here.
So if I click here, you'll be able to see the data.
Now, this data it stores basically in a binary format, it's not readable properly, but I think some of the messages you can still able to understand, like
my name is Bappi. Okay, I have given.
Uh now let me show you whether it is able to uh store my checkpoint inside my database or not.
So let's say if I re-execute my um backend, uh whether I will be able to see my old uh old uh conversation or not. Let's say I given my name is Bapi, okay.
So this uh this checkpoint would be available or not. Okay, so for this, maybe I can just give a separate name here.
Let's say Alexa will give, and uh what you can do you can also change the trade ID if you want. Let's say I will give default trade one.
Okay, now if I re-execute my
backend
okay, now if I open my database, I have to refresh
this
okay. Now see another trade got created, and still my previous trade is available here, okay.
Previous trade is available, and in the response, also you can see my name is Alex, and this is a separate trade it is coming.
Okay, so that's how guys uh uh we have seen it is able to store my checkpoint, still it is able to store my conversation inside my database,
okay.
Amazing now. Uh this is ready. Now we have to add uh we have to integrate this thing inside our front end app because right now we tested inside the back end file only, but I have to add
inside my front end. So, what I'm going to do, guys, I will open up my front end.
So this is the front end app trade, or maybe I can create another same file.
I'll just try to copy and paste
and I'll just rename it
app
db.
so with the help of that, you can understand.
Um, like this is uh this is actually database, this is trading, this is simple app. Okay, you can understand. So db means this this has the uh database uh actually update.
Now see here you don't need to change uh uh I mean um uh in in all the code only just change you have to do uh here
in the chat uh uh chat trades. Okay, so whenever I was uh actually creating this uh session state in the streamlet, right? There I was uh using simple list only, okay.
And whenever you are using simple list, that time what is happening if I am refreshing my application and it is re-executing from the beginning, and this particular
list is getting created again, and all of the data we had inside the list, it was getting erased. Okay, this is this was the problem.
So instead of taking this simple list here, so here I have to connect my database.
Connect my database means in the back end I am already storing my checkpoint inside my database, inside my SQLite database. So what I'm going to do, uh instead of uh instead of actually
instead of actually giving a simple list here, I'll try to load my all of the trades okay from my database only, and I will just try to provide a list here,
okay. So for this, in my backend code, I'll just try to do a simple
I'll remove this code, it's not required. So here I'll just do a simple modification.
let me show you the modification.
Yeah, so here I'll just try to write a function here.
I'm going to name it as uh
get
uh all trades.
Okay, get all trades.
So here uh I'll just try to first of all show you this one.
see, first of all, I will write a script, then I'll just try to convert to a function, otherwise, I think you might get some difficulties.
So here uh first of all, I'll
write my checkpoint
checkpoint now. see checkpoint object is nothing but it's a database object right now. We are using SQLite Saber, so it has a function.
The function name is list, okay.
List.
So if you give give this function, call this function list, and if you execute, so what will happen? Basically, it will return you uh how many trades right now you are having inside the database.
But inside this list uh param list function, you have to provide a parameter.
Either you can tell okay, I need uh I need let's say information about my default trades one. So you have to give this name here, okay. You have to give this name here.
Why is that? Uh here, you have to give this name here. You can give the trade name here, but I don't want to give the trade name any specific trade name. I want to get all of the trade right for this.
You have to provide none here. So basically, you are telling I don't need any specific trade, I need all of the trade informations.
Okay, now see this will return you.
Uh this will return you the trades
trades. Okay,
I'll give equal sign now. If I print that
okay, print that print all of my trades now. Let's execute this file again.
Okay, so this is giving you a generator object, and you know that if you're getting a generator object, so what you can do, you can run a full loop on top of that. So for uh, checkpoint
checkpoint,
or let's say trade
or let's say, I'll just write, right,
in trades? okay?
Uh once you have done that, or you can directly write uh uh write like that. Let's say instead of writing two line, I can directly run a for
for
checkpoint in checkpointer.
I think this is also checkpoint, right?
Yeah, checkpoint in checkpoint dot list, okay. Then after that, um
uh what I'm going to do, I'm going to just uh print my checkpoint.
Both name is same. Okay, so what I can do, I can maybe
write like that.
CGPT. Okay, that means checkpoint.
Now if I
re-execute.
Now see guys, here we are getting all of the trade right now. It is available inside my uh inside my
database, as you can see.
And here we are getting lots of trades because if I open my chatbot, we are getting uh six trades right now. And why six six trades?
Because every time if you execute the um execute the graph, it will generate three three checkpoints.
Why I told you because uh
our actually workflow having three checkpoints. So in every conversation, every execution, three checkpoint would be available.
Okay, three checkpoint would be available. So this was the first trade, and this was the second trade. We executed two times, that means six six times is available.
Okay, so all of these six trades you are getting here, okay. But uh here I whenever I will extract that, so this would be a kinds of duplicates to us. I only I will only
check the unique trades here, okay. Let's say here I how many unique trades I'm having uh default trade one and default trade, only two uniques, okay. Otherwise, everything is repetitive one.
So I'll also try to handle this part as well. So, once we are getting all of these, uh, this, uh. these actually checkpoints.
now, from the checkpoint, only I only need this. um
config,
config.
now, if I re-execute my terminal,
now. I'm getting the config only. Okay, now from the config I I need this trade ID only. First of all, I need to go to the configurable.
So this is a lease, uh this is actually dictionary, right?
Hard dictionary. So I will give the key
configurable
now. Again, we are getting another dictionary, and here we have the trade ID. So I only need to extract the trade ID.
Now see, I'm getting all of the trade, but I'm getting repetitive trades, okay. Same uh same actually name again and again, but I only need the unique one.
So for this, I think you know um set right set inside python. So what our set does sets basically um
will give you the unique uh unique actually name. So here I'll take a set,
I'll just try to create empty sets and I'm going to name it as
all threads.
Okay, and whenever I'm getting my
trades, I'll just try to add inside my trades.
Sorry, uh
I'm going to add inside my
um set.
So there is a add function we can use for this.
Then I'll just try to print my
all trades right now.
Now if I execute
now, see I'm only getting trade one and my trades, okay.
that means the unique one. Now I have to provide as a list, okay.
I have to give as a list here because here the session state we created, it it it takes a list, right? But here I'm getting a dictionary as you can see here.
I'm getting a dictionary I'm returning as a dictionary. So, what I can do, I can convert it to the list.
So instead of
printing um
this, I will just do the type type conversion operation.
Just try to convert to the list
now. If I execute,
now see it is a list right now. Okay, now simply I'll just I'll just try to write inside a function.
So I'm going to name this function as def get
all trades
okay, and all of the code I'm going to write inside that
Instead of printing, I'll just do the return operation.
So everything is fine. Now, this function basically will return you uh all the threads, okay, now from the database itself.
So now uh here uh in the app db,
whenever you are importing this chatbot, right?
so right now we have to import from the agentic chatbot db backend, okay, instead of the simple agentic chatbot backend
because we are using db db backend right now. We have to import chatbot as well as the get all trades, okay. This function we have to import now.
Simply you just need to call this function here.
Whenever you are
initializing these uh chat trades, instead of giving the simple uh list empty list, you will give this function name.
Okay, so what this function will do, it will get all of the trades and it will store inline inside my chat trades.
Okay, so this particular code is sorry, this particular data is coming from my backend from my database. Okay, that's how so.
If you restart your application as well, it will not effect on my app because every time this function is getting executed from my backend
and it has the connection with my checkpointer, and checkpointer is connected with my database, right?
Chatbot.db. So every time it will open the chatbot.db and it will get how many trades you are having, only this part will return here.
Okay, this part will return here, and after that, we are just passing it here. That means if I am refreshing my page, if I am closing the application, it doesn't matter.
Every time I'm extracting my trades, I'm getting my trades, I'm facing my trades from my database only.
But previously I was doing inside my memory because I was using simple list, and simple list only creates the instance inside the RAM.
Okay, and if you refresh your RAM would be getting cleared.
I hope you got the concept, guys. Okay, now let's try to execute and see whether it's working or not.
So here I will open up my terminal
clear, then I'll just try to run my app so streamlit
run
app
db.py
now. See guys, uh, you you can already see uh I already created some trades right here.
manually I created some trades, and this trades is also getting load here.
You can see I did some conversation like Alex, then my name is Bappi, and this is the current trade right now. So, what I can do maybe I can delete my database and do start a new conversation.
let's try to delete it.
Okay, it will not getting delete because it is running in the app right now. I can try
some temporary file. Also came. I'll just try to delete. Okay, now I'll freshly execute my app.
Now let's do the conversation.
Hi, my name is Bubby,
I am
teacher.
Okay,
great. Now I'll create a new chat. I'll tell hi my name is
Alex.
I am a learner.
Okay, done. Now if I uh click my previous uh conversation, now you can see this is my previous conversation and this is my current conversation.
Now the best part is that if I refresh my app, right, see still this conversation remains same.
Okay, now if you also close your app, let's say I'll close my app from my terminal, see it's close, okay? And I close my application.
Okay, I close my application. Now, if I restart my application, see if I restart my application, now still it will be able to load my previous conversation, and anytime
I can continue the conversation. Let's say here I'll just try to continue the conversation.
Who am I?
See, it is uh giving you you are Alex, a learner who is seeking knowledge and growth, blah blah blah.
Okay, now I can also do the conversation here only who
am I
see you are Bhappi, you are a teacher, you are in the uh you enjoy helping students learn and grow in their knowledge and skills.
Okay, so yes, guys, uh that's how actually we can add the permanent persistence memory uh right now inside our Agentic chat bot, and now this is like more powerful.
Uh actually, it will not erase your conversation, it will not erase your checkpoint if you restart your application like chat GPT. Like if I open my chat GPT, right?
Anytime, and I can anytime I can see my previous chat, previous trades as well.
Okay, if I close the app also, if I turn off my computer, also, if I disconnect my internet connection, also still these are the things would be common.
These are the things would be available because they are using a permanent persistence memory.
Okay, they're using some kinds of database, whether they're using Postgres, whether they're using MongoDB, doesn't matter, but they're using some kinds of database because of that.
This thing is permanent, like our application.
Okay, I hope you're getting it, guys.
Okay, so yes, guys, that's how we can slowly slowly make this particular chatbot more advanced, and
in my next video, I'm going to show you some more advanced features, guys. we will be adding inside this identific chatbot and we'll try to make it more powerful, okay.
And for this, guys, please try to complete all of this video if you want to implement this kind of project because going forward, I have lots of plan
I will be bringing lots of project here, okay. So, for this, definitely you have to understand all of this concept.
Okay, so yes, guys, this is all about from this video. I hope you liked it and you have understood the entire implementation.
If you found my content useful, please try to subscribe to my channel, hit the like, and please share it with your friends and family.
And all of the code I will share in my description from there, you can download.
So, guys, in this video, we'll be learning one very important and interesting concept called observability.
So, I think you have already heard of this kinds of word like observability, monitoring, tracing, okay, of agentic application or any kinds of
JNI powered application. See, we use this observability monitoring tracing not only in agentic application, but also we use this kinds of concept in any kinds of LLM powered application.
So, whenever you are implementing any kinds of LLM powered application with the help of Langchain or Langgraph or any kinds of framework,
this observability monitoring tracing is super important there, okay.
Without that, you can't actually debug, monitor, and evaluate your application.
This is not possible.
So, for this observability, guys, uh uh we can use one uh very interesting and powerful tool called Lang Smith. Okay, so what is this Lang Smith? Langsmith is a observability monitoring tool.
it is created by Lang Chin, and with the help of that, actually, we can monitor any kinds of LLM powered application, whether it's Agenti AI, whether it's any kinds of rack
system, okay. Any kinds of application we can monitor here, real time we can monitor here.
Okay, so first of all, let me give you the idea what is this Lang Smith is and why it is required.
Then we'll try to see the practical demo how we can observe how we can monitor our entire Agentic chatbot with the help of this Lang Smith.
Okay, each and every integration I'm going to show you guys. And trust me, guys, if you learn this concept, I think
it would be very helpful for you whenever you are creating production grade, uh, uh, agent application.
because in productions, whenever you are creating these kinds of system, there would be lots of bugs. there would be lots of issues, and you can trace everything in a single platform.
with the help of this, Langsmith. This is super important, guys.
So, as you can see, guys, uh Langsmith is a debugging, monitoring, and evaluation platform for application builds with LLM
and AI agents.
It is made by Langchain team, but it can also work with application that do not use Langchain.
Okay, so I already told you this Lang Smith is uh let's say it is developed by Langchain, but if you are not using any uh a Langchain let's say framework inside your application development,
still you can use this Lang Smith with other framework integration as well.
Okay, it has all kinds of integration.
So let's try to understand why this is useful.
So whenever uh you are creating any kinds of chatbot or any kinds of let's say agent uh powered application or any kinds of LLM powered application,
there you perform some kinds of steps, some kinds of operation, right? Let's say user can sense the questions, then in between you can construct the prompt, then you can perform the LLM call.
If you're implementing any kinds of agents that will use any kinds of tool or database, okay, then it can also use memory and checkpointer for the retriever, then
it can give you the final responses. So that means in between there are some hidden operations are happening, but this is not visible to you, okay.
If you're writing only the code, if you're not monitoring the entire uh if you're not let's say tracing the entire application, this part is invisible to you,
okay. So that's why you can see LangSmith is a debugging, monitoring, and evaluation platform for application building um uh built with large language model or AI
agents. Okay, because inside all of this application, this hidden operation happens.
Okay, this hidden operation happens. So if you're using Lang Smith, so how it will happen.
Lang Smith records this complete execution as a trace, that means whatever execution you are doing here, okay. Lang Smith records this complete execution as a trace.
Okay, it will uh uh record all of the execution as a trace, allowing you to inspect every step, including inputs, outputs, error, execution time, token uses, tool calls, and model behavior.
Okay, this is super important, guys. I think by the definition itself you can understand whatever hidden operation you are executing, okay, whatever things are happening in between,
everything Langspeed can record as a trace, okay, in that platform itself.
Okay, so that anytime you can see the input, output, errors, execution time, token uses, tool call, model behavior, each and everything should be visible to you in a single platform.
Okay, now as you can see for your uh Langar of Agentic chatbot, Langsmith can help you. That means the application we are developing right now.
So here, this Lang Smith uh can help us for finding why an agent selected the wrong tool.
Let's say you are running your agents and it has selected a wrong tool, it is giving you some kinds of other responses, but you don't know why, okay.
Why it is giving you these kinds of output, why it is selecting the wrong tool.
If you want to see the step-by-step execution, like after user query, prompt construction, lm call, which tool it has selected, okay, based on the prompt or lm call.
Okay, if you want to understand these things, you have to first of all monitor, trace your entire application, okay.
Monitoring is important, any kinds of application, whether creating mldl, cb, whatever project you are creating, monitoring monitoring is super important.
If you cannot monitor your application, that means in production you will be finding difficulties for sure.
Okay, that's why application monitoring is super important, and for this, Lang Smith is a very powerful tool we'll be using.
Okay, so that's why find uh why an agent selected the wrong tool.
we can easily understand with the help of Lang Smith.
Then inspect the exact prompt sent to the model. That means you can see like whether this uh
prompt construction is happening in a good way or not. The prompt you are constructing, um, whether it is right or not, it is going to the LM or not. Okay, each and everything you can inspect here.
Then debug failed nodes in a lang graph workflow. That means if any of the nodes uh let's say failed during the execution, you can easily monitor inside the Lang Smith dashboard.
Then measures responses, latency, and token cost. So that means if uh
some of the model is taking much time, you can see like how much time it is taking, why it is taking the time, and how much token token actually it is uh.
Spending okay to give you the response, each and everything you can monitor, then review conversations and multi-trun trades.
That means you can review the construction, uh sorry, conversation.
Uh review conversation and multi-uh trend trades. That means you can see the entire conversation, even you can see the trades conversation.
Trade conversation means I think you know we have integrated the trades inside our agentic chatbot. Now, user can create different different trades, user can create different different chats, right?
So you can see the trades as well.
Not only the single conversation, you can also see the trades wise.
Okay, this is also possible. I will also show you this part. Then compare different prompts or model versions.
You can also compare different prompts or model versions, then you can evaluate chatbot quality before and after the deployment.
Okay, that means all of these uh things you will be getting um inside this Lang Smith, and it will help you for these kinds of work,
okay. If you are using this this inside your application development, so I think apart from this, there is nothing you can monitor inside your application.
If you can monitor these are the thing I think
your application should be production ready and you won't be having any kinds of problem, okay. Going forward. So now we'll try to see guys this line speed in practical.
That means the application we have created.
this code is already available in my description. From there, you can get it uh get the code, guys.
I think you remember we created a agentic uh chatbot, okay.
And in my last video, I showed you how we can integrate database features, okay, so that it can uh it can have the permanent persistence memory.
Okay, so first of all, let me show you the application, guys. We have developed.
So, guys, this is our agentic chatbot we have developed so far, and we can perform any kinds of chat operation. Let's see if I give a prompt, give me a
roadmap to learn.
Okay, amen.
So, see, this is giving you the detailed roadmap, and you can see the previous trades as well.
You can also continue the conversation with the previous trades you had here, and this is your current trades, okay.
And if you refresh your application, still this previous conversation will remain same because we have added the permanent memory here with the help of database.
Okay, so in this particular video, I already explained this concept. If you haven't checked that, guys, please try to go through this recording.
So, see, guys, uh, here we have performed uh conversation, it's completely fine, but uh this application doesn't have any kinds of observability or monitoring
connection. Okay, so I can't monitor this application like in the back end, what is happening?
Let's say uh if I deploy this application in production server, so I don't have any kinds of platform there I can continuously monitor my application,
what is happening, how much token it is uh taking, okay, or let's say any of the nodes is giving you any kinds of errors, so I can't see these kinds of let's say uh issues,
right?
So, for this, we can utilize this Lang Smith platform.
So you have to visit smith.langchain.com.
So if you visit this website, guys, this is the Langsmith platform.
So, first of all, here what you have to do, you have to create an account, okay?
So here you just need to create an account, guys. You can use your Google, GitHub, Discord, anything you can use, and you can create an account. So I already have an account, guys.
I will just try to log in.
So once you log in, guys, you will be able to see this kinds of dashboard. So this is your Langsmith dashboard, and previously I uh already created some of the project here.
I already traced some of my project, that's why it's coming here. But if you are using for the first time, you won't be able to see this kinds of uh like project name here or tracing name here, okay.
So, first of all, guys, if you want to use this lang-smith inside your application, you just need to collect an API key, okay?
And this is super easy to use, you don't need to write uh like any kinds of code if you want to use this Lang Smith, guys.
Only you just need to add some of the environment variables, and automatically this Langsmith will start tracing your application.
Okay, I'll uh show you this part.
So if you want to get the uh um API key, so what you have to do?
You just need to go to the API section. So I think API is available in the settings, and here is the API key, guys. Okay, now previously I already created some API key.
What I will do, I'll just try to remove some of the API key so that I can create a new one.
So I'll create a new API key.
So you can give the name.
So let's say I'll give the name of
agentic
chatbot.
So everything just keep it as easy as it is, okay. Don't need to change anything now, just create the API key.
So once you have created the API key, just try to copy and you have to add this API key in the environment variable, okay? So let's say this is our app.
so this application we have created, guys. This is the code, I think you remember in my previous video, previous part.
So now you just need to open this.env file.
after that, here you have to add some of the environment variable. Let me show
you. So these things you have to add here, yeah. So see these things will common for all the project you will be creating going forward, only you just need to change the project name.
So, see, first of all, you have to provide langsmith tracing.
Uh, this parameter is equal to true. Okay, that means you are uh allowing your asmit uh allowing your langsmith to trace your entire application.
Whenever you are executing your application, langsmith will automatically start tracing your application, it will automatically start monitoring your application.
That's why this parameter you have to give as true. Then you are telling what should be the endpoint, that means after tracing it, or the data it will get okay.
The let's say information it will get while it will save those information, okay. It needs an endpoint.
So, endpoint is a lang smith platform. I'm giving you have to save everything in the Lang Smith platform, that means inside this particular platform.
This is the dashboard, right? So, this is what actually we're doing.
Then you have to pass the API key now to authenticate with your dashboard, you need a API key.
So, what I will do, I'll just copy this API key, and here you have to provide the API key and make sure you don't share this API key with anyone, otherwise, they will be able to
use your platform, okay?
Then you have to provide the Lang Smith project name, okay?
Because every time, whenever you will uh execute for the first time, it will create a project, right?
Inside the project, it will start tracing all of the execution.
So, project is important. So, here I'm giving agentic chatbot project. Okay, if you are creating any other project, you can change the name as per your requirement.
Once it is done, you just need to save this file and no need to change any word, okay? No need to change anywhere. I can uh re-execute my app again.
So I'll stop the execution clear and let's re-execute my app streamlit run my app.py.
Okay, so once you have done, now what I will do here I already saved this uh API key.
so it's done. Now I'll go to the uh home page.
Yeah, now let's execute my app. See my application is running right now.
Now, here again I will give the prompt. Let's say I'll give hi
my name
is
Bubby.
I need a
plan to learn.
I'll send it
now. See, it is giving you some kinds of response.
Okay, now once I go to my platform, okay.
Once I go to my platform and if I refresh here,
so see this Agentic chatbot project is created few seconds ago. See, automatically it has created. I didn't change anything inside my code, okay.
Now if I go inside that, now inside the project, guys, you will be able to see your trace. Okay, so this is our first trace that means we have executed uh only one time. We have given a single prompt.
That's why that's why one trace came, and by default, this trace name will be taken as lang graph because we are using Langgraph.
And now if I click on this uh this trace, our first trace, so whatever message you have given as an input, you will be able to see, and whatever output you got from your AI even
you will be also able to see, okay. And this is also coming as a chatbot interface, okay. This is like very interesting.
Then there is an option called details, so you have to click on details, okay.
If you click on details, you will be able to see all of the details. That means you have executed your line graph and it has a chat node. I think you remember.
Uh we are using a chat node if you can see uh our entire application workflow. So this is the chat node. Inside chat node, we are using uh LLM, right?
We are using a large language model, uh, OpenEI model, and we are using GPT 3.5 turbo model because I used uh default model there, okay.
And by default, GPT 3.5 Turbo would be available. Now, everything you can see which model, which node you are executing, okay, each and everything is visible.
Now you can see the input and output you got here.
You can even see the attribute. Okay, all of the attribute metadata version, everything is visible here.
And if you hover on each and every let's say uh staff here, you you you will be able to see the um uh let's say estimated uh token cost.
You can see token cost and uh how many how much token actually it used, okay.
How much token it used for input, output, total, okay. Each and everything you will be able to see that. Okay, that's how you can see the each and every execution of your application.
If you are using multiple LLM calls, you will be able to see the multiple LLM. You can see the prompt. Okay, each and everything should be available here.
Okay, now let's say if I do for the second time, what I will do, let's say
I will give another message.
Um, let's say how much
time
it will
take.
Now I got a response. Now, if I again go to my um dashboard, now see another trace has created, okay, because this is my second run.
Now, if I go to this trace and you will be able to again see the uh conversation, okay.
So, how much time it will take based on that you got the entire output, then you'll be able to also see the uh token okay, like input token, output token, okay,
total token each and everything would be available here. Now, even you can also switch to your previous uh trance as well.
So, if I go to my previous trance, this is the first trance, this is the second trance, okay.
Everything you can see, even you can see the name.
So, this is trend one and this is trend two.
Okay, so that's how everything would be available, and even if you zoom out here, so you'll be able to see some other information right side, like start time, latency,
like how much time it took to execute, then whether you are using any data set or not, then tokens cost, okay.
First tokens, then metadata Lang Smith endpoint, okay, each and everything you will be able to see.
So, yes, uh, that's how you can utilize this uh Lang Smith platform.
Uh, only you just need to add those uh three to four things in the environment variable, and tracing would be automatically
happening okay inside this particular dashboard. But one issue I think you have observed here, which is that let's say here, let's say if I create a new trades, okay.
Let's say I create a new trades, and if I do the conversation, let's say I will give hi
I am buppy.
Let's say this is completely new trades,
okay.
But if I go to my um dashboard, that means Langnessmith dashboard, so as you can see,
in the same um, I mean trace only, it has created my
uh my current execution that means the current trace, the uh execution we have done right now. So, see uh here I give an I uh my name is Bappi and hello, I can assist you today.
Okay, so that's how actually it is uh
uh it is not separating my trades, instead of that, it is saving everything inside a single trace only.
So, here if you want to separate your trades, guys, uh it is also possible because Langsmith uh by default has this trading features here.
So if you want to separate out each and every trades, okay, and the trades you are maintaining here, so it is possible for this inside the code you have to only modify uh modify one particular line.
Let me show you.
So this code only you just need to modify.
See, here I was writing the configuration in the configuration. I was only giving the trade ID, okay.
and we are passing this configuration whenever we are executing the chatbot, whenever we're invoking the chatbot. Okay, now instead of that, you have to write this configuration, okay.
Some other information you need to also pass this metadata and the run name. Okay, so run name.
See, every time this run name is coming as a lang graph by default name, but you can change this run name if you want, you can give any kinds of run name. That's I give I'll give chat trace.
Okay, you can also give any other name, and if you pass this configuration, guys, right now this uh a trading would be uh trading would be applied.
That means all of the trades, individual trades would be saved in the trades. Okay, let me show you.
So I'll remove this configuration right now. This is not required.
I'll use my new one, okay. New configuration, yeah.
So let me show you the fresh execution. So for this, I'll remove my
uh I'll remove my let's say project.
So here just go to the tracing and select your project and just try to delete the project.
Okay, done.
Now I will re execute my code.
So let's say here, uh, I'll give a message. Hi,
my
name is
... Okay, done.
So this is, uh, this is the trade guys. I just start the conversation now. If I come here,
see, my project has created; if I go inside that, so first trace as created, that the name of the trace is chat trace because we changed the name, and this is the conversation we have done.
Okay, now let's say I will give another message, uh, I will create a new trades here
and I'll perform another message. Let's say
I am Alex.
Now, if I come here,
now if I go to the trades,
now guys, you can see trades has created. Okay,
now this is the trades.
This was my first trace.
There, I perform. Hello, my name is Bappi.
Okay, how we can assist you today?
Now let's see, if I give another message: "Um,
I need,
um. I need a plan
to learn python
.". Now, if I go to my trades, so see inside the same trace, uh, inside the same trade, there is, uh, two trans right now.
Um, now if I go to this, uh
Trades, as you can see, the first I given: "Hi, my name is Bappi ." Uh, how and it it has given you: "Hello, Bappi. How I can assist you today ?" Now, in the second trace,
you can see I given: "I need a plan to learn Python ," and it has given you the plan. Okay, that means in a single trade, now it is storing multiple trans —that means multiple conversation.
Previously, I also did for Alex.
See, Alex is also available here. Uh, yeah, you can see the Alex.
But it takes some time, guys. I think it takes, uh, 10 to 20 seconds to update in the trades. Okay, that's why initially, whenever I showed you, uh, this information was not updated.
Now see here also; whenever I did, let's say, Alex right?
Uh, this is the Alex, Alex conversation.
This is the Alex conversation: "I'm Alex, I need a plan to learn python ." As you can see, I am Alex, and here I given you, "I need a plan to learn python ." Okay, so that's how, guys,
every uh, trades, you will be creating, all of the trades would be available. Inside the trades or whatever conversation you'll be doing, it would be saving as a trend.
Now let me show you another: let's execution. Let's say in the Alex only, I'll tell
how much
time it will take.
Now this is my third trun, okay?
Now if I come here,
so you have to wait for some time,
then this trun would be updated here.
Now see, it got updated: trun 3. Now if I click here, now this is the trun three guys.
And here I asked, "How much time it will take ?" And this is the answer I got. Okay, so that's how, guys, you can separate out the trades um by adding this line of code only.
You just need to update your configuration and everything will remain same.
Okay, so that's how, guys, with the help of Lang Smith we can continuously monitor our application, we can continuously trace our application.
Lots of things we can perform with the help of this Lang Smith.
Going forward, also I'll be using this tool, okay, in my project development, and I will also show you some other advantages we can utilize from this
LangSpeed itself, okay? So all the code I'm going to uh upload in my GitHub and give the link in the description.
From there you can get, and please try to practice in your system and to let me know if you have any question.
So yes guys, this is all about it. And if you found my content useful, please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like.
In this video, I'm going to explain one very important concept, one very important features inside our agentic chatbot, which is tools.
If you are implementing any kinds of agentic system, this tools is very much important.
Without tools, an AI agent cannot perform any kinds of action.
With the help of this tools integration, we can make our AI agents more smarter and intelligent and powerful.
So far, the application we have created it doesn't have any kinds of tool.
It can only use the large language model and give you some kinds of response.
So if I show you my application, guys, so this is the application, guys, so far we have developed.
This is our Agentic chatbot with the Line Graph we have developed so far. And we have added lots of features in this particular application.
We saw how we can create the basic workflow of our Agentic chatbot. We saw how we can add the streaming features.
We saw how to add the trading features.
Okay. We saw how to add the persistence memory, even how to integrate the database with that.
Even in my last video, I showed you how we can add the observability tool to monitor the entire application. And we created a dashboard.
This is the LangSpeed dashboard, guys. And here continuously we're tracing our um like conversation.
So this is the application, guys. And the problem with this application is let's say if you are asking any kinds of uh question, uh, which is latest, uh which is not available in the large language
model, that time this particular chatbot will not uh able to give you the response.
So let's say here we are telling hello, uh tell me
about
Python.
So if I give this prompt, it will be able to give you the response.
So see, guys, it is uh able to give you the response, and why it is able to give you the response about the Python because uh this Python information is already available in the LLM knowledge base.
Okay, so the model we are using, uh every model has a knowledge cutoff date, and the model we are using this model got trained till 2022.
I think till December, it uh this model got trained, and that time actually Python information was available in the internet, that's why it is able to generate the response.
But let's say if you are asking anything which is latest information, this information is not available in the knowledge base. That time your chatbot will fail.
Now, let's ask about a latest uh information uh uh into my chatbot. So here I will tell uh give me
all the latest news
for today's
now.
See, it is telling I understand you are looking for the very latest news.
However, uh as an AI, I don't have real-time access to the live news feed, and my knowledge cutoff is a specific point in time,
typically a few months ago.
Okay, this means I cannot provide with you today's uh minute by minute uh news headlines.
Okay, to uh get most current news, I highly recommend checking reputable uh reputable news sources directly, okay, and blah blah blah.
That means this chatbot is directly telling you okay, I don't have the access to the latest data, okay, because this this is using a large language model,
and this large language model has a knowledge cutoff date. Okay, I think till 2022 or 2024, I don't know, but till the date actually they have trained this model,
and uh um I actually in that period of time, whatever news were available in the internet, this has the information.
Okay, but if you are asking anything which is latest, this model will not able to give you the response, okay.
So, this is the problem right now, even uh if if you want to perform like other things as well. Let's if you want to uh let's say uh see the stock market analysis report, okay.
The latest stock market analysis report, this model won't be able to give you the response. So, let me give you another demo.
So, tell me
the latest stock
of Apple.
So, as you can see, as an AI, I don't have access uh to real-time live stock market data, stock uh prices uh fluctuate uh uh fluck uh
fluctuate uh consistently uh throughout the trading day.
Okay, and my knowledge cutoff means any specific price I could I could uh give you would be outdated almost immediately.
Okay, that means it is not able to give you the real-time information about this stock. And if you're asking anything, let's say you are asking about the current weather, okay.
Let's say I'm asking about tell me the
tell me the current
weather
in let's say New York.
So see, it is telling you again I don't have real-time access to the live data weather data.
Okay, so this is the problem with our uh agentic chatbot we have created so far because it doesn't have any kinds of tool.
Okay, so tool means uh it is kinds of uh function, it is kinds of API, okay. It is kinds of let's say
uh different different tools that my agent can use to get the latest information or perform any kinds of action.
Okay, so let's see if I go to the chat GPT and if I ask the same question, chat GPT will be able to give me the response.
Okay, so let's say I will copy the same question.
Uh I'll copy this question and if I ask in the chat GPT, see chat GPT will be using some kinds of tool in action. See,
see, just try to notice here now. See, it is searching over the internet, okay.
See, it is searching over the internet and it is finding different different latest news, and once it has collected all the latest news, then it will refine that particular news
and it will give me all of the see news for today's.
Okay, and the reference uh reference URL as well, like where it got uh it referred that particular headline, where uh it uh referred that news, okay. Each and everything it is giving me.
Now let's see if I am asking uh this question as well. Tell me the latest stock of Apple again, it will be using some kinds of tool.
See, it is using some kinds of tool, and after that, it will give you the response.
See, it is using this stock market analysis tool, and it is giving you the real-time Apple
stock stock data.
Okay, then you can also ask about the weather information
again. It will be able to give you the response because it has the current weather tools as well in the back end with the help of that particular tool, it is real-time sourcing
the current weather information in New York and it will give you the
weather see.
Okay, so this is called actually tool in action. Okay, so whenever you are creating the agentic system, it should have lots of tool okay.
And wherever it needs any kinds of tool, it will automatically decide and it will select that particular tool. Let's say here I was asking about the news, right?
That time to get the latest news, why what I have to do? I have to perform the internet search operation, I have to perform the Google search operation. So here it is using some kinds of search tool.
Okay, with the help of the search tool, it is giving you all kinds of latest information, latest news. Then I asked about the latest stock of Apple.
Okay, now it is using the stock market actually tool.
With the help of this tool, actually, it is getting the real time, uh, real time actually um
the uh real time actually stock of Apple and it is giving you the response.
So it is using some kinds of stock, stock price or stock related tools in the back end. Now again, I asked about the weather.
So here it is using a weather tool. Okay, with the help of weather tool, it is uh hitting some kinds of uh API of the weather and it is getting real time this weather information, okay.
The given location we are giving.
Okay, so that's how things are working. So that's how chat GPT uh has lots of tool connection, okay.
Not only three to four tools, it has lots of tool connection, so you can ask any kinds of question whether it's a latest news, whether it's any kinds of outdated news,
whether you want to perform any kinds of tasks, okay. Everything it can perform because it has the tool, and without this tool, it can perform the action.
Okay, I hope you get it. So, these kinds of things we will be also integrating inside our agentic chatbot.
So, whenever we are asking these kinds of question my agentic chatbot will be also able to give you the response, it will be also able to use this kinds of tool and perform the action.
Okay, so yeah, in this particular video, we'll be learning this concept, guys. We'll try to see how we can integrate the tools inside our agentic chatbot.
And trust me, this is a very important concept. If you are implementing any kinds of agentic powered application, you have to use the tool. Okay, there are lots of tools are available
over the internet, over the market.
as per your requirement, you can select the tools and you can integrate inside your uh chatbot or whatever application you are developing, and you can even create your custom tools,
it is also possible. I'll show you both of them, okay. So, guys, before I discuss about the tools concept, the tools integration inside our agentic chatbot. First of all, I want to show you the demo.
Like after adding these tools, how my Agentic chatbot will work. So I already integrated the tools inside my Agentic chatbot. This is the updated version. First of all, let me show you the demo.
So, see, this is the updated application. Now, if I ask uh the these kinds of questions, let's say I will give um give me the
Latest news
in AI.
Okay, now if I send this prompt, it will be able to see uh it is it will use some kinds of tool, okay.
So, see it is using tabily search tool. So, with the help of tably search tool, it is searching over the internet uh about the latest news in AI, and this will give you the response.
See, this is giving you the response.
See, so all of the latest news it has given me, okay, from different different uh paper, different different publication, it has given me all the latest news in AI.
Even you can see the um like tools, uh tools action.
As you can see, internally it is using some kinds of
URL, some kinds of let's say uh resources, and it is giving you this in kinds of information, even in chat GPT. Also, you'll be able to see this uh uh uh this backend uh execution.
Okay, this is also possible.
So, every like said tools execution you will be able to see if you want, you can also open it and you can see.
Okay, so this kinds of thing we have also um uh implemented inside our agentic chatbot, and throughout this entire video, guys, I'm going to show you how we can develop these things, okay?
How we can add this particular tools integration inside our agentic chatbot. Now, let me ask another question. Let's say here I will tell um um calculate
okay, um, this number, okay. So let's say this is my expression.
I want to do a mathematical calculation, and inside this agentic chatbot, I I am using a tool called calculated tool.
So, with help of this calculated tool, you can calculate any kinds of complex, let's say, expression, any kinds of complex let's say um uh equation
you can calculate here. Now, if I send this, now you will see that it will be using calculator tool.
Okay, now with help of this calculator, it is calculating the entire uh let's say number and it is giving you the response.
So, any kinds of complex math problem you can give, it will be able to perform that.
Okay, so once it is done, let me show you another demo. Then I have given another prompt. Tell me the latest stock price of Apple.
Again, you can see it is using some kinds of tool, it is using stock price tool, and it is able to give you the latest stock price of Apple.
Okay, even you can also ask the stock related any other companies, let's say stock price of Google.
So stock price of Google now. See it is using get stock price uh tool and it is able to give you the latest stock price of Google is uh that much, okay.
So, yes, guys, that's how our entire agentic system is working right now, and we are we have already integrated uh uh some tools okay inside our
agentic chatbot. That's why it is uh performing like chat GPT. But chat GPT is having lots of tools, guys. Um, if you want, you can also integrate lots of tools inside your application.
This part I will leave it to you.
First of all, let me show you the entire development, then you can uh you can improve this application a lot. So, first of all, uh I'll be discussing about the tools, guys.
What is tools and why tools is required, then I'm going to show you the implementation.
So, guys, first of all, let's try to understand about the tools, what is tools exactly and why it is required and how tools works.
Okay, so as you can see, uh in agentic AI, tools are external functions, APIs, database, or any kinds of service that an
AI agent can use to perform actions beyond generating the text, okay.
So, previously the application we created, guys, this agentic application, the previous version application that means in my previous video, it was only able to generate the text. Okay.
if you give any kinds of let's say prompt based on the prompt, if this information is available in the knowledge base of the model, it is able to generate some kinds of text, okay.
But with the help of these tools, an agent can um agent can perform action, okay. Like I showed you right now, right? I uh I uh perfect I did different different prompting in my agent.
I asked about the stock price, I asked about the latest news, then I asked to calculate uh some kinds of mathematical equation, and it was performing some kinds of action with the help of some
third pet tools, okay.
So that's why our agent can perform any kinds of actions, okay. Uh, using the tool beyond the text generation.
So our agent cannot only generate the text, okay, it can also perform some kinds of action with the help of this tool. So this is very much important.
So a normal LLM can only respond based on this knowledge and the information in the prompt, okay.
An AI agent works with tool and it can search, calculate, retrieve the data, execute code, update database, or interact with other systems as well.
Okay, so by this definition itself, I think you can understand what is tools exactly and why this tools is super important.
Okay, so with help of tools, you can perform any kinds of searching operation, calculate operation, retrieve data operation, you can even execute any kinds of code.
Okay, I think in chat GPT you can execute the code, you can debug your code. Okay, how it is happening?
Because it is using some kinds of tool, and that tool actually it is working with the Python interpreter, okay.
So, in the Python interpreter or any other let's say program you are using, it is using that particular interpreter, it is executing the code, it is reviewing your code,
it is finding the bugs inside your code, and it is giving you the final response. Okay, this is the problem inside your code. So, everything is happening with the help of these particular tools, okay?
So, they are using these kinds of tools, external tools, and they are performing this kinds of operation.
Okay, I hope you get it. Now, let's try to understand a simple example.
Suppose a user asked what is the current weather in Texas, okay. The agent does not know the live weather by itself.
Now it can call a weather tool. Okay, let's say you have already integrated the weather tools inside your agents. Now your agents will automatically decide which tool to call.
Now you are asking about the weather, so definitely it will let's say hit this get weather tools, okay. It will use this get weather tool and you are asking for Texas, okay?
So that's how the location you are giving it will find the weather okay of that particular location, then the tool returns the current weather and the agent uses that result to answer the user.
Okay, so that's how the entire system works. Now, some common tools in Agentic AI.
So you can see web search tools can be used a lot whenever you are creating this kinds of agentic application with the help of you can perform search operation over the
internet and you can get the current information.
Then calculated tool. Okay, I think you saw the calculator tool, you can perform any kinds of complex mathematical operation.
Okay, then database tool, you can even read and writes data inside your database or any other, let's say, storage service.
These uh tools can be also used inside your agentic chatbot. Then rag retriever tools, okay. Sources doc uh searches over the documents or vector database.
will in future we'll also try to add these uh tools inside our agentic chat, but we'll also add the uh RG functionality. Okay, I will show you this part as well.
So, this is also important things like in chat GPT, you can upload any kinds of documents, right?
And in the document you can perform the uh you can perform the source operation, you can perform the query operation.
How it is happening because it has the rag retriever tool, then you can use Python tool with help of Python tool, you can execute the code, analyze the data. Okay, everything is possible.
You can even use email tool with help of email. You can read email, you can draft your email, you can send the email. Okay, so everything is possible.
Even in chat GPT or Google Gemini, you can connect your email, okay.
Even from there only you can send the email.
This is also possible, and how it is happening because it is using email tool, then calendar tool.
You can use, you can even access your calendar, you can use different different API tool like you can use weather API tool, finance API tool, CRM API tool,
any kinds of payment system API tool, any kinds of API you can connect with your Agentic chatbot.
Okay, Agentiki system, then custom businesses tool. Let's say if you have some custom businesses, okay.
If you want to integrate that particular tool, let's say you can create the tickets, you can check the inventory, you can generate the reports, okay.
You can update the customer records, everything is possible here. So these are the common tool guys. You can integrate inside your Agentic system.
Okay, apart from that, there are lots of tools are available.
You can search over the internet, okay. There are thousands of thousands tools are available.
Whatever you need, okay, you just try to integrate inside your project itself.
Okay, very simple. Then how tool calling works, guys. As you can see, the typical workflow is the user gives a request, first of all, then the agent understand the goal.
Let's say previously I showed you some kinds of action, right? I asked about the stock price of Google.
So this was my user request, okay.
My agent understand the goal. What is the goal? It has to understand the sorry, it has to get the latest stock of the Apple, okay, or Google.
Then the agent decided whether uh uh whether a tool is required.
Then our agent was understanding, okay, to give this particular answer whether I need to use any kinds of tool or not. So, in this scenario, definitely it has to use the tool because inside the LLM.
Uh the default LLM it doesn't have these kinds of information. Definitely it has to use the tool. Okay, so the agents will decide okay, it has to use the tool, it it needs the tool requirement.
Okay, then it selects the appropriate tool because inside my application there are multiple tools I have added. Now, which tool to call, okay, which tool to use?
Because here I ask different different uh questions, right? And uh for each and every question, uh it uh it should use different different tools, okay.
It it's not like that uh for all the questions it will be using one specific tool, okay? Because question might be different, prompt might be different.
First of all, it has to understand the goal based on the goal, it will automatically select the specific tool it requires, okay.
That's why it selects the appropriate tools, then it generates the tool arguments, okay. Tool argument means here we are asking about let's say give me the latest news in AI.
So, what will happen?
it will search this uh this particular word in the internet, okay, because it is using tably search tool, right?
And you know, tably search tool, what it does, it does the internet search operation the way you search the Google, right? it will be using tably search and it will perform the search operation, okay?
And this will give you the latest uh information of that.
So that's why uh this uh uh it generates the tool argument, okay. Let's say whenever you are giving any kinds of uh let's say equation, let's say calculate
calculate
this number with this number
now. It will be using calculated tool, okay. See and what is the uh tool argument here?
This expression, okay. This expression is the tool argument right now, and it is calculating that, and it is you are able to see the response, okay.
Then tool execution in action that means tool will execute and this will give you the response, and this response the result is returned it to the agent.
That means whatever responses you will be getting from the tools, okay. Uh, sometimes these responses won't be readable to the user.
Okay, so that's why what you have to do, you have to send this response to the large language model again.
That means your agent again and agent will try to refine that particular output and you will be able to see the final result. Then the last one, the agent produces the final responses.
Okay, that means once my tool execution is complete and whatever output you are getting from the tools uh will try to pass to the agents, and agents will try to refine that particular output, okay?
And this will generate the final responses to the user. So that's why the agents produces the final responses.
Okay, example uh you are asking, let's say what is uh uh 25 uh percent of uh 8500.
Now agent decide uh you have to it has to use calculated tool.
Okay, now it will perform the tool call.
Now, this is the calculation it has to do, right?
this is the expression it has to calculate. So after calculating, this will uh uh your let's say uh uh tool has generated this output.
Uh let's say this is the final response. But if I show this response to the user, user won't be able to understand in a in a good way, okay? So I have to generate some kinds of readable response.
So again, I will send this particular result to my agent.
Now, agent will try to refine this out, let's say answer and it will generate a final responses. You can see now agent is uh generating 25% of 8500 is 2125.
Okay, now this is more readable than this one, okay. So that's why this this step is super important.
And whenever you are using any kinds of tool whenever your agent is calling any kinds of tool so this eight step it is following, okay, and we'll also follow this
step eight step to implement tools integration inside our AI agents.
Okay, this is the entire idea, guys. So now, guys, I think pretty much clear how the tools works and what is tools exactly, and in the chat GPT also, how chat GPT works,
and whenever you are asking any kinds of real-time question, how it is able to give you the response because it has the tools connection, okay.
Lots of tools connection because of that, you are able to see the latest information or any kinds of action you can perform here. Now, let's start the implementation, guys.
I will show you the entire implementation how we can add the tools inside our Agentic chatbot.
So, guys, first of all, let's try to understand the workflow after adding this tool node inside our workflow, how our workflow will look like and how it will work.
So, as you can see, this is the first workflow we have created so far.
So, this workflow has only one particular node which is chat node.
So, basically, if user is giving any kinds of input, it is going it going to the chat node, and chat node is giving some kinds of output.
And right side, you can see this is the updated workflow will be creating inside this video.
basically, we'll be adding our tools node here.
So, as you can see, this is the updated workflow.
So, here uh you if user gives any kinds of input, it will go to the chat node, and here actually we'll be using something called tool condition function.
Okay, there is a function called tool condition function. So, here I have already written what is this tool condition function.
It uh function does it's a tool condition, it's a uh pre-built conditional age function that helps your graph to decide
should the flow go to the tool node next or back to the llm. Okay, that means whatever input user is giving, okay.
Let's say if user is asking, tell me about Python. So I think you know that inside large language model, this information is already available.
So in this scenario, your agent doesn't need to call the tool, right?
It can only use this chat node and give the response, and the response will go to the end directly, right?
But if user is asking, tell me the latest news in AI in 2026, okay. This information is not available inside the large linkbase model knowledge base.
That time your tool condition, okay, tool condition function will decide okay. Now it has to use some kinds of tool. That means this kinds of question will redirect to the tool nodes.
Okay, so this is how this tool condition works. That's why you can see the definition. So this tool condition is a pre-built conditional edge function.
Okay, I think I already told you about conditional conditional workflow, okay. How conditional workflow works. If you haven't checked that, please try to check my previous video.
So conditional edges function that helps your graph to decide should the flow go to the tool nodes, okay, or back to the LM. Okay, now I think you got it.
What will happen here?
Okay, now here we have added this tool.
So this tool we call it as a tool nodes, okay. Inside this graph, this tool is a call we call it as a tool nodes. So tool nodes is also a pre-built node inside Langgraph.
Okay, so as you can see in Langgraph, tool node is a pre-built node type that acts as a bridge between your graph and external tools, okay.
That means inside tool nodes you can use any kinds of function APIs, utilities, etc.
So, as you can see, normally in Langgraph uh you would write a node function yourself, okay.
It takes state and return the state.
So far, we have written like that, but a tool node is a ready-made node that knows how to handle a list of Langchain tools. That means these tool nodes you don't need to write separately, okay.
This is already pre-built inside Langgraph, you just need to define that okay as a node, and it will automatically okay, it will automatically handle uh
like the list of the tools you will be adding inside this tool nodes, okay. Then it its job listen for tools calls from the LLM.
Like let's say user wants to search something on the internet about the latest information, or let's say he or she wants to get the weather information,
so automatically this tools node will decide which tool to use because it has the list of the tools, okay.
Automatically, based on the input, user input, it will decide which tool to use and automatically route the request to the correct tools, okay.
That means if user is asking about latest information in AI, it will be using search tool.
Let's say if user is using if user wants to know about the current weather, okay.
So that time it will redirect to the get weather tool.
That's how it will route the request to the correct tool, then pass the tools output back to the graph. Okay, so that's how the system works, okay.
That means whenever you will pass any kinds of input, first of all, this tools condition will decide whether it has to use the any tool or not, or whether it has to use the default large language
model to generate the response. Okay, but if it needs any kinds of let's say tool uh tool functionality, that time it will automatically route to this tool notes, okay.
And tool nodes will try to decide which tool to use for what kinds of input.
Okay, now I think you are pretty much clear with this particular workflow, and this workflow will try to develop inside our system.
Okay, so for this, first of all, I'm going to show you a notebook experiment, guys. We'll try to write everything in a Jupyter notebook.
I will try to understand the entire tools concept there, then we'll try to um integrate inside our Agentic chatbot we have created so far.
So, here what I have done, guys, as you can see left hand side, I created a notebook folder, and inside that I already kept my previous notebook I showed you, right?
So, this is the previous notebook I created at the very first time, right? there I showed you the chatbot workflow. We created this workflow, and this was the simple workflow.
So, here I created another notebook called Tools Demo. Now, if I open it up, so you can see this is the tools demo related code.
So here basically I'm going to explain this code like how we have to add these tools inside our workflow and how we can.
how we can practically test that okay. So once everything is working fine, then we'll try to integrate inside our development. And here I already added that documentation.
The documentation I showed you, tools documentation. If I click here, so this is the documentation, guys.
I already showed you this documentation, right? So this documentation reference I already given in this particular notebook. You can refer it here now.
Here, first of all, I'm going to select my environment.
So let's select my environment.
So this is the environment.
Now, first of all, we'll import all the necessary library. So, as you can see, we are importing state graph, start end from line graph, then type dict, annotate it. So these are the things are common.
I think you are pretty much familiar with this now. Base model, human masses and one thing, guys, I have done actually my open AI API key is over. Okay,
my limit is over.
That's why I am using like uh Gemini model, and if you want to use Gemini model, so that time you can import this library called chat Google Generative
AI from Langchen Google Geni. Okay, and for this you have to install one library. So this is the library, guys, Langchain Google Generate BI.
Okay, and this specific version I have installed in my uh uh in my environment. Okay, so again you just need to open your environment and just write pip install hyphen r requirement.txt.
Okay, if you do that, it will automatically install this library inside your environment. So I have already done that, so let me open it up.
So, see this is the alternative way to use uh any kinds of large language model if you don't have open AIPI key or if your API key limit is over.
That time you can use these are the free to use large language model, okay. Uh, but if you want to use open AIPI key, guys, you can refer my previous notebook.
I think in previous notebook I used the open AIPI key here. I use this open AI model, okay. Chat open AI model, only this part you just need to change, okay.
and one more thing you have to collect, which is uh uh like Gemini API key that means Google API key, and how you will get this Google API key.
So, for this, you have to go to the
Google
AI Studio, okay. This particular website,
and here you can click on get started
now. Left hand side, you will see this API key option. Get API key. I'll just click on get API key.
Now from here, you just need to create an API key. Okay, I already created the API key, so I can copy and I can simply paste it here.
Okay, so make sure you collect your own API key, guys. I'm going to remove my API key after this recording, so don't use my API key.
Try to create your own API key from here.
Okay, once you have created the API key, then you will be able to execute this notebook. Then I'm importing this add message from graph itself, then load EMB to load my environment variable.
Then uh I'm importing some other additional library as you can see from Langgraph pre-built. I'm importing this tool node.
Okay, I think I already told you about tool nodes, right? So here in this demo, I told you about the tool nodes.
So this tool nodes will uh basically help you to uh tool nodes will basically help you to uh uh so yeah, I think this is the tool node, yeah.
Tool node. So this particular tool node, okay. So this tool node will help you to define your nodes, okay? That means tool nodes, and you don't need to write this tool node separately.
This is already pre-built inside Langgraph, okay. That's why we're importing from pre-built. Then there is another function called tool condition.
So this function I told you. So this tool condition we also need to add as a conditional edges.
So basically, this function will decide whether it has to use the tool or it has to use the simple LLM call. Okay, so this is also pre-built function inside Langgraph.
We'll be importing them.
Then I need this tabula search.
So tabily search is the internet search tool.
With the help of that, you can perform the internet search operation. Let's see if user is asking any kinds of latest informations, like chat GPT I showed you. Okay, previously the demo I showed you.
if user is asking about latest information, anything which is let's say completely latest and available over the internet. So with the help of tabily search, we can get this information, okay?
And if you're using tabily search tool, guys, you have to install uh these two libraries Langchain Tabily and Tabily Python.
Okay, so this two libraries you have to install, and this is the specific version I'm installing in this project.
Now, what you have to do? You just need to simply write paper nerd.
requirement.txt.
Okay, if you do that, it will install all of the necessary library inside your, okay, inside your environment.
Okay, so this two library is required. If you are using tablizer's tool, then, uh, we'll be importing these tools. Okay, right now we have to create the tools.
Okay, and whenever you want to create your custom function, okay, let's say custom function as a tool, that time this tools has, uh, has to be imported
with the help of this tool. We'll be creating a decorator, and this decorator will be
Will be represent my function as a tool, okay? I'll show you this part how to do that. Then request and math module, okay? So these are the import you have to,
you have to write inside your code.
Done. Right now, first of all, let me load the environment variable. So I have loaded my environment variable, okay? Now here, I'm initializing my model guys. So as you can see here, I'm initializing.
Gemini 2.5 flash model, and this is the creativity parameter I think you already know about, and this is your LLM object.
And if you want to use uh open AI large language model here, this is very much simple;
only you just need to write chat open AI, okay? And if you want to use Gemini model, you have to use this
particular code, okay? And if you want to use any other provider as well, simply just try to change here.
You can go to the chat GPT and you can ask, "Okay, I want to use grok Model, it's a Grok meta model
or open. I want to use open router provider and I want to this this model. Okay, so this particular code will change and you will get this code from the chat GPT or any kinds of documentation;
you can change it anytime here.
Okay, so this will my
large language model, this will uh this will be my last language model. Okay, now we'll be initializing the uh tabily Search.
Okay, so Tably Search is a Internet search tool, I already told you about right? And to use this Tabily search tool, you need an API key.
Okay, so for this, what you have to do: you have to go to this Tabily website. Okay, Tabily, you just need to write "Tabily API key ". Go to the first website
and just try to continue with your Google.
Okay, so here you will be getting your API key. If you don't have API key, please try to create from here.
So you just need to create here, give the name, let's say I'll give demo.
And simply create the API key, okay? Once you have created, just try to copy this API key,
and
you have to place inside your environment variable.
So here, you just need to create another key called tabily API key ," and here you just need to paste your API key.
That's it, okay? I already have my API key; I'm not going to change it here.
Okay, so API key is also collected now.
See, this is our first
tools actually we have defined. So Tabily, uh, is it's a like a tool inside like agentic AI, if you are creating against an Agentique AI project. So Tabily is a tool by default;
it's a tool, so you don't need to give this particular decorator sign, so you just need to create an object of Tabili search.
So inside uh Tabily search, you will just need to give maximum result. Like, how many uh results you need uh whenever it will search, uh do the search operation?
Let's say it has searched for latest AI news.
Okay, in 2026, it will search maximum in five websites. Okay, five website, and it will give you the response.
Okay, I think previously I showed you this part; I think I created Langchain agent right there. I showed you how to use the tablet search, right?
Then topic, topic basically I want to search the general topic related search operation and search depth advanced.
Okay, so this kinds of parameter you have to pass inside tablet search, and this will give you a search tool object. Okay, and then you have to create this object, so this will become your first tool.
Then the next tool, guys, I have created here called calculator tool.
So you can see I have written a custom function, so just try to ignore this part; let's say as of now I haven't added this decorator, so Let's say I'll remove this decorator.
First of all, you have to write a custom function.
So, see, this is the custom function I have written. So here, I'm using math module, and here, I if you are passing any kinds of expression, right?
Any kinds of mathematical expression, so this function will be able to calculate that expression and it will give you the result, and if any exception is occurring, it will raise the exception.
Now let's see, if if you want to Create any kinds of custom function as a tool.
Only you just need to give this particular decorator, this decorator at the red tool, and this tool we have already imported here, as you can see from Langchain course: tools, tools, okay.
Now, this will become our tools.
Okay, now this will become a tool object.
Now you can use this tool inside your agents.
So this is super simple, guys. Okay, and this is very much interesting.
You can create any kinds of like Python custom function and you can convert it as a tool and you can use it inside your AI agents.
It's not like that, always you have to use the predefined tools, okay. It's not like that because I I can write any kinds of custom function okay for my work, and that has to be my tools, okay.
That has to work with uh work like it my tools.
So I can do that.
This kinds of customization is also available inside Line Graph.
Now, as you can see, this is my second tool, calculated tool.
Now, the third tool I created get stock price.
Now, so let's say if you if if user is asking about any kinds of stock price about Apple, Tesla or Google, whatever.
So this tool will be working that time and it will give me real-time stock data.
Okay, so as you can see, again I written a custom function, so this will basically take any kinds of company name, example Apple Tesla or whatever,
and here I'm using a website as you can see. This is the website alpha vantage.co.
Okay, this is the website.
So, in this website, basically, uh, this is the API endpoint of this website, and to hit this API endpoint, you need a API key. Okay, so let me show you this website first of all.
So, this is the website, guys.
So, this website has all of the stock-related real-time data, okay. the stock market data, stock market data API for LLM and
LLM and any other let's say uh uh application you are implementing, okay? So, here basically you just need to collect an API key.
So, to collect the API key, so there is an option get free API key.
I'll click here
now. You just need to give your organization name. Let's say I'll give DSWAT BAPP and you just need to also pass your email.
Let's say I'll pass my email, and once it is done, just try to click on get free API key.
Okay, so this is your API key, just try to copy that
and don't share this API key, guys.
And try to use your API key on API key, okay? And here you just need to paste this API key.
Okay, now this will become your this will become your
um
API endpoint.
See now here you just need to pass a symbol only. Let's say I'll give
Apple
okay.
I'll pass like that.
See now this is giving you this stock data related apple.
Okay, real time, you are getting a JSON response. So that's how we are using this uh uh website, guys.
That's how we are using this API, and to hit this API endpoint, I am using request module inside Python.
We are passing this URL and it is giving you the JSON response, and we are returning that okay to the LLM.
So this is our next tool I have used here. So in this uh uh like demo, guys, I only use three tools.
You can add like more tools here if you want.
You can add like get current weather informations, you can add let's say emailing tool, you can add let's say Google Drive tool, any kinds of tool you can add.
Only you just need to go to the chat GPT and ask, like, okay, I need to use this tool how to write that particular function. This is a simple Python function you need to write.
Okay, so just for just to show you guys, I used only three tools in this particular project, but you can add you can feel free to add more tools here, okay. Anytime.
Let's say let me show you another example. Let's say, if I go to the Chat GPT, and if I, let's say, ask, "I, want to
add a tool in
my agent
that will
fetch
weather
given
location,
real time,
give me a Python
function.
So, see, this is the get current weather tool.
Okay, now simply you just need to copy this code,
and here it is telling what to install here, okay.
And it is telling this API key you also need because it is using open weather API, I think. So let me copy this function as it is.
just I'm I'm showing you okay how to add different different tools. Okay, you can take the help from chat GPT anytime, and you can create this kinds of custom function.
So let's say here I'm going to add another tool.
This is my tool,
okay. Get current weather tool, it will take a location, and based on the location, actually, it will uh
uh give you the real-time information. So here I need to import this operating system library
import OS,
so and it needs an API key, okay? Open weather API key.
So, how you will get this open weather API
key? You can copy this key and search on Google.
So, this is the weather API
So, this is the website, guys. It is using get API key.
Now you just need to first of all sign in. I think
first of all, I'll create an account. Okay, I think I don't have any account.
I'll give the password. I'll confirm all of these
things and let's create the account.
Email is already taken. Uh okay, previously I think I already used this email, so let me sign in and see whether it's working or not.
Okay, guys, let me log in. I think I do I am having some issue.
First of all, let me log in with this website.
So, guys, as you can see, I have successfully signed up uh in this website. Uh basically, I had I forget my password.
Okay, and now I change my password, and now I'm able to visit this website. Okay, first of all, you just need to create an account here.
Then once you have done, uh, here you will see one option called API key,
and here is your API key. Okay, so you just need to
create an API key. Let's create an API key.
I'll give the name let's say agent
generate.
this is your API key.
Let's copy that,
and here you have to write it
inside your environment variable.
And this should be the inner.
Okay, open weather API.
So that's how you can collect the API and now it will work.
So I will re-execute from the beginning.
So here I have added another function that will basically face the real-time weather information.
Then here what you have to do, guys, you have to make a tool list.
So here you just need to pass all of the object one by one. First of all, I created search tool, right?
So I will give the search tool,
then I created uh calculator,
okay. Calculator,
then I created get stock price, then
I created this current weather,
This function I'll pass here.
Okay, so that's how uh let's say whatever tools you are creating, you are just you just need to make a tools list, okay? You have to give one by one.
All the tool list you have to give one by one, okay.
Just try to remember. Let's say you are creating 10 different tools, you have to give 10 different list here.
Once it is done, you have to do the bind operation with your llm. That means you just need to tell your llm okay, now you have the tool, so that's why I'm not going to use the simple llm right now.
so the llm object we have created is completely fine.
This is completely fine, okay.
Now we just need to bind this tool with the llm.
So here there is a function called bind tools, and inside that you have to pass all of the list of the tools, and now you'll be using this object llm with tools. Okay, now let's bind that tool.
Done. Now we are defining the state. I think the same state you remember we created previously this state.
No chance.
Let's define that now.
This is our chat node, guys. I think you remember we created this chat node, and here we need to create another additional node called tool nodes. Okay, I told you about this tool nodes right?
In this my
uh excalator file, you can see this is the node. Additionally, we are adding this particular node, and this is a predefined node, okay. You don't need to separately write that.
So here we are using this tool node function.
I think we have imported this
tool node, and inside that we are passing the tool,
okay. Tools, list of the tools we have, and this will become your tool nodes. Let's define both of the nodes now.
Once it is done, guys, now we'll try to create the graph. Now we are using uh state graph and we are passing the state. Now we are adding the nodes.
The first node we are adding, which is chat node, okay.
We are adding the chat node as you can see.
Then the second node we are adding the tool node.
You can see the tool node, okay.
We are adding this tool node.
So both node we have added. Now we have to the edge connection. Now, how my edge connection will look like.
As you can see, first of all, start to chat node.
So start to chat node, then
chat node itself will have a conditional edges with the tool condition. Okay, I think I told you about this one.
Chat node will have a tool condition, okay.
Edge connection. Basically, this tool condition will decide whether it has to call the tool or whether whether it has to use the default large language model.
So that's why this connection would like uh will look like that.
So you will be using add additional conditional edges and from chat node to tool condition, okay. Now, this tool condition will decide whether it has to use any kinds of tools or not, okay.
Then here you just need to write another edge connection tools to chat note. Okay, why you have to write this one? Let me show you.
If I let's say don't give this line, let's say I will comment this line.
So, what will happen? Let's try to see.
Let's say I have uh added my chat node and tool condition.
Now, if I show you compile and show you my graph, so that's how my graph looks like okay, and this is similar to this particular graph, okay.
And one thing I think you have observed here, I'm not using the simple LLM.
Okay, right now I'm using LLM with tools, so that means this object because here I did the bind operation with my tools, okay. So make sure you add this line, otherwise, it will not work.
Okay, so many people uh do this mistake. So basically, they use the simple LLM and uh they they feel like okay, it is not using the tool, so that's why this object has to be called here.
Now, let me show you my execution.
So now uh here we are giving a message. So, first of all, I'm giving hello, and you know, like uh uh for the hello, actually, it doesn't need any kinds of tool, right? So, this will my regular chat.
So it is telling hello, how I can help you today. Now, here I'm asking another question. Let's say what is uh uh this particular expression, okay.
what would be the result of this expression mathematical expression? And now it will use the tool, okay? Because it has the calculator tool, I think you know.
So previously created the calculated tool.
So this is the calculated tool, right?
It will uh use that particular tool.
Let's execute.
See, this is the result it has given me.
Okay, now here I will ask another question: what is the new movie release in 2026?
Now, again, it will use the tool.
See, new movie release in 2026, and all of the URL it has also given it has referred. See, this is the different different website. my tool has referred.
That means I'm using tabily search tool, right? And it has
so my tabily tool did the internet search operation and it found the latest movies, okay. As you can see, and it has given me all of the title of the latest movies, as you can see, okay.
but here the output we are seeing. See, this output is not properly readable.
Uh, this output has also some metadata information. Okay, so if I give this kinds of output to the user, so user will confuse okay, what to read.
So that's why I have to pass this output to the agent again.
That's why I told you in my
file itself.
Okay, so you can see our tools listen for the uh uh tool calls, okay, and once let's say it perform any kinds of tool calls,
uh then it automatically route to that particular correct tool, then pass the tools output back to the graph.
Okay, why it has to pass this output back to the graph because of that, because this output is not readable. So, again, what I will do this output I will try to pass to the
the output we are getting. See, right now this is our architecture. So, whatever output we are getting from the tools, it is getting ended.
Okay, now we have to again give this output output to the chat node okay. If I pass this output to the chat node chat node will try to refine this output and it will generate a readable output for me.
Okay, so that's why I have to do little modification inside my architecture. So let me show you.
So here
I'll just try to add this line, okay.
Basically, the tools output you are getting, okay, you are again sending to the chat node.
Okay, this is the modification you only just need to do. Now, let me again execute.
okay, so I have to execute from the beginning.
Now that's how your structure will look like. See, right now we are not returning the tools output. Instead of that, the tools output we are getting, we are again sending to the chat node.
Okay, and chat node will refine the output and it will go to the end node.
Now, let me show you my output
now.
See, again, uh, this with this is using tool.
See now, see the result, guys. Okay, see the response.
Previously, it was only giving this number, but right now, this giving the result of this equation is this.
This is more readable, right?
Because right now the output we are getting from the tools, we are again passing to the chat node, and chat node is doing the refinement.
Now, here I'm asking what is the new movie's release in 2026. Okay, now if I send this prompt,
so this is the response I'm getting. Here are some new movies released schedule uh for this date, okay. And you can see all of the movie it has given me.
again, this is a list, okay. so what I can do, I can get the
get the output.
Now I just need to get this text.
Now see that's how you can extract the final result. Now, see this is more readable.
Okay, this is more readable.
I hope you get it, guys. Okay, now let me show you another question.
Uh, first find out the stock price of Apple using get stock price tool, then use the calculator tool to find how much it will take to purchase
uh 50 shares. Okay, now this kinds of question I'm asking. Let's see whether it is able to use my tool or not.
Now, see again I'm getting the result,
and if you want to get the text, you can
extract from here,
okay. The stock price of Apple is that much, and to purchase 50 uh 50 shares, it would cost around that but that much of money.
So, okay, now I think you saw it is able to use the tools right now, and this is not a simple chatbot. Okay, this has the tool connection, it can perform any kinds of action.
Even you can also ask about the real-time weather information. Let me also ask
what is the current weather in let's say
New York.
The current weather in Newark, uh, New York is uh moderate rain with a temperature that
this is the temperature, and feeling like
see this is the temperature, uh, humidity and the pressure.
Okay, each and everything it is giving you.
Okay,
so yeah, guys, our system is working perfectly.
Now we'll be integrating inside our Agentic chatbot. This is the complete notebook experiment I showed you, and you have already understood the concept, okay.
how to add the tools and I mean how to add the tools and how we can write our custom tools as well, each and everything I showed you.
So, guys, now we'll try to add inside our project. So, here what I can do, I can simply
create a separate file so that you can refer all of the previous code as well.
So, I'm going to create a
file here.
I'm going to name it as let's say
this name
agentic chatbot
tool backend.
Okay,
and inside that I'm going to copy all of my backend code I had.
Okay, the same code you just need to copy paste here.
Same code.
And here I will do the modification. And again, I just finished my open API key limit, that's why I'm using this Gemini model.
Okay, but if you have your open API key, you can uncomment this line and comment this line, okay? So alternative approach I showed you here.
So now here I'm going to first of all import all of the necessary library
from my
notebook,
just import all of this necessary library,
okay.
After that, we are loading the environment variable, it's completely fine.
Then if you have open API key, you can uncomment this, but I don't have, I'll be using Gemini model.
So once uh model uh initialization is done, so let me comment also so that
it would be easy for you to remember.
So this is the LLM definition. Now we'll try to define the tools.
Okay, so here we'll try to define all of the tool the tools we have created here, okay. All of the tools we'll try to define here.
So let's copy all of the tools.
So here I copy pasted all of the tools.
So first tools I had my search tool, tabli search tool, second tool I had my calculated tool, third tool I had my stock price, and the fourth tool I created this
way. There
I'll also copy this one
copy and
paste it here.
Okay, some error is coming.
okay, now it is solved. Uh the problem was that I just copied till here, okay.
and the last part was uh not copied. Uh now I think this is fine.
Okay, now this is fine, but here I have to import another uh things which is this
any, okay?
So any and voice,
import voice
and import
from typing, I will import this any.
So in the tools also, I have to do the same thing.
Fine now uh I think everything is good. this is my calculator, this is my carry stock, this is my current weather
tool,
and this is my chat state.
This is my chat state. So here let me comment.
This is my chat state. Now I'll define my nodes.
Same nodes only.
Okay, one more thing. I just forget to do.
I just need to do the tool bind operation.
I think you remember.
Here we just need to bind this tool. Let's do that.
So before initializing this state, I will just bind this tool.
Let me comment here.
Bind tools to llm.
Now, the state definition is also done.
Now I'll define my chat notes.
So this is the chat node, and the change I have done instead of calling the simple llm, I'm calling llm with tools.
Okay, this object.
Now I'll define my second node, which is tool node.
Okay, tool node.
So I think remember here also I did the same thing.
Tool nodes. Okay,
now this, this is my connector that means my check pointer
for the persistence memory
check pointer.
this part I already taught you. Okay, this is common for all.
Now we'll try to define the graph.
Okay,
we'll try to define the graph. So, as you can see, this is our graph. We are adding the nodes where this is the edge connection.
We are using the tools condition, and at the last, we are just doing this.
Uh, this uh edge connection as well. That means whatever tool output we'll be getting, we'll try to send it to the chat node.
That means in the same tools demo.ipynv file I showed you the same thing. Okay, I just copy pasted the code only. Okay, nothing changed.
The same code I copy pasted. That's it.
Once it is done, I think this function you remember. This is the helper function for this streamlit front end
we used, okay.
Uh, that's that means with this function we are getting the threads.
okay. For this streamlit we created, I think, in my previous video. I think you remember.
So, yes, guys, this is the modification we have to do in the backend dot pie.
Now everything is fine. I think let me check.
Everything is fine now.
We are ready to uh test inside our front end as well. So now I'll just write another front end file.
So here I'll copy this file as it is,
and the last file was the db, right?
Yeah, last file was the db.
So I'll just copy and paste it
and I'll just rename it.
App tool
dot pie.
Okay, so it has the db with tools uh tools code as well.
Okay, now here the change you just need to do, which is um
yeah, if you don't change, it's completely fine, you can use it as it is. Okay, there won't be any kinds of problem, but one uh I think UI update you won't be able to see.
I think at uh whenever I show you my application for the first time, right? As a demo, that time you saw whenever I was executing my agent, it was showing it is using some kinds of tool.
Okay, see right now if I execute my app. So, what will happen? Let me show you first of all, okay. One more uh just modification you have to do.
Uh this import, okay. Uh, previously I'm importing from agentic chatbot db backend. Now I have to import from agentic
chatbot tool backend. Okay,
so this update only
and make sure you have your
Lang Smith Lang Smith environment variable that means the Lang Smith API key and everything because it will trace everything in the
language Smith. Let me open my language Smith platform
and
let me execute completely fresh. So, what I can do I can delete this one
I can delete this project and let me execute completely fresh
now.
I will execute my app
my app tool.py. Okay, this file
stream
late run
app
tool.py.
Now, this is our chatbot.
Now let's give the prompt.
I'll give hello.
See it's working. Now I'll give
tell me the latest news in AI.
See, right now you are getting the output like that, but you didn't see it is using the tool, okay.
Which tool it is using, but previously in the demo itself, so it is using some kinds of tool, even in the chat GPT. Also, if you're asking, you will be able to see some tool calling, okay.
Some tool calling is happening, right?
So let's say if I ask the same question in
chat GPT, you will see some kinds of
tool calling is happening. See, here it will tell, like, okay, I'm I'll search for the internet.
See, searching for the internet, is using some kinds of search tool. So, I want to also see this kinds of interface.
whenever my agent is using the tool, I'll be able to see that okay. This is using some kinds of tool.
Okay, so if you want to see that, you just need to do little bit UI update.
So, in the streamlit app, you just need to do some little bit modification.
So, here
itself you just need to do the modification.
Let me show you.
So, here you just need to do the modification whenever you are sending the user input, right?
And whenever you are uh just hitting the agent, that means here, here you just need to do the modification.
So, what I have done, guys, I just given this code to the chat GPT and I asked I just need to see this uh tool progress, uh tool progress
on my user interface whenever it will use any kinds of tool, just try to do the UI update.
So then again, chat GPT given me this code. Let me show you.
Chat GPT given me this particular code.
So from here,
um everything needs to be changed.
This part,
so this is the update uh chat GPT given me, guys.
So right now, uh basically it will uh automatically understand whenever it will uh use any kinds of tool. That time you will able to see in the user interface, okay?
So this code you don't need to remember, guys. Uh, you have chat GPT, you have Gemini.
Anytime you can do the modification inside at the UI interface because this functionality is completely user interface. Uh let's update. Okay, so as a agent TKI engineer, this is not your task.
there are some front end developer they will take care this part. Okay, I need to import one two things which is tool masses
uh here only tool masses, okay. That's it.
Now, this is the updated code.
Now, if I execute this code, let me show you what will happen. So, I'll re-execute my app.
Now, if I ask the same question, tell me
the latest news
in tab.
Yeah,
now you will see that it will be using some kinds of tool.
Now, see it is using tabily source tool, and it is doing the real time search operation, and the response it is generating, it is again giving to the chat nodes and chat
note is refining the output.
Okay, now you are able to see the
uh refinement result, and you can also see the tool execution. That means in the behind the tool, what is execute what the execution is happening? This is also available, okay. Like chat GPT.
Chat GPT, you can also see the behind execution process, like what the website it has referred and everything. You will be able to also see here, okay.
This is also possible.
Now, let me ask another question. I'll tell um
calculate
this number.
Now you'll see that it will use my calculated tool.
See, calculated tool.
Done.
Okay, now here I will ask. Now, here I will give another prompt. Uh, what is the current weather in New York?
Uh, okay, guys. One problem I found it is not able to use my uh current weather tools. Okay, why? If I show you the code, see whenever I did the bind operation, right?
So here I didn't add my uh current weather tool here. So this is the problem. So, what I will do, I'll just try to copy that code.
Uh, that's why I'm telling why it's not working.
Uh yeah, so I'll copy this code as it is
and paste it here.
Okay, now I think it should work. Let's see.
I'll re execute my app.
Now, here you can ask the same question.
What is the current weather in New York or any other city?
Now see it is using get current weather tool, and this is the current weather in New York right now. Okay, and you can also ask any other question as well.
Tell me
give me all the movie
list
in 2026.
See, it is using tablies rule and it will real-time source over the internet, and this will give you the result.
See, this is the entire result I'm getting, all the latest movie information I'm getting here.
I'm using right now. My uh Agenti chatbot is working like chat GPT.
So chat GPT has this kinds of tool as well, that's why it is giving you real-time informations.
Okay, and our chatbot is also working in that way. Now, if I open up my um
uh Langsmith dashboard, so if I go to my project now, here all of the trace has executed, even you can see trade-wise,
okay. Trade wise, you can see now let's I will see this particular trade. So I will open it up
and you can see the execution. Now, here you can see, guys, I have added the tool, and automatically, this tools has integrated inside my Langsmith dashboard as well. Now, see, this is my chat node,
okay. And whenever you given this message, it will go to the chat node. Chat node will hit the invoke the LLM and LLM has the tool condition integrated.
Okay, now tool condition has decided okay, it has to use the get current weather tool because what was the question? The question was what is the current uh weather in New York?
So it will go to the tools condition, tool condition will decide okay, it has to use the tool and which tool it will call get current weather tool, okay.
This tool it will call now. Tool condition will try to redirect uh this this thing to the tool nodes, okay.
And now tool nodes will uh select this get current weather tool, and what would be the location new work?
And if you pass this new work to the get weather, uh get weather function, this will return you the current weather information in new work. You can see this is the output, okay.
And this output we are sending again to the chat node, okay.
You can see say again sending to the chat node. Now, this is the input as well as the user input.
We are sending it, and AI is generating this refine output.
Okay, so that's how the entire system is working right now. Okay, now I think you can see, guys, what is the use of Lang Smith as well?
Because in the Lang Smith itself, you can debug everything after which note which node is executing, whether it is able to select the right tool or not.
Okay, so that's how we can understand each and everything. I hope it is clear, guys.
Okay, so yes, guys, uh, this is all about uh of our agentic chatbot. Now, uh, this agentic chatbot is uh not a simple chatbot.
Okay, this has the tool connection, it can perform different different actions. Now, uh, I can tell this is more advanced Agentic chatbot we have created.
Now, uh, some other functionality also needs to be added in this Agentic chatbot.
We'll also try to add the RG functionality that is you can upload any kinds of document you can apart from the chat operation.
So, yes, uh, this is all about from this implementation. I hope you liked it.
So, if you like this implementation, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel and share this video with your friends, friends, and family.
So, guys, this is our Agentic chatbot we have developed so far, and we have integrated lots of features with this Agentic chatbot. Now, this is not a simple chatbot right now, this has like
conversation, like trades, it has tool integrations, it has streaming features, even it has the persistence memory with the permanent database. Okay, so this is not a simple chatbot right now.
Now, the functionality I have added here, this REG functionality that means RAG functionality.
Now, in this chatbot, in this agentic chatbot, you can upload any kinds of documents, okay, and you can start doing the conversation on top of that, like chat GPT, okay.
So, chat GPT also has the same features.
If I show you the chat GPT, so in chat GPT, also you can upload any kinds of documents and you can perform chat on top of that. So, first of all, let's see our application, okay?
So, here let's say I will upload a documents.
Let's say this is the documents I will upload. So this is a research paper. Actually, I published this research paper.
So, as you can see, this is the paper, guys. The paper name is
development of multiple combined regression method for rainfall measurement.
Okay, so here you can see I was uh I was the author.
Okay, so I contributed in this paper. So this paper covers
about the rainfall measurement, okay.
by by using some regression methods. Okay, you can go through the paper. This is also available on the research kit.
Okay, now what I'll do, I'll just upload this paper on my Agentic chatbot.
I'll select this paper. I will upload it.
See, it is getting uploaded and it is processing.
Okay, so once it is done, now see here you can see the successful message. Now I can perform the chat operation. Now I'll just ask what is
range fault measurement
based on
the
uploaded PDF.
Now see it is using my rag tool.
Okay, so internally I created a rag tool, it is utilizing my rag tool and it is giving you some kinds of response.
As you can see, the document highlight that predicting the amount of rainfall recorded in millimeters uh is uh crucial. It it uh notes that uh conventional methods for forecast
for seeing rainfall using equipment based on climate coordinate uh coordinations like temperature, humidity, and uh weights are not productive.
Okay, instead of instead, the paper process using the machine learning
procedure and specifically predictive regression analysis technique.
Okay, so yes, if you go through the paper, guys, you will be able to see the same things this paper paper covers. Actually, we proposed some regression method for this rainfall measurement technique.
Okay. now you can also ask any other things, like, say, "What, is the
methodology,
uh, methodology
of
this paper
?" In
methodology.
Okay, now I'll send this prompt
now. See it is again using the rag tool, and it is uh it is giving you the entire methodology uh we have written in the paper. You can see uh this is the entire methodology.
So if you go through our paper methodology, you will be able to see the same things we are discussing there, okay.
So that means like chat GPT, we are able to upload any kinds of documents, okay, and we can perform the conversation.
So in chat GPT, also you can try, you can upload your documentation, okay, and you can do the conversation on top of that.
And we have also integrated the tracing features with our Agentic chatbot.
That means it will continuously monitor our Agentic chatbot, okay, and we are continuously tracing the execution on the Lang Smith platform, guys.
As you can see, these are all of my trace, okay, and you can monitor the entire trace entire let's say application in this langsmith
dashboard only.
Okay, so this part I also showed in my playlist. just go through and check this that how we can add this Langsmith functionality inside our application, okay. So, yes, this is the features, guys.
I have added inside our agentic chatbot and trust me, this is very much important whenever you are creating agentic system.
Now it is all the agentic uh applications are you uh applications are having these kinds of REG functionality.
That means uh you not only you can um do the conversation with the tools and the default large length based model, instead of that, you can upload your private documents
and you can continue the conversation on top of that. Okay, everything is possible here.
So, uh, yes, guys, this is the application, and apart from that, this application can also handle different different conversations. Let's see if I'm asking, tell me the latest okay, latest news
of FIFA.
Okay, 2026
did
Brazil
on the game.
Now see, this is the question, this is the latest information I'm asking, and my agentic chatbot will be using some kinds of search tool and it will give me the response.
Now see it is using tabily search tool.
I already told you about what is tably, right? And it is doing the internet search tool. it is doing the internet search and it is giving you the real-time response as you can see.
Yeah, so this is the answer in the FIFA World Cup uh 2026 uh group C match which ended in a one by one
draw.
Okay, then uh Vinicius Jr. scored uh Brazil in this uh simulated game.
Okay, so this was the uh like match, guys. If you have already watched that Brazil match, you saw like uh this was a draw match actually, and this uh Vinicius Junior actually scored
um
uh one goal for the Brazil.
So, yes, guys, that's how our Agentic uh chatbot works, and you can upload any kinds of documents right now, and you can start the conversation on top of that.
Apart from that, whatever functionality we have created so far, whatever tools we have integrated so far, it will be working like a same, right?
So now let's start implementing this functionality inside our Agentic chatbot.
But before that, first of all, I want to give you the idea about uh rag, what is readable augmented generation techniques and why it is useful,
okay, and how this system works. Okay, first of all, we'll try to understand, then we'll start the development, guys.
So, guys, uh as you can see, uh rag in agentic chatbot it's a very important feature, uh, not only in agentic chatbot, uh, whenever you are working with the
generative AI technology, especially with the large language model.
This rag is very important, uh, like component of that. Uh, if you have already studied about JNI, I think you already work with rag concept, right?
So, rag helps us actually in three majors uh uh actually field one is the outdated knowledge. So I think you know whatever large language model you are using, it has a knowledge cutoff, right?
So if I'm talking about the let's say GPT 4 or GPT 3.5, right? Uh it has a knowledge cutoff till 2021.
Uh this model got trained, and after that, actually, whatever um new data came in the internet, this model doesn't have the access to that data,
right? Because it has a knowledge cutoff. That means if you are asking anything regarding after that date, this model won't be able to give you the response. So it's not like that.
Again, you have to fine-tune that model, okay, on the new data because fine-tuning at the end it's a costly task.
for this, you need a good instance, you need good infrastructure, you need lots of money, you need you need lots of data, right?
So that's why uh researcher introduced the rag concept, and with the help of rag, actually, you can
give external data to the large language model as a knowledge base, and your LM will be able to generate the response uh
you are asking about the latest information you have already given, right? So, this is the concept of the rag.
So, that's why if your model has outdated knowledge, that time rag is very important for that, and only things you have to create a
detailed knowledge base, okay, with your custom data.
Now, the second thing is the private data, okay.
So, what is private data?
private data means let's say
just I showed you one example. I uploaded my paper, right? I uploaded my research paper. So this research paper is my private data, and I want to perform some conversation on top of my private data.
I want to understand about my private data. Not only research paper, you can upload any kinds of private documents of yourself.
You can upload about your life story, you can upload about your let's say any kinds of inventory list, okay. Anything you can upload and you can perform the conversation on top of that.
Okay, so this private data actually is not available in the
LLM.
Okay, the default LLM we are using, so that's why uh we have to create this rack technique so that I can upload any kinds of private documents and I can start
doing the conversation on top of that.
Okay, I can ask anything, I can get any kinds of feedback from my like chatbot. Then the third is the hallucination.
Hallucination happens let's say whenever you are asking your agent to do something, let's say you are asking,
give me some, give me some, let's say.
Uh research topic link okay for that particular topic. Let's say this topic your
agentic chatbot doesn't know, right? let's say this is completely new topic, so uh this is not available uh in the um in the large language model knowledge base.
So that time what will happen? Uh it might generate some wrong URL, right?
It might generate some wrong URL, and if you go to the URL, you will be able to see this URL is not working, this research article is not working, right?
So instead of what you can do, maybe you can give some of the resources, okay.
You can give some of the document uh to your agentic chatbot uh as an external knowledge, and you can uh tell, like, okay, now refer this uh actually
knowledge, and you can generate some um like research topics or let's say URL, okay, on top of that.
So that time actually your LLM will not do the hallucination, but if you are not doing that, uh there is a possibility your um chatbot will do the hallucination,
okay. it might generate something wrong information for you. So that's why this RG technique is super important whenever you are creating these kinds of system.
That's why nowadays uh all of the application you have seen, like chat GPT, Gemini, okay, uh, these are the application are using this uh RG concept in their um
application. that means you can upload any kinds of documents, okay, PDF, whatever, and you can perform the conversation on top of that.
Now let's try to understand how this uh rag works. So this rag came from actually in-context learning techniques. So, in in-context learning, what happens?
So, this is the like a high-level diagram of this in-context learning.
So, here uh we not only pass a query, okay, to the large language model, uh, with the help of uh with this query, we also give some kinds of external
context, okay. Then we prepare a prompt and this prompt will try to send to the large language model, and large language model will generate some kinds of response.
Now, let's try to see this part in action. So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to give you one example.
Let's say
uh here you are asking about your um let's say paper.
So I uploaded one paper, I think you remember, called Rainfall Measurement Paper.
So if I ask directly this question, okay, to my large language model, let's say here I'm using very old large language model, and this large language model trained
till let's say 2019.
Okay, and if you see my paper, guys, this paper I published around 2021.
Okay, so this paper information definitely it's not available inside my large language model.
So if I'm asking about this, let's say paper, let's say tell me about this rainfall measurement paper, okay.
Rainfall,
rainfall paper.
Okay, let's say I'm asking my large language model. This is my entire prompt.
I'm passing to the large language model. That time large language model will definitely not provide the response because it doesn't have the information.
Okay, so in context learning, what happens instead of giving the direct query, you can also pass the context. Context means here you can give the entire paper.
Okay, you can pass the entire paper.
Okay, you can extract all of the content or you can directly give the paper okay as a context, and you can combine a prompt. Let's say tell me about rainfall measurement paper, and
here is the
paper
okay, content, and you are already passing the paper here, right?
You are already passing the paper here. That means you are giving the query as well.
Okay, you are also giving the paper.
Okay, then you are asking, tell me about the rainfall measurement. Now your LLM has the context as well as the query. Now it can generate the response.
Okay, you are asked, uh it can generate the response, the question you are asking by using this particular context.
Okay, in real life, also let's say if I'm asking you anything which is completely new,
and let's see if you don't don't know that information, if you don't know that let's say question, that time you will directly say, Okay, I don't know.
But if I give you some kinds of context, let's say I will ask about uh tell me about
let's say Brazil team.
Okay, uh so what you will do if I give you some context, let's say if I give you list of the Brazil player
let's say name list, then you will be able to give me okay, these are the player uh players are available in Brazil team, right? It's it's like that.
That means you are not only giving the query but also you are providing the answer, that means the context, okay. The entire paper.
Now LLM is referring the paper and it is generating the question you are asking.
That's you are asking about rainfall measurement, it will be able to understand about the rainfall measurement from the paper and it will give you some kinds of refined response.
So that's how in-context learning works, okay. But the problem with in-context learning is so let's say here the paper I am uploading, it might have lots of content, right?
It might have lots of content.
Content means if you see the paper, all of the words you can consider as a token, right? And if you count all of the token there is a chance this token, okay, number of token
might increase than your input length of the model, input limit
of LLM.
Okay, so every model has an input limit, right?
token limit. If you open any kinds of model, right in Google, you will see that it has an input limit, token limit. Let's say the model we are using.
This model can take uh thousand okay, thousand token input at a time. But if you are passing the entire paper, let's say the paper token I have counted, it is around 5000 token.
Okay, 5000 token. That time, definitely this token is bigger than your input token limit. That time that would be an error, okay.
and There would be some kinds of input error that means you can't pass that many of tokens as an input to the model, okay. So this was the problem with the in-context learning.
So that's why from the in-context learning, one concept has introduced the concept name is rag.
Okay, so in rag, actually, what we do instead of giving the entire documents directly, we perform something called chunking. We perform something called splitting, okay.
We divide our entire content in a different chunk, different split, and we pass this uh different chunk okay,
one by one to the model. So this is the like updated architecture as you can see. Let's say here I am having an entire documents.
First of all, we'll try to extract all of the content from the document itself, okay. We'll load the documents and we'll extract all of the content from the documents as you can see, okay.
And once it is done, we'll try to perform some kinds of chunking operation. We also call it as a speeder, text speeder. Speed means let's say this is my entire docs, right?
This is my entire content, and I'll just try to create a different different chunk. I'll try to divide this content okay in a different different part.
This is called text speeder.
Okay, now let's say if your original documents it is around 5000 token okay.
Now, after doing this speeder or chunking, every uh every let's say chunk will have let's say 1000 token.
Okay, 1000 token. That's how you can create five uh five actually chunk here, or let's say four chunk here or six chunk here. It's completely up to you.
Okay, but it uh this input should be uh less than your model input.
So once you have created the chunk, then you will be using some kinds of embedding model. I think you know about embedding model.
What embedding model does basically embedding model we use to convert our text to the number because the large language model we are using, right?
It can't take directly the English text as an input, okay, internally because this is some kinds of mathematical equation. So we have to convert as a number, right?
We'll be using this embedding model and we'll generate some kinds of vector embedding.
This is called vector embedding, right? This is called vector embedding. Now, this vector embedding we have to store somewhere.
This is called actually vector database, and we call also call it as a vector store.
okay. Especially in rag, you will be using vector database, not a traditional normal database.
Okay, here you have to use vector database because there is a concept called similarity search or semantic search you have to perform, and this is only possible in vector database only, right?
Then you will be storing all of this vector in the vector database, okay. Now this will become your knowledge base, this will become your knowledge base, guys.
Okay, now this knowledge base we have to connect with our large language model right now.
Okay, now this part actually we perform the retriever operation. That means if user is asking about a question about the let's say the paper I have uploaded, rainfall measurement.
So, first of all, this question will go to the knowledge base, okay? Because knowledge base has all of the okay,
all of the information about the rainfall measurement because I have uploaded the entire paper, it is available right here, right?
So then this retriever it will go here and it will perform a semantic search operation and will only extract that part which is required for the query.
Let's say here I'm asking about what is rainfall measurement, but if you open the paper, instead of rainfall measurement, is it has lots of like uh C topic,
it has the related works, it has the methodology, okay. Then it has some comparison, it has some data set introduction, okay, it has some diagram pre-processing section.
So I don't need all of the information, I only need that part where it covers what is rainfall measurement exactly.
Okay, so with the help of the similarity starts, it will only found that information, okay, which is you are asking in the query, and it will give you that particular
relevant response. So here you can see this question will go to the knowledge base, and knowledge base will return some relevant response based on the query you are asking. Most relevant chunk, okay.
We call it as a most relevant chunk or context. Then you are combining the query also here. You can see the query you are also combining, then you are preparing the final prompt.
That means you can you are combining this query with the prompt. Let's say this my query is what is rainfall measurement, and you got the rainfall measurement answer. Now we are combining the prompt.
what is the
tell me about rainfall measurement, and here is the context. Then you are generating uh entire prompt and this prompt you are passing to the LLM. Now LLM has the query as well as the context, okay.
The question you are asking, then LLM will try to read that, it will understand and it will refine some kinds of uh final response and it will uh show you this particular response, okay?
So that's how the entire RG system works. Okay, so this is the better version of the in-context learning because in context learning we pass the entire documents, okay.
And what is the problem with the entire documents?
Because it has an input limit. But here,
if you are giving, let's say, thousands of thousands token input as well, it doesn't matter because it performed the chunking operation, it performed the splitting operation,
and all of the entire documents would be split into different chunks and it will store in the vector database.
Then you can perform any kinds of uh retriever operation, okay, similarity source operation, and you can perform this kinds of question and answer on top of your private documents.
So that's how this RG system works, guys. Okay.
I hope this part is clear to all of you. Now we'll try to implement this system, guys, inside our agentic chatbot. But before that, I want to show you the notebook experiment, okay.
Like uh, let's say I will show you the step by step procedure how we can implement this REG with our agentic chatbot. because we are using Langgraph, how we can do it with the help of Langgraph.
I'll show you the entire experiment, and once our experiment is working, then I'll try to integrate inside our actual code.
So, guys, as you can see, this is our entire code, and this code I have already uploaded in my GitHub, and link is given in the description.
So, here in the notebook folder, guys, I added another notebook called RAG Demo.
Okay, just open this notebook, and here I already written all of this code uh required to implement this reg functionality, right? Instead of writing from scratch because it will take lots of time.
Instead of that, maybe I can go through my implementation, right? So here just try to select your environment. After that, uh, first of all, you have to import all the necessary libraries.
Okay, so here I have already imported all the necessary libraries, guys. As you can see, open AI, open AI embeddings. Okay, even I've also imported this
Google generate API because if you don't have OpenAI API key, if you don't have OpenAI, let's say uh provider, that time you can use
alternative way for running this project. You can use Gemini model and Gemini model by default you will be getting some free uh free access.
Okay, you can use that particular model, so that's why I'm importing this Gemini.
And if you want to use this Gemini, you have to import this chat Google Generate API functional. And I have already installed this in my requirement as you can see.
This this library I have already installed there. Apart from that, you have to also import this Google Generate API embeddings because I don't have open AI embedding model, right?
I don't have open API key, that time I can use Gemini embedding model. Okay, so that's why both I have imported. let's say whichever you have, you can use them.
Okay, then load enb pie pdf loader. See if you are implementing RG that time this thing is required. If you are uploading the PDF document, that time from Langchen community, you can
import this PyPDF loader. This is already available in document loader, and for this you have to install some library like uh LangChann community.
Uh then you have to install Fire CPU. Fire is a vector database, okay.
Apart from Fires, actually, there are some other vector database are available like uh OVT is there, Chroma DV is there, Pinecone is there.
Okay, maybe in future project we'll try to use, but uh in this project I'm going to use Fires, okay, Fires vector database, and FIS is a in um in storage database,
that means uh it will create uh the database inside your uh computer, okay.
Inside your computer, computer um hard drive, and there are some cloud-based uh uh vector database are available like Web8 is there, then PineCone is there. You can store all of your vectors in cloud.
Okay, this part I will also show you later on. Then PyPDF you have to also install because uh we'll be uploading PDF documents here.
So, in this project, guys, uh, only just to show you, I'll be considering the PDF documents. But if you want, you can also have the docs format, you can upload Excel format.
Okay, this part you can go through the simply Langchin documentation. Okay, there you will try to see how to load the documents, how to load the Excel documents, okay.
Each and everything they have given. But here I'm going to only consider PDF documents.
Then one another uh library you have to install called Langchen Text Splitter, and this Lang Chann text splitter will be using for this uh for this actually chunking operation, okay.
from the entire document will perform different different chunk, right? And with the help of this Langchen Text Splitter will be doing this particular work.
And here I have already specified the version, these are the version you have to install. And how to install?
Open your terminal and just execute
pip install hypner requirement.txt. Okay, if you do that, it will install in your system, okay. So I have already installed all of the necessary library, guys. I don't need to install again,
but if you are doing it for the first time, you have to install these at the library, okay.
I mean, all the comment I have also given in my readme.md file. So once it is done, guys, let's import all of the necessary library. You can see I'm importing this uh
recursive characteristics Peter from Langchen text better, and with the help of that, we'll be performing the chunking.
Then uh we are also importing a vector database, it is also available inside LangCh and community vector store.
I'm importing files, okay, and files as implemented by meta IIT. Okay, by Facebook, uh this uh vector database has implemented. Then we are importing tools, graph, then annotated type dick.
These are the things are common add messages, human messages, base messages, okay.
And from Langgraph, we are also importing some pre built uh let's say
node like tool node and tool condition. So these are the things are common. Okay, so this is our entire import. Let's import them
one by one.
So, see guys, I have imported uh successfully. Now we have to load the environment variable.
So, as you can see, we already have the environment variable here, and here I have already added all of my API key.
I used Tavili API key, I used Open Weather API key, Google API key. Okay, and this API key I collected from Google AI Studio if you want to use Gemini model.
So in my previous video, guys, I showed you uh showed you this part okay how to collect all the API key.
you can go through that recording.
Then from Langsmith tracing, guys, we have added these three uh four things, and here you have to pass the Langsmith API key as well from the Langsmith platform, okay?
So these are the credentials you need. Now let's load all of them.
Now, if you're if you're already having this open AI key, you can uncomment this line and you can use uh open api model open AI model.
And if you don't have open API key, if you have only Gemini key, that time you can use this definition.
Okay, so here we are using Gemini model.
So let's load the Gemini model. Now we'll try to uh load my paper, okay. One of my documents. So here I already kept my documents, my paper. That means this paper I already
uh I already copied in the folder.
Okay, you can use any other documents as well. So this is the name of the PDF.
So I have to load this particular PDF. Now for loading it, I'm using PyPDF loader because this is a PDF file. Now let's load that.
Okay, so once you do the loader.load operation, you will be able to see the entire documents. Now let me show you the entire documents. So this is the documents now.
By default, Langchain loads your documents into document format, okay, as a page by page.
So how many pages this is having?
I think this PDF is having 15 pages, okay.
15 pages content I have extracted, okay. And you can see some metadata are available, but the main part is that the content. So let me show you.
Uh, here is the content, paste content, okay. And in the paste content, you will have all of the uh text okay. I have in my PDF, and these are some meta information.
Now we'll try to perform this this operation. That means we have extracted the entire document. Now we have to perform the chunking, guys.
Okay, we have to perform the chunking. Now, this part actually performs the chunking operation. We are importing recursive character textplitter, and here we are defining the chunk size, okay.
That means each of the chunk will have how many token?
Okay, here we have defined each of the chunk will have 1000 token.
Okay,
and there is a another parameter you have to provide called chunk overlap.
This chunk overlap basically means that there it has to add some overlapping, okay. Overlapping overlapping means let's say let's say it is uh it is extracting 1000 token.
Okay, let's say till here you have 1000 token.
Okay, now next again it will create another chunk, right?
Uh let's say from here it will start, but if there is a chunk overlap, let's say 200, what it will do, it will go back to 100 watt, let's say 200 watt uh
starts here, then it will create uh again uh 1000 tokens from here. Okay, that means from your previous chunk, okay. There is an overlap I am creating so that my model can understand.
Okay, after this token, after this, let's say chunk, this chunk is starting. Okay, so that's why this overlapping is important, and this is the concept of rag.
Okay, I already covered in my YouTube channel. There is a dedicated general TBI playlist. I am having you can go through that playlist. There I covered this rank concept in detail.
Okay, you can understand these are the concept there. Then after that, we are splitting the documents, we are passing the entire documents, and you can see we are creating the chunk now.
Total, I got 444 chunks here. Okay, that means I got 44 chunks here, okay.
By divide uh by um doing the splitting of my entire content, okay. And each of the chunk will have 1000 token because our chunk size was 1000 token
and this this is completely hyperparameter number. You can also change this number that's per your requirement. Now, guys, we'll be defining the embedding model right now.
And here, if you have OpenAI API, guys, you can execute this code.
this code actually loads the open AI embedding model and it is stores in the files uh vector database. But if you don't have open AI, you can execute this code.
and This code uses Gemini embedding model. You here we can see I'm using this Gemini embedding model and we're storing our vectors, okay.
you are storing our vectors inside my files vector database, okay.
Files vector database, and for this, this is the code files.prom document, and you have to give all of the chunk and your embedding model as well.
Okay, now if you execute this code
now, see here you will be able to see um
one uh one database, but uh this is only visible if you write this line
Ha! vector store save local, okay. And here you have to give the name.
Now if I execute
Again,
now see it has created the files database here, okay, in your computer.
Okay, that's why I told you this is an in-computer database, it will store inside your computer storage.
Okay. Now we'll uh see the vector store. So this is the object of the files vector store.
Now we'll just try to create a retriever.
Okay, retriever means if you want to perform this semantic source operation, you have to create a retriever of the entire database you have created because user will give a question,
and this question will first of all go to the vector store, it will extract the most relevant chunk and it will combine your query, then it will prepare a prompt.
Okay, for this operation, you have to create this retriever object. How to get the retriever object? You just need to write vector store as retriever, okay.
then here you have to provide the search type, and here we'll be using similarity search operation and the search keyword is four. That means it will extract four relevant response at a time.
Okay, let's see if you're asking about what is rainfall measurement, it will go to the vector store and four relevant chunk it will try to extract. Okay, so this is the parameter.
If you make it as five, it will extract five chunks. It will, if you give let's say two, it will only extract two chunks. Okay, that's how these things works. Now we'll try to create the retriever.
So once retriever is created, guys.
Now these things we want to integrate inside of agentic chatbot and agentic chatbot.
If you're using rag concept, you have to uh you have to actually create a tool of your entire rag you have created, right?
But in simple rag, we don't create the tool, we just directly perform the question and answer on my retriever with my large language model, okay?
But here we we have created agentic chatbot and agentic chatbot works with the tool.
So, guys, as you can see, I have written this retriever functionality as a tool, and this is the function I have created, and I made it as a custom tool.
So, before showing you this one, first of all, I want to show you how retriever works. Let's execute retriever independently.
So, I'll copy this one
uh retriever.invoke, and here let's pass a query.
I'll give
what is
rainfall
measurement.
Okay, now see this will return you.
this will return you actually four relevant information
see four relevant information. Why? Because this SARS keyword you have set it as four.
This k parameter is four right now, that's why four relevant response it is giving you. See, these are my four relevant chunk. I am getting about the rainfall measurement. Now this will go to the my
and this will go to the my query.
that means I'll add the query here and we'll prepare a prompt and this will go to the llm. Now LLM has the context as well as the question, and LLM will be able to generate the final response for me.
Okay, so that's how this
this system is working, okay.
That's how this retriever is working. Now I have to make it as a tool because here we are creating an agentic chatbot and agentic chatbot works with a tool, okay.
Now, here you can see I have written the same thing just in a function, it will take the query.
I'm doing the invoke operation, whatever documents I'm getting.
First of all, I'm checking if document not found, so though no relevant information was found, and if it is found, then I'm extracting the documents.
So here you can see some metadata information are available. So from this metadata, I'm uh extracting the document sources. Okay, sources means which PDF it is referring.
You can see here there is a section called source.
Title is there, source is there. You can see source. Okay, so that's how I'm extracting. These are the meta information page and content.
So this information I'm extracting, and we are joining in this uh um like uh list and we are returning it.
That's it, okay. So this is the function I have written, and we made it as a tool because this is our custom function.
And if you want to make it as a custom function, uh as a tool, then you have to use this language and tools, okay, decorator. There, we have already learned it, uh learned this previously, right?
So this is my tool right now, and I named it as a rag tool.
Now, further step will be same.
That means we'll be adding the tools inside a list and we'll try to bind that with our large language model.
So you can see I'm binding binding my large language model with my tools.
Execute
first of all, I'll execute this code,
then execute this.
Okay, now we have to define the state.
Now, this is our state,
and see here I haven't added other tools because I want to only show you the rag functionality, that's why I'm only using one tool.
But in my actual code, I have also some other tool like calculator, web search tool, then weather tool, then stock market tool. Okay, I think you remember. Then this is our nodes.
So in the node itself, I am using my LLM width uh tools, okay. This particular updated one,
and here is another node which is tool node.
Now, here I am defining my graph structure and we are adding the edges.
And I think this part you already know how to add the tool nodes and tool conditions there.
Now, finally, this is our graph, and this graph we also saw in my previous implementation.
Now, guys, we'll try to invoke our chatbot. Now, see, this is our regular message.
Here I'm just doing um chatbot.invok. I'm giving a message hello, and for this, it doesn't need any kinds of rag tool.
it will generate the answer from the large length based model only. Hello, I'm here to answer your question about the PDF document.
Okay, now uh here I'm uh passing my uh here I'm passing my prompt as you can see.
So here I'll just try to tell um using the PDF notes,
explain about the rainfall measurement technique in a conscious way.
Okay, now you'll see that uh it will use the rack tool and it will retrieve the information from the knowledge base and it is giving you the final response as you can see.
The provided documents primarily discuss rainfall prediction techniques using machine learning regression analysis rather than detailing specific uh
specific rainfall measurement techniques, okay. And blah blah blah. Now, if I only want to get the text, I will just extract the text from here.
Now, see this is my final answer, guys. I am getting okay. So that's how, guys. Now we can perform any kinds of chat operation on my PDF. I have loaded here.
Okay, that means this architecture we have implemented in my notebook.
Okay, I hope you clear, guys. Now we'll try to add this functionality okay inside our app.
So as you can see, this is our app we created so far. Uh, this uh this was our final app.
Uh final app, I think last app we created this one app tool. Okay, we are integrated the tool.
Okay, now what I'm going to do, guys.
I'm going to add this uh rag features with our actual application, and we'll try to conclude this particular video.
So, guys, uh, we have seen the entire notebook experiment of the rag, like how uh how to implement the rag functionality inside our agentic chatbot.
And main thing we have learned this tool, right? Now we have to create this retriever as a tool, and this tool will be using inside our agentic chatbot.
So now, guys, we will be integrating this feature since inside our actual agentic chatbot we have created so far.
Now, this was the last file I created app tools.py. Okay, this was the front end, and the back end was this one agentic chatbot tools backend. Okay, this was my backend code.
Now, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to create uh
create uh another file.
Maybe I can make a copy of this file
copy
and I'm going to just paste it
and I'll just rename it. Okay,
instead of tool backend,
I'll give rag backend.
Okay, I am keeping my old code as well so that you can get a reference. Okay, you can um you you will have this code so that in future, whenever you are practicing, all of the code will remain same.
so agentic chatbot rag backend dot pie. Okay, so this is my updated code.
Updated backend I'm going to write here.
Okay, and in this code, I'll just do the modification.
And for front end, also, uh, I'll just create another one.
this app tool, right? Instead of app tool, I'll copy
and I'll paste it first of all, then let's rename it.
Instead of tool, I'm going to give rack
Okay, now first of all, let's uh update our backend. So I'll open my backend
and here update would be
first of all, we'll uh import all the necessary library,
whatever we have imported in my notebook. So this is my updated library, guys.
As you can see, PyPdf loader, recursive character, splitter, Google generative uh embedding, okay, files and all we are importing everything, right?
Then after that, we'll be
uh we'll be just loading our embedding model.
So after large language model definition, we'll just try to load our embedding model, okay. The embedding model I was using in my notebook.
So here I think you remember I was using this embedding model.
Okay, let me close some of the file.
This file, this file,
also this file.
Now, after that, we'll just write a function.
Uh, this function will basically uh take a PDF file and it will extract the documents, it will perform the chunking, and after chunking, it will store all of the chunk in my vector
database. Okay, that means this step I perform, right?
This step I perform okay, separately.
I'll just do inside a function.
So let me show you this function I have already written
after this embedding model
just a minute.
here I have defined this model two times, right?
Okay, so I have to remove
so what I can do, I can
remove and rewrite again.
Okay, now I think it's fine.
Now I have imported all the necessary library. This is my model, this is my embedding function.
So this is my embedding model.
Now we'll just write this function.
So this is the function I named it in this rack document.
This will take a file path, and we are defining the database path. That means it will create a folder called files database. Inside that, all of the vector would be saved.
Now we are loading the like file, extracting the document, performing the chunking operation.
Now you can see chunking operation after that. We're storing everything in the files vector database, and then we are saving this database inside our local.
Okay, this is the function we'll be using, and this function we have to use from the front end.
So whenever I'll upload any file from the front end, that time I have to execute this function, and this function will create my knowledge base. Okay, this knowledge base would be created.
Okay, now I'll just write another function for the retriever.
Okay, so this function what it does basically it loads your vector database. Okay, that means the database we are creating, knowledge base we are creating.
First of all, it will load with the help of files.load local will be loading this and we'll pass the embedding model.
And there is another parameter you have to provide called allow dangerous deserialization is equal to true.
Then we'll create the retriever again. So vector store as retriever.
We are giving the similarity search and this k parameter, like that.
Okay, this this part we are doing. Then we are creating the retriever object. Now, with the help of this retriever object, I will be able to perform the inbox operation.
That means I'll be able to do the source operation, similarity source operation.
Okay, now we'll just write our rag tool
rag tool as a function.
So this is our rag tool, guys. As you can see, we created the same same function, we copy pasted the same function from here, okay.
This one now.
This will take the query. We are doing the first of all, we're getting the retriever. We are calling this function getRetriever.
This will give me my retriever object. I'll do the invoke operation, whatever document I will get. I'll extract all of the content from here.
Okay, then I will return it.
That's it.
It's coming.
Now, after that, we'll be defining all of our tools as it is. Okay, this will remain same.
You don't need to change anything. Our source tool, our calculator tool,
then our get stock price tool, then our get current current weather information tool.
Everything will remain same, only the change I have to do here.
Okay, here I have to add another tool, which is my rag tool.
rag underscore tool the function I have created.
Okay, this one.
This function.
I have to pass as a tool.
Then we are doing the bind operations.
Then we are defining the state.
And one more change we'll be doing inside our chat node. now this is a simple chat node we created previously. It doesn't have any kinds of system prompt. Now we'll add a system prompt here.
Let me show you my updated nodes. I have created.
So this is my updated notes, guys.
Okay.
So here I added a detailed system prompt as you can see.
And this is my system message. As you are a helpful agentic chatbot with access to several tools?
Use tools, uh, you uh tool uses in instruction, use rag tool for a question about uploaded PDF or documents.
Always retrieve relevant documents content before answering the PDF related questions.
Use search tool for current events, recent information or or information uh that requires the internet search.
Use calculated tools for mathematical calculation, do not calculate complex expression manually when calculator is available.
Then get stock use whenever user asking about any kinds of stock price and get weather whenever user is asking about latest weather informations
and answer general questions directly when no tools is required.
Do not invent information from the uploaded documents. If the user asks about the PDF but no documents is available, ask them to upload the PDF.
Okay, after receiving a tool result, provide a clear and helpful final answer. So that's how, guys, we defined a clear system message to our chatbot right now.
Okay, so every agentic chatbot you will see it has a message, okay? It has a prompt system system. We call it as a system prompt, and with the system prompt basically it uh performs all the operation.
That means whenever you are asking anything uh inside a chat bot, okay.
It uh it works like step by step. How it works because it has a proper system prompt, and this thing you have to provide, okay.
So far, we haven't given, but now we have given a detailed system prompt because now we have made it more advanced.
Now I want my chatbot to be worked like a professional way, okay. That's why we have it we have added this entire system prompt.
Now, in the message you will give the system prompt as well as the state message user is giving, then we are invoking it, and whatever response we are getting, we're just returning it.
Okay, so this is a simple modification you have to do inside your chat node, and all of the node will remain same. Your tool node, then we are defining my checkpointer squalite database.
Then this is our graph, okay. All the graph definition, everything will remain same, no need to change anything, as well as my helper function for streamlit front end. This will also remain same.
Okay, so this is the change, guys. You have to do in the backend file.
Okay, so this is the change you have to do in the backend file. Let me check whether anything is required or not.
I think everything is fine.
Okay, fine. Now I have to change my front end. Now, what I will do, I'll just try to open my front end app
rag.py.
Now see what I have done, guys. I just copied my existing front end code to chat GPT and I asked I need a document uploader function
features on my chatbot.
So try to create uh streamlit user interface for that.
Okay, so then I got this code. Let me show you.
This is the updated code I got.
This
is the updated code I got. So basically, this has the document upload features. Okay, so if you don't know about front end design and all, don't need to worry.
So, this is the work of a front-end developer.
So, I also took the help from chat GPT and I uh created this front end part. Only the change you have to do here, okay. First of all, you have to change this uh import operation.
That means right now we are importing from agentic chatbot rag backend.
So from agentic
chatbot rag backend, okay.
We are importing chatbot, then get all threads
uh.
Get all threads, okay. This one, and we are also importing ingest rack documents, okay. That means this function. This function I need whenever I will upload any kinds of documents on my streamlit.
So this function will be executed and my vector store will be ready. Okay, that time, then everything will remain same, only the change here it has done. Let me show you.
see, this is the new code it has added. If you if you compare with your previous code, so this part has changed, okay.
So here in the uploaded um section, that is in the user input section, it has added another one called uploaded file.
So basically, here it is taking a PDF file upload, and uh, we are taking this PDF file which is uh saving as a temporary file, then we are calling this in
just drag documents. We are passing inside this function, okay?
And this function is creating my knowledge base. This knowledge base is be created, that means this uh uh vector store would be created.
Once my vector store is created, now you'll be able to perform the chat operation.
Again, we are taking the user input and doing the chat operation, okay? That means all the code are common, only that buzz uh that part is changed. Okay, that means upload document part is changed.
Now let me show you my updated front end, how it looks like.
So, streamlit
run
app
_reg.py.
So as you can see, this is my updated front end. Now we can perform the chat operation. Now let's perform the simple chat initially. So let's say I'll give hello.
I am Bappi, and this is happening in a like new trades, okay?
Completely new trades,
and internally it is also tracing our application, okay.
It is also tracing our application with the help of Langsmith.
Now I'll give uh tell me about
let's say
Python.
So this is a simple chart.
So it is telling you about Python.
Okay.
Now here I will ask uh
what is the answer of
this equation. Let's say I'll give a mathematical equation.
I'll see it will use my calculator tool.
See calculated tool it is using, and this is the final result I'm getting.
Okay, now, I'll ask, uh,
"What, is the
current
weather
in,
let's say,
now ?". It will use my
Get Current Weather tool. and this is the current weather in Dhaka right now.
Okay, now I will ask about the latest information.
Tell me the
latest
news.
Okay, latest news
of FIFA
FIFA World Cup
2026.
Now see, it is using Table Eser 2
and here is the
answer I got.
Okay, about the FIFA World Cup.
Okay.
Now I will ask uh I will upload a document.
Let's say I'll upload a documents.
The same documents, let's say I'll upload my paper.
My paper got uploaded, and I'll tell
you uh tell me about
rainfall
measurement
uh
just done
the PDF
uploaded.
Now see it is using rag tool and it is giving you the entire response about the rainfall measurement.
Okay, this amazing. Now, I'll tell her, tell me
about
the
abstract
paper.
now. See again it is using Rag2, and this is giving you the entire abstract checks from okay.
Now I'll ask uh who is Bukhtir Ahmed Bhapi
mentioned
in the paper.
Now again it is using React tool, and now it is telling Bukhtira Ahmed Bhapi is one of the six author of the paper development of multiple combined regression method for
informal assignment. And here is the address and email address. Okay, amazing, right? So that's how, guys, our Agentic chatbot.
right now it's working and it has it has lots of advanced features right now.
And the current one we have added this RAG functionality.
Now you can upload any kinds of document and you can perform the conversation on top of that, okay.
Like chat GPT, like chat GPT, also you can upload any kinds of documents, okay, and you can start doing the conversation here, okay.
This is also possible, and one more thing I want to show you. So if I go to my Langspeth right now, so if I go to my trades,
so I'll go to these trades,
and here all the conversation I have done.
So the last conversation I did uh this one.
Now, if I go to the tool condition,
okay. I'm Bapi. I think last conversation was that okay. This one,
yeah. Now you can see here uh whenever I did the conversation, first of all, it went to the chat node, then large language model, then um it was redirected to the tool condition.
Tool condition was selected. The tool now it selected the rack tool, okay. And inside rack tool, we are using this vector search retrieval operation, okay.
And with the help of that, it is doing the vector search, and it found actually four relevant response.
I can see okay from my knowledge base, and this four relevant response went to my chat notes again. That means my LLM with the prompt, and then uh it was generating the final response.
Okay, so that's how this entire system is working, and in the Langsmith platform itself, you can monitor the entire system. Okay, this is the best part of this uh of this actual application. is.
So, yes, guys, uh, this is the um Like uh chatbot we have created so far. This is our agentic chatbot we have created so far, and everything is working fine.
And all the codes I will be shared in my description section. From there, you can check it out and let me know how this uh learning is okay.
whether you are able to learn uh the agent TKI concept from my playlist or not.
So if you found my content useful, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel and share this with your friends and family. Okay, your support is required.
So if you are supporting me, guys, I'll get lots of motivation to bring these kinds of content. Okay, in this video, we'll be learning one very interesting concept called human in the loop
inside our agentic chatbot with the help of Linegraph.
If you are following my entire playlist, guys, from the beginning, I think you remember in my introduction video I already talked about this HITL that means human in the loop concept.
that means this is the component of an AI agent whenever you are implementing any kinds of AI agents, whenever you need any sensitive task,
you need this HITL concept that means human in the loop concept. Okay, uh, so in this video, guys, we'll try to learn this entire HITL concept.
We'll also see the practical and we'll also try to integrate this functionality inside our agentic chatbot.
So before I start this uh implementation, guys, first of all, I want to show you the demo, how this HITL looks like,
and after adding this inside our agentic chatbot, how it is going to work, okay. We'll try to see the demo.
After seeing the demo, we'll try to understand this concept in a theoretical manner, then we'll see the practical implementation as well. So, guys, this is our agentic chatbot.
That's how this chatbot looks like. So, right now you can upload any kinds of document and you can start a conversation okay on top of your documents.
This is possible. So, let's try to test our chatbot. And I already integrated this HITL with this Agentic chatbot.
I'm first of all going to show you the demo, then after that, we'll try to see the practical development. So, here uh you can perform the simple chat operation.
Let's see if I give hello, so your chatbot will return something. See hello, how I can help you today. Now we'll ask what is the
what is the
current weather
in Dhaka.
You will see that it will be using different different tools. Okay, that means it will use uh weather tools and it will give me current weather informations, okay.
Uh, given any kinds of location, even you can upload any kinds of documents. Let's say I will upload one of my documents.
Let's say I will upload these documents,
okay.
Okay. Now this is one of my resume. I have uploaded now. I'll ask some question on top of this PDF.
So tell me about
here
the PDF.
Okay, upload it.
Now we'll see that it will be using RagTool and it is giving you the entire uh entire actually introduction of Bukhtier Hamed Bhapi.
He's a data scientist over five years of working experience in the field of general T BI LLM ops, autonomous AI system. Okay, and blah blah blah. You can see the entire summary of me.
Okay, so that's how guys you can perform any kinds of conversation on any kinds of documents.
Okay, now here let me show you this HITL functionality I have added in this agentic chatbot. So basically, here I have added this HITL for one sensitive task.
Okay, sensitive task means I think you would know that uh with the help of this agentic chatbot, I can see any kinds of stock price, right? So let's say if I'm asking uh let's say what is the
stock
price
Apple okay, so I think you know that it has a tool. that tool actually real time faces the stock prices, okay, given any kinds of company.
So if I let's say send this prompt, you will see that it will use that tool using get stock price tool. Okay, and this is the current uh stock price we are getting of the Apple.
Now I want to perform a sensitive task with this agentic chatbot. Basically, I want to purchase a stock of Apple, okay. I want to let's say purchase 10 stock of Apple.
Now, this task required actually human observation, that means human approval. It's not like that you want um you are giving your agents uh the 100% authority to perform all of the tasks,
it's not like that because there are some sensitive things you have to monitor, okay, manually, and this is this needs actually human approval. So, here let's see if I am asking to my agents purchase
okay, purchase let's say 10 stock
of Apple.
Okay, let's say I'm asking this question, and this is a sensitive task, and for this, you will see that it will ask for human approval. Okay, now if I send this prompt
now, see it is asking for the human approval, human approval required. Approve buying 10 shares of Apple, yes or no.
Do you want to give me the permission?
Um, if you want, I can buy. So for this, you have to provide yes, otherwise, you can reject this particular uh approval.
Okay, so let's see if I am giving yes, I will approach this approve this purchase.
Now we'll see that it will use my purchase stock tool and it will purchase the shares of the Apple. Okay, now if I'm again asking this thing, let's say
purchase 10 stock of
Google.
Now see again it is asking for human approval. Now, right now, let's say if I'm rejecting the purchase, you will see that it will not purchase that.
Okay, your request to purchase 10 shares of Google was declined. Okay, so this is called actually H I T L, that means human in the loop.
basically, if you have already used any kinds of agentic system, guys, okay, you will see that this kinds of functionality they are having, they will ask for human approval.
if you are already using any kinds of code editor, also like
this anti-gravity or cursor AI, okay, there also you will see that whenever you want to generate something, generate some code, or if you want to create any project,
you will it will ask for the human permission, okay. If it required that time, you if you are giving the permission, okay.
At that time, actually, it will perform all of the task otherwise, it will decline that.
Okay, so this functionality guys, uh, we have integrated inside our agentic chatbot, and now this chatbot is super advanced. Okay, now it can do all of the tasks, and you can actually
integrate this HITL not only in this stock uh pri price parses, uh, but also you can integrate uh these things in any kinds of let's say
task you are performing. I'll show you okay how to do that, and you can feel free to add so many tools here, okay. Uh, so many autonomous tool you can add here.
that you want to send automatically email. You can add the emailing tool if you want to check out your Google Drive, okay.
how many files are present and if you want to upload any file, so you can also add these kinds of tools. Okay, I already talked about the tools, and this video is already available over my channel.
You can see that okay, how to add different different tools. So, yes, guys, this is the demo of this HITL human in the loop. Now we'll try to see this human in the loop
what is this human in the loop? Okay, why it is required in a theoretical manner. Then I'm going to show you the practical implementation of that.
So, guys, if you are completely new to my channel and if you haven't subscribed yet, please try to subscribe to my channel.
if you found my content useful, please support me if I get your support, so definitely I will get lots of motivation and I will bring these kinds of content more.
So, please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like and please try to share this with your friends and family as well.
So, guys, first of all, let's try to understand what is this HITL is.
As you can see from the definition itself, HITL that means human in the loop is a design approach in agentic systems where a human actively participates at critical points of the AI workflow,
either to supervise, approve, correct, or guide the model's output. Okay, so this is the concept actually, it's required.
Uh, whenever you are performing any kinds of sensitive task, whenever you are performing any kinds of let's say very critical task, that time this
HITL is required. And if you are creating this kind of agentic system, I think you know that uh why you need to exactly add this HITL feature because inside an agentic
project, actually, there would be multiple kinds of tasks. Let's say uh here uh inside our chatbot we have added different different tasks.
Let's our chatbot can perform internet search operation, it can give you the weather information. Okay, so for these kinds of tasks, actually, I don't need this HITL features, okay.
But let's say I showed you one demo, I need to purchase a stock price.
This is a critical and sensitive task, okay, and definitely needs human approval. Otherwise, if I give the full authority to my AI agents, uh it may actually do something wrong, okay.
Let's say I will tell please purchase 10 shares of Apple.
Okay, so what it can do, it can let's say purchase 20 shares of Apple, okay. it can let's say spend more money okay of me.
So that's why this human in the loop is required in this kinds of critical task. That's how inside an agentic AI project there would be multiple uh like scenario.
Uh you might need to add this HITL. Okay, it's not necessary to add this HILTL to all of your features, all of your tasks.
Okay, or wherever you feel like okay, this is required for me, you can add it there.
Okay, so that's why you can see this HLTL, it's a design approach in AI uh agentic AI system, okay, where a human actively participates at a critical point of the AI workflow.
that means this is your completely your design uh flows of here. Okay, you will be designing this kinds of HITL uh functionality inside your project.
Now you can see think of uh HLTL uh as putting a human checkpoints inside an AI pipeline so that important decisions are not made
autonomously by the model. Okay, that is what I told you.
So whenever you need this kinds of critical task handling, you are not going to give the full authority to your agent, so that time it will not automatically take the decision,
okay.
Uh by your agent, that time you will be available okay in this particular loop, and if you approve that particular task, this will perform, otherwise, this will not perform.
Okay, this is what actually this definition says. Now you can see why HITL exists.
as I already told you, to help agentic system, that means whenever you are creating any kinds of agentic system, so to help the agentic system, you need these kinds of HITL.
For an example, let's say you want to implement an agent that will prepare a post, okay? That will prepare a LinkedIn post and it will post over the LinkedIn platform.
Okay, so here to create the LinkedIn post, it doesn't need any kinds of human approval, but whenever it will post that let's say
on the LinkedIn platform, that time this human approval is required because human will review the entire post.
Uh, if the post is fine, then they will approve this post and this post would be published over the LinkedIn platform.
Okay, so here basically this HITL helping the agentic system okay to perform the complete task.
Okay.
I think you can understand what I am trying to say. Then the second to add the accountability. Accountability means let's say I already told you agentic system can make mistake.
So let's say if you are telling I need to purchase 20 stock of Apple.
Okay, so there is a possibility your agent will uh your agent will uh will try to purchase let's say for uh 40 stock of Apple.
Okay, so there is a problem, right? So before purchasing that stock, first of all, you will try to review that whether the amount you want to purchase it is fine or not,
the price Apple is having for this stock it is fine or not. If everything goes fine, then you will try to give the approval, otherwise, you will try to reject. Okay, so that's why this HITL is exist.
Uh it will help you to help the agentic system and to add the accountability as well. Okay, now we can see HITL ensures accuracy.
Definitely, if you are implementing this HITL inside your agents, there would be uh higher accuracy inside your agentic system.
otherwise, there are some problem. I think I have already explained that okay, what would be the problem?
so if you are adding this one, so definitely accuracy will increase inside your agentic system.
That's why in chat GPT, Google Gemini, whatever agentic system you are using, all of the applications are having these kinds of HITL functionality.
Okay, in Chat GPT, also maybe you have observed it will tell you okay, do I need to perform the uh perform this task or not?
Okay, if you give yes, then it will perform, otherwise, it will not perform.
Okay, then safety definitely safety is required. as I already given you one example, that stock price purchase demo.
So there let's say if I'm not giving these kinds of HITL features that the times that is a possibility, our agents will purchase more
stock which I which I don't need.
Okay, so definitely this is one kinds of safety. Then the next thing is ethical alignment.
Let's say if you are doing a task that have some kinds of ethical alignment, let's say we are preparing a post for the LinkedIn,
and that post should should not have any kinds of let's say sexual content or let's say abusive content.
so that time actually you can have these kinds of ethics, you can basically review that and if you approve that kinds of content,
then your agent agent will basically post that, otherwise, it will not post that. That means if your content is having
these kinds of uh sexual and abusive content, it will reject and if it doesn't have that, that time you will try to approve that. Okay, so this kinds of ethical alignment um uh also ensures this HITL.
Then better user experience. as I already told you, um, if you are adding these kinds of things, so definitely there would be better user experience uh as you already observed inside our app, right?
So it was giving some kinds of uh uh approved uh let's say input, and if you are approving that the task was happening, if you are not approving, the task was not happening, so this is kinds of
better user experience. Okay, you are providing with the help of this HITL. Then some common HITL patterns as you can see, action approval patterns approve, reject before execution.
Uh, as I already told uh showed you one demo, right?
So basically, whenever you want to perform any task and if it needs any kinds of action, so here you can perform with the help of this HITL, you can approve or reject
before the execution, then output review and edit pattern. So maybe you have seen um any kinds of uh uh block generation, let's say agent.
So what it does basically it generates some kinds of output, then it waits for the human review, okay?
Uh human review and edit. So if the review and edit and approve these kinds of output, then it will finalize that, otherwise, it will not finalize that. Then ambiguity clarification pattern.
So sometimes your agent is asking, let's say.
Uh, your your agent is getting confused, Let's say you are asking your agent to schedule a meeting on Friday.
So let's say in this week also you have the Friday, and next week also you have the Friday. So that time your agent needs a clarification.
Now, which Friday it needs to schedule the meeting. So again, it will ask you. actually, I'm a little bit confused which Friday you are um like talking about this Friday or the next Friday.
So this is called ambiguity clarification pattern, then escalation pattern.
Let's say sometimes what happens in some kinds of chatbot, so it talks with the customer, and when it feels like okay, it cannot handle this kinds of scenario,
it will redirect to the actual actually um
actual owner of that company, and they will basically handle this kinds of scenario. Okay, this is called escalation pattern, and that can be also implemented with the help of this HITL.
Okay, so yes, this is the entire idea of this HITL.
I think you have understood. Now uh we'll try to see how this HITL works, okay.
Uh, in a practical way. First of all, I will uh I will show you this uh diagram-wise uh how this HITL will work. So for this, here I have taken an example. So here I have taken a basic workflow, guys.
As you can see, this workflow you can consider this is a post generation workflow. Let's say you can generate any kinds of LinkedIn post. So you can see it has the start node.
First of all, user will pass a topic, and if submits the topic, it will go to the your line graph workflow, okay, and it will execute the start node,
then it will perform the research operation of that particular topic, and once it found the content, it will prepare the content and here it will
post that particular content over the LinkedIn. But here we'll try to add this HITL feature, okay?
Because before posting that, definitely it needs the human approval, it will ask me whether I have to post or not.
Okay, so if I review that, if I approve that, then it will post, otherwise, it will not post. Then this workflow is getting ended. So let's try to understand this HITL um with this particular example.
So, see what is happening. Let's say you are passing a topic name here. Let's see what topic uh you are passing a topic name of machine learning, let's say ml.
Let me take this color, let's see what giving ML topic. Okay, so this ML topic you are submitting here and it will go to your uh Lang Graph workflow.
So this is the Langgraph workflow we have created, let's say. So, first of all, here it will prepare a state. I think you know that we have to prepare a state, right?
And here, what would be the state? State would be the topic and as well as the draft that means draft post it is generating.
Okay, so it will uh first of all uh invoke this uh uh workflow and it will go to the research node, and research node will perform the research operation, it will try to find ML related uh
let's uh let's say information and it will prepare a post. Okay, once post is prepared, then here we'll try to add this HITL feature, okay. HITL feature, human in the loop features.
Okay, now how human in the loop feature works. Let me give you as a high-level uh like uh high-level idea.
Uh definitely we'll try to see in practical manner how to write in the code, but I will give you this one high-level code diagram how it will work.
Okay, so see whenever you are implementing this HITL inside any kinds of node, right?
Uh, that time you will be using one function called interrupt. Okay, this is already available inside Langgraph. Uh inside Langgraph, actually, this HITL implementation is super easy.
So there is a function called in interrupt, okay.
Interrupt
interrupt function.
Okay, so once you will use this interrupt function, this execution will pause here. Okay, this execution will pause here, unless and until you are not giving any kinds of input.
So let's say here I will take a variable called decision.
Decision is equal to
okay.
Interact. Now here user will pass something. Let's say if user pass this decision,
decision is equal to is equal to yes, that time post will happen.
Okay.
Else
it will resist.
Okay, so this is the high level code diagram. You can understand that's how actually Langgraph will work.
Okay, so here we'll try to use uh one function called interrupt, and this function will basically pause the execution unless and until human not give human is not giving any kinds of input.
Okay, now you can uh define your input like what kinds of input you need from the user. This kinds of functionality also you can add here, okay.
Then after getting the input, you can uh execute your workflow.
And one more thing which is very important whenever you are implementing this HITL, you have to add the checkpointer, okay. You have to add the persistence memory.
Uh, we we have already seen the persistence memory, okay. persistent memory basically saves all of your state, right?
Inside a memory, whether you can use any uh in-memory saver, that means you need in your RAM or any kinds of permanent database, you have to use that
because whenever it will perform the pause operation, right?
let's say here it is performing the pause operation. So to execute it again, let's say whenever user is giving the input, okay. After getting the input, this will execute, right?
So whenever it will execute, it's not like that, it will execute from the beginning, it will execute why it has paused that particular execution and how it will understand by seeing the state because
state is saving all of the information and while it is getting loaded, it is getting loaded in the database, okay, in the persistent memory,
and from the persistent memory it will load that and it will see that okay. I stopped in the post uh nodes, and now I have to continue from the post node instead of continuing from the beginning.
Okay, that's why the checkpointer you have to define this state uh persistence memory you have to define whenever you are implementing this HITL concept inside
Lang Graph.
Okay, line Graph, it is super important.
Okay, I hope you clear, guys. So that's how this uh HITL will uh HITL will work um in practical, and uh you can implement this HITL in any kinds of node, okay.
Any kinds of node or any kinds of tool you are using, you can define that. We'll try to see that.
And one more thing, whenever you are giving this input, right?
let's say this interrupt is waiting for the human input, and whatever input you are passing, let's say here you are passing this yes input. Okay, so this yes input will consider as a command, okay.
It will consider as a command.
so this command actually will go to the again your let's say node, that means your chat node, and if
your chat node is getting this yes command, that time it actually it will it will feel like okay, now user wants to post that, okay. Then your posting will be happening.
Okay, so that that means this command is required,
a command keyword is required whenever you are using this interrupt function, and whatever let's say user input you are getting, you have to store in the command.
Okay, now this thing I will also show you in the code.
I think by seeing the code, I think this concept would be more clear in your mind, right?
But before the code implementation, I have given you high-level overview so that whenever I will explain the code, you won't be having any kinds of confusion.
Now, guys, we'll try to implement this HITL with the help of Langgraph. Uh for this, actually, first of all, we'll try to see a simple example.
I think you remember the Agentic chatbot we are creating so far. from the very beginning, I have taken this simple workflow. Okay, so this workflow has one node which is chat node.
So if you basically give a input, it will generate the output of that given input and you will be able to see the output of that. Okay, so here uh what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to add a simple
Uh simple actually example of this HITL. So basically, here whatever input is coming right in this particular node. So here we'll just try to add a HITL feature. Okay, HITL feature.
So here we'll try to first of all uh ask the user, do you want to really ask the question?
Okay, do you want to really ask the questions to the model? If user sends yes, okay, I want to perform, then the answer would be generated, otherwise, answer won't be generated.
Okay, it it looks like very funny, but just to make you understand, actually, I have taken this example.
First of all, let's try to see the HITL implementation with this very simple example, then I'm going to show you with the advanced example as well.
Uh, we'll uh we'll use our agent TKI code, the code we have implemented so far, and we'll try to integrate these things, okay.
There, but before that, I want to show you the implementation part, how it can be done. That's why this example I'll be taking.
Okay, so I think you have understood what I want to do.
So, whatever question is coming, first of all, here uh we'll just try to add a HITL feature. Uh it will ask for the human review. Do you want to really ask the question?
If user gives yes, then um this question would be uh going to the chat node and user will be able to see the output, otherwise, user won't be able to see the output.
Okay, this is the implementation we'll try to do.
Now, for this, here I already prepared a notebook. So inside notebooks folder, I already kept uh kept a notebook as you can see HITL demo.
Let's open it up, okay? So I think this code is pretty much common. I have taken the same uh this this example. I think you know that I created a simple chat workflow.
Okay, I copy pasted the same code and I added this HITL functionality there. Okay, so first of all, here we are importing all the necessary library as you can see here. We have taken both model.
If you don't have open AI you can use Gemini model for this.
We are using this this library and uh some other library we are also importing, and we are also importing the checkpointer because I already told you if you are implementing this HITL,
you need this uh persistence memory. Okay, then uh one new import I have done, which is this from Langar of types. I have imported interrupt function and command, okay?
Because I already told you uh here uh if you want to add any kinds of HTL uh HITL functionality, you need this interrupt function, okay. So this should be interrupt. Sorry, there should be a T
okay interrupt function. So this interrupt function is required.
So with the help of this interrupt, you will try to pause the execution and you will take the input from the user, and this input will basically become your command.
Okay, so you can see this command is also required. Then load ENV, type dict, annotated, and the base message. So let's input all of the necessary library
and make sure inside your environment variable all of the key are present, okay?
Whatever key you are using so far. Now let's load the environment variable, and after that, here I don't have open AIP key, that's why I'll be using Gemini model.
And for this, I already collected my Google API key. Let's initialize my model, and here we are preparing the state, guys.
As you can see, this is our state, the same state we are using, and here you can see in this chat node we have added this interrupt functionality that means HITL functionality, okay.
That means here, okay. Here we have added this HITL functionality. So if you want to add the HITL functionality, you have to use this interrupt function. I already told you.
You can see inside chat node. See, this is what this was our previous chat node, right? Now, this is the update I have done.
So here I have I'm using this interrupt function, and in this interrupt function, you have to give some like uh uh metadata.
That means the first metadata you have to give the type, so type should be approval. Reason model is about to answer a question, okay. Then question, whatever question user is asking.
This question you have to pass in the question section and the instruction, okay.
Approve this question, yes or no. That means this instruction user will be able to see, okay. Once you will execute the node, this this message actually would be visible to the user.
Do you want to approve this question? Yes or no?
Okay, if user pass yes, then this question would be going to the chat node and user will be able to see the output.
And if he sends, let's say no, and that time it will be rejected. Now, here we are checking, you can see decision.
Okay, decision, and here we'll try to expect a parameter, expect a key called approved.
Okay, so if this approve is is equal to is equal to no, let's see if user has given no, that time I'll simply return the uh messes.
Okay, that should be the AI messes, no approved, okay, not approved.
if user gives yes, that means I'll simply invoke my large language model, I'll pass the masses and user will be able to see the output.
So this is the simple things you have to add, and the main thing here the interrupt as well as the command, okay.
Command functionality I'll show you the command where to add, but here we are basically using the interrupt to pause the execution here, okay.
And from the front end size, that means from the front end side, that means from the user side, we'll get this approved, okay. Approved key.
I'll show you this part now. Let's execute this node. Now, here we are building the entire graph, guys. You can see we're taking the graph, we are adding the node, we have only have one node.
we are doing the edge connection and we are preparing the check pointer.
So, here just to show I am using this in-memory server check pointer, and we are building the entire graph, okay, and we're passing the checkpointer, and that's how your workflow looks like.
Okay, so this is the same workflow now. To execute the workflow, guys, you need this config, you need this thread. I think you remember if you are using persistence memory, you need this thread.
So here I created a dummy thread and we are initializing an input, explain the gradient descent in a very simple terms. Okay, this is let's say our user input.
So this input will uh invoke with this workflow we have created, and the workflow object is app.
So you can see we're invoking this input and we're passing the configuration.
Now let's execute.
Now, see, guys, here you will get one result.
this is the result, okay.
you can see this is the result you are getting. So here you can see this is the human message.
Explain the gradient descent in a very simple term, and whenever it is going to the chat node, there we added that HITL.
Okay, that means here the interruption is happening, it is pausing the execution. Okay, you can see you cannot see any kinds of output.
Okay, the model output you cannot see unless and until you are not providing any kinds of input. Now, if you want to provide the input, so first of all, let me show you the interrupt message.
So, this is the interrupt message you can see, and this is the introduction uh instruction approve this question, yes or no, and some other metadata we have provided. This is also coming here, okay.
Now, what I'll do, guys, I'll take the user input. So here I am preparing the user input. I am showing the same message to the user, and here I am taking yes or no from the user.
Okay, so let's say this is my user input. So now user is giving let's say yes, okay.
Uh uh, let's say user wants to see the message.
that means the output. Now, if I give yes, now inside user input, what will be present?
Yes, okay, it will present yes. Now, how this present how this input we have to return to the HITL as a command, okay.
Now right now you can see we are again invoking this workflow, but right now inside invoke functionality we are giving this command keyword.
Okay, we are giving this command keyword inside that we're telling resume is equal to approved.
So you have to pass a dictionary.
You can see we're giving approved and user input. Okay, so that means approved should be user input.
So that's why here I've written this condition.
Uh, where is that? Yeah, if decision approved, because it is uh this approved uh key is getting created newly, right?
If approved is equal to is equal to no, that means it will reject, otherwise, it will approve that. So that is what actually we are doing here,
okay. that is what we are doing here.
Then we are again passing the configuration and we are again invoking our workflow.
Okay, now one error I'm getting.
Okay, so guys, we are getting this error because inside our env we haven't set our environment variable yet, okay.
so let's try to set all of my environment variable, all of the key.
So this is my updated key I have
added here.
Now let me save and let me re-execute this notebook. Okay, so again, what I will do, I'll just try to execute from the beginning.
So let me restart.
Now let's execute all of this code.
Now interrupt interrupt message we are getting. Now we're taking the user. Let's say user is passing yes.
Now we'll try to invoke this workflow again.
Now see this execution is complete. Now we'll see the final message, You can see this is the final message we are getting about the gradient descent.
But let's say if user is giving no, that time what will happen?
Let's say again I will execute this uh code.
User is giving no.
Okay, I have to re-execute from beginning because
here I have running as a cell by cell, right? That's why
now I'll give no
now. If I execute my final
uh final result, now you'll see the output.
Now you can see not approved because user has given no.
Okay, so that's how guys you can add these HITL uh features inside any of your node.
Okay, it's not necessary to add inside your node always. You can also add this inside the tools, okay. This part I will also show you uh after this demo.
Okay, so yes, guys, this is how how we can um add this HITL, and we have seen this simple demo.
Now let's try to see the advanced example uh with our agentic chatbot we have created so far, and this is the uh this is the actually workflow we have created, and you remember
uh because uh inside a workflow we are using some kinds of tools, right?
And uh, this is our workflow, final workflow.
And this code we have already written, as you can see. This is the code we have written in my previous video. If you haven't checked that, please try to go through the recording.
So, here actually, I added the rag functionality and we added uh lots of tool here previously, right?
You can see we have added lots of tool.
now, guys. First of all, uh I want to show you uh this
uh agency chatbot execution without using HITL. Okay, let's say if I'm not using HITL, uh what will happen that time?
Let's try to see an example.
So here I'm going to create a file, I'm going to name it as chatbot
chatbot without
human in the loop. Okay, so after seeing that, we'll try to add the HITL and we'll see the benefit of that. Okay, so chatbot without HITL.
So what I'll do, so the code I have written, the previous code that means the rag backend, I think you have seen my previous video.
I'll copy this entire code as it is, and here I'm going to paste it.
Okay. So here I'm not going to change anything, only the things I have to add,
a new tool here.
Okay.
So here I'm going to add a new tool.
So I think you remember, in this particular in this particular chatbot, the sensitive the sensitive part is the
stock price. Okay, let's consider the stock price.
So here we are getting the stock price, right? Given any kinds of company.
So here we'll try to add a new tool.
So that tool will basically purchase the stock for me.
So here I have written a simple dummy, let's say, uh tool. So it will it will only do the print statement, that is written statement.
But in actual chatbot, definitely here you have to use some kinds of API. That API will connect the Apple, let's say stock company, and it will purchase the stock for you.
But just to show you, here I have taken a dummy function. So this function, what it does, it takes the symbol as well as the quantity, like how much quantity you want to
purchase and which company you want to purchase, and based on that, it will give you some kinds of success statement. Let's say you have successfully purchased this stock, okay?
So this thing I have converted as a tool, and I named it as a person stock, okay. Perse stock tool. Now, what I have to do,
I have added a new tool, and this tool I have to add inside my tool list.
So I'll go below,
and here I have to add this tool.
The tool name is Perse Stock.
Okay, then we are binding this tool, everything will remain common, no need to change anything.
Just a minute, let me check.
So everything is fine.
We have added this in the list now.
I will go below to list.
this is my checkpointer. We are using SQLite database and we are creating the entire graph.
And this is our helper function, it's completely fine. But here at the last, I will add a
simple
Okay, this is my simple CLI code. Basically, I want to execute this file okay in my terminal. Okay, that's why I have added this code.
First of all, I am printing some message. That means this is agentic uh chatbot CLI, and here I have taken a demo trade, okay.
Because if you know that if I want to because you know that if I want to execute my chatbot workflow, I need this trade, so that's why I created a demo trade, and here I'm running a while loop.
Okay, in this while loop, I'm taking the user user input from the user, and if user is giving let's say exit or quite, I'm telling goodbye and breaking the loop.
Otherwise, I'm taking the user input, okay, and preparing inside my state, then we are invoking our chatbot, okay.
We are passing the trade ID, then whatever response we are getting, we are just printing in the terminal. So this is a simple CLI code I have written, okay, just to execute my entire workflow.
Now let me show you how this thing will work.
So I will open up my terminal and I will execute this file chatbot without HITL.
I'll just write Python chatbot
without
HITL. Okay, now see if I execute
now.
See, it is uh
asking for the input. Let's say here I will give hello.
It's giving hello. How I can help you today.
I will ask what is the
stock price
of
apple.
Now it will use that get stock price tool and it will extract the
stock price of the apple. Now see the stock price of apple is uh okay, that much. Now I will tell
okay, purchase
10 stock
of
Apple.
Okay, now see if I
if I send this prompt,
it will directly purchase the stock, it will use that tool, right? like a purchase stock tool, and it will purchase the stock, and here you can see the message.
I have successfully placed the order to purchase 10 stock of Apple. Now see here, it is not asking any kinds of user input, right?
Although this is a sensitive task we are performing, but it is not asking any kinds of input. So there is a possibility it may do some mistake, right?
Instead of purchasing 10 stock, maybe it can purchase 20 stock, right?
Let's say instead of purchasing
stock in Apple, it will purchase the stock in Google.
Okay, so this kinds of mistake my agent can perform. I think you know this is completely large language model and it can perform any kinds of wrong, uh wrong task, it can do hallucination.
I think you know that, right? It's not always perfect.
So here definitely I need a human approval here, okay. If I want to perform this kinds of sensitive and critical task,
so this is the execution you have seen without HITL, and this is the problem here, okay.
Right now, I'm going to show you if I add this HITL with this chatbot, what will happen right now? Let's try to see. So I will exit this terminal.
Now, here I'm going to create another file
and I'm going to name it as chatbot
chatbot with
HITL.
Okay, and here what I'm going to do, I'm going to
I'm going to copy paste the same code
okay from my previous file and I'm going to paste it here. And the modification I will do here in this particular tool.
Okay, in this particular tool,
this
stock price tool. Okay, yeah. So here I'll do the modification.
Why here I will do the modification because in this tool only I need the human approval, okay. Whenever user is asking to purchase a stock, right?
That time here only I need to perform the interrupt operation, and whenever user is giving, okay, you just need to purchase it.
User is giving yes, uh yes command. That time this tool will execute, otherwise, this will not execute. Okay, it will not purchase the stock for me.
So for this, I'll do a simple modification.
Um, see, instead of this this function, I have modified with this function.
Now just try to see, okay. And most of the code, I think this is common to you because I already explained previously, okay, in that simple demo. Right here, I'm using interrupt function,
and here I just
done a check statement here.
Okay, now I have to import this interrupt function as com and command function.
So let's import it as well.
I'll import it here from Langraph Types. I'm importing interrupt and comment.
Now we'll go to my tool again.
So this is the tool, okay?
Yeah,
so see here I'm not adding this HITL inside my chat node, okay. Here I don't need to add inside my chat node because here I'm using a tool, lots of tool okay.
And inside only get sorry, purchase stock price.
In that tool, only I need this HITL functionality.
Okay, always remember whenever you are using tools and you are creating these kinds of advanced chat advanced HMTKI application, right?
In chat node, you don't need to add it, you will be adding inside the tool.
That means with the tool, you are performing some kinds of tasks, you are performing some kinds of action, and there this HITL should be integrated, okay.
Not in chat node, but in my previous example, the simple example I have given you, just to show you, I added the HITL in my chat node.
Okay, I hope you clear.
Now, inside tools only, I will add this functionality.
So this is the code for that.
I'll close some of the window
chat with HITL. Okay, now this is the
uh this is the tool, guys. I have written.
this is the update I have done. So here uh, whenever it will use this use this tool, that means my agent will use this tool.
That time you will it will see the interrupt function here and it will pause the execution here, okay?
And user will able to see one message approve buying.
that means what how much how much quantity user will provide. Let's say user is provide 10 10 stock.
Okay, I want to purchase 10 stock of Apple. So this 10 will come here.
So 10 shares of symbol means the company, okay.
That's I'm giving Apple. So Apple will come here.
So do you want to purchase it? Yes or no?
Okay, user will see this message.
okay.
In interrupt, only you can directly show the message.
Then once user will pass this yes and no, it will store inside the decision, okay?
And right now I'm not storing inside as a dictionary, but previously, the previous example I showed you, right, in the notebook.
In the notebook, here I was storing as a dictionary.
Okay, that's why I was checking the condition like that because here I was passing as a dictionary.
Okay, I was passing as a dictionary, but right now, here I'm taking as a simple string. Okay, yes and no.
So here I'm checking if this decision is a string and I'm doing the lower operation. If it is yes, then I'm returning this statement.
Starter should be success message purchased, order placed for quantity shares of symbol.
Okay, symbol should be symbol and what it should be quantity. That means here I'm giving a success message. Your order has been placed, okay. Or let's say you have successfully purchased the stock.
Otherwise, if user is giving no, okay, in the else block, you can see purchase of shares of the symbol was declined by the human.
Okay, and strategies cancel right now.
Okay, so this kinds of statement we have written inside our tool, okay.
And this thing you have to follow if you want to implement this HITL in any kinds of tool or any kinds of task you are implementing going forward, okay.
Now I want to give you a task instead of purchase talk, maybe you can add another tool that will perform some kinds of sensitive and critical task.
Okay, and in that task, you just need to add this HITL functionality.
Okay, this should be your task after this implementation.
Just try to make this Agentic chatbot more advanced.
you can add some more advanced tasks which needs human approval, and you can add this functionality here, okay.
Now, this this is the update I have done.
Now the next update you have to do.
Next update.
If I go below,
already this tool is added inside the tool. I don't need to add now. Your chat node will also remain same, no need to add anything.
Uh only
this CLI CLI code you have to change. Okay, right now uh user is giving the
user is giving the interruption message that means the command.
So this thing you have to add take from the user.
So here
this is the CLI code I have written.
Because this this CLI doesn't have any
HITL input, right? Now this has the HITL input. So again, the same loop I have written print statement demo trade while loop, I'm taking the user input.
If user is giving exit and quite, I'm like just breaking the loop.
Then uh I'm preparing my state, okay, with the help of user input.
Then I'm invoking my
workflow, okay, and I'm passing my trade.
Now we'll check this uh interrupt.
Let's say whenever you are invoking the workflow and user is given, let's say hello, that time just let me know whether this interrupt interrupt uh interrupt will happen or not.
Definitely there won't be any kinds of interrupt when interrupt will happen. Whenever you will ask purchase 10 stock or let's say purchase any stock of any company, right?
That time that tool would be executed again, okay.
that means our purchase tool would be executed, and whenever that tool will be executed, that time this interruption, okay, you will get the interruption.
That means you will get something in the interruption variable, okay. Otherwise, you will not get anything in the interruption variable.
That's why we're checking if interruption variable has something, that means if interruption happens, definitely some message you will get okay in the interrupt
interrupt variable. If you got the masses, that time you will feel like okay, there right now there is interruption has happened inside my code, then he will ask the human.
Okay, so what is the interruption? Okay, you will show this prompt.
You can see I'm showing this prompt as a HITL message, okay.
Whether he uh he has to approve or didn't uh this uh uh approved or not.
So this thing I will take inside my decision.
I'm taking the input from the user, your decision, okay. I'm just making it as a lower, then whatever decision user is giving, I'm again re-invoking my chat bot, okay.
And right now I'm giving the command and we are giving this resume parameter is equal to our decision, okay, which we are giving as a command.
Then we are passing the configuration again, and whatever result we are getting, we are showing the masses and we are also printing in the terminal. So this is a simple code I have written.
Now let me show you the execution.
So again, I will open up my terminal, and right now I will execute this
chatbot with
HITL.
Now see,
here I will give hello.
Hello, how I can help you today, Now I will tell what is the
stock
of
stock price of apple.
Now, see this is the stock price of the Apple as you can see.
Now I'll tell purchase
okay, 20 stock
Okay, purchase uh 20 stock of Apple. Now it will use that purchase tool, right?
And there would be interruption that will basically happen the interruption that means HITL will apply in that particular tool and it will ask for the human input.
See now HITL has been triggered and it is asking for the human improved uh improved approve buying 20 shares of Apple.
Do you want to approve yes or no?
So here I will tell yes, I want to purchase it.
Now if I execute this code, you'll see that I have successfully purchased an order to purchase 20 shares of Apple. That means
this tool has been executed and this tool has purchased the shares for you, okay.
Of the Apple. Now, again, if I let's re-execute this code, let's say
purchase,
let's say purchase
20 stock of Google.
Now again it is asking for the human approval.
Approve buying 20 shares of Google, yes or no. Now, if I let's say give no, now it will decline.
Okay, declined. So you can see I'm sorry, your request which purchased 20 shares of Google was declined because you given no.
Okay, right now just tell me which one is better, okay, for this kinds of sensitive tasks, this kinds of critical task without HITL or with HITL.
Definitely with HITL, it is more accurate and more secured, okay. Secured version of our Agentic chatbot.
Okay, now guys, I think you have got it.
How to integrate this HITL inside our Agentic chatbot?
Okay, now guys, let's try to add this functionality inside our user interface. So, what I have done, guys, I just copy pasted the same code, okay.
I just copy pasted the same code and I given to the chat GPT and I asked, I just need to add this HITL uh
uh HITL functionality on my user interface, and chat GPT has given me one updated code. Let me show you.
Only you just need to update inside your front end. So maybe
I will create a separate file of the front end.
Let's say I will tell it as app
underscore hitl okay.
And this is the updated code I got from the chat GPT guys. Again, if you don't know about the front end design, no need to worry.
There are some front end developers in your uh would be in your company, so they will handle this kinds of scenario.
Okay, but uh again, if you don't know, you can take the help from chat GPT and this is the updated version of our front end. Okay, this has the HITL that means approval user interface.
Okay, that means the first time I showed you a demo, right? It was asking for a human approval, yes or no button, so it has added that particular functionality here, okay.
Otherwise, my backend code will remain same.
There won't be any kinds of changes.
So, what I will do again, I'll create another file here. Let's say
I'll copy the name
and I'll create a new file. I'm going to name it as agentic chatbot hitl backend. H it l backend, okay.
Backend.py, sorry,
backend.py okay, and whatever code I have written inside chatbot with HITL, I'll just try to copy paste as it is.
Okay, so here from here I just need to copy chatbot with HITL. I'll just try to copy the same code and I'll paste inside my agentic chatbot hitl backend.py.
Okay, and no need to change anything, only you just need to remove this line.
Okay, this CLI is not required.
I'll just remove that code and everything will
remain as it is.
Now here in this app HITL, you just need to change this import, okay?
So now the import is agentic chatbot HITL backend. So agentic
chatbot HITL backend. Okay, so from here we are importing all the functionality and this is the updated code.
Now let me execute and show you this execution.
So here I'll stop the execution clear and I will run streamlit
run
app
HITL.
Okay
now this is your interface, okay. The same interface I think you saw.
Now here you can perform any kinds of chat operation.
Tell me the
latest
news
In AI.
You will see that it will use some kinds of search tool.
So see, it is using tabily search tool and it will give you the uh latest news in AI.
You can see uh this is the latest new uh news I got, and this is the news of Andropix. Okay, the latest news. Now here I will ask
I will try to check my HITL code HITL functionality.
So here I will tell
latest, or let's say, what is the stock
price of
It is using my get stock price, and it is giving you the latest stock price of Apple.
Now it tells purchase,
purchase, let's say 20 stock
of Apple;
now we'll see that it will ask for the human verification. Now see human approval is required, and this is the user interface we have added with the help of charge GPT.
Now if I approve this purchase, now you see it will use purchase tool and it will purchase that uh that shares for me.
You can see your order to purchase 20 shares of Apple has been replaced successfully.
Okay, now if I let's say give another one,
uh purchase 20 stock of let's say Google.
Now again it will ask for the human verification.
Okay, now if I reject this purchase,
now see it will tell your request to purchase 20 shares of Google was declined.
Okay, so that's how this system is working right now, and we have successfully added this HITL functionality inside our Agentic chatbot.
And you can also see the live tracing on the Langsmith platform.
You can go to the trades
and you can open up your trades and you can see all of the execution.
Okay, now you can see guys, it hit your HITL functionality.
This is also available here, okay. You can see that. So, guys, our Agentic chatbot is ready and we have added all of the functionality okay.
We have discussed previously in my introduction video in my um theoretical video.
Okay, I think remember if you are following this playlist from the beginning, I think you know that we have already explained about all of the core component of agentic application.
We have added all of this core component inside our agentic application, and now this is like more advanced.
Now, the only part is left, the deployment part.
in my next video, guys, I'm going to show you how we can deploy this agentic chatbot okay over the cloud platform.
And I'm not going to show you the simple deployment, I'm going to show you the CI CD deployment. Okay, that means continuous integration and continuous delivery.
So there I will try to set up the entire CI CD pipeline and we'll try to deploy this project over the AWS cloud. Okay, I'm going to show you another deployment on the render cloud.
Render is another cloud, and there you can also do the deployment. Uh, first of all, I'm going to show the AWS deployment, then I'm going to show the render deployment as well.
Okay. That means right now this uh bot is running on my local host. This agentic chat bot is running on my local host, and it cannot access um by any kinds of people, right?
You can only execute this bot. But let's see if you want to make it live, right? if you want to make make it live to the entire world, that time you have to deploy this application.
So, this uh uh deployment part I'm going to show you in my next video, guys. So, yes, guys, this is all about and I hope you liked my content, guys.
If you like my content, please try to subscribe to my channel and hit the like and please try to comment in the comment section if you have any question.
in this video, I'm going to show you the final deployment of that identic chatbot.
So, guys, as I already told you, here we'll be doing something called CI CD deployment, right?
And I already told you what is uh CI CD full form, it's continuous integration, continuous delivery, or deployment, right?
since it continuous integration, continuous delivery, what happens? Let's say you are the developer.
Okay, let's say you are the developer.
So, what is your task? Your task is to develop a project in the development, let's say, environment.
So, development environment means like your local system. Let's say you are using your laptop or computer, that's a local computer,
okay. Local
computer.
Fine.
Then what we are doing, I think you remember, we are committing this code to the GitHub, right? We are doing the code management.
I think you remember that means that means whenever I was adding some new feature, I was pushing this code to the GitHub.
Yes or no?
Okay, with the help of Git client, we are pushing the code in the GitHub, GitHub server.
Now, what happens actually? Let's say after deployment, so this is called actually development server, and I can write this actually development environment.
Okay, development environment. So after implementing this project, what we have to do?
We have to deploy this project, yes or no?
Let's say somehow you have deployed this project on the AWS cloud. Let's say this is your AWS cloud.
Fine.
So let's say you have deployed this project to the AWS cloud
manually. Manually, you just created a let's say instance there. You create you just took a machine in there, a kc2 machine, and you manually deployed this project. Now it will give you some endpoint.
Okay, endpoint.
So with the help of this endpoint, any of the user
okay, user can access your application.
Now let's say after four months or let's say six months, you want to add some more features in this let's say uh application. Let's say you are deploying medical chatbot.
Let's say you want to add some more data, you want to add some more knowledge base, and you want to add some more features in this application.
Then what you have to do, you have to again develop this let's say features in your code.
Then what you will be doing again, you will be deploying this application to the AWS cloud.
Now just try to see whenever you are deploying the project for the second time, let's say this is the first time you have deployed, then you are trying to deploy for the second time.
Then what you have to do? First of all, you have to stop this application in the AWS.
Okay, stop this application, then you will be uploading your updated code, then this code will reflect to the endpoint, then user will be able to access that.
Now, let's say in between, whenever you stop this AWS server, let's say your
application, let's say it took three hours, it took three hours to change the entire source code, that means change the entire features okay of your application. So, what will happen?
Three hours user won't be able to access your application.
So they will come your website and they will see server error, okay. Server error actually they will get.
So if user is getting this kinds of experience, so definitely it would be a negative, let's say, effect okay, on your application.
So next time, actually, they are not going to use your application, yes or no?
Let's say if chat GPT is down for the uh let's say three hours, definitely people will move to the Google but or any other let's say uh software,
whatever actually we are having.
Okay, so now see chat GPT is also updating their let's say application day by day.
But did you ever observe this server is down? No, you are not seeing this server is down, but still they're able to make the changes in their application. How?
Because they are following something called CI C D approach, continuous integration, continuous delivery.
That means this application is keep on running, but in the back end, they're pushing their source code, they're pushing their let's say new features, and this feature is automatically getting updated.
Okay, so this is collected CI C D. That means you are not going to deploy this application manual. Instead of that, what you have to do? You have to follow the CI C D. That means what will happen?
Let's say you have changed something in your code, you will push the code to the GitHub. Okay, GitHub will automatically up uh let's say deploy your code to the AWS cloud,
it will automatically push your code to the AWS cloud and your endpoint would be automatically updated.
Okay, automatically updated so that if user is using your application, okay, they won't be filling any kinds of let's say server down issue.
Okay, server down issue, actually, they won't be filling.
Got it. So, this is what actually uh we have to do. That means we'll be creating the entire pipeline, entire let's say CICD pipeline.
So we'll be just pushing the code in our GitHub, and GitHub will automatically trigger this action, and my code will update it to the AWS cloud, and AWS will update the endpoint.
Okay, now see the automated process will be doing now. Whenever we will let's say push our code to the GitHub, GitHub will automatically trigger how it will trigger for this.
You have to use some CI C D tool, okay. CI CD tool,
CI C D automation tool. So here there are different kinds of CICD tool.
So the first tool you can use something called GitHub Action.
Okay, GitHub Action you can use, then you can use something called Jenkins,
okay. Jenkins, then you can use something called circle CI.
Circle CI.
So these actually three famous tool actually we are having in the market right now.
So people are using more this GitHub action because GitHub Action, you don't need to set up anything, it is already set up everything in the GitHub.
But if you're using Jenkins and Circle CI, you have to set up this server manually.
Okay, so here we'll be using GitHub Action because it is already inbuilt with the GitHub, we don't need to set up anything.
Going forward, I will also show you how we can let's say use Jenkins Circle CI, these are the services as well. Fine. So yes guys, this is the complete high level architecture of our deployment.
So, guys, here you can see this is our application code, and we have written actually so many files.
But if you see the final files here, which is this app HITL and this uh agentic chatbot HITL backend, okay, because this was our last
uh last update we have done, right?
So instead of like uh deploying all of these file guys, what I'm going to do, I'm only going to copy the final file, okay.
The final code, and I'm going to create a new uh folder, and inside that I'm going to keep these are the code, okay. Uh, just to explain you all the concept, guys.
I have kept all of my previous code, and this is not required actually to run my final project.
So my final project is right now this app um app hitl. Let me show you.
So let's say if I execute this one
streamlit
run
app
hitl okay.py.
Now we'll see that my agentic chatbot application will be opening.
So, guys, as you can see, this is our application we have implemented so far.
So, here uh what I'm going to do uh instead of moving all of this file, I'm only going to take my final file, which is this uh front
end app HITL and my backend, which is agentic chatbot HITL backend. Okay, apart from that, I need this requirement.txt file.
Uh yeah, so I think if I have these are the file, then I will be able to run my final application. And I also need this .env file because inside that you have all of the credential.
So, what I can do, I can maybe create a new folder here and uh let's create this folder.
or I'll just create a GitHub repository, okay?
Because here we have to do the CICD deployment, and for this, first of all, uh you have to create a GitHub repo and you have to uh push all of your code okay in that particular repository.
So, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to open up my GitHub.
So, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to create a new repository.
Let's name it as uh Agentic
chatbot.
Okay, Agentic chatbot using Langgraph.
Okay.
Now uh what I'm going to do, I'm going to simply
add a readme file.
Then I'm going to take this git ignore.
Here I'm using Python programming. Let's like the Python.
Uh, you can also take any kinds of license. Let's take this Apache license. You can also take any other license, is completely fine.
Now let's create the repository.
Okay, once a repo is created, click on this code and copy this link address and open up your local folder, and inside that open up your terminal.
Okay, you can also open up your git bash, it's completely fine. Now here simply write git clone
and paste your URL. You have copied from the GitHub and clone this repository here.
Okay, now you can see I have successfully cloned this repository. So now what I'm going to do, I'm going to simply redirect this folder.
So C D
Agentic
chatbot using line graph. Okay, now I'm inside this particular folder.
If I show you, see, I'm inside this particular folder right now. Now here I have to move my code file. Okay, my final code file. So what is my final code file?
I'll take this app HITL, then this Agentic chatbot HITL backend as well as this dot ENV
file, and I need this requirement.txt, okay.
Yeah, I think these are the file I need only.
Now I'll copy this and I'll try to paste inside this new folder I have created. Okay.
Now if I open up with my
Visual Code Studio, let me open up.
So this is my okay, this is my old code. Now I'll try to open it with my Visual Code Studio.
Yeah, so you can see guys, this is my uh final code, okay. I have copied from my previous code.
Yeah, this is my final version of the code. Now, uh, what I can do, I can maybe rename these are the file, instead of keeping this file name like that. I can rename it.
So, first of all, let's try to change this backend file name.
So, here
let's rename it.
So, here I'm only going to name this file as backend.py,
okay? backend.py.
And this app hitl, I'm going to name it as
only app.py,
okay?
app.py.
Now make sure uh whenever you uh you have renamed this file, you also need to uh change the import, okay?
So it has automatically changed because I'm using one extension.
That extension automatically will uh like uh trigger uh whenever I'm changing any kinds of file name, it will automatically change that uh input in my other file as well.
Now you can see I'm importing all uh everything and it's coming one
warning because I have to select my original environment, which is Langgraph test. Okay, this environment now. I think everything is fine, okay.
Now here uh what I have to do, guys. I have to
uh I have to
let me check again.
Ha, so everything is fine. Let me show you whether it's working or not. So what I can do, I can
stop my previous execution and
let's open up my new terminal.
Now I'll execute this app subconda
env
list.
So, this is the name of the involvement. I'll copy,
and I'll just write "conda activate
my involvement
". Now, after that, let's execute my app.py. So, "streamlit
run
app.py"
now. See, this is the application. Now let's uh test this application.
Uh see right now you can't see any comp uh any of my old trades because completely right now I have copied my chatbot in a new uh new actually folder, okay?
And right now all of the execution will be happening from the beginning.
So let me test this chatbot whether it's working or not.
So here I will pass hello.
See it's working, okay. Hello, I can uh help you today. That means everything is fine. That means this is our final code we can utilize right now for the deployment.
Now, guys, let me write all the deployment state action. We'll be following for this CICD deployment.
let me right here.
This is the
this is the entire step. Okay, you can see this is this entire step I have already prepared for this deployment. So let me open the preview.
Yeah, now you can see here.
So, see, this is a streamlit app, and we have to deploy the streamlit app over the AWS cloud as a CI C D and for CI C D
tool-wise, we'll be using GitHub Actions, okay?
And GitHub Action is already uh already actually let's say built in Cicd like tool, you don't need to set up this GitHub Action server separately. This is already running on the GitHub, okay.
You just need to um you just need to actually configure that GitHub Actions by adding some commands, okay. By adding some commands inside a file. We call it as a cicd.yml file.
This file I'm also going to show you how you can write that. But as you can see, this is the deployment step we'll be following.
First of all, we'll try to build the Docker image of our source code, okay.
we'll try to dockerize entire of our source code, then we'll try to push this Docker image to the Docker hub.
Okay, then I'm going to launch a EC2 machine on AWS server. then I'm going to pull my Docker image okay from the Docker Hub to EC2.
Then I'm going to launch my like image.
That means I'm going to execute my application as a Docker container inside EC2 machine.
Okay, then I'll do some port mapping, then you'll be able to access your application, okay, from the remote URL.
Now, for this Docker knowledge is definitely required, and I am expecting you are already familiar with Docker, but if you don't know about Docker and all,
So don't worry, I have a complete uh like let's say tutorial on my channel. As you can see, I have a complete um video, ultimate ML ops full course in a one video.
So this is around 11, almost 12 hours of recording, and this course covers everything about the MLOps. I have already covered Linux, okay.
Then some other tools as well, you can see in the description section.
See lots of like MLOps tools I have covered, and here we'll be seeing one section.
I think from this hour itself, you can start watching Docker concept. Okay, you can see the Docker concept I have also covered in this particular course itself.
Now, if you are completely new to the Docker and if you want to learn the Docker, okay, how Docker works and why Docker is required. I'm going to suggest you go through this recording.
I'm going to add this video in my description. From there, you can check it out. Okay, you don't need to watch from the beginning.
Maybe you can only complete the Docker part at least so that you can um you can see the deployment part, okay. You can um understand like how Docker is helping for this CICD deployment and all.
Okay, so yeah, this is the requirement.
Then uh here I have added this step.
First of all, we have to log in to the AWS console, then we'll be creating the IAM user, okay. Then after creating the IM user, we'll try to set the policy, then we'll try to create the EC2 machine.
Okay, we'll be taking Ubuntu instance.
After that, we'll try to open the EC2 instance and we'll try to set up uh Docker there, okay? Because by default in the EC2, there won't be any kinds of Docker, you have to set up it.
Once the setup is complete, then uh you will be um able to set the port. Okay, that means by default streamlit runs on port number 8501.
Okay, so we'll try to do the port mapping, then we'll try to set up our entire project as a self-hosted runner. That means we'll try to connect our AWS with our GitHub.
That means once let's say we'll try to push something in the GitHub, automatically my CI CD pipeline will trigger and all of the new changes will be available over my AWS.
Okay, that means automatically my deployment will be happening. So, this kinds of pipeline we have to create by creating this self-hosted runner. Okay, I'm going to also show you how to create that.
Then once everything is complete, then I'll try to uh like set up all of my secret. Okay, so you can see uh if you want to run this project, you need these are the secret.
Uh, apart from that, some additional secret is also required, like um registry, docker username, docker password, okay, image name, AWS access key ID, AWS secret
key, uh secret access key, okay, AWS region.
So these are the thing additionally you need because if you want to uh authenticate with AWS account, uh programmatically, you need these are the credential.
Okay, we'll try to create this credential as well. I'm going to show you okay how to do that.
And I am going to push my Docker image to the Docker hub for this Docker credential is also required, and you should have also account in the Docker hub.
And after that, whatever credential I'm having, I think you already know that these are the credential I need to execute my entire agents.
Okay, like if you're using OpenAI model, you can set the open API key, uh tablet API key, open over there, Google.
Okay, if you're using Gemini, you can set the Google API key Lang Smith, Lang Smith endpoint, LangSmith API, then Lang Smith project. Okay, so yeah, this is the step, guys.
will be following for uh deployment, okay. For this CICD deployment. Now, first of all, guys, here I'm going to create a Docker file.
So let's create a Docker file here.
So to Dockerize your entire application, you need this Docker file, okay? And inside this Docker file, you have to write some Docker-related command.
Now, what are the command you have to write?
So, this is the command, guys, and this thing you will be able to understand uh from that particular video I suggested you because in that video I have covered like what is this uh
uh beige image, okay. Uh, what is this involvement, what is this working directory?
Okay, each and everything I have explained there. If you are completely new to the Docker, first of all, try to complete that recording. I think that would be easy for you, okay.
But if you're already familiar with Docker, I think you know that these are the command we need to create uh the Docker image, that means to containerize entire our application,
right? So, yeah, we are setting this uh
command inside the Docker file, and here you can see we have to install the requirement.txt. Okay, we are also installing in this particular command, and I have already commented out.
See now, this part you need to prevent Python cache file and enable immediate container logs. Okay, then this code you need to build the essential supports package that required
compilations, then lib GOMP1 is a uh commonly required by fire CPU. That means here I am using fire CPU for the vector database, right?
That's why this library you also need to install, okay, whenever you are upgrading this machine.
Then you need this requirement.txt.
it has to copy in the
Root folder, then you can see we will be installing this requirement.txt, and this is the command we are writing.
Then we are copying all of our source code inside the root directory, then we're exposing the port, and by default, streamlit runs on port number 8501.
We are exposing the port, and this is the final command to launch the streamlit server.
Okay, so yeah, this is the Docker file, and with this Docker file, you need another file which is.dockerignode.
Ignore okay.
So inside this dot uh docker ignore, uh, you have to write some of the unnecessary files and folder which you don't need to uh
integrate inside your Docker image.
Let's say if you have your virtual environment, okay, in this particular folder itself, that uh you don't need okay, whenever you are creating the Docker file, right?
So that time you can ignore this one.
So that means whatever file and folder you will be keeping inside dot docker ignore, it will ignore during building the Docker image, okay.
Like this gitignore, and you know gitignore what it does, it ignores the files and folder, whatever you will be adding inside this gitignore, okay, so that it won't be pushing inside our
GitHub repositories.
Okay, so these are the things actually I don't need inside my Docker image, so that's why I'm ignoring inside dot uh docker docker ignore.
So once it is done, then I'll try to add this uh cicd.yaml file for the GitHub Action Cd deployment.
So for this, you have to create a folder.
The folder name should be dot github.
Okay, so this is the folder name we usually use, and this folder name you don't need to change. If you are changing, it will not work. So by default, if you are using uh this uh
GitHub actions for the CICD deployment, you have to create this dot github folder. Inside that, I'm uh you'll be creating another folder called workflows,
okay.
Workflows make sure you are using the same name, otherwise, it will not work.
Okay, workflows
and inside this workflows, you will be creating a file called
cicd.yml uh yaml okay, y a ml.
Okay, this is a yaml file, and inside that you have to mention all of the command you need for the cicd deployment.
Okay, now just verify whether everything is fine or not inside dot github workflows and cicd.yaml file is available.
Okay, now guys, uh what I'm going to do, um
I'm going to maybe close this file. This is not required.
Yeah, I'm going to open up my new port.
Yeah. Now, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to add all of the CICD related command and these are the CICD related command you will be getting in the internet
itself. Okay.
you can simply search I want to perform CICD deployment okay, uh on AWS, and I have a streamlit
application for that. I need this uh Cicd.yaml file.
So you will be able to see this YAML file is available okay over the internet. You don't need to memorize it, you will be getting this thing in the internet only.
And if you have the chat GPT Gemini, simply you can open the chat GPT and Gemini. You can ask, okay, I need a cicd.yaml file commands.
Uh, I have to do this deployment, okay. Streamlit app on the AWS as a CICD. So I have already prepared the cicd.yaml command. So let me show you. So this is the
command, and most of the command you can see this is a Linux command.
if you are completely new to the Linux command, so again in my MLOps course, okay, on my YouTube channel, I already covered the Linux, okay. Relax generated command.
You can see Linux is also covered. Okay, you can go through the Linux video as well to understand how this command works, okay?
So, yes, this is the like uh uh structured command you need to execute uh whenever you want to perform CI CD with the help of GitHub Actions.
So, first of all, you have to define a name of your application. So here I have given streamlit aw CICD, you can change the name anytime.
Then on push, okay. That means if you are pushing on the main branch, that means right now I have the GitHub, right?
This is the GitHub, and here I am using main branch. That means whatever push I'm going to do on my main branch, this pipeline will trigger, okay.
Only it will ignore if you are changing the readme file because readme is not a feature, okay.
README is kinds of file there. I just try to write some metadata for my project, right? So if I'm changing anything in my readme, that time out CSD pipeline should not be triggered.
That's why path ignore, we are writing readme file. Otherwise, if you are changing in any file, this pipeline will start. Okay, this CSD pipeline will start and your deployment will be happening.
Then we are giving some other like parameter as well, like workflow dispatch.
Concurrency, okay, permissions. We are giving each and everything.
And this is already uh, I mean, uh predefined actually workflows you have to write if you're using this uh GitHub Actions for the CICD deployment.
Okay, this is not our code, so CICD with GitHub Actions documentation. If you check, so they have written these are the commands should be added inside your CICD.eml.
Now, here the main thing is the jobs.
So here, first of all, continuous integration will be happening inside continuous integration. We are just only equing the command, okay?
We are taking an Ubuntu instance and we are only equing the command. Then the second step we are building and pushing the image to the Docker Hub.
So here, first of all, we are verifying with the Docker Hub account. So make sure you have the Docker Hub account. So if you don't have, you can create so simply search for Docker Hub, okay.
Docker hub, go to the fast website and make sure you have an account here. Okay, I already have the account, that's why it got login.
Okay, but if you don't have account, guys, please try to create an account.
So let's say I will sign out.
So here you can sign up, okay. Sign up, you can fill your information after filling.
You will be able to create the account. So I already have the account, I'll just try to sign up.
Sign in.
So this is my email and password. I'm going to sign in with my Docker Hub.
Okay, and this is how your Docker Hub will look like. Okay, previously I already pushed some of the image, that's why it's available, but for you, it would be completely empty.
Okay, so Docker Hub is a service that you can store all of your Docker image okay. You are creating.
You can also use AWS uh ECR service, but this is fine. I can use Docker Hub also, it's completely fine.
Okay, in AWS also to store your Docker image, there uh there is a service called AWS ECR, elastic container registry.
Okay, you can also use that, this one, but I'm going to use Docker Hub for this particular project.
Maybe in future, I'm also going to show you that elastic container registry how to use that because I want to minimize my cloud cost, that's why I'm using these are the free uh
free to use actually hub, okay, to push my image.
And uh yeah, so here you can see we are authenticating with the Docker Hub, and after that, we are building the image, okay.
We are building our Docker image, then after building, we are pushing this image to the Docker Hub.
Then once my second step done, then it will start the third step.
There you will try to deploy your image to AWS EC2 instance, okay.
As a self-first runner for this, this is the command. So it will again authenticate with your Docker Hub and it will uh take that image and it will run on your EC2 instance, okay?
And to run your app, you need some credential. I think you remember, you need Google API key, tablet API key, open open weather API. Okay, so whatever let's say API you have used, right?
You have to write all of the API here.
You can see.
Uh, what is that? Yeah, but you are not going to directly give the value. So this value you will be reading from the secret, okay.
We call it as a GitHub secret. I'm going also going to show you how to add this secret, but make sure whatever API key you are using, you have to write here.
Okay.
And here we are checking all of the API keys are available or not. If not available, we are just
like launching a match call secret is missing, okay.
Then this is the code, and finally we are running our Docker image and it is starting the server, okay, and some other necessary command we are also running, okay.
Everything will be running in that Docker video I have already given you, okay. In my MLOps course.
Now, this is the cicd.yaml file, guys. You need for this deployment.
Now everything is ready.
Now let's try to create the server, okay.
Server means I will follow this step, okay. First of all, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to log in with my AWS console.
So let's try to log in.
I already logged in with my AWS console. Make sure you have the AWS account. If you don't have the account, guys, please try to create one account.
I already logged in with my AWS console, and that's how your console looks like. Now, here the first thing you have to search for the I am user.
Okay, I am user, that means identity access management.
then I will go to the I am user section, and here you have to create an user.
Okay, let's create an user.
So I'm going to name it as let's say agentic
okay, agentic user.
You can give any name, it's up to you. Now I'll click on next.
Then you have to add the policies, okay? And which policies you have to add?
So here I think I have already written.
Uh yeah, so after logging to the AirWest console, we are creating the IM user, and this is the policy you have to add.
Okay,
So here, let me check again. Amazon easy to full access. Okay, huh?
Because you only need the easy to instance. Okay, so I'll copy this
and here I'm going to
search it here. Okay, so Amazon easy to full access. I'll provide this access and I'll click on next.
Okay, see why we are giving this permission because in my AWS account there are lots of services we are having, right?
And it's not like that. I'm going to give all of these services access to my like project to my code.
Instead of that, I'm only going to give the access the service actually I'm using.
Otherwise, there is a possibility it might use some other service and I will end up with lots of costs, right? But I don't need that, so that's why I am only giving the access the services I'm using.
So here I'll be using EC2 instance. EC2 is a virtual machine inside AWS. Okay, once it is done, let's create the user.
Okay, so
some error is coming.
The specific username is invalid, must content.
Okay, so I think the name we have given this is not
okay. There I have given a space, right? But it should not be having any kinds of space.
So I'll give this hyphen sign. Now let's click on next.
Now I'll provide this.
Amazon EC2 full access.
Click on next.
Now everything is fine. Create the user.
Okay, so my user creation is done. Now I will go inside the user and there is an option called security credential. Just try to click here
and here you will see this one access keys.
Okay.
Now I'll click on this create access keys.
Now select this command line interface CLI and just do the confirmation. Okay, once everything is done, now click on the next.
Then I will click on this create access keys.
Okay, now this is our access keys and secret access keys, guys. You need to authenticate with your AWS because I am going to access my AWS account from my Python code, right?
from my actually GitHub actions.
that's why this credential is required.
Okay, now you can download as a csv file as well. Let's try to download this thing I need later on.
Now, this service is creation done.
Okay, now this this is creation done. Um, we have successfully created the I am user and we have given the policy and we collected our access key and secret access key.
Now the next step you have to create the EC2 machine, Ubuntu machine. Okay, now let's do that. I will go to my home and here I will search for
EC2 instance.
Okay, let's open this EC2 instance, and EC2 instance is a virtual virtual computer service, okay, inside AWS.
Now I'll just try to click on launch instance, uh launch without a walkthrough.
Okay, now you have to give a name, so I'll give agentic
okay, agent t chatbot
machine. Okay, you can give any name, it's up to you, and make sure you select this Ubuntu instance.
Okay, there are some other instances available like macOS, Windows, Red Hat, but I will take this Ubuntu instance because this is the most used instance whenever you are doing the
production grade deployment.
Now, once it is done, you can select the instance type that means how much memory, how much CPU you need, you can select the configuration here. So for this project, at least 4 GB RAM is required.
Okay, and I'm going to take 2v CPU.
I think this T2 medium is fine for me. Okay, but if you are creating a heavy project that needs lots of computation, that time you can also take some bigger instance as well.
Some bigger instance are also available, like 32 GB memory, 16 GB memory. Okay, you can see everything is available. Now I'll take this T2 medium. Okay, this is fine for me.
Now, here you have to create a key value pair.
Uh click key pair.
Now you can give the name. I'll give agentic.
Let's create the key.
And once it is created, you can select it from here. Okay, agentic.
This one. So this key you need whenever let's see one to access your this EC2 machine from any tart petty tools like putty and mobile extreme. That time it is required.
But for our case, we'll try to launch in the same Google Chrome only. Okay, there uh you can launch the uh terminal, okay. Your easy to install terminal. this is also possible.
Now, here you have to uh check mark these two options low sttps and low shtp traffic from the internet, and here you can take the storage, at least try to take 32 GB
storage,
and everything is fine, no need to change anything, simply launch the instance.
Okay,
so I'll go below and click on view all instance.
Now see my instance has created and it is running. Okay, make sure it is running, otherwise, you can keep on refreshing this page.
Now, simply I'll click on my instance ID, and here you will get one option called this connect button.
Okay, but before connect button, I think you remember what I told you.
I told you to do the port mapping as you can see.
Uh
okay, port mapping. I think we can also do later on, but you can do the port mapping right now.
if you want, so let's do the port mapping. otherwise, we'll do it later on, okay? So simply I'm going to connect my instance. Okay, so there is a connect button.
Just try to click on the connect button and make sure you select everything as default.
If you want to connect this this let's say C2 instance from any third party tool, that time you can use HSS client and you can use mobile extreme putty. These are the tools to connect, okay.
But I'm going to connect from my same AWCLI only.
I'm going to simply click on connect.
Now see in a different tab, it will open up your this ec2 instance terminal.
Okay, this will be your Linux terminal, and there you have to execute all the command to set up your entire server. Okay, now see this is the Linux server we are getting, guys.
That's clear, and for this, you need some idea about Linux command Ubuntu Ubuntu operating system, and this thing I have already covered in my ultimate MLOps
full course. Okay, there I have already covered about the Linux. You can study about that, okay. For the deployment, guys, you need little bit of understanding MLOps.
If you know about MLOps, it would be easy for you to do the deployment. Now, guys, what I'm going to do, I'm going to set up all of the
uh all of the package I need here.
So for this, I mentioned all of the command as you can see. Uh first of all, you have to upgrade your machine.
So for this, just copy this command
and execute it here.
Right click and paste and execute.
Then I'll copy the next one.
See, you just need to copy this command
one after one and just execute inside the terminal.
Done. Now I'll copy paste this second command.
So, see this is a completely new create newly created machine, and here you have to upgrade the package manager.
Okay, so we are upgrading, and for this, we are using sudo apt-get upgrade this command.
Now I'll give yes permission and upgrade this machine,
and that's how your production server looks like, okay. That's why you you maybe heard of in production you need to know about Linux, okay?
Because every production server they're using Linux, especially the Ubuntu instance. Okay, they're using now. This is also done. I will clear the terminal.
Now let me see the next command. Next command, you have this. Um
you have to install this Docker. Okay, now to install the Docker, this is the command.
First of all, let's download the Docker.
There is a HS file you have to download.
Then after that, we'll try to install it.
Past the next command.
And this is the last command you have to execute.
Now see Docker successfully got installed inside our Linux instance. You can check it.
For this, you can run this command Docker hyphen hyphen version.
So you'll see that Docker is running right now.
Okay, but previously Docker was missing.
Okay, I can maybe close my local local host execution.
Let's close it.
terminal is also running. I'll stop it.
So fine. we have successfully installed Docker. Now the next step I have to
configure my EC2 as a self-hosted runner.
For this, just open up your GitHub and go to the settings. Okay, make sure you are using your GitHub, okay? Not my GitHub.
Go to the settings and left hand side you will see one option called actions.
Now go to the runner.
Okay, here just try to select this new self-hosted runner,
and you will see this Linux operating system. Just try to select that,
and these are the command you have to execute inside your EC2 instance. I'll copy the first command and execute in the terminal.
Then I'll copy the second command I'll execute in my terminal.
I'll copy the third command
and let's execute it here.
That means you are connecting your AWS with your GitHub.
Okay, that means whatever change you will let's say push in your GitHub automatically And this will be this will be like let's say available inside your AWS.
then I'll copy the last command
and execute.
Okay, so two more command you have to execute. So inside configure this command.
Now see, GitHub action is getting initialized and it is it is already connected with my GitHub.
Now, here it is asking for the intended name of the runner group.
I don't need to give any runner group name, I'll simply press enter, then it is telling enter the name of the runner.
So here make sure you give the same name self
hosted.
Okay, that means in this uh YAML file, that you remember.
Here you have given this name, okay.
Continuous deployment, you have given ransom self-hosted. You have to give the same name here, self hosted. Okay, so make sure you are giving the same name, otherwise, it it will not work.
Now I'll press enter.
Now it is asking uh there would be any following labels.
Uh I don't need any label, I'll skip it.
Press enter, then it is telling enter the name of the work working folder. I'm going to again press enter.
Okay, now it's done.
Now, simply you have to copy this last command and you have to execute, and you will be able to see that uh your uh AWS will be connected to your GitHub.
See, connected to the GitHub and listening for the jobs.
Now you can test it here. So simply you can again click on the runners.
Now see your self-hosted runner, it is already ideal. That means your AWS is connected with your GitHub and it is listening for the jobs.
Now, right now, if you push anything in your uh in your let's say repository, right? If you push any any code, automatically it will get deployed over the AWS um AWS cloud. Okay, how?
Because you have written this YAML file, inside this YAML file, all the commands are available for the deployment operations, okay.
But one more thing I have to do, which is this secret credential I have to add. Other without this secret, it will it will not work. Okay, so definitely the secret needs to be added.
So let's add the secret. Now, if you see the last step,
uh last step is that you have to add the secret key in the GitHub actions. Okay, so let's do that. I'll go to the GitHub again, go to the settings,
left hand side. You will see one option called secret and variable, and go to this action section. Okay.
Now, here you have to create a new repository secret.
So, first of all, you have to
create this registry.
registry should be
docker.io because we are using Docker Hub.
So make sure this is the key name and this is the value name. Okay, inside secret, you have to give the value and add the secret.
Okay, done.
You can see we have added this secret.
Now I'll uh create another one new repository secret
and I'll do it for the next one.
I'll add my docker username.
So what is my Docker username if you go to my Docker Hub.
So this is my hub.
If you just click on my account, here you will be able to see the username. Okay, so make sure you check your username in your Docker Hub and copy the same name and give it here.
Now the next thing I have to add the Docker password that means Docker Hub password.
So make sure you are giving your Docker Hub password, okay?
So let me give my password, guys. So this is uh this is like secret password. I don't want to show you, so that's why I'm going to pause the video after adding the password.
I'm going to show you the next step.
So, yeah, guys, I have successfully set my Docker password. Okay, so that's how you have to add all of the secret inside this secret variable. Now let's try to add the next one the image name.
So image name, I'm going to let's say give the same name like Agentic Chatbot.
So with this name, actually, your Docker image would be created. Okay, you can also change this name as per your requirement. I have given agentic chatbot.
Now let's add the secret.
Now next, I have
this AWS Access key ID.
Now, while you will get this AWS access key ID? I think remember we downloaded one CSV file. Okay, this CSV file. Let's open it up.
I'll open in my notepad. So this is the secret and secret access key.
So first of all, let's copy this access key ID.
So before this, comma this is your access key ID. Okay, I'll copy
and
paste it here.
And make sure you don't share this credential with anyone, otherwise, they will be able to access your account. Okay, I'm going to remove after this recording.
Don't use my one.
Okay, try to use your one.
Now AWS Access key is done. Now next I'm going to add AWS secret access key.
Secret access key. Okay. Now where you'll get the secret access key?
So this part is your secret access key. Okay, that means after this, comma whatever you have, this is your secret access key. Let's copy
and paste it here.
Done now. Next you have
the AWS region.
So right now I'm inside you will see that I'm inside US East One region,
North Virginia, E West East One. Okay, if you're in other region, you can give this name. Okay, but right now I'm inside US East One. I will give the same name here.
What is that?
Yeah,
let's copy.
So all the command I have given in my README file, you can check from there, guys.
Done now.
Next, I have to add
the OpenAI API key.
If you're using OpenAIPI key, guys, you have to add the openai API key. Okay.
And make sure you add your value here.
So I'm using Google Gemini model now because I don't have OpenAI API key.
So that's why I'm not going to pass my OpenAI API key, but I just showed you okay how to add your open API key. So make sure you pass your open API key here. Okay.
Now here I'm using
Google API key. That means I'm using Gemini model. I'll be using my Google API key instead of OpenAI.
You can also remove this part if you are not using OpenAI.
But I have showed you if you're using OpenAI, you can add it at this.
Now I'm going to add the tablet API key.
Tabile.
And what is your tablet API key?
It is available inside your environment
variable.
So this is your tablet API key. Let's copy
and give it here.
Then next you have this
open weather API key.
Let's copy my Open weather API key from this in ENV.
Okay, now next I have to add
after open weather Google API key.
So here I have my Google API key.
Now next
you have this
Langsmith tracing
because we are also using Langsmith for monitoring your entire application, right? To trace all of the execution.
And this secret would be true.
You can also verify from your environment.
So tracing should be true, okay?
And don't give any quotation, okay. Quotation you don't need to give.
Now next I have this
Lang Smith endpoint.
This is the endpoint
now. Next, I have this
Langsmith API key, and
here is your Langsmith API key.
Done now. Next you have
this
Lang Smith project name.
Okay, that's how whatever API key you are using, you have to add inside the secret.
Okay, that's how you have to
prepare the secret variable.
So what is the name?
Agentic AI project, agentic chatbot project.
This is the name I think I was using.
Even you can also open up your Langsmith platform, you can verify.
Yeah, so Agentic Chatbot project. Okay, if you want to create a new one, you can also create an uh uh it's completely fine.
But here I am tracing all of my execution.
Alright, so all of the secret I have added, guys. Uh let me check if I am having anything else.
No, I think everything is added. Okay, now see all of the secret we have added.
So right now, this secret is not visible uh to the public, okay?
So this is available inside my account, inside my secret, okay.
And my application will pick up from this particular secret only. That's why everywhere I have given secret dot your API name, or let's say key name.
Okay, so that's how you don't need to expose your API key or um, I mean to the audience.
Just try to make sure you are adding inside the secret, okay. This is super important.
Now everything is done. Now we are ready for the deployment.
So, right now, our server is connected, my GitHub is connected, my uh self-hosted runners runner is running, everything is done.
Now, simply I'm going to push the changes. Okay, now let's try to push the changes. I'll commit the changes.
So, here I'm going to open up my terminal. I'm going to write git add.
So, see, these are the
file I'm going to push.
Yeah, so everything is fine, but let's let's delete these are the file.
This is actually created uh because I have executed this project, right? And it has created the persistence memory, but I want to delete it, okay.
I want to like push completely new new project okay to the cloud.
So I'll delete this at the file.
So everything is fine now. Let me push the changes.
So I'll open up my terminal, I'll just write git add space
dot,
then git commit type in m.
I'll give let's say updated, now
just write git push
origin
main.
Now, push is done.
Now, if I go to my GitHub,
okay.
Now see everything is updated in my GitHub and your workflows is running. Okay, you can go to the action and you can see your first commit is running.
This is your first uh attempt to the CICD deployment. Okay, and this is a one-time setup, guys. This setup you have to do one time, and going forward, you don't need to do this setup.
Okay, going forward, you will only just try to change your upgrade and automatically it will be getting deployed.
Now, see three step it is running continuous integration, building and pushing image, uh push Docker image and deploying to the AWCC2.
So continuous integration is already completed.
Now building and pushing image is running.
Okay, so right now my image is getting builded.
Okay, you can see it is set up in everything, all the package and everything.
So this process may take some time. Let's wait.
Now see requirement got installed successfully. After that, it will push the image to the Docker Hub.
Now you can see in the Docker Hub I don't have any kinds of image name with the help of agentic chatbot.
Okay, now you'll see that after some times this image would be available.
Everything is happening automatically, guys. Okay, because I have set up the entire server, I have written that YAML file, and all of this command is available, so everything would be automatically.
This is the beauty of CICD deployment.
Only one time effort, okay, one time configuration, one time setup, and rest of the life you can enjoy.
And that's how production deployment happens.
Um whatever application you can see, right?
Everything is connected with CICD pipeline, and that's how they're
set up in the server.
You can also use any other cloud like GCP Azure.
it's completely fine.
The step will remain same. Maybe some functionality would be different, okay, in that cloud.
Now see, uh build and push is complete.
See the green tick mark that means complete. Now deploying this image to the AWS EC2.
Now it is pulling the image and it will run on my EC2 instance.
Okay, see all the three steps are complete. All the three steps are getting green tick mark. That means everything is fine. There is no error inside our workflow.
Okay, we have successfully uh deployed.
Now I will go to my instance and there you will see one option called public DNS. Okay, Let's try to copy this URL and paste over the new tab. And if I execute, see.
right now, this application is not going to open because we haven't done the port mapping. Okay, port mapping is required because by default our application is running on port number 8501.
Okay, so we have to do the port mapping.
So to perform the port mapping, you can go back to your instance and there is an option called security.
Just go to the security,
there is an option called security groups. I'll click on security groups,
and here you will see one option called edit inbound rules. Okay, now here you can see your uh port number is not defined here.
That means 8500 um 8501 is not defined here, so just try to add the rules and port number you have to write 8501. Okay, this is the port of streamlit.
You can also verify in the cicd.aml at the last whenever you are running your image, right?
So there you said that
yeah, see you are doing the port mapping to 8501. This is the port, okay. By default, the streamlit application runs port 8501.
Now you have to select this 00. Okay, that means you can access from anywhere and simply save these rules.
Done. Now I'll go to this instance again, instance ID.
Now I'll copy this public DNS again.
Okay, and make sure after this URL, you are you are giving this clone
port number 8501. Okay, 8501. Now, if I execute, now I'll see your application will be running, and this is completely live right now.
Okay, now if I share this URL with anyone, they will be able to access my agent.
See, this is running on the AWS server right now, and this is completely live. Okay, now you can purchase any kinds of domain name.
Okay, then you can change this name with your domain name. On domain name, this is also possible, okay.
But if you know till here, I think it's completely fine. Uh, the domain part, I think this will take care by the front end developer.
So, right now our chatbot is running live, okay. We can test whether it's working or not. So let's say I will give hello.
See how I can help you today.
Then I have given another message. I am Bhappi. Now it is telling nice to meet you, Bappi. Now I'll tell
me the current
weather
okay in Dhaka.
Now see it is using my get weather uh tool and it is giving you the kind of weather in Dhaka.
Now we'll ask uh
uh latest
news
uh in FIFA
now. See it is using tabli source tool, and this is giving you the latest news on FIFA.
Okay,
so this is the latest news
you're getting
now.
You can ask any other thing. Let's say you can ask about the
um stock price.
Tell me
tell me the stock
price of
Okay, this is the current stock price of Apple.
Now you can also purchase any stock, so you can just write purchase.
Uh let's say 20 stock
of
Apple.
Okay, now again we have added these HITL features. That means that means human in the loop, it will ask for the human verification.
Now, see asking for the human verification. Now, if I approve,
now my share would be purchased. Okay, now you can even upload any kinds of document. You can start the conversation.
You can also create a new trade.
This is also possible. Let's say I've created new trades.
Okay, now here I will ask upload any kinds of documents. Let's say I will upload my resume
and I will ask, tell me about
book deer Ahmed
Bhappi based on
the
PDF
uploaded.
Now, see it is using rag tool,
and it is giving you
about myself, okay, based on the resume I'm having.
Okay, so that means everything is working fine, and this is completely live right now.
You can share this URL with your friends and family, they'll be able to use that.
Okay, so amazing guys, we have seen how to perform the deployment.
Now, the uh I mean good part I want to show you about the CICD deployment is that now let's see in future if you want to add any new chains here, okay.
Let's see if you want to add any new features, you don't need to manually let's say uh set up everything again in the cloud server.
Okay, you don't need to manually copy paste your code and set up everything, only you just need to change and upload inside your GitHub. Automatically, this deployment will be happening.
Let me show you.
Let's say in this app.py, um, let's say right now, let me show you one like a small features. Okay, I will be adding here. Let's have a refresh my app.
So right now you can see it is agentic chatbot with Langgraph. Okay, let's say I want to add an emoji here, okay. Let's say I want to add an emoji. So, what I'm going to do,
I'll go, I'll go to that part that I'm creating this title.
I think here I'm creating the title, right?
Here, so let's say I'm going to add an emoji.
So, simply let's add an emoji.
So, let's say I'm going to add this this robotic emoji, okay? So, I'm going to add this robotic emoji, refresh,
and uh yeah, save it, and now we have to commit it again, okay? You have to commit your change again.
So, let's commit our change again.
So, I'll just write:
"Git. add space, dot
git, commit hyphen -m.
let's say I will give new feature.
add it
,". okay, and "git push
origin
main.
Now, push is done. Now again, I will go to the GitHub
and I will see that your pipeline will automatically
get triggered.
Now see, again action is running. I'll go to the action.
Now see, new feature added; this pipeline is running again. Okay, and this version is having a new update.
Okay, again it will build the Docker image, push the Docker image to the Docker Hub.
So you can see in the Docker Hub itself, you will see your
application
and that is your image.
See agentic chatbot?
So right now it is having only
uh one image. Okay, and it is uploading the next image here.
So let's wait.
See, again, all of the execution is happening and you don't need to do anything, okay? And still, your server is live. See, if you refresh here, if you start the conversation, it will run.
Okay, it will not, uh, it will not actually shut down, okay? But if you're not creating CSD pipeline, that time there is a possibility it will get shut down, okay?
And user will feel, uh, this application is not working, and then you may lose your user, right?
So that's why CSD is required.
In the back end, all of the deployment is happening, but you are not going to, uh, you are not going to see anything right now. If I come here, see, deployment is, is, uh, completed now.
If I come here now, if I refresh my application
now, see that new update has added here.
Now see this, uh, emoji has been added here.
Okay, so this is called actually CICD deployment, and that's how you can continuously add new features without shut down your application,
okay, without let's say stopping your application.
And this is what actually we use inside the industry, inside the production deployment.
Okay, I hope everything is clear, guys.
So, if you found this content useful, please try to subscribe to my channel and share this video with your friends, friends, and family, and please try, try to like on my video, guys.
Okay, and if you have any question, please try to comment in the comment section.
I would like to see your comment, and I would like to see your opinion.
Okay, whether This playlist is helpful or not?
Because I have covered each and everything. I have implemented the project, I showed you the end to end implement, uh, end to end deployment, everything I showed you, okay?
And lots of things are coming as well.
So guys, yeah, we have seen the deployment. Now we will see that how we can, uh, terminate all of the server because if you keep on running it, it will charge you.
So let's say once, uh, we have deployed everything, our learning is over.
Now I'm going to
Show you how we can stop the server, okay? Let's ... if you want to stop the server, how to do that?
So for this, okay, one more thing I want to show you. Let's say, if I close this terminal, okay, if I close this terminal, also still my application will be working,
okay? So still my application is working, okay? So now, if you want to, uh,
let's ... let's say delete this instance, first of all, you have to select it.
Then there is a option called instance.
State, and there you will see called "terminate" and "delete instance ." Okay? So if you do terminate and delete, it will delete, uh, everything. Okay? But if you stop it, it will stop;
again, you can restart it.
But I'm going to delete everything because my learning is over, and I'm going to terminate and delete now. After some time, it will be deleted. Okay?
Now you have to delete your I am user as
well. So let's go to the I am user left hand side. I am user is available;
select the I am user and delete it from here.
deactive the keys and just write confirm.
So it will be deleted.
Okay.
If you want, you can also delete your uh Docker image you have uploaded in your hub. Okay, this is also possible. You can also delete here.
But I'll keep this uh uh image okay in my Docker repository so that later on I can use it anytime.
Okay, so yes guys, uh that's how we can do the CICD deployment, and we have completed our deployment.
Okay, so right now you can see our application will not run because I have deleted all the instance and this is offline right now.
So, see this is offline right now, okay. So, yeah, you can try. I will share all the resources, all the code in my description. From there, you can try.
And please try to support my channel, guys. If you support me, definitely I will bring this kinds of content more in future. So, yes, this is all about for this uh deployment.
I have showed you on the AWS cloud.
Now, in the next video, I'm going to show you how we can deploy this project over the render cloud. Okay, render is another another cloud.
There you can also deploy this project as a CI CD. So, what is render? Render is a cloud platform, so there you can deploy any kinds of web application.
Okay, uh, this is the like a very fastest uh and uh very easy to use cloud platform. So, here you don't need to do so many configuration, okay.
Uh with some few clicks, actually, you can do the deployment. I'm going to show you how to do that, and definitely for this, you have to create an account on render.
And render is not completely free, but they have a free instance. In that free instance, you can at least deploy some application, okay.
But if you want to do the production grade deployment, okay, with some higher infrastructure and higher instance, that time you have to take the subscription, okay.
But I think this is fine as a learning purpose and just to just to actually live our app, okay, just to test our app, we'll be using the free instance.
So, free instance is having like very low configuration like machine, and I think this is completely fine for us so we can manage that.
Okay,
so if you found my content useful, guys, please do uh try to subscribe to my channel and please try to share and please try to hit the like.
I need your support if you provide the support, guys, so I can bring this kinds of content more in future. So uh let's start with the deployment, guys.
First of all, here you have to create an account. If you don't have account, guys, please try to create an account with your Google um uh Google address. You can create your account.
So I already have the account, I'll just try to sign in.
So here I'll just try to sign in with my Google.
So after sign in, guys, you will be able to see these kinds of interface. So this is the rendered dashboard.
And previously I deployed some app, that's why it's coming, okay, like that. But for you, it would be completely empty.
So here, uh, what I have to do, guys. Uh, first of all, I have to uh I have to actually commit my code to the GitHub, okay.
And uh in my previous deployment video, I already pushed this code in my GitHub. So this is already available in my GitHub repo.
As you can see, this is the repository we created, Agentic chatbot using Langgraph. So we can utilize that.
And one best part is that if you are using render, so render uh it is already having the CI CD integrated, you don't need to set up the CI CD separately, okay,
like we did in on AWS, right?
Here CI C D uh it is included, okay.
Only you just need to connect your repository, and automatically this CI CD uh pipeline would be created. You don't need to manually create that.
That's what I'm going to show you. So, first of all, here just try to copy this URL, okay?
Copy your GitHub URL and in on render you will see one option called new. Okay, just click on new, and here is a service called web service. Okay, just click on web service.
And here you can see git provider is available. Okay, just try to paste your URL.
Or you can go to this public repo uh git repository and you can provide the URL. Okay. And if you want, you can also pass your existing let's say Docker image.
So I think you remembered uh in my last video, I uh like pushed my Docker image in my Docker hub.
So you can also provide that image URL that uh and with the help of that, you can also perform the deployment.
You can also use your GitHub to do the deployment, okay?
But make sure you have this Docker file here.
So I already have the Docker file, and previous uh in my last video, I already created this Docker file. So Docker file should be available, okay. So we have the Docker file, it's completely fine now.
Simply, what I'm going to do, I'm going to just paste this URL here and I'll just connect this repository.
Okay, once you have connected, you can provide the name, the name you want to provide for this deployment.
But I will keep the same name and the language you have to select the Docker. Okay, if you don't have the Docker, you can also select the simple Python.
But I have the Docker, I'll try to select the Docker, okay. Language, then everything will remain same as it is, no need to change anything. And here in the instance type, see they have some plan.
You can take the plan as per your requirement. If you have, let's say, a very high configuration project that needs lots of computation.
That time you can take these are the like plan, but uh we'll be using this uh free plan for the hobby project.
Okay, just to show you, I'm using this free plan and it is having 512 mb RAM and 0.1 CPU code.
Okay, it is uh it would be a little bit slow lagging, but uh just to I mean make our project live, it's completely fine because nowadays none of the cloud provides the free uh
free let's say instance, right? To uh do the deployment, but at least they are providing. I think this is fine for us, right?
So I'll select this free instance, then here you have to set all of your environment variables uh you have inside your project.
So I think you remember inside our project, these are the environment variable is required. So try to set one by one.
So uh I'm not using open AI, so I will not set the open AI, I'll select set from tably.
So tably API key. Here you have to give the value.
Okay, then the next one you have
this open weather API key.
That's how I'll try to add all of the environment variable I have here. You can also upload your,
uh, smith,
tracing
Langsmith endpoint.
Then
Langsmith API key.
then we have Langsmith project.
So, yeah, all of the API key has set successfully now.
Uh in the advanced advanced part, you don't need to do anything, just keep it same as it is now.
Let's try to deploy our web service.
Okay, now it will start building your Docker, okay.
all of the setup, everything will uh uh going on here.
So we have to wait for some times, okay.
So this will set up and prepare everything, and once this starter should be live, you will be able to access your application.
Now let's wait, guys.
So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to pause the video.
Once this uh um Docker building is complete, then I will come back.
So, as you can see, guys, our application is live right now, and all of the um setup has complete successfully.
Now we can access this application. So this is the URL. Just try to copy this URL and open in a new tab.
So you'll be able to see that your application will open.
Yeah, so it has loaded my application. So this is our Agentic chatbot. Now let's test this chatbot.
let me zoom out so that you can see the entire screen. Yeah.
So now let's test this chatbot. So here I will give hi.
So see it's giving you hello. I can assist you.
Now I'll tell
what is the
current weather
in
So this is the current weather in Bangaluru. Now I will ask
tell me
the latest
score of
FIFA.
Okay, today.
Yeah, so this is the score it has given.
Now you can um you can check about this
stock price.
What is the
stock
price of Google?
Okay, so the API I was using uh so the rate rate limit has been over. Okay, so I have to create another API key, it's completely fine. Now let me test uh with my documents upload.
So, I'll just try to
provide my resume and ask:
Who is
Bhaktier Ahmed
Bhappi,
based on the
PDF uploaded.
now? It is giving you the entire answer about me, right?
So yeah, uh it's working perfectly. So only the issue we found uh our API key we're using, right?
For this stock price, uh this has been, I think limit is over, so I have to create an uh another API key and I have to set there because we are using the free one, right?
And free one definitely has some limitation, it's completely fine.
Yeah, so it's working fine. Then you can also create a new trades.
Okay, you can create a new trades and you can uh again do the conversation. Let's say hi, I am Alex.
Okay, see everything is working fine, okay. Now this application is completely live. You can share this with your friends and family, they will be able to access your application,
and uh this will not charge you, okay, because this is running completely on the free instance, and that's how you can deploy any kinds of project, okay. Uh, just for the testing purpose, okay.
But if you want to do the production grade deployment, that time just try to make sure you are taking the subscription plan.
Now, guys, one best part I will show you, which is this CI CD.
Okay, uh that means if you are changing something inside your code and if you are again committing to the GitHub, so what will happen?
So let's say right now, here I have an emoji.
Okay, so I want to remove this emoji.
as of now, let's try to consider this is our features. Okay, we are adding inside this chatbot.
Uh, where
is that part? Yeah, so here. So let's I will delete this emoji, okay, and I will again push my changes to the GitHub.
So let's say app file updated.
now I'll push the changes.
Done now. If I go to my GitHub,
see this commit is over.
Okay.
Um, I have file address added.
Uh, now here if I come to this uh uh I mean render and if I go to this event, so you have to go to this event
and there is an option called manual deploy.
Just try to click here, okay?
And there is an option called deploy last commit.
Okay, so you can also like make it as automated. There is a setting you can run on that. Uh, but if you just click here deploy latest commit.
Now, if I let's say deploy latest commit,
so you'll see that automatically
my new feature should be added.
See, still my application is running.
See, still my application is running and my deployment is going on.
Okay, so that's how they have integrated this inbuilt CI C D and all of this, okay. Whatever we have learned in my previous deployment.
So here you don't need that much of configuration, only few clicks you can do the deployment. Okay, so this is the best part uh on this render cloud.
Uh let's see.
So, see our application is live now. If I go to my application refresh,
so see this emoji got removed, okay. So that's how we can add our new features and you just need to commit the code on GitHub and you can just trigger that pipeline, okay?
And you can also make it an automated. There is a settings you can run on. So, yes, guys, that's how we can do the deployment. Now I'll show you how we can delete the instance, okay.
Let's say this project I have deployed now. How I can delete this instance, okay.
So for this, you just need to go to the settings
and go below.
There is an option called delete web service, and you have to copy this command
and give it here and delete the web service, okay? So if you delete it, so this service would be deleted and your application would be offline.
Okay, so yeah, that's how we can do that. So if you found my content useful, guys, please try to support me.
And this is my LinkedIn profile.
if you want to connect me, guys, you can connect on my LinkedIn, you can follow me on LinkedIn, and please let me know how you are enjoying this complete list.
If you found this useful, so please try to tag me on LinkedIn.
Okay, I'll be happy to see that, and just try to implement something from your end and please try to tag me.
So if you are tagging me on LinkedIn, I would be happy to see your work and definitely I will put my feedback and comments.
Okay, so guys, as you know, I started a complete Agentiki playlist on my YouTube channel and I completed our first orchestration framework, which is Langgraph.
So we have studied uh about this Langgraph in depth, we have seen each and every component of Langgraph.
Even I showed you one amazing uh end-to-end project implementation, which is one Agentic chatbot.
If you haven't checked those videos, guys, this is already available in my playlist, guys. It is already available on my YouTube channel, uh DS with Bappi.
So all the recordings are available.
Uh, you can go through all of this recording, okay. Uh then I told you uh after completing uh like our first orchestration framework, we'll be implementing some amazing project, okay?
And one project we have already developed in this uh playlist itself, okay.
So as you can see, uh our first project was around uh uh eight plus hours of recording.
Uh we have uh implemented the entire Agentic chatbot with the help of Lang Graph database, LangSmith Tools, Rag, HITL, AWS, and render.
So, guys, uh in this video, what I'm going to do, uh I'm going to utilize the same concept we have learned so far inside our Agentic AI
playlist, and we'll be implementing one very interesting and amazing project in this video.
Okay. And in this video, we are not only going to develop this project, uh, we'll also show you how we can deploy this project over the cloud platform as a CI CD.
Okay, that means first of all, we'll try to implement the entire project completely end to end.
Then after implementing, I will also show you how we can deploy this project and we'll be using CI CD pipeline for that. So the project name is BubPGPT.
So this sounds uh seems to be funny, but yes, actually, I'm going to implement uh one project here called Buppy GPT.
And this would be kinds of your chat GPT. So basically, we'll try to recreate this chat GPT okay uh with our own workflow. So I think you have already used Chat GPT, right?
chat GPT it's an agentic AI chatbot. So here you can perform the chat operation, you can upload your documents, okay.
Then you can also activate the voice mode, then you can see the conversation trades, okay.
Then it has also connected with different different tools, like you can perform real-time source operation, you can
solve complex math problem, you can generate the codes, okay? Each and everything you can do here.
So, yes, uh, in this video, guys, uh, we'll be developing our own chat GPT. So, I already named it as Bub P GPT.
So, let me show you first of all the application demo, how this application uh will work and how this application uh will look like, then after that, we'll start the development, guys.
So, as you can see, guys, uh, this is the application uh we'll be developing named BubPGPT. You can give any name okay as for your needs.
I have given Bub P GPT, and I think first time someone is creating Chat GPT with the Gemini model.
Why I I have used Gemini model because I wanted to use free resources. Um, I I didn't want it to use the paid one.
I could have used the open AI model here, but for open AI model you need open AI subscription.
But uh there are many learners that don't have the open AIPA key. That's why I thought let's try to integrate any free model, okay? open source model, and uh Gemini actually you can use uh uh freely.
Okay, there are some free limits you can utilize that. But if you want, you can also integrate any other model, you can also integrate open AI model, it's completely up to you, okay.
But the main things here we have to learn this concept, like the way they have created the chat GPT, okay.
You can see all the functionality like tradings, the documents uploader, this model selection.
Okay, then uh you can also uh open this void voice mode, you can uh uh give your voice, and automatically your voice would be recognized and you can perform the chat operation here, okay.
And it has also connected with uh different different tools. But here I tried to integrate uh actually a few tools here. Um, because um here I want to show you okay, uh, this project implementation.
So you can add as much as tool you can, okay. You can add all kinds of tool. I already told you about the tool in my playlist. I think you remember, right?
If you go through the playlist, I already discussed about the tool, so you can integrate as much as tool you can, okay.
Whatever tool you need, but I added few tools here just to show you the working demo. Now, first of all, uh let me show you the working demo how this will work.
And one thing, guys, I think you have seen uh in chat GPT you can also create the account, you can log in with different accounts.
Okay, this is a full full stack application, but here we avoided this part. We didn't added any kinds of account uh I mean login functionality here.
We just uh created the interface okay of the chat GPT. I think this is fine for learning purpose. This is completely fine. If you want, you can also uh use full stack uh let's say framework.
You can also create uh these kinds of account functionality and all, okay. This is completely up to you.
So, yes, guys, this is the interface as you can see.
It has the trading features that means you can switch between any of the trades and you can see the older conversation you have done, even you can also create a new conversation,
you can upload any kinds of documents, you can select your model. Okay, then you can also activate the voice mode uh if you want to speak with your
chat uh bub PGPT. Okay, and there I have also given some suggestion.
You can also see that, okay. I think you can't see uh the interface because of my video. So, what I can do, I can turn off my video now. I think you can see the full uh application.
So here is the voice mode and everything, right? So, guys, now let's uh test our Buppy GPT. Okay, uh, I will provide some prompt. Let's say first of all, I'll tell
hi
I am
Buppy here.
As you can see, it is giving hello bubbi. It's nice to meet you. How I can assist you today.
Tell me about gradient descent in simpler
word.
Now it is telling you about gradient descent.
Now we'll ask something um something about latest information.
So I will give this prompt. What was the score today for Argentina in FIFA World Cup? So let's see.
Now you can see it is using real-time website tool, and it will find out the latest information.
So you can see based on the website result, Argentina defeated
Austria 2 by 0 in FIFA World Cup match today. Lionel Messi scored both goal making him the all-time legend uh leading scorer in world cup history.
Okay, I think if you have already watched the last match of Argentina, you will see that
this was happened okay. Last match, last match. So, yeah, it's working fine.
You can also switch any other model if you want.
Okay, let's say I will take this pro model, okay.
Now we'll ask something. Let's say
I want to do some calculation. Let's say what is the
result
of
so I'll give a complex mathematics here.
Now you can see it is using calculated tool
and it will solve that.
Now you can see this is the result.
Okay, now here what I can do, I can upload any kinds of documents. So let's say here I will upload any kinds of documents, let's say we'll upload my resume
and I can do the conversation here.
Now see it's getting uploaded. Now you can see, you can ask the question about the document, and I'll tell
uh, who is
book tier,
Ahmed Bappi
based on
PDF.
Now you can see it is using document search tool, and this will use my document to give the response.
So this is the rag features you have in this kinds of agent chatbot.
Now you can see based on the provided PDF, Baker Bap Ahmed Bhappi is a data scientist with five years of working experience specializing generated
BI.
Okay, and it is he is um
and you can see it is telling each and everything about me. Okay, now you can also continue the conversation. Uh
how
many
projects he
has done.
Give me
all the name.
Okay, you can see based on the documents. Uh Bappi uh has worked with uh uh worked on four main projects. As you can see, these are the projects actually I have mentioned in that resume.
Okay, amazing, it's working great. Now you can see it has also voice mode. I can also activate the voice mode and I can ask something. Let's say
See, tell me about python programming and give me the hello world program. Now, if I send this prompt.
See,
it's giving you the entire response, okay, with the hello world program as well.
Okay, so yes, uh, that's how guys chat GPT works. Uh, even in chat GPT, also you can give this kinds of prompt and it will be working.
But yes, uh, chat GPT is like a very uh very actually advanced agentic application because inside that they have added so many functionality, okay,
deep research and all. But again, yeah, we have just tried to create recreated that application here, okay, by focusing on some major component,
okay.
Whatever we have learned so far. I think this is very much interesting.
Okay, if you want, you can also upgrade this project as per your requirement, and you can add new new features like chat GPT okay if you want,
and going forward, I'm also going to create some other project as well, so that you will be learning some more concepts.
Okay, so yes, guys, this is the entire demo of the application we have seen, and throughout the entire implementation, guys, we'll try to recreate
this application.
Okay, I think this would be fun. So make sure you watch this video till the end.
And if you found my content useful, please try to subscribe to my channel and share this video with your friends and family.
Now I'm also going to show you the memory features. I also integrated the memory here, that means it can remember my previous conversation.
So I think you remember at the very first, I told yes, my name is Bappi. Okay, like hi, I'm Bapi here. So let's see whether it is able to remember my name or not. So, what is my name?
So, as you can see, you introduced yourself as a buppy earlier. Is it correct?
Yes,
okay. Now I will remember that uh it's nice to chat with you. That means it has also long-term memory integration.
If you uh want your chatbot to remember something, it will remember. Okay, this will save that information in the long term memory. Okay, uh, this thing will also try to add with a database.
So, yes, guys, uh, that's how uh you can implement this uh this amazing uh agent ki chatbot named Bub P GPT, or you can give any kind
of name if you want, like chat GPT. And if you go to the home page here, also you can directly give something.
Let's say I'll give search the latest so if you click here, it will automatically come search the web
for latest TI news.
Okay, so you can directly send this prompt.
Okay, that's how I added some prompt here, summarize the uploaded documents, say something to the memory, use calculated tool. Okay, if you want, you can also give some more suggestions here.
Okay, it's completely up to you.
So, guys, now we'll start the development of BubPGPT.
Uh, before starting the development, first of all, I want to show you the high level architecture diagram, like whatever the component will be implementing in this um uh in this project.
So, as you have seen, this has already one front-end server.
it is running on basically HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
So the entire front end you can see, right?
I have created with the help of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. if you want, you can also use any front-end framework like Next.js, React, okay.
It's completely up to you. But again, if you don't know about front-end development, it's completely fine. There would be a separate team for that.
They will try to design this front end part okay for you. And if you don't know about HTML, CSS, JavaScript, don't worry.
This thing you can easily generate from uh Chat GPT, even you can also generate from Papy GPT if you want.
Um, so you just try to ask, I need this kinds of interface, it will create.
You can use that ready-made template and you can edit, okay, as per your requirement. but uh chat GPT actually they're using some kinds of front end framework for these kinds of user interface.
So every application has this kind of front end server.
Okay. Then it is connected with a backend server.
And the back-end framework wise web use will be using here fast API. That means the application we have created it is running on Fast API.
Okay. And FastAPI is a production ready backend framework you can use. We'll be also using FastAPI here. Okay.
We'll try to handle all of the get request, post request, everything with the help of Fast API. Chat GPT also running on some kinds of uh backend uh server.
Okay, maybe they have used Fast API, we don't know that.
Then you can see this backend server is connected with a workflow. Okay, that means some agentic workflow.
So here we'll be using Langgraph to implement this entire workflow.
Um, I think chat GPT they might be using any other agentic framework.
Okay, I don't know which framework they're using, but here we'll be using this uh Langgraph because we have completed Langgraph so far inside our playlist.
Okay, we'll try to use the language for the entire agentic workflow. Okay, we'll try to create our entire agents. Um we'll try to create the nodes, we'll try to create the tools, okay.
Each and everything we'll try to create with the help of line graph. Then this uh workflow will be connected with lots of tools, okay.
Like we'll be using some separate tools, we'll be using rag tools, okay. For document search, we'll be using memory tools. As you saw, it has also remembered okay.
My conversation, even you can also retrieve the old conversation, how it is happening with the help of memory tools. Then some external uh API tools we'll be using, like web search tool.
Okay, um, then if you want, you can also integrate uh current weather information, so each and everything you can integrate here, then it will have one node tools,
tools node.
then uh it has also database connection. That means uh for the I think if you have already understood about this uh language, it has a concept of state, okay.
The state uh uh checkpointer saving, we have to use some kinds of database, and here we'll be using SQLite database, okay, for this state tracking, and uh
for long-term uh long-term conversation stories, we'll be using SQL uh Alkami. Okay, this will store basically my um um like long-term conversation in that particular database, and whatever state
information we are having, we'll try to save inside this scalar database.
And for rag pipeline, guys, we'll be using Chroma DB vector database and we'll try to generate the vector embeddings. And here we have used Gemini embeddings because Gemini is free to use.
you can also use any other embedding model, it's up to you, okay. With the help of Gemini Embeddings, we'll try to generate the embeddings and we'll store in the Chroma DB.
And it's not necessary to use the chroma db. If you want, you can also use uh FAS Pinecone, but PineCon is a paid one. You have to take the subscription, then you will be able to use that.
Then Wave It also, Wave It is also there, it is also like a paid one.
So in this project, I try to use all the services as free. Okay, that's why I'm using ChromaDB.
Okay, ChromaDB is in a storage vector database that you can store all of your vectors, then some external APIs will be using like Tavili API, okay, then Google Gemini
API for the LLM and embeddings. And if you want, you can also integrate any other API as well here, okay? So, yes, this is the high-level architecture of this um
uh uh Bap P GPT.
Now we'll try to follow this architecture, we'll try to develop each and every component in detail.
So, first of all, we'll be creating a GitHub repository for this project.
so here I'll open up my GitHub.
Let's create a new repository here.
I'll create a new repository.
Um, I'm going to name it as
Buppy GPT.
Then
here I will make it as public repo and add the readme file. I will also
add the dot gitignore, and here we'll be using python and license. You can take any license. I will take this Apache license. Okay, now let's create the repository here.
once you have created this repository, now just click on code, copy this link, make sure you copy the HTTP link and open up your local folder. And here let's try to clone that.
So
git clone.
paste the URL
okay, so cloning is complete. Now I'll go inside that so cd bub p gpt okay.
Now I'm inside this folder and here I'm going to open up my um I'm going to open up my
uh VS Code. So let's open up my VS Code.
So this is my VS Code.
Let me zoom.
Everything is fine.
Yeah. So here the first thing guys, uh, what I have to do, I have to create a virtual environment, and after creating, we have to
install some of the library for this project, then we'll be creating the folder stack chat. So let's do it quickly.
And if you are implementing this project, guys, I have implemented a similar kinds of agentic chatbot in my previous project.
if you go through that recording, all of the concepts I explained in detail, like tools, rag, okay, then um memory,
each and everything I explain in detail. So if you are completing that video, it would be easy for you to implement this project.
Okay, if you're completely new, but if you already watched that video, if you already know these are the concepts, then it would be easy for you.
So here I'm not going to focus on the theoretical explanation.
Instead of that, I'm more going to focus on the practical development because I'm expecting you are already familiar with this concept, okay?
So yeah, make sure if you are completely new, go through that uh previous recording, okay. I have on my playlist
now. Uh here the first thing will be creating the
um
creating the
So let's create the environment.
So how to
buff PGPT?
Yeah, first of all, you have to clone the repository.
Okay.
Then after that, you have to create the environment.
Yeah, so you have to navigate the project directory first, then you have to create the environment.
So all of this step I'm writing so that it would be easy for you to set up, okay, later on.
Great.
Virtual environment.
So to create the environment, you need to run this command. So conda
Great.
Hyphen n buff pgpt, Python is equal to will be using Python 3.11 and hyphen y.
We're giving the yes permission.
Then once the environment is created, we have to activate the environment,
then we have to install the requirements.
Okay, once requirement installation done, then you'll be running the app.py
okay.
App.py should be our endpoint here. So now let's uh refer this file and install everything one by one.
Okay, so first of all, we have already inside my BubPGPT folder, and I'll create the environment here. So I'll copy this command, open up my terminal.
Let's create the environment.
Then we we have to activate that. This is the command.
Okay, activation is complete. Now here we have to add a requirement file.
Requirement.txt file. And inside that we'll be mentioning all of the requirement we need here.
So I already prepared all of the requirement, guys,
with the specific version I will be installing here. See, these are the requirement I need for this project.
I need fast API for the backend server, and to run the fast API, you need ubicon then Jinja, okay, and then Python multipart. So these are the dependencies of Fast API.
Then Python..env I need for environment management that means whatever api I'm going to mention I'm going to mention inside this.env
file.
Okay.
Then I'll be installing the orchestration framework like Langchain. Then we'll be using Gemini model.
For this, you have to install this Langchain Google Gen EI, then Langchain Core, then we'll be using Langraph orchestration framework for this agent workflow,
then Langchain Textplitter. I need I will be integrating reg feature, rag feature, and to parse our documents, we need that.
Then Langgraph checkpoint SQLite. That means uh to save this uh persistence memory. I need SQLite um saber.
Okay, then Langchain Chroma. I need uh because for vector database, I will be using Chroma DB.
Then Chroma DB have to install iPDF. Here will be only considering the PDF document.
But if you want, you can also use uh like docs file, you can also use Excel file. Look at this part you can add. Simply go to the Langchain documentation, you will be able to see that.
Then Langchen tabily. So internet search operation will be using tabily search, okay. Then tabily python, this is the dependency for Langchen Tabily, and SQL um
Alchemy will be using for this Long-term conversation stories. Okay, we'll be creating a database and there we'll try to save everything.
Okay, so yes, these are the requirements I need. Now we have to install this requirement, and this is the command for that. Let's copy and we'll install everything here.
So let's wait This process may take some time.
So in between, what I can do, I can collect all of the API key I need
for this development.
So here
what I'm going to do, I'm going to first of all collect the Gemini API key. Okay, this is available inside Google
AI Studio.
Go to the Google AI Studio
And here we'll just click on get started, and left hand side you will see this API key,
and here you have to create an API key. Okay, so I already have my API key, I'll just copy that. If you don't have you, just try to create from here, okay?
So after that, you just need to add it here.
So this is my Google API key.
Okay, this is my Google API key. I collected and don't use my API key, guys. I'll be removing after this recording.
And once it is done, then you have to mention the Google model, which model you want you want to use as default. Okay, let's see if user is not selecting the model.
That means the by default model I'll be using Gemini 2.5 flash model.
Okay, and this model has some free access limit. You can use that.
Okay, so we'll be adding this model. If you want to use any other model, you can simply do that.
Okay, you can go to the chat GPT, you can ask, I want to use this model.
What should be the model name?
You can use that. Then the next API key I need for internet search operation because as you see, we'll be integrating the tools, okay?
And for real-time search operation, we need a tool called tabily search.
So tabily search needs the API key.
So let's collect that API key as well.
So here, what I'm going to do, I'm going to search for tabily API key.
Okay, now let's
open this.
Here you have to log in with your account. Let's log in with my account,
and here you have the API key. Okay, so previously I already created the API key. I'll just try to copy, but if you don't have, just create from here.
So let's add the tabily API key here.
Tabily API key.
Okay,
yes.
Now uh tabily is also done.
Now, what I have done, guys, for this development, I also integrated Lang Smith here.
That means
I can continuously monitor my chatbot, the bub PGPT.
Okay, we are tracing on Langsmith platform. Let's log in my Langsmith.
So if you don't have the account, just create one account in Langsmith. You can continue with your Google.
Okay, so here you can see we created a identific chatbot test.
So here we are tracing everything, okay. Whatever chat we have done here, it is tracing everything. You can monitor from here,
okay. You can monitor from here, even you can also see the trades.
Okay, you can also see the trades, different different trades. Okay, everything is visible. So we'll be integrating the this Langsmith also inside this project.
So for this, you need Lang Langsmith API key.
Okay, so why do we get this API key?
It is available in settings
API key. Okay, now just create an API key.
So I already created my API key, I'll just try to use that. So for Langsmith tracing, guys, you need to add this four four variables here,
okay. The first thing Lang Smith tracing is equal to would be true, then Langsmith endpoint.
Um, this is the endpoint api.smith.langs.com, then langsmith API key. So this is the API key I have given, and here you have to give the project name. So here I'll tell give let's say
BubPGPT
Bub PGPT. So this is the project, okay. You can give any name. Uh so it will basically create that name here, uh that name here, and you'll trace all of the information there.
Okay, so yeah, so these are the API key as of now.
I need for this uh project, but if you want, you can also use uh any other API key, you can use real-time weather, uh weather, let's say API key to get the weather information.
You want you can also use any kinds of stock price uh uh stock price API key if you want to get the latest stock okay of any company. So this thing I already added inside my previous uh uh chatbot.
So this part I want to I want to leave it to you.
I want you to integrate these are the features okay inside this uh puppy gpt. So just try to add real-time weather information search and real time stock price, okay.
These are the things just try to add, and for this you can use any any other open open open source let's say API provider for that. So, yes, so these are my environment variable.
Now let me see my installation is complete or not. Yeah, so installation is completed, there is no error, okay? It's completely fine.
So, yeah, now uh what I'm going to do, I'm going to just push the changes.
Okay, so here you can just write requirement.
Requirements
and
API added.
Now, if I go to my GitHub
refresh,
see everything is up to date. Now,
what I have to do, guys, I have to create the folder structure.
whatever folders and file you need, I will just try to create, then I'll just uh uh implement all of the component one by one.
So now let's create the files and folder I need. So first of all, I need uh files here called agent.py.
So here I'm going to write my agent workflow, then I'll be creating another file called tools.py.
So here I will be writing all of the tools, okay? Tools functionality.
Then I need another one called rag.py.
So here I'm going to write all of the um rag related code that means document uploader vectors store everything.
Then I'm going to create another file called
database.py.
So here we'll just try to write all of the code related database, okay.
Database integration.
Then I need
anything else.
Okay, I need my endpoint, which is app.py.
Okay, so this is going to be my endpoint, my fast API endpoint.
And for HTML and CSS, I need a folder called template
templates. Okay, inside that I'm going to create a file called index dot HTML.
Okay, so inside that we'll be writing all of the HTML, CSA, JavaScript, related code in a single file.
Okay, and if you don't know about HTML is completely fine. Even I also took the help from chat GPT to generate my user interface, the user interface you have seen. Okay, this user interface.
So, yes, uh, as of now, this thing is required,
and if I need anything, I'll just try to create later on, okay. Now you can again, commit the changes, like "folders
and
". so "folders and file added Okay.
now, first of all, guys, what I'm going to do, I'm going to create my agent workflow.
So let's create the agent workflow. I'll just try to close this at the file.
So I'll open up my agent.py
and here we'll be creating our agent workflow with the help of line graph.
So let's import some necessary library.
We'll import all the necessary library and here make sure you select your environment, which is
this one
bub PGPT.
Okay, now this error would be
removed. Now here we are importing operating system sqlite path from pathlib, then dot env because we need to load this environment variable,
then certify.
Uh you need uh why certify is required because see sometimes if you're using Windows operating system, there would be some kinds of path related error,
okay.
To prevent that, this is the safer code you have to add.
Let me show you.
So this code you have to add, okay, waste.invironment SSL uh C E R T file, okay, uh certified.wire and request C
a bundle certified.wire. You have to add this two lines. So if you're using Windows operating system, uh you won't be getting the error related path issue.
So it uh doesn't happen to all the operating system.
Sometimes uh in uh in some operating system it happens, okay. That's why I added this code just for a separate purpose.
That means if you are executing my project in future, you won't be having any kinds of problem.
But if you're using Linux win uh macOS, I think this line is not required, but still, if you keep it, it will not
make harm okay in your in your project. So I'll just try to add it to prevent the path issue.
Then apart from that, I need some other um other libraries as well.
Yeah.
So these are the library I need.
And I think all the libraries are common, guys. Uh, here I don't need to explain these are the library again.
Uh, we are using this chat Google General TBI for this Mini model initialization system uh message we are importing from Langchain, then from Langgraph we are importing state graph,
start mass state.
Okay, then from pre-built we are importing tools node, tools condition, okay. Then checkpoint, we're using uh sqlite saber.
And from um okay, so this line I don't need to write as of now because whatever tools I'm going to write, I'm going to import here.
Okay. So yes, uh, these are the like uh import I need as of now. Now, what I'm going to do, guys. First of all, I'll just create a directory.
Okay, here I'll just create a directory.
So why directory is required?
Because uh I think you know that uh this uh langu graph will have a state, right?
so for our for our let's say this workflow, what would be the state?
Okay, state should be the message state. That means whatever user is giving the input message and my chatbot is replying whatever response, so this should be my state,
okay. That means if I create the workflow, so how my workflow will look like? Let's try to understand.
So for this, I created a demo.xxcalidor file, and here I just
created the architecture. So this is the architecture, guys. so this is my line graph workflow.
So here it will have a chat node and this will have a tool nodes, okay?
So whatever user will give the message it will go to the chat node and chat node will decide so here basically we'll be using something called tool condition.
This tool condition will decide whether it has to use any kinds of tool for this question or not.
If it doesn't need any kinds of tool, it will directly go to the end node, otherwise, it will use the tool now.
It will automatically select the tools like which tools is required to give the answer, and the response will go to the end node. Okay, so this is my uh this is my actually
uh workflow.
Okay, and what should be the state for this workflow?
So this should be the state, okay. This should be the chat chat state, that means whatever input user is giving and whatever response it is generating. Okay, this we have to add in the chat state.
So this should be the state, okay? So yeah, so if you want to save this state um in the uh in the actually physical database, that time we'll be using SQLite database because if I'm saving
inside my RAM, so if you close your application, this would be erased, okay.
But I don't want that, I want let's say if I close my application also, like chat GPT, still I'll be able to see all of my chat history and message, right?
So for this we'll be using SQLite uh SQLite database, and to save this SQLite database, we'll be creating a
data folder here, okay. So inside data folder, we'll try to create the database, SQLite database, and we'll try to save all of the checkpoint there.
Okay, so for this, this data folder is required.
So to create the data folder, I'm going to use this code.
Uh you can see I'm using path library and inside that I'm giving data data folder and I'm using mkdir command to create the
data folder. So, first of all, it will check whether this data folder is available or not. If available, it will not create, otherwise, it will create.
That's why I'm giving this parameter exist okay is equal to true.
Okay, yeah.
Now uh here we'll just try to define the list of the model uh we want to uh we want to show to the user.
Um
yeah, so these are the model guys I have considered for this project allowed model gemini 2.5 plush, gemini 2.5 pro and so on.
If you want to use any other model, you just need to rename this this uh dictionary and the default model if user is not giving any kinds of model, the default model I'm taking Gemini
2.5 plus from the environment variable. Okay, here we have already set.
Yeah, this is for the safer purpose. Okay, let's say if user is not giving any model by chance, that's why you can take the safer uh I mean default model,
okay.
Yeah, so once it is done, now we'll try to create a system prompt.
So this is the
system prompt, guys. I have prepared.
As you can see, you are a helpful identity assistant named Bappi GPT, similar to chat GPT. You can answer normal questions, use tools when needed.
Okay, search uploaded documents using rag tool, search web for the latest current information using tablet search. Remember important information using memory tool.
Okay, recall any kinds of old conversation using memory.
And you can also use calculator for mathematical operation. And here I have set some rules. Okay, so that's how you can change this prompt as per your requirement. I have given this system prompt.
Now the first thing, guys, uh, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to
build our agent, agent workflow.
so let's do that.
I already written that function. Let me show you. So here I'm not going to write from scratch because this code I have already written from scratch in my previous uh previous project implementation.
So most of the codes are common. There is no new thing we have added yet. That's why I will try to copy paste.
So see, this is my
function I have written named build agent. So this will take the model name, okay?
Because to
uh to uh create the agent, you need the model. And uh first of all, what I have to do, I have to normalize the model and. Normalize the model name means if user sometimes let's say he is giving
any other name, okay.
Let's say if it is not matching with this name, so that time um my code will give me error. So make sure whenever you are giving the model ID, make sure the ID should be same like that.
You can go to the Gemini documentation, you will see that they are giving the ID like that. Okay, so we have to give the same ID.
So if by chance from the front end I'm getting any other different name, I'll just try to normalize that first of all. So for this, we'll write a function here called normalize model name.
It will take the model name and it will do the normalize. First of all, it will check if not model name, use the default model.
Otherwise, first of all, it will do the strip operation, then it will check if model name is not in allowed model, return the default model. Otherwise, return the same model user is giving.
So this function we are applying here just to
just to what? Just to do the model name verification, the model name it is matching here or not.
Okay, yeah.
So this kinds of simple simple function you have to write inside your code so that your application would be more robust, okay? Because user can give anything, so you have to handle in the back end.
Now, here we are using this Gemini model chat Google generative way. we are giving the model temperature streaming is equal to true, and we are creating the llm object. Then
before creating the chat node, first of all, you remember I think we have to bind the tools okay with the llm because here we'll be using the tools, right? And for this, we need list of the tools.
We'll be creating the tools, okay. Just don't worry, I'll create the tools as of now. We haven't created so after binding, we'll be using this object lm with tools.
Now, here we have written another function for chat node.
So this is my chat uh chat uh chatbot nodes, and we are preparing the system masses and we are also giving this state, okay. And
here you can see we are using this uh llm with tools and we are doing the invoking operation, and after that, we are just returning the masses, okay.
Then the second node we are using the tool tool node. That means if you see the architecture, so this node is created now. We are creating this tool, this node.
Okay, tool node. So once tool node is created, we are creating the workflow state graph.
We are giving the message state.
Okay.
And message state is already available inside this line graph. Okay, you don't need to separately write that. It is already in built inside line graph.
If you are creating this kind of chatbot, you can directly use this message state. I think previous video I already discussed this part.
So message state we are taking, then we are adding the nodes. First of all, we have to add the
chat node, right? Then we have to add the tool node. So adding the chat node, then tool nodes, okay.
Then we are doing the edge connection. First of all, the start to chatbot,
start to chat chat node, okay.
Then uh we are using conditional edges, okay.
Condition is that means chatbot to tools condition, chatbot to tool condition, okay.
That means there would be tool condition, then
uh tool condition to chatbot,
tool condition to chatbot again. That means whatever response we'll be getting from the tools, right? This should be refined with my LLM. That means I may begin passing to the chat node.
So, yeah, this is the connection, and now we have to give the persistence memory, which is my
sqlite. So here we are already creating the data folder. I think you remembered
this data folder.
So inside data folder, we are creating a database object called Langgraphcheckpoint.sqlite, and sqlite is a local database you can create inside your storage only.
Okay, if you want, you can also use any remote database as well.
Okay, you can set up this.
This is on any server, and you can use that. But again, for this, you need a cloud platform like AWS, okay. Then has your GCP. So there you can set up the database server, you can store all of the
store all of the data, but again, I'm using the free resources, that's why I'm using the local one.
Okay,
for this you don't need to pay anything. Then same trades is equal to false.
So this thing you have to make and this will become your connection object.
Now you will be initializing the escalate server, and this connection object will pass here, and this will become your check pointer,
and this check pointer you will be using whenever you will do the workflow compilation.
Okay, done.
So this is what you have to just write for this build agent.
Okay, so now guys, uh, it's done. Now the next thing we have to prepare the tools, and again, I'm telling you guys all of this concept I have completed in my playlist, okay.
Just go through one by one all of the concept you can see tools, rag, okay, agentic chatbot, workflow, okay. Each and everything I have already discussed in my playlist. Just try to go through that.
if you are first time in this implementation, you might get difficulties for sure, okay. But if you cover all of this recording, you won't be any kinds of uh you won't be having any kinds of problem.
Okay, this is my promise. So that's why I'm telling you, I'm not going to focus on the theoretical part, I'm only going to focus on the practical development because theory I have already covered.
Okay, yes.
So, yes, so now let's work on the tool.
so for tool, guys, what I'm going to use, I'm going to use this tools.py, and inside that I'm going to mention all of the tools I'll be using in this project.
So, first of all, let's import all of the necessary library.
Um,
yeah,
so I'll import math module uh.enb, then we'll load the environment variable.
Okay.
Then here
we have imported tools from Langchain Code Tools, then Langchain tabily where you importing tabily starts.
Okay,
yeah.
So, first of all, um here what I'm going to do, I'm going to initialize some tools.
First of all, I'm going to use this
Okay, web search tool. So I'm using tabily, and here we're giving the some parameter like max result topic.
Okay, search depth. These are the parameters we are giving, and this will become your tool. And here you don't need to use the tool decorator because tabily is already a tool.
Okay, so you don't need to give that.
And I need a other tool as well, like I need calculated tool.
So this is my calculated tools.
So you can see this is a simple custom function we have written for calculator.
It will take any kinds of expression and it will do the mathematical operation, and it will return the result.
And if you want to use as a tool, I have to use this tool decorator.
Okay, that means website and calculator we have added. Now we'll be adding some more tools, like
we'll be adding the
memory tool. That means you can save any kinds of
information if user is giving let's say user is giving remember something, okay.
It will use that memory tool and it will save that information in the long-term memory, and for this we have to use the database. So we'll be writing that thing as a tool.
Then if you want to search memory, that means if you want to get any older conversation, which you did long time ago, it will retrieve from the database, okay.
So again, for this, we will be writing a tool, okay. So that's how we'll be writing different different tool and then one more tool you need, which is this
rag tool. That means if user wants to search something over the documents, you can use the rag tool. So this part we'll just try to write, but before that, we'll be writing another function
called trade.
This trade is required because here I think you saw we will be using the trade, right? Different different trades.
Okay, user can create different different trades, okay.
And anytime they can switch between another trades, so for this, every time we'll be using the trades.
So for this, here I have written another function called set current trades, and if user gives any kinds of trade ID here,
it will try to set that particular trades and this trade will be considered in that particular session. And by default, if the user is not giving any trades, it will be using the default trades, okay.
So this trading concept I also discussed in my playlist. You can go through that now. First of all, what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to use the database related
database related tools. So for this, there is a file I have written called database.py.
Let's open it up and let me show you
all of the
function you need here.
I already written this code, let me show you.
Very simple.
Only the database operation I have written, and here we are using SQL alchemy database. Okay, for this you need the knowledge on SQL Alchemy.
If you don't know, just go through any YouTube video and try to understand SQL Alchemy how it works with Python.
So here we're importing dead time, path leave, sql alchemy, very uh importing create engine, column, integer, string, text, date time, sql alchemy
or importing ORM, okay, uh declarative base, session maker. Each and everything you will see from the tutorial itself. I'm not going to explain this here because again, this is a theoretical concept.
You can understand this thing from a YouTube tutorial how SQL Alchemy works. But this is a simple code I have written. Basically, this code will try to connect with the SQL Alchemy server.
So here we're creating a local server, you can see.
Okay, we'll be creating a local server. If you want, you can also install this SQL Alchemy in the remote server.
for this again, I told you you need to use AWS GCP or any other cloud provider, there you can set up that, but again, that would be costly.
That's why I'll be using the local one just to show you the free resources. So, again, we are creating the data data folder, okay.
Data folder.
Why every time we're creating the data folder? Because if data is not data folder is not there, first of all, it will create, and inside that it will save this db object, okay.
So every time you need to check, okay.
and this parameter you have to provide if already available, no need to create. Otherwise, just try to create.
Okay, so this is my database URL, SQLite clone.
then you have to give slash data folder inside that chatbot memory.db. This object would be created, okay. Inside that we'll try to save all of the information.
First of all, you're creating the engine, okay. where you're providing the database URL and some connection method.
Then we're getting a session, okay.
After getting the session, we are creating some class. You can see first of all, this class will return you the schema like table name, ID, trade ID, title, created at updated at okay.
This is called actually uh schema, okay.
Uh database schema, then chat message, for chat message. We are uh returning the schema like ID, trade ID, role, content, created at okay.
These are the information we'll try to save inside chat message and for long time uh long term memory.
That means if user wants to save any kinds of long-term conversation, that time we'll try to set ID, trade ID, memory.
That means the conversation and the created when it got created, okay.
And the table name should be long term memory that time, and for chat message, that means the regular message, whatever message user will perform, it will become as a chat message
table.
Okay, now we are initializing the database with this function, and this is the function for create or update conversation. So this will take the trade ID and the message, okay.
If you give if you give the message, it will update that conversation in the table.
Okay, so you can see here we have written the code for that,
okay, and this code will also help you to prepare these trades.
Okay, that means every time you can see whenever user is passing any kinds of message it is taking the message title and it is only taking the 40 character of that. So this part I'm doing here.
Okay, so from the user masses, uh first message, I'm taking the first 40 character and I'm preparing a title and I'm showing you inside the trade masses.
Okay, so this is what actually we have written here in this function.
Then once it is done, we are listing all of the conversation.
Okay, listing conversation means uh whatever conversation we have here, okay.
Uh, we are listing all of the conversation with this
with this function, okay. Then
save chat masses, okay. That means if you if user wants to save any kinds of masses, so it will be using this function for that.
Then if user wants to get any kinds of history, previous story, it will be using this function for that. So it is only doing the database operation.
You can see it is uh uh adding adding the data, it is retrieving the data, that's how it's working.
If user wants to save any memory,
any kinds of let's say let's say I I'm telling my chatbot I am Bubby, okay. Try to remember me.
That time it will use this function, will be using this function as a tool, okay, as a long-term memory. That's why we are using this schema that time, okay. Now let me go below.
And if user wants to search anything about the previous question, that time we'll be using this function as a tool that time, okay, for a long time,
long-term memory uh concept. So, yes, uh, this is the um database related code, guys. I have written and will be using uh inside our tools right now.
Now let me import
uh these are the functionality first of all. So you see from this database I only need to import
from database.
I need to import save memory and search memory. Okay, save memory I'll be using to save my conversation and search memory. I need to
get my previous conversation, okay. Old conversation.
Now these two things I will be defining as a tool.
Let me do that
so.
Here I'll just try to add after calculator.
Remember this. Okay, if user is asking just to remember anything, it will use this tool that time, okay.
And it will take the conversation and will save inside the memory. And for this, we are using this save memory,
this function, save memory, and we are defining as a tool, and one more thing we need the
recall memory.
If user wants to let's say
if user is asking about old old conversation, let's say if user is asking what is my name or what was my hobby,
that time it will use the recall memory tool and it will search the memory that is in the database, it will search the old conversation and it will return that.
Okay, so these two things I have used as a tool.
I hope you get it, and one more tool I have to create.
Um
more tool I'll be creating here
called this rag tool.
Just a minute, yeah. One more tool I need called rag tool.
Okay, rag tool you need. Let's say if user is uploading any kinds of documents.
So, this document uh um you have stored in the vector database, okay. And from the vector database, you will be performing the retrieving retrieving operation.
That means you will try to retrieve the informations for this. This tool is required.
So let's create this rag tool here.
I'm going to open this rag.py inside that I'm going to write all of the rag related code, and again, this rag related code is uh uh
common from my previous implementation. First of all, let's import the necessary libraries.
Okay, I'm importing these necessary libraries, then again I need that
environment related
command. That means if you are getting the path issue, that time this code will help you to prevent that, and some other library I need.
These are the library like from Langchain, we're importing Chroma, Chroma DB, then Google generative embeddings.
We'll be using Google Generative BI embeddings model, then documents we are importing from Langchain code, then recursive character text Peter for the chunking operation.
Okay, what is chunking?
What is uh why chunk is required in the rag each and everything I have discussed in my rag video.
So here, okay. Implement rag in agentic chat, but you can go through that,
yeah.
Then PyPDF reader because we'll be considering the PDF document. But if you want, you can also upload any other document as well, txt docs, okay. It's completely up to you.
Then doc to text. Then here we'll be creating two more directory.
One is the uploads, okay.
Let's say whatever document user is uploading, I'll try to store in the uploads folder, okay. For this you're getting the directory, and on one more vectory we're creating called ChromaDB.
Okay, let's say whenever it is creating the vector store, right?
Chroma DB actually use your local storage to save the information. That means the vector is stored. So that time it will create a ChromaDB directory. Inside that, it will save everything. That's it.
Two directory we're creating, then we'll be initializing the embedding model.
So this is our embedding model.
Okay, we are using Gemini, Gemini embedding 001.
This model.
Now we'll be creating the vector store.
So this is our vector store.
We are using Chroma DB, and this is the name of the collection name Agentic Chatbot Docs.
We are giving the embedding model and we are providing the Chroma DB path.
Here you can use any vector database, you can use Pinecone, Vo8, whatever you want, you can use any vector database.
Okay, it's not like that. You have to use Chroma DB always.
Now, here I have written a function.
So, this function, what it does, let me show you. This function basically reads the
uh reads uh reads the reads uh file text. Okay, that means if you give provide any file, it will read read that whether it is a PDF or whether it's it's in a doc format.
Okay, so basically, here you can upload txt MD PI csv.
Okay, and you can load that. But here we are considering the docs and PDF format.
And if you want, you can also load these at the documents as well.
So once it's read everything, it will load that. Like if it is PDF, it will use the PDF reader to read that documents.
Okay. If it is docs, it will use the docs to text and it will load that.
Okay. And if you want to consider like mdpy, you can write another other condition as well.
So it will use that and it will load that. But here by default, I have written the code. Uh I'm using path.read text. Okay.
So what it does, if you are providing this txt, mdpy, csb, it can still load that documents and it can extract the content from that.
Okay, and
there is an exception I have given unsupported file like upload pdf docs txt md pi or csb.
if user is passing any other file format, let's say dot pickle or any other file, that time I'll raise the exception.
Okay, so exception has handling is also required whenever you are doing this kinds of scenario.
So, yeah, this is the function to load the documents. Now
we'll be writing the final function to create the vector store.
So this is the function we'll be using to create the vector store as you can see.
Add documents to react, it will use the file path and the trade ID.
Then we are doing the chunking operation, we are giving the chunk size and chunk overlap, creating the chunking, then we are we are taking the paste content,
okay.
that means content from the documents and we're storing in the vector store, okay, and we are returning the path. So this function will basically create the vector store, okay?
Vector database, and it will store everything in the vector store.
Okay, now for retrieve operation, that means if user is asking anything regarding the documents, it will retrieve the information by using the simulator
source. I think you know every vector database is having a similarity source okay, operation. So in this function, we are doing that.
So retrieve from RAG where user is giving the query as well as the trade and the k parameter.
So by default, k parameter is four, that means four relevant information it will extract from the vector database. We are doing the similarity source operation that means retrieve operation.
After that, whatever result we are getting, we're just loading inside result and we are returning it, returning it as a string.
Okay, so this is what we are doing inside retrieve from lag, and this function will be using as a tool right now.
So here what I'm going to do, I'm going to open up my agent, sorry, tool, and here I will try to import that function.
So let's import
um the function name is retrieve from rag.
So let's import it here. So from
rag
import
retrieve
what's the name?
retrieve from rag.
Okay, we will be importing here, and now we'll just try to create a tool.
So here maybe I can create the tool. So this is the tool name.
search uploaded documents. User will give the query and we'll be using retip from rag. This function will pass the query trade id, and it will give me the relevant answer, okay.
For that query, we are using this this code for that. So I think now you have understood like how we have arranged everything, how we have prepared all of the tool.
Okay, we have created the database tool, we have created the rag tool, we have created a search tool, we have created a calculated tool, each and every tools are ready, okay.
Now in the agents,
we'll be importing the tools right now.
Let's import the tools.
So here we'll just write
from
tools
import
tools.
okay, so we have to create a tool object. So here at the last, what I'm going to do,
I'm going
to just prepare the list of the tools.
So yeah, so you can see it is a list.
Inside that first of all, I'm passing the calculator, then search uploaded documents. Remember this, recall, and web search.
All the tools we have created, we are just passing one by one here.
Okay. Now, if you want to add any other tools in future you can add it here.
So I'm going to give you a task, guys. You just try to add the real time with the weather search tool and stock price tool.
Okay, this tool two tool you can add at least here.
Okay, now this thing we are importing here.
Tools.
Now we are using this tool for the bind operation.
Okay, now we are doing the bind operation and our
workflow is getting created.
Okay, so that means still here everything is fine, everything is good.
Okay, now one thing I will do before the testing.
See, here we are building the agent, right? So it's not necessary to build the agents every time whenever you are initializing the chatbot, okay?
Because if you're building from scratch, so I mean it will take some time, right? So instead of that, maybe we can create a cache agent cache that means we can build one time and save in the cache,
and every time whenever it will um uh reinitialize the chatbot instead of building from again, we can take the agent from the cache. Okay, so for this, this code is required.
So simply you can write this code. So here I created a dictionary called agent cache,
and we created a function called get agent. So you will only pass the model, okay?
Model name.
So what will happen? This will go to the normalize model name function and you will get the correct model name, and you are checking if selected model
in agent cache, okay, not in agent cache, then you will try to build the agents, okay?
Otherwise, what you are doing, you are taking the existing agent only, so you are not building again the agent again and again, okay. So this thing you can write now.
We can test whether this uh workflow is working or not. So I can open up my rag dot sorry app.py and here I can test it. So I'll just try to import import um
from
agent
input,
get agent.
now.
Agent is equal to get agent.
Here you have to pass the model name.
So let's say I'll give the same name
this model name I'll give
so it will only take the model name, I think.
Yeah, model name.
Okay, now we can do the invoke operation.
Yeah, so we have written this code for testing, okay? So here we are using this streaming, right?
So that's why instead of invoking, I'm just doing agent.stream, and we are giving the human message here, and stream will return a generator object, and for this we are using this for
loop and we're getting the answer token by token and we're streaming that.
And here is the code.
So let's test it whether it's working or not. I will open up my terminal and uh I'll just execute python app.py
now. See all the folders are getting created.
Now, here we are getting the response as you can see, streaming response.
So, this is the block about uh machine learning we got.
See, okay, that means everything is working fine, and here we are given uh like uh testing trade just to test
the workflow because this workflow needs a trade right here, right? We are we have given a testing trade here in this configuration.
Now you can see um
all of the folders got created, and you can see this is your state uh state actually um state database, it is serving inside SQLite,
and this is the Chroma DB.
Um that means the vector database will be creating here, and the upload folder as well. As of now, we haven't uploaded anything, that's why it's coming like that.
Now we can ask anything uh that may use any tool. Let's say I will ask,
tell me
today's.
news of
AI.
So definitely it will use the tool that Miss Tabili search tool.
Let's see.
Now see it has done the internet search operation with the help of tabily,
and it found the result, okay, regarding the today's news of AI, and you can see it has referred different different website here, okay. Different different website URL are present.
Okay, so from this URL it has extracted the news, and this is what we got in the answer, and one best part is that you can also
see this database that means whatever messages are available inside that. So for this, you have to install one extension called SQLite
okay, viewer.
So this extension you have to install.
So this is the like author.
You can install this extension. I already installed that now. After installing this, you will be able to see your data data sorry, database.
Now let's double-click and you will see that all of the information it has saved here, all of the like checkpoint you can see.
Okay, all of the checkpoint it has saved here
with the trade ID as well. And trade ID is nothing but test ID as of now we have given.
So now let's uh test the long-term memory as well. That means uh it is able to save my um save uh my long-term memory in my uh conversation database or not.
I think remember we used the SQL SQL Alchemy database for that, right? so if you are um if you are let's say doing any kinds of conversation with your chatbot if you want to remember something,
okay. That means the long-term conversation, it will also remember with the help of this database. So for this, we'll test that.
that's why I have given a prompt. My name is Bhappi. Remember that.
And I think you know that in database, database.py we created a function called
SaveMemory, okay. Save memory, and this thing I created as a tool.
Now inside tools.py, you'll see that this uh remembered these uh tools will be using this save memory, save memory function.
Okay, that means if user is giving any kinds of conversation, it will save inside the memory, the SQL alchemy memory, right?
And you it will automatically use that tool.
If user wants to remember something, it will use this tool and it will store that conversation in the database itself. Okay, we'll try to test this part. So for this, we are giving this prompt.
My name is Bappi. Remember that, and if you want to execute, first of all, you have to initialize the database, okay?
Because if you check the database inside that we created a function called uh init db. Okay, we have to initialize the database.
First of all, database would be created, all the table would be created, then we'll be able to store that.
So let's import it. So in the app.py from database
import
init db, then we'll try to initialize the database. Okay, now I think it will work. Let's test it.
I'll open up my terminal,
clear, now I'll execute my app.py.
Now you can see that memory saved successfully, got it, Bappi. I remembered your name. Now, if I go back, now you'll see that this database uh database is created, chatbot memory.
This is my SQL alchemy database. Now, if I open this, okay, now you'll be able to see the table.
Okay, all the three table has created chat messages, conversations, and long-term memory, and it will save in the long term memory. I think remember in the database.
So I think remember, whenever it will save something, right?
Save memory,
it will use my
long-term memory, of the long-term table, long-term memory table. So in the long-term memory table, you'll see that it has saved my information. My name is Puppy.
Okay, so that's how uh it will it is working.
Okay, so right now, if you are asking, let's say,
what is my name?
Now it will use that. sorry, not here.
I have to ask it here.
What is
my
name?
Now it will use that um
uh tool that means this tool again
recall memory tool, and it will search in the memory that means in the database, and it will get this information until the reply that. Let me show you.
Okay, you can see your name is Bhakpi, so it is using
your conversation story.
Okay, that means your long term long-term memory. Yeah, so everything is working fine, guys. Uh uh, we have already tested and our workflow is working great. Now, what we have to do, guys?
We have to uh we have to
uh create the front end, that means the user interface will be taking all of the masses from the user and we'll try to connect with the backend.
That means we'll create a fast API server and there we'll try to make the communication.
Okay, so to for the front end, guys, uh, here we will be using this HTML uh file, index.html file.
Inside that we'll be writing all of the HTML, CSS, JavaScript code, whatever you need for this user interface.
Okay, the user interface we created. And again, if you are not familiar with these kinds of HTML, CSS, okay,
JavaScript, no need to worry. Even I also took the help from Chat GPT.
I already generated this template from Chat GPT and chat GPT written that HTML, CSS, JavaScript code for me, whatever required for this
user interface, okay. But uh in your team, there would be some kinds of person they will be working on this front-end design part. You don't need to worry about that. So let me show you.
This is the code I have generated from chat GPT, guys. Again, you don't need to remember this code.
You can take from uh you can generate this code from ChatGPT or Gemini, whatever you want. So here is the HTML, CSS, everything I've written in the single file itself.
This is the design of that front end, each and everything you can see.
Color.
So this is a big file.
See,
okay,
all of the front end uh code I have written here, and the see this is the JavaScript code. Okay, so in the JavaScript, some um
that means uh back end API is getting triggered as well. I'll show you.
These are the part.
See, this is the entire code we have generated from chat GPT.
Okay, chat GPT, and one more thing I have done.
I think you saw the voice mode, right? Here is the voice mode. See this is void mode you can add two way. you can use uh python voice API inside python.
I think you know there is a library called speech uh speech recognization library. You can use that for this voice voice mode. Either in already this um uh Java script.
Okay, JavaScript there is a library.
there is a library called let me show you
this voice features.
Yeah, so here is the code part. So in JavaScript, uh there is a already inbuilt library called speech recognization. So here we we're using this speech recognization library here, okay.
You can see we're using this speech recognization library, and automatically it will um use your Windows microphone, okay, and
it will start listening you okay, and whatever uh speech you will give, and it will try to listen, it will try to understand, and it will try to convert that speech to text.
Okay, so this is already available inside JavaScript. Uh if you have already studied about JavaScript, I think you know that this library is available.
So you don't need to separately write inside Python, okay? You can directly use the JavaScript functionality here.
So we have already used the JavaScript functionality and we are doing the speech recognization. That means this part.
Okay, now if you click here, it will start listening, okay, and you can like tell something and it will automatically recognize that. So we are using this part here, okay.
So yes, this is the entire HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code we have written inside HTML and index.html and this code you can generate um from chat GPT Gemini
anywhere.
Even you can also copy this code and you can give uh give it to the chat GPT and you can ask explain this code in a simple manner, you'll see that it will explain like what are the functionality
it has already.
Okay, but don't worry, this uh front-end part um you can implement
with any kinds of front-end developer. You can see it with them, you can just tell your expectation what kinds of front end you need, they will try to develop for that.
But uh uh if you're creating production grade uh like uh application, better to use any front-end framework for that, like next.js
is there, okay.
In market
next.js is there, react is there, okay. These are the framework you can use for these kinds of front end development, okay.
But here uh we are creating this front end with the help of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
Now, let me show you how this uh design will look like. For this, uh, we'll just write our first API code, that means our first api server.
So for this, we can write inside our app.py.
Let's open it up, and this part we can maybe keep inside our test.py. Okay, let's create another file called test.py.
I'm not going to delete it, I'm just keeping it just for your reference. Okay.
Now in the app.py I'll just remove everything.
Now let's import all the necessary library.
Yeah, so again, I will import
this.enbow certify, and this is for the path issue. Okay, we have to add, then we'll be importing the fast API
related functionality.
So you can see we're importing just on UI ID. I need for this trading, okay. Every time we need to create a unique trade, and for this UI ID is required, then if you go on fast API, okay.
Fast API from fast API we're importing, these are the libraries, okay.
And here we'll be showing the streaming response, and inside fast API, already streaming response function is there, you can use that.
Then just on response, then Jinja template. So these are the things we need, and definitely you should have little bit knowledge on fast API, okay. How fast API works here. Then
from
Langchain, we'll be importing these are the functionality.
So we are importing human messages, AI message, AI message chunk, tool messes.
Okay, so basically, we'll be doing the verification, like what kinds of response we are getting from the workflow, whether it is human message, AI message, okay,
or AI message chunk, tool message. Based on that, we'll try to filter out the content.
And apart from that, I also need to import my agent.
Okay, agent from agent, we are importing our get agent function. This will return me the agent.
Let me close these are the things.
Then after that, we'll be importing some other
functionality from the database.
So from database we are importing init database, init uh db, save chat masses. Okay, that means this function, save chat message.
then we are importing get chat history,
okay. Get chat history, then create or update conversation, this function, and list conversation.
Okay, these are the functionality I need.
Then from rag and tools, I will import.
So from rag, I will import this add documents to rag.
That means if user is asking any uh uploading any document, will tries to call this function first of all, it will add the document to the rag.
Okay,
that means my vector is stored.
Then from tools we are importing send current trade ID because every time I need to create a unique trade ID if user is creating the trades, okay. So these are the functionality I need to import.
Now let's initialize the fast API.
So we'll initialize the fast API.
That's how we can initialize the fast API and we can redirect the folder. That means the templates inside templates folder. I have my HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code.
That's why you are giving this directory. Then we are again creating this two folder if it is not available, uploads and data, and we'll be initializing the database, my SQL Alchemy
database. Okay, database should be initialized first of all.
Then let's create the default route.
So this is our default route, okay?
And here we are using uh asynchronous asynchronous programming, guys. Uh, because instead of running my
endpoint as a sequence, I can run in parallel, and this concept I have already told you, I have already discussed in my playlist. You can see asynchronous programming is available.
You can go through that, okay. Why asynchronous programming is required for AI agents, okay?
especially it is already integrated in Fast API. If you are using Fast API, you can integrate this asynchronous programming.
So please go through this session, you will understand why asynchronous programming is required. I'm not going to explain this part, okay.
Again, so yeah, that's why I'm using essence keyword, and this is my home route. That means my default route. If user is visiting our let's say server, you will be able to see that index.html page.
Okay, we are rendering that here now. Let me show you.
Let's
render it.
Here we'll try to render. So here we'll mention two more things in my environment variable, which is
the
app host and app port.
Or you can also directly write here.
Host should be
point zero point zero point zero.
This is my local host at port number. I will give
eight zero eight zero.
Okay, now this two part I don't need.
Here it should be app because my file name is app and inside that I'm creating a app app uh object.
Okay, now this is my host, this is my port, and it will reload every time whenever you will change something. And with the help of uvicon, we are running the first API server.
Yeah, so everything is fine. Now let me execute and show
you. so first of all,
I'll close my previous application. Okay, previous application is also running.
Now let's clear.
Now python.py
now I'll give the permission
now it is running on post number localhost port number 8080.
Let's open it up.
Local host port number 8080.
So this is the interface, guys. Okay, we have created uh with the help of chat GPT. Okay, so it has all the button, this chat input box, document uploader option, this voyage option.
Then you can select the models from the front end, send the prompt. Okay, so each and everything we have created here. Now we have to make it as functional.
So, first of all, uh, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to write more route here.
So,
first of all, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to write a route. That route will fetch all of my previous trades. I have done the chat operation.
Okay, that means uh if you saw like uh previously, it is you can see all of the trades. Previously, whatever trades I did the conversation, right?
You can switch between any of the trades, you can see that. So, this thing I have to fetch for this. What I can do, I can write a route
here. So, this is the route
after this home route. I'll add this okay, slash conversation. Okay, and this last conversation we are calling inside my JavaScript.
Let me show you
here.
This is the function we have written. So this will basically call this route, okay, and it will load all of the conversation conversation trades and it will show in the front end, okay.
Now let me show you.
If I refresh,
no chats is available.
Okay, now let me do the chat and let me show you.
Because right now we haven't done any chat operation, right? That's why it's not showing.
Okay, this is the first time we are doing right. So, first time you won't be able to see the conversation, but let's complete it, then I will show you.
Okay, yeah, then uh the second thing we have to add, which is
this uh this one actually, these features. So let's say now if I switch to any any let's say um uh trades.
So let me run this previous app, then I think I can explain better.
Yeah, now this is running. Now see if I click on any of the trades, right?
So you'll see that the previous conversation story I am able to see that. Okay, that means each of the trades is having a conversation, okay. So this conversation uh I have to also load for this.
I'll be creating another route in my fast API server.
So this is the work of Fast API, right? You can create different different route and you can treat uh hit that route anytime, okay. From your uh JavaScript code or any other code, you can hit that.
So here, this is the route I have created called history, and it will take the trade ID as well. That means which trade you want to see the conversation. Okay, you have to give the trade ID.
So trade ID. So basically, this will get this story.
Okay, how we'll get this story because we are using this
get history function from the database. Okay, and previously here you can see for conversation we are using list conversation function.
Okay, it will list all of the conversation. So these two functions we are using here, okay. And this
slash story we're calling inside my
JavaScript.
Let me show you.
See, here we are calling this last story.
Okay, first of all, you're getting the um traits, then we are getting the history and all of the messages you are able to see that.
Okay, so this is the function you need here
done now. The next functionality I have to write for the upload operation. Let's say if user is uploading any kinds of documents, if they are uploading any kinds of documents, what will happen?
Let's try to do that.
So for this, I have written this function,
written this route.
This is the route,
okay. Slash upload.
So it will uh take the uploaded documents, and after that, here we are calling that function.
Let me show you. So we are taking the file name, we are taking the file, and we are generating the unique ID of the file, okay.
Then here create and upload the conversation, okay.
Uh, so here uh basically we are calling this function just to uh just to save the message. Let's see, user has uploaded any documents here. It will also save in the story.
That means the database story.
We are using this function, and here we are using this add uh documents to the rag.
This function, so this function basically will read that documents, process it, and it is stored in the vector database.
Okay, then we are returning the response.
So I think you are getting okay what we are doing here.
Very simple, okay. So every time whatever user is doing, you have to save in the database, okay. All the activity you have to save in the database, then you are doing the other stuff.
Now we'll do this general conversation.
Like
if user is asking anything, this will hit my
chat route.
That means I will be able to see my streaming response.
So this is for this, this is the function I have written.
Okay, again, I'm using asynchronous because I want to run in parallel. so I named it as chat stream. so this is the route slash chat slash stream.
and
this thing also, you are calling from this
JavaScript.
okay. as you can see. So JavaScript is hitting that route, and
we are taking the user message trade, okay.
Trade we are taking, and every time whenever let's say
user is clicking on new, okay, new, that means new button.
That time, what will happen? one New trade would be created, and here we are setting the trade at that time.
So trade we are taking, selected model we are taking, then we are preparing the user message, we are initializing the agent as you can see.
We are calling the get agent function, and this will give me the agent, okay. After that, we are updating the conversation in the database, then we are saving the chat message as well.
That means every time it will save the conversation, okay. Whatever conversation user is doing, while it will set in the chat message, that means in the chat message table here in this table, okay.
It will save all the conversation.
After that, we are setting the current trade ID, we are preparing the config, that means the trade, and we are written, we have written another function called event
generator. Okay, so here it is using asynchronous.
Uh, so here basically what we are doing, we're preparing the human message, then we are running the stream stream code.
You can see we are doing this agent.stream, we are passing all of the input and configuration, and we are just showing the answer token by token.
And for this, we are using some kinds of utility function like should stream chunk, then SSE data. Okay, these are the things you need.
Uh, because sometimes, whenever you are uh uh calling any kinds of tool, tool will give you the raw response, and this raw response you don't want to show in the front end, right?
So for this, you have to do the some filter operation. So this code I have written here, let me show you.
So this is the code. These are the utility function unit.
Yeah.
SSC data.
Then should stream chunk. So basically, it will first of all check whether it is a tool tool response.
Okay. Then it is a AI message or not. Okay, these kinds of things, verification it will do.
Then it will extract the text from the chunk. That means instead of getting the raw message, it will only take the content and it will return you.
Okay. So this is what actually we are using in this function. You can see we are using in this function.
should stream extract from chunk as a token by token, then we are showing it in the console. And every time we're doing the yield operation, okay.
So if you're using uh asynchronous, I think you know what is yield, right?
Uh you can go through that recording, okay.
Then we are using um fast API streaming response function, and we're giving this event generator
uh function inside that.
Okay, so basically, this will show my response as a streaming one by one token.
Yeah, so yes, uh, this is the uh code you just need to write in the fast API server, fast API uh endpoint.
Now I think everything is ready.
Let me see.
So everything is ready. Now we can test our app.
I'll come here, refresh.
Okay, now let's do chat operation.
Hi,
I am buppy.
Let's send it. Okay, if you send it, so what will happen?
It will hit that
this route, okay. Chat stream route.
So you can see uh hi buppy. It's nice to meet you. How I can help you today, and it has also taken the trade right now. I can create another trade again. I'll do some message. Let's say
my name is
Okay, okay, Alex. I have saved your memory. Nice to meet you. Okay, this is another trade. This is another trade. Okay, and if I click here, you can see the conversation here.
Okay, you can see the conversation here.
Why it is happening? Because of this two functions, two um
two method.
One is this last conversation, it is uh it is actually um filtering out all of the trades you have in the database.
Now, if I show you my database, right?
The chat memory database. Now, see every time whatever conversation you are doing, chat message you are doing.
Yeah, so I have refreshed now. You see, this conversation is available. So, whatever conversation you are doing, right? Hi, my name is Bappi.
Okay, blah blah blah. All the conversation you will see with the trade ID here, okay.
Trade ID here, and here is the conversation,
and here is the long-term memory.
Okay, so that's how we are saving inside our database every time.
Now let's test uh any other message. Let's say I'll tell tell me
the latest
news
in AI. So basically uh it will use the search tool that time. Let's see.
See, it is using web search tool
and see you are getting the response.
Now let's ask another question
calculate
this.
You'll see that it will use calculator tool.
And this is the response. Now you can also upload any documents. So if you are uploading right now, so it will hit this route.
Upload route slash upload. This one. Okay, and it will create the vector stored.
You can see that vector is to be created, and you can perform the chat operation on top of that. Let's upload, let's have a upload.
Done. Now you can see the uploaded documents as well. It is available in the upload folder. See the document you have uploaded, it is available. Now we can perform the chat operation. Who is
Boktier
Ahmed
Bappif.
Now it will use document search that means the RAG tool. Okay. Now you can see that the my vector story is created.
So this is my vector story.
Okay, so this is the beauty of this um chatbot.
Now see it is telling about me, right?
Okay, everything is working fine. Now let's test the voice mode whether it's working or not.
Um
I'll give the permission.
How many years of experience Buktier Ahmed Bhapi is having
okay? It is not able to recognize my name.
Okay, let me do it again.
How many years of experience he is having?
Now good. Now let's send it
now. See, based on the uploaded documents, Buktira Ramad Bhappi has five plus years of experience. Amazing, it's working fine. Okay, even you can do the voice mode as well, dictate mode as well.
Okay, now you can select different different model. Let's I'll select this model.
Now you can ask anything.
Uh tell me about
Now see, it is telling you about ML.
Now you can generate code, you can do real-time source operation, you can upload your documents, you can use the voice mode, you can create different different trades.
Okay, anything you can do like chat GPT. Okay, so our application is prepared. Now we have given some suggestion. You can also use this suggestion to prepare a like instance prompt.
Okay, instant prompt. This is also possible. So, yes, guys, uh, that's how we have created the entire system, and uh this is uh like a chat GPT application we have created.
Our own chat GPT we have created now. We can deploy this application over the cloud and we can make it live so that other people can use it.
And uh, my request would be to everyone just try to upgrade this uh application as much as you can. Just try to add integrate more features, okay?
Just try to integrate more features, more tool. See here, I have used few tools, right? I have used uh very few tools here.
What is the tools?
Um, here is the tools. Okay, I have used very few tools here. You can use as much as tool you can.
Okay, just try to use as much as tool you can and make it like more powerful.
Okay, now you can
um also test the memory.
My fave colors is
red.
Is red okay.
Now you'll see that
it will save this information in the memory.
Okay. Now you can ask
what is
my favorite color.
Now it will use the long-term memory to give you the response.
Now see your favorite colors is red.
Okay. Now you can also see in the long-term memory.
You can open this memory, you can go to the long-term memory refresh.
So you'll see that
my favorite color is red.
Okay.
Everything is available. Now in the Lang Smith, also you'll see that it's tracing your
execution.
Now see Bap PGPT.
Now all of the trades you can see, even the trades as well.
In which trades, how many conversation you have done, each and everything you can see here.
Okay, all of this thing you can monitor here, everything you can debug here. Okay, see everything is available.
And this monitoring part also I told you in my playlist.
Like how to monitor your AI agents.
And I already explained about this Langsmith. Okay, you can go through that. So, yes, guys, everything is working fine.
we are good.
now we'll try to deploy this project over the AWS cloud as a CI CD.
We'll just try to make it live because right now it's running on localhost. Now we'll make it live, we'll try to do the CI CD deployment here.
So, guys, uh our app is ready. Now we'll be deploying this uh application uh as a CI CD over the AWS cloud, but before that, let me push all the changes
because we have updated all of the component one by one.
So, simply here. I'm going to give
um
updated all
component.
then I will push the changes.
and apart from that, I also added the deployment state here, as you can see.
Uh this is the deployment step will be following.
let me show you.
So now if I refresh in my GitHub,
so see all the codes are updated, okay.
And this is the deployment step, guys. will be following.
So here, first of all, I will be logging with my WS console, then there I will be creating I'm user that means identity access management.
After that, uh uh there we'll just try to um give some of the permission, okay.
like what are the services we'll be using? So here we'll be using EC2 instance and ECR, elastic container registry.
So in the Elastic Container Registry, we'll try to store our Docker image, okay?
Because we'll be using Docker service here to containerize entire our application, and we'll try to store in the ECR services here is a
I mean Docker image storage service so that you can store any kinds of Docker image.
so this is the description for the deployment.
First of all, we'll be building the Docker image of our source code, then we'll try to push this Docker image to the ECR, Elastic Content Registry of AWS service, then
we'll launch our EC2 machine.
Uh, if it is a virtual machine, then we'll try to pull our image from ECR to EC2, then we'll try to run this
Docker image as a container, then we'll do some port mapping.
After that, uh, we'll be able to access the application, and these are the policy we have to provide whenever we'll be creating the I'm user.
Okay, so this is the entire step, guys. I have written all of the command, everything, whatever you required. I just mentioned it here.
So we'll just try to follow this readme file and we'll try to perform the deployment.
But uh, before doing the deployment, guys, you need some of the file here.
Um, let me show you what are the files you need. Yeah, so the first uh things you need, which is the cic.yml.
Uh, but before that, let's create a docker file first of all. So docker
Okay, so we'll be writing this docker file.
Docker file.
And again, if you are not familiar with Docker, then if you are not familiar with uh this kinds of ml ops concept.
So on my YouTube channel, I already have a complete MLOps course, guys. Here I have already covered all kinds of MLOps tools like Docker.
Okay, I have also covered Linux, MLflow, DBCH, and everything, but you don't need to cover all of them. Uh, if you are completely new with the Docker and all, you can go through this recording.
I think Docker starts here, even you will see this uh
um
timing, okay.
Uh this timestamp. So from here you can uh uh see right what is the Docker.
Simply you can uh click on the timestamp, you will be able to see the Docker.
So just try to learn if you don't know about Docker and if you want to understand the Docker command, just try to go through that recording.
So here let's try to add all the Docker related command,
this is our Docker file, okay? And these are the command you have to mention in the Docker file. So, first of all, we are taking the base image and Python 3.11. we are using.
then we are creating the working directory.
then we are setting some environment variable just to prevent some error.
then we are running. these are the commands.
and just to upgrade our uh, um, like Ubuntu instance and install some tools. then we are copying the requirement.txt. we are installing the requirement.txt after that.
We are copying all of the source code in the root directory, we are creating the folders like uploads and data, these two folders we are creating.
Then after that, we are exposing the port. We are running our application on port number 8080. So I think you have seen that.
This is the port, okay. We are running our application. Make sure you are giving the same port. If you are changing the port, here you have to also change.
Then this is the command to run the our app.py server. So if we can um app uh so we are running the app.py inside app.py we are having this app object, okay.
We created this app object, so we are running it here, then we're uh giving the host and as well as the put.
So this is the Docker we have to write, and if you're writing Docker, you need another file here called
dot
docker
ignore
inside that you will just write all of these folders and file you don't need whenever you are building the Docker image.
Okay, so these are the things I will avoid, and that means any kinds of virtual environment or these are the file I'll just try to avoid whenever it will build a docker image.
It's kinds of your uh git ignore, so whenever you are pushing anything in the GitHub, right?
You are ignoring something in the git ignore. These are the files, so same thing you have to write in the Docker ignore if you want to ignore anything whenever you are creating the Docker image, okay.
Yeah, then
Docker file is done. Now we'll just try to create a folder.
I'm going to name it as.github.
Inside that, you have to create another folder.
The folder name should be workflows, okay.
Just make sure you are giving the same name, otherwise, it will not work because as a CI CD tool, guys, here we'll be using GitHub Actions. Okay, I told you we'll be using CI C D approach.
So if you are pushing your code to the GitHub, automatically it will get deployed over the AWS Cloud.
Okay, we'll be creating that pipeline, and as a CICD tool, we'll be using GitHub Action and GitHub Action it is already available on GitHub.
Okay, it is already um um, I mean uh pre predefined setup, you don't need to set up the GitHub uh um sorry,
uh this uh GitHub Action server separately, it is already running on GitHub, so that's why you need this folder and workflows, and inside that you will be creating a file called
cicdotyml.
Okay, so this is the file. So inside that you will you have to write all the CICD related command.
and these are the command you will be getting from the internet only.
If you just search GitHub Action CICD deployment command, you will see these kinds of code would be available over the internet,
even you can also generate from chat GPT.
So this is the command I have prepared, guys. Here I have mentioned all of this tape and command you need to perform whenever you are doing the CICD.
First of all, we are giving the name of this workflow, then whenever you are pushing your code on the main branch.
That time, what will happen? This will trigger.
Okay.
So in continuous integration, what we are doing, guys, we are authenticating with the AWS account.
Uh, with the help of this secret key, AWS access key, doubles access uh secret access key and region. We are authenticating, then we are logging into the Amazon ECR.
We are building the Docker image, then we are pushing this Docker image to the Amazon ECR.
Okay, then in continuous deployment, what we are doing again, we are authenticating with the account, our AWS account with this credential.
Then we are logging into the ECR, we are pulling that Docker image and we are running inside our EC2 machine.
Okay, so these are the commands I have written, guys. And you know that to run this application, you need some involvement variable.
So these are the environment variables in it, and all the involvement variables I have mentioned here. Okay, you can see I need Google API key, Google model, tably API, Lang Smith.
So whatever key you are using, make sure you are adding in as environment variable, okay?
And we'll be reading it from the GitHub um GitHub secrets.
We'll try to add all of this credential in the GitHub secrets because directly I haven't mentioned inside my code, so that's why always secret file should be um written in secrets, okay.
GitHub secrets. So, yes, uh, this is the entire CICD.yml, and uh we'll be using this file for the deployment.
And I'll share all of these resources in the description from there. You can check it out.
And if you want to learn more about this cicd.ml and again just try to check that uh ml of scores that I already discussed about the CICD.
Okay, so inside CICD, I already explained that concept, you can go through that.
So, yeah, now uh let's try to
follow the pipeline.
So, if I go to my GitHub, so this is the pipeline. First of all, let's log in with the AWS console.
Make sure you have the AWS account, guys.
I already have the AWS account, I'll just try to log in.
I'll just sign in with my management console.
So here you just need to
give your authentication
authentication credential, that means your email and password.
So let's give my email and password and let me log in with my AWS console, guys.
So this is my AWS console, guys.
just try to log in and you will be able to see this kinds of interface. So here the first thing uh what we have to do, we have to create an IAM user. Okay, let's create the IAM user.
So here just search for IM identity access management,
and here I'll just click on IAM user,
create a new user.
I'll give the name let's say mapp GPT.
You can give any name, you can attach the policies now. Here you need these are the policies Amazon EC2
full access and ECR.
Sorry, ECR and EC2 Elastic Container Registry and EC2 machine.
so this is the service. Here I will just try to search and select uh then I will just try to add another one.
This one and
this one Amazon EC2 full access.
Once we have done, I'll just click on next.
Now see both uh permission I have given, and why this permission is required because I want uh I don't want to give the full access to my um
to my uh let's say project whenever it will do the deployment.
Um otherwise, um if any mistakes is there, it will be using any other services as well. Okay, there is a possibility.
So to prevent that, we are only giving the permission and the services we are using from AWS. Okay, now I'll just create the user.
So user creation is done. Now I'll click on the user.
I'll go to the security credential
and here you'll see one option called create access key.
I'll select the first option, command line interface, and confirm do the confirmation.
Click on next.
Now let's create the access key.
So this is our access key and secret access key. You need to authenticate your AWS account from your Python client. Okay. Now I'll just try to download as a csv file.
Done.
And make sure you just keep this file.
I need it later on whenever we just uh create
the GitHub secret. Okay.
I'll just try to open in a notepad plus plus.
So this is the credential. This is your access key ID. This is your secret access key ID.
Okay.
Yeah, perfect.
Now let's click on done. Now the next step we have to follow.
Uh we have to create the ECR repo to store the Docker image. Now let's create the ECR repo.
I'll go to the home and I'll search for ECR Elastic Container Registry. Okay.
So this is a fully managed Docker container registry.
And this is the alternate alternative of Docker Hub. Okay, the Docker Hub you used, right? In Docker Hub, also you can store the Docker image here. this service actually AWS has created.
Okay, this is this is the AWS container registry.
Now I'll just create a new registry, give the name. I'll give
GPT.
You can give any name, everything, just keep it as it is. Now create this repository. Okay, this is the repository, and copy this URI and keep it somewhere. Okay, I need it later on.
So maybe in readme file, I'll just try to store here. Okay.
Perfect.
Now uh it is also done. Now I'll again click on home and see the next step.
Next step is you have to create a EC2 machine, Ubuntu instance.
Now let's search for EC2, EC2 instance virtual service in cloud.
And here I will just try to launch an instance.
Uh click on launch without as uh without walkthrough.
Now give the name.
I'll give up pgpt
machine.
Again, you can give any kinds of name here.
Then you have to select this Ubuntu instance. Okay, most of the production server would be Ubuntu, and there are some other operating system as well, but select the Ubuntu one.
Now here you can uh you can select the instance type, okay?
Like uh how much memory, how much CPU you need, you can select from here. So at least here I'll just try to select this four.
Um sorry, not this one, huh?
Uh 8 GB memory. Okay, this 8 GB memory at least I will be taking for this project and two CPU codes.
But if you have a very let's say I mean heavy project, that time you can use some heavy instance here, okay.
And all the instance, how how much it will charge per hour it has already given you the estimated cost. So I'll select this one.
Once it is done, now you can create the key value pair.
This is optional. Uh, optional means you have to create it if you want to access your EC2 instance from any third party tools like mobile extreme and putty, that time it's required. So I'll give Bap
GPT.
Now let's create the
key value peer.
Now see one PAM file would be downloaded. This PAM credential you need whenever you want to use any third party tool. But I don't want to use any third party tool, I'll be using uh this
instance in the same AWS console only. I'll tell you how to do that.
Now just try to select these two options allow stps and allow stp traffic, and uh you can also select your storage, like how much storage you need.
So I'll take uh 8 GB storage as of now.
You can increase it. Okay, it's per your requirement. Let's say you can take 32 GB or 16 GB at spare your requirement.
So here I'll just try to launch the instance.
Now click on view instance.
Now let's refresh,
and you can see our instance is running. Okay, now I'll click on this instance, and here you will see one option called connect button. Okay, just click on connect.
And if you are using any third-party tools like mobile extreme and putting that time, you can use SSS client to connect that. Okay, these are the command you have to execute.
But I'll just launch this terminal in the same AWS
console only. Now let's connect that.
Now see it will open a new window, and there you will see a
Ubuntu terminal, and there you have to set up everything.
So this is the Ubuntu terminal.
Now let's clear,
okay. And if you don't know about Ubuntu, again you can refer my course.
So there I already discussed about the Linux operating system. Okay, how to run the Linux command page and everything. So first of all, here I have already given all of the command.
First of all, you have to upgrade the machine. So these are the command you have to execute. Just try to copy and right-click and paste and run.
So this is a new launched machine, and here I have to upgrade and set up all of the requirement tools I need here.
Then I'll copy the second command
and I'll execute.
So I'll give yes permission.
Yeah, so it will upgrade all of the tools.
Now, here I have to install the Docker because initially there is no Docker in this instance. So this these are the command you have to execute to install the Docker.
Okay, let's clear
paste.
Now I'll copy the next one.
Then I'll copy the next one.
paste and run
Then the last command, this one.
Okay, so Docker is installed successfully. Now you can check it. So Docker IPN version, you can see this is the version is running.
Okay, now the next thing, guys, we have to configure our EC2 as a self-hosted runner. That means we have to connect, okay. We have to connect our GitHub repo with our AWS account.
Okay, so that if you are committing any changes, okay, if you're pushing your code, it will automatically deploy it over the AWS cloud. So for this, this is the connection we have to build.
So for this, make sure you are using your GitHub repo, guys. The same repo you are updating your project, not my repo.
So let's create another um tab here because I want to refer this command, okay? From this one. So now here you have an option called settings.
Click on settings, and there will see one option called action and go to the runners.
Okay, now create a new self-hosted runner,
select this Linux,
and you have to execute these are the command one by one. Copy and execute in the situation terminal.
So that's how we'll be connecting.
Next command
and execute,
then again third command
and execute.
Done.
Now we have this command.
Now I think uh we have executed all of this command. Now we have to run this configure command.
Let's copy this and execute.
Now see GitHub action initialized and it has connected to my GitHub. Now it is asking intent the name of the runner group.
I'll press enter simply. Now it is asking to the name of the runner.
Okay, now name of the runner is
self-hosted.
Self-hosted. Okay, make sure you're giving the same name.
I'll copy.
And here I'll just try to paste it.
Self-hosted.
Then it is telling in uh this runner will have any following labels. No, I'll press enter.
Then it is telling name of the work folder. I'll again press enter.
Okay, done.
Now the last command you have to execute this one.
So if you execute your GitHub would be connected to the AWS.
Now see connected to the GitHub and listening for the jobs. Now, if I come to my repo, now if I go to the runners again, now you can see that uh this status is ideal.
That means my AWS is connected with my GitHub. Now if I push anything in my GitHub, it will automatically get triggered that CCD pipeline and all of the code would be deployed over my AWS cloud.
But before that, we have to set this credential. Okay, these are the secret credential in my GitHub GitHub secrets. So let's do that.
So for this, again, uh here you will see one option called secret and variable.
Click here and click on this action.
Now here you will see this repository secret, just click on new repository secret, and here you have to add all the secret one by one.
Now, first of all, you have to add this Google API key or whatever API key you are using, you can add here one by one.
So this is my Google API key. Let's
let's copy that.
Yeah, here
I'll copy and paste it here
done now. Next, I will add my
Google model.
This is the model.
That's how you have to add all of the secret one by one. Now tably IPI key.
Now, next you have this Lang Smith tracing.
It should be true.
Now Lang Smith endpoint.
This is the end point.
Now Lang Smith APIK.
Now next you have this Lang Smith project.
Project name.
So this is the project name BGPT.
Done.
Now we have to add the AWS related credential. They have AWS access key.
So why do you have the access key in the CSV file? I think remember. We have already downloaded.
Let's copy this access key before the comma till here.
I'll Copy and paste it.
Then next I have AWS secret access key.
And in this file only, you have the secret access key. After this comma, okay, whatever values you have, just try to add in the secret.
Now next you have this AWS region.
So right now I'm inside this region called North Virginia US East One. Okay, if you are in other region, you can give the name. I'll give US East One.
Make sure you are writing in same way.
US East One. Okay.
Sick add the secret.
Now last I have to add my ECR repo name.
So why do you have the ECR repo name? I think remember we copied one URI, right?
Yeah.
So here is the name. Just try to copy after this slash and add it here.
Done. Okay, all of these secrets we have added one by one. Now it's time it's time to commit our changes.
I'll go to my repo.
Now let's commit the changes here.
Cicd.
Add it.
Now push the changes.
Done now. If I refresh.
Now see if my action is running, workflow is running. Now I'll click on action.
Uh I'll open the CI C D
workflow. Now see continuous integration is running. So it is building the Docker image and pushing it to the ECR. All of the execution you will be able to see.
So let's wait. This process may take some time.
Building is done. Now it is
pushing the image to the ECR Elastic Container history.
You can even check in the ECR.
So
let's create a new tab and I'll go to the Elastic Container Story.
So this is my registry. I'll click here.
So see the image has been pushed.
Okay, now it is running continuous deployment.
Now it will pull that ECR image and it will run on my C2.
Now see pulling is completed.
Now see it will run the Docker image as a container.
Done. See all of the execution are green, that means everything is fine.
Now I'll come to my instance and there is an option. Um URL you will get public DNS. Just copy this URL and paste it here and execute.
See, initially, this application will not open because right now this is running on port number 8080, but we haven't done the port mapping.
So if you want to do the port mapping, just come here and there is an option called security. Click on security, go to the security groups,
and you have one option called edit inbound rules.
Then add the rules, and here just try to add port number 8080. Okay, and just try to okay.
One more thing you have to add this 000. that means you can access from anywhere, then save the rules.
Then I will go to my instance,
copy this
URL again, and at the last, I will give port number 8080. Okay, now if I execute, now see my application is running, okay.
See how uh PGPT is running, and this is completely live right now. You can share this URL with anyone and they will be able to access. Okay, now you can purchase any kinds of domain name.
You can also change the domain here. Now let's test whether it's working or not.
Okay, now here I have given hi, it is giving hello. How I can assist you, uh, how I can help you today, and it has also loaded my previous trades. why?
Because in my GitHub I already um updated my database, right?
So from database it is loading in the old conversation. Okay, that's why you're able to see that. See that now. Let's uh do the chat operation.
I'll tell
my name is Bappi.
See now you can even create a new thread and you can do the conversation. But let's continue here.
Now here you can upload your documents,
your any kinds of documents. Let's say I will upload my
resume.
Okay, now I'll ask who is
booked here based
on
PDF.
Now it is using my doc search tool and it is giving you the response. Okay. Now you can even search any latest information.
Latest
news in Bollywood.
Now see real time search operation it is doing,
and this is the latest news I got.
So yes, guys, everything is working fine. Okay, now this is completely live.
And now if I let's say close my this this window, that means this terminal still my application will be working. See, okay.
Now the best part is that uh if you push anything, right? If you push anything, push any new chance,
um automatically this pipeline will trigger and all of the
new features would be added in your um deployment server uh without uh let's say stopping your application.
This is the main benefit, okay. So this is the one time setup, and rest of the life you can
enjoy.
Now, yeah, everything is done. Now we have seen the deployment. Now let's try to stop all the instance we have created because our landing is over.
I don't want to keep it running, otherwise, it will charge me. And one more thing I want to show you this uh Lang Smith monitoring.
So if I go to my Lang Smith in the PGPT, see the last execution. Okay, it has done okay. Perfect. Now let's try to
terminate everything.
So, first of all, I will terminate my ec2 instance.
So select it and click here, instant state, and terminate and delete.
Okay, if you stop it, it will stop, but it will it will not delete, okay. But I will delete it everything.
Terminate and delete now. See, after some times it will delete it and shut down.
Once it is done, I will search for ECR
ECR Elastic Container S3
and whatever history I created I'll select and delete it.
I'll give delete message
and confirm.
Then I will delete my IM user as well
delete
deactive
right confirm
and delete.
Okay, so everything is deleted now.
This server is down.
So see now this uh URL is down because we have deleted everything.
So fine guys, uh we have done.
Um now I will share this code and everything in the description.
from there you can
check it out. I will add a beautiful README here.
README, let's say information so that you can see all of the commands, all of the steps in the README itself. Okay, now this was the AWS deployment.
now if you don't have the AWS account, guys still you want to deploy this application and you want to test for this you can use render. Okay, there is another one called render.com.
You can use this uh platform, and here you can do the deployment, okay? So for render, I already created a video in my playlist as you can see.
Uh deploy agent tk chatbot on render for free with Docker. You can simply uh check this video and you will be able to deploy this project over the render cloud as well.
Okay, so yes, uh, this is all about guys. I hope you like this uh uh implementation.
If you found this uh this implementation useful, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel.
So this is my channel, guys. Please try to subscribe. Uh let's hit 100k subscriber as soon as possible.
And uh I have lots of plan for this channel.
I'll bring lots of content related agent DKI, MCP, okay, uh data science. So each and everything would be available in one place.
And if you want to connect me, guys, this is my LinkedIn profile. So here you can also connect me.
You can also follow me here.
So definitely um we'll try to keep in touch. And if you have any kinds of question you can feel free to reach out here.
So, guys, in this video, I'll be developing one end-to-end multi-agent application with the help of Langgraph.
So, in this video, the application I'm going to develop, the application name would be TripMate AI.
So, TripMate AI is a multi-agent application.
here you only just need to mention your trip location, and this will give you the entire plan with respect to the location
you are planning for the trip, and this will also give you some amazing information like your flights, your hotels.
Okay, then it will give you the travel itinerary, even it will give you the day-to-day plan you will be making whenever you are on a trip.
So, this is a very much a cool application we'll be developing.
Why? Because we know that all of the people out there they're very much interested, uh especially in trip, especially about the travel.
So let's say whenever we are planning for any travel, let's say country A to B. So before going to that particular country, we just need to make some plans, right?
Let's say um if I want to visit that country, so which flight I have to take, okay, after let's say taking the flight,
in which hotel I have to stay, right?
Then why I need to visit, what are the memorable locations there, right?
Even what would be my day one plan, day two plan? Let's say I have that much amount of budget, so how much money I should spend in day one, day two, like that.
Okay, so this is the major problem um whenever we are planning for any kinds of trips. Okay, so why not? We can create a multi-agent system so that agent will prepare the entire plan for us, okay?
Only just need to give the location. Let's say I want to visit uh let's say uh uh uh country A to B.
Okay, I'll only just provide that much information to my agent, and my agent will prepare everything for me.
Okay, even I can download that particular plan as a PDF file, and I can take it on my smartphone anytime and I can visit and you are okay.
So, this is the system guys will be developing throughout the entire video, and for this, we'll be using some amazing tools and technologies.
Okay, so guys, first of all, I want to show you the application demo, how this application looks like and how this application will be uh working. Then after that, we'll start the development.
Okay, so to implement this uh entire system, guys, I have used some amazing technology. I have used a fast API, so it is running on fast API back end.
Even I have used HTML, CSS, and little bit of JavaScript to design the entire front end. Okay, as you can see, this is a beautiful front end I have created.
Then for this agent workflow, multi agent workflow, I used line graph. Okay, and uh the large language model wise, actually, I'm using Grok um.
Uh Grok actually playground that means Grok platform.
So from the Grok platform, guys, I'm using Lama model, okay. Meta Lama model.
Then uh for the memory persistence memory, I'm utilizing Postgres uh SQL database.
So if you know PostgreSQL is an amazing uh database, okay, whenever you are implementing this kinds of agentic AI application, so Postgres you can utilize okay.
Uh here uh this Postgres uh supports uh so many functionality whenever you are implementing these kinds of agents.
So for our uh persistence memory, guys, we'll be using Postgres database inside this development and Postgres. I'm not going to use the local Postgres server instead of that.
I have set up uh this uh Postgres on the render cloud. Okay, my Postgres is running on my render cloud. Let me show you.
So this is my Postgres server, it is running on render cloud. So from here we just connected our application, okay. So right now this is not local anymore.
So if you close your local system as well, still this uh this uh uh application will be running.
Then for the real-time search operation, guys, uh, for uh finding hotels or for finding uh different different uh itinerary uh for a specific location, uh we'll be using tably,
okay. Tabily search tool. So with the help of that, we'll be doing the internet search, real-time internet search, and we'll try to figure out all of the latest informations about that country, okay.
Then uh for the flight information, guys, we'll be using uh aviation stack platform. Basically, they provide the API key.
With the help of this API key, you can get the entire flight information, okay.
for any kinds of country. So, yes, these are my tools, and technologies uh we'll be using for this development.
And after this development, I'm also going to show you how we can deploy this project over the render cloud.
Okay, so here we are not only going to develop this project, even after completing the development, I will show you the deployment part as well. So make sure you watch this video till the end.
And if you uh found this content useful, please try to subscribe to my channel and please try to share this with your friends and family. And please, guys, hit the like.
And I need your support if you are supporting me, guys. Definitely I can bring these kinds of content more, and uh, yeah, it would be amazing, okay, all together.
So please try to subscribe to my channel. This should be my request to all of you. So, yes, this is how my application interface looks like.
Uh, you can see this is a tripmate AI platform, a multi-agent travel planner with Line Graph.
So, here basically you can plan your perfect trip with AI.
You can start flight, discover hotels, generate a complete travel itinerary using multi-agent line graph system.
Okay, now for an example here, uh, what you have to give. So, here you have a input box.
So, basically, you can mention uh where to why do you want to let's say go for the trip, you just only need to mention.
Let's say here I have given some example plan a complete seven days trip, uh seven days Japan trip from Bangladesh under one uh two lakhs.
Okay, let's say you have two lakhs budget, you can provide this information. So, what I can do, I can copy this information, I can paste it here.
Let's say maybe I can tell uh plan a complete seven days.
Let's say here I will give
I'll get Nepal tool.
Okay, Nepal trip from Bangladesh under two lakhs.
Okay, so let's say this is my uh this is my uh let's say plan for the trip. Now simply you just need to click on generate plans.
now see
um after some time you will see the entire plan would be ready.
even you can download this uh down uh download that plan as a PDF file.
Let me show you. So, guys, as you can see, uh it has successfully generated the seven days Nepal trip from Bangladesh under uh 2 lakhs Taka.
So, as you can see, this is the trip summary.
we have planned a seven day Nepal trip from Bangladesh that includes a visit to Kathmandu, then
Pokhara, then Chitwan, and others exciting destinations and blah blah blah. You can see so first of all, it has given the flight information.
Let's say if I want to visit Nepal first of all, I have to I have to go to the Dhaka.
And Dhaka to Kathmandu, there is a flight, and this is the flight information it is giving, and the times as well when this flight is available.
Okay, then some hotel suggestions it is giving. So after you reach to Kathmandu, so in which hotel you just need to stay, and what would be the cost per night, even it is also telling you.
Apart from that, it is giving you the day by day itinerary.
Here is the day-by-day itinerary. Day one, Dhaka to Kathmandu, you will be visiting.
Okay, so it is giving you the entire step, okay.
See,
then when you reach the Kathmandu, so in day two, what should be your visit location? It is giving you the entire visit location, okay, and what is the entry fee, each and everything it is giving you.
Then Kathmandu to pokhara again it is giving you the plan.
You have to take a bus or private card, okay? And this is the estimated cost for that.
Okay, so that's how it is giving you the entire summary. So then day four, day five, okay, day six, day seven, and the entire estimated budget is also giving you like how much money uh
I mean it will spend um in seven days. Okay, if you are visiting Nepal so it is giving you the estimated cost about flights, accommodations, transportation, food and activities, total budget.
Okay, then the final recommendation it is giving you. Uh, you can see some final recommendation we are also getting.
So, yes, uh, if I get these kinds of things, guys, okay, in just one place, it would be amazing for us because otherwise, what I have to do, I have to individually search Google.
Let's say what is the best hotel in Kathmandu, okay, and how much let's say price they are taking.
So I have to search individually, I have to search the flight in uh flight information individually, I have to search hotel information individually, okay.
I have to search this day-by-day itinerary individually, okay. So, yeah, this takes time and it needs lots of exploration, right?
Uh, I have to search on Google, go to different different website, just try to see their review. Then after that, I'll try to select this one. Then again, I have to note it, right?
I have to take a note. Let's say I will visit uh A to B, B to C okay, and it will take that much of money. This is the estimated time. I have to note everything, so that much time I don't have.
So, why not? We can bring everything inside of one platform, okay. One
uh one, let's say, uh one system.
There, I only just need to give my trip plan and it will generate the entire plan for me.
This is what we have developed, guys.
Okay, so this is very interesting and real-time application, guys, because right now this kinds of application will be uh seeing, okay. people are using there.
Are some platform they are providing these kinds of let's less of functionality? all users need to give the location and it will give you the entire trip plan for that.
Okay, now if I go to the cut uh Nepal, right?
So I don't have any kinds of issue because I know what is the estimated cost there, what is the best hotels there, right? What is the best flights there, right? Uh uh in day one, day two, day three.
why I need to visit, which which is the best location to visit there in seven days, all the information I have.
Okay, so I don't need anyone to guide me there.
This is what guys will be doing. Now you can see there is a download PDF option. If I click on download PDF, so you can see this PDF file would be available.
Now you can take this PDF file on your smartphone, okay, or on your laptop, anywhere you can take, and you can just open it up and you can see okay what you have to do.
Amazing, right? So, yes, guys, this is the things we will be developing.
Even you can also copy this information and you can also paste it anywhere, even you can also send it uh to your friends and family.
This is also possible, okay.
So that's how not only uh not only Nepal, you can give Japan, Dubai, Thailand, okay, global, anywhere.
While you just need to visit, just try to mention here you can generate the plan, okay, with respect to that.
And uh, I already told you this uh uh this is also utilizing the Postgres database, all the information it is saving in the Postgres.
This is uh already uh um Postgres servers we have created on the render render server.
Okay, render is a cloud platform, and let me show you.
I have my PG admin.
So in PG admin, I connected my remote server that means my render Postgres server, and here you can see the persistence memory checkpoint.
So see, these are my persistence memory checkpoint, and you can see this is connected with render cloud.
See, this connected with render cloud.
Okay, and all of me, all of my persistence memory checkpoint, all of my conversations are saved here.
Okay,
even I am also using Lang Smith here
So as you can see, I'm using Lam Lang Smith guys to monitor my entire application. It is using this travel agent project and it is monitoring the entire entire application, okay.
So, yes, guys, uh that that's how we'll be developing this entire application end-to-end, completely end-to-end, we'll try to develop.
So, yes, guys, this is the entire application.
this is the entire application demo. Now let's start the development.
So, guys, before starting the development, first of all, let's try to understand the application overview and the application architectures.
So, as you can see, tripmate AI, this is a line graph multi-agent travel planner system.
So, you can see this is a multi-agent travel planner that turns a natural language trip request into a practical travel plan with flight suggestions,
hotel ideas, and day-to-day uh itinerary.
Uh the projects uh uses a multi-agent workflow built with Langgraph. And why this project? Uh, as you can see, planning a trip usually means jumping between multiple websites, tools, and spreadsheets.
Okay, as I already told you, let's say if you are planning for a trip, right? you have to visit multiple websites to look for the flights, information, hotel information, right?
Then which location you just need to visit there, right? These are the things you have to explore and you have to take a notes on the spreadsheet or anywhere, then you will be making the entire plan.
So this takes lots of time, right? And it needs lots of exploration, even sometimes you you may miss out anything, right?
so this project brings that flow into one experience by combining a flight search agent, a hotel research agent, and uh itinerary
plan planning agent, and if uh final response agents, okay, all coordinated through a line graph workflow. That means in a single place we'll be combining all of them,
and each of the tasks uh would be mentioned to each of the agent. That means for the flight search operation, we will be creating another an agent for uh hotel.
Uh hotel information will be defining another agent. Uh for uh itinerary planning will be defining another agents. Okay, for final report generation will be defining another agents.
That's how we'll be creating multiple agents together, and those agents will be
uh those those agents will be responsible for generating the entire trip summary for me, okay. Trip plan for me. So that's why we call it as a multi-agent system.
So here we are not utilizing one agent, we are using multiple agents, and each of the agents will have some kinds of tools to complete that uh particular task.
Okay, so here is the entire uh like architecture, guys, as you can see for this project. So, first of all, I already told you here we'll be utilizing multiple agent.
As you can see, here we'll be utilizing multiple agent. The first agents will be creating the flight agents, okay.
So basically, this will search the flight and find the best option for visiting location A to B. Okay, and for and to get these kinds of flight informations, it needs some tools, right?
And here we'll be using aviation stack API. So, this aviation stack API, what it it can do, it can search real time flight informations, right?
And it will give you that particular flight information to the flight agent, and flight agent will try to utilize that.
Okay, so optionally you can also use Stabili search here, but I feel like uh aviation stack is having all kinds of flight integration in one place, so that's why we'll be using
aviation stack API key here.
Then second agents will be developing these hotel agents. So, what this hotel agent agent will do, it will search hotels and compares options.
That means it will only look uh it is not only going to look for the agents, it will all uh it will look for the best hotels for you, okay. Best hotels uh with respect to your budget, right?
So, this hotel information it will try to find, and for this, we will be using some kinds of tools, right? And here we'll be using tabily search, okay.
So, tabily search with the help of tably search will try to figure out the best hotels
from that particular location and we'll try to give the suggestion. Optionally, you can use the Google Place API. This is optional, but uh I'll be using tabily tabli search, okay?
Because this is completely free to use. Then the next one, itinerary agent. So this basically creates the day wise itinerary.
that means uh why do you have to visit? Okay, what are the activities you have to do there?
What are the best places? Okay, each and everything this particular agents will try to get it for uh for you, and again to get these are the information.
the best in best visit location activities will be using tabily API key again. Okay, so with the help of tabily, we'll perform the internet search operation and
real time will get the information and it will try to use this information in my itinerary agents. Then fourth, I'll be using this final response agents.
That means it will be using all the information and it will try to prepare the entire plan for you, entire tree plan for you.
Okay, that means it it combines all the information and generate a final response.
And again, for this, we'll be using a large language model and the large language model wise we'll be using Lama3, okay? And we'll be using Grok provider.
I think you know Grok provide some free uh free limits. Okay, you can generate API keys and you can access some model, okay. Completely free.
You don't need to pay for that, but there is a limitation, but it's fine, okay. For this particular task, I will be using this free API key.
But if you want, you can also take the subscription, you can use some premium model, it's completely up to you.
Okay, so yeah, uh we'll be using this grog provided here.
yeah, then you can see uh each of the agents will be connected to a shared state that means shared memory, and we call it as a state.
If you are already working in line graph I think no, there is a concept of state, right? We have to create the state, and these are the state I need, guys.
Okay, I need user query, that means whatever user will pass, I'll save inside the user query.
Whatever flight results I'll be getting, I'll try to save in the flight results. Whatever hotel results I'll be getting, I'll try to save in the hotel results.
Whatever itinerary response I'll be getting, I'll try to save inside itinerary results.
Whatever final response I'll be getting, I'll save inside final response. Okay, and whatever my agents will try to reply, okay.
that entire plan I'll try to save inside my message state, and this shared state will be storing inside one amazing database, guys. We call it as a Postgres square, okay.
So this database will be using for my memory, okay.
Memory memory purpose will be using that means we'll try to store all of the checkpoints, all of the conversation here.
Okay, so it will basically have the conversation story, user preferences, agents output, and state updates.
Okay, so this is the entire architecture, guys. will try to follow and will be implementing this entire agents.
Okay, I hope you get it.
So, guys, as you can see to develop this entire application, I need the four agents here uh the flight agent, hotel agent, then uh itinerary agents and the fine
final response agents. Okay, so we'll be developing four agents and we'll try to combine them all together, and this will become a multi-agent system, okay.
Yeah,
so first of all, uh to implement this entire system, guys. What I need I need to create my GitHub repository.
So there I'll try to create a repo and um I'll start writing the code.
So for this, let's open up my GitHub, guys. I'll open up my GitHub,
I'll go to my repository
and let's create a new repo here.
I'm going to give the name of this repo. So, what I can do maybe I can copy this name
and I can give it here. Okay, let's say this is my name,
and simply I'll just try to make it as public.
Uh I will add the readme file gitignode wise. I'll be taking Python
and license. Let's take this
MIT license. Okay, you can take any license, it's up to you.
Uh okay, everything is fine now. Simply, what I'll do, I'll just try to create this repository.
Okay, so my repo is created, guys.
Okay, next thing I'll just try to clone this repo. I'll just click on this code and copy this http URL and I will open up my local folder.
So here I'll open up my terminal
and let's clone it.
So git clone
paste that URL.
So it has already cloned my repo. So now I'll go inside that. So C D the name of the repo is strip metai. Okay, so now I'm inside this folder.
I'm inside this folder. Okay, now here I'm going to open up my visual for studio.
Okay, perfect.
So here I already moved my architecture file, which is demo.excalidraw, So here I'm using Excalidraw file format. So for this, you have to install one extension called Excalidraw,
Okay, Excalidra.
So this is the extension you have to install. So if you install, you will be able to open this file, guys. Okay, and here you will be getting this architecture diagram.
So fine.
yeah.
Now next guys, what I have to do, I have to first of all uh create the environment and we have to create the folder structure. So to create the environment, guys.
Um here, uh, what I can do, I can write this step.
How to run
first
create the environment
virtual
environment.
So
to create the virtual environment, uh, you have to use this command
conda
create
hype in n.
then you have to give the name of the environment. I will give let's say
travel,
then I'll give the python version. So python is equal to
3.11. Okay, I'll be using 3.11 and hyphen y. That means I want to give the permission. So this is the command you have to use to create the environment.
Then second, you have to activate the environment,
activate the environment.
So to activate the environment, you have to use this command
conduct activate
travel.
Then next you have to install the requirement file.
Install the requirements.
So we'll be using this command. So pip install
ipnr requirements dot
txt.
Okay, so yeah, uh, these are the step we have to follow. So, first of all, let's recreate the environment.
I'll copy this command and I'll open up my terminal.
That's clear.
Let's create the environment first of all.
Okay, uh, there is a space I have given, but uh this space should not be there,
it should be hype in L only. Okay, now copy this again
and execute it here.
Okay, done. Now I have to activate the environment.
So this is the command.
See, I have activated now. I'll be installing the requirements, but for this, I need to create the requirements file.
Requirements.txt.
Okay.
So here I need to mention all of the requirements I need for this uh
agent.
So I already uh noted all the requirements I'll be using.
So these are the requirements, guys. I need I need Langgraph definitely to create the agent workflow.
Langchain, you need because if you want to use Langgraph, so Langchain is the dependency, and whenever I want to load any large language
model and all, right? I have to use the Langchain there. Then we'll be using grok provider, that means LLM provider.
That's why we'll be installing Langchain grok then Langchain community is also required. Then we'll be using tably search tool.
We'll be using Langchain Tabily, and I told you I'll be using PostgreSQL database. For this, I need this uh PS uh
ycop g binary, then uh uh this pull.
Uh the uh these two things I need, okay, for this um uh database.
Okay, database and another thing I need this Langchain checkpoint Postgres. Okay, these are the dependency for the database, okay. Then Python.nv to manage the environment credential.
So let's create this.nv file.
Okay, here we'll try to mention all of these uh credential, secret credential, then tabily python unit request library unit.
I already told you about the Postgres, right? Uh I will save my checkpoints in the Postgres database.
That's why this uh length uh Langgraph checkpoint Postgres is required.
Then uh I'll also get the um um um I mean flight information, right? For this, um, I'll be using one package called airports data. So inside airports data, some informations are available.
We'll try to utilize that.
Then uh I'll be considering all of the country, right? whenever I'll try to search for the flights, so that's why there is another package called Py Country.
So inside that, all of the country informations are available. We'll try to also use that. Then fast API for my entire um
uh back end and front end development, then uh fast API dependent dependencies evicon with the help of evicon, uh, we'll try to launch the fast API server, then the
Ginja to templates. Okay, so these are the requirements, guys. I need and I already mentioned all of the version, okay. And you should also mention the version. Uh, otherwise, what will happen?
Let's say uh uh if you if you not mention the version, so if you are running this project after two months,
there is a possibility uh one of the packets will get updated and that functionality will be deprecated. Okay, that time you will get the error. so that's why it's uh necessary to add the version.
Okay, this is super important. Now let's install the dependency. So I'll copy this command
and I'll try to install the dependency here.
Okay, let's wait uh once it is installed, then we'll try to
um see the next step.
So, apart from this dependency, I also need to install some other tools as well. Let me show you.
So installation is complete and there is no added. Okay, it's completely
fine. Now, guys, uh, what I need, I need some more tools. Okay, I told you we'll be using this uh pg admin to see my tables, right?
My conversation checkpoints, even you can also see the different uh conversation it has saved right in in the memory, so you can able to see that because uh I'll be creating this uh Postgres
server on my render cloud, and to see that I need this PG admin, okay. Pg admin
this graphical user interface. you have to install that.
So let me close my pg admin and let me show you how to install this. pg admin.
So if you want to install the pg admin, guys, only in just Google, just try to search pg admin,
okay.
Pg admin download
for Windows.
So this is the website, just try to visit
or you can directly search like Postgres download, okay?
Postgres SQL download.
So this is the website.
Here just try to choose your operating system. Let's say I'm using Windows.
You can also select other operating system as well,
and there is an option called download installer.
Okay, now you have to choose which one you will be downloading.
So make sure you are installing the latest one, okay? 18.4. So here is the download option.
Just try to click here, it will start downloading that.
Okay, so this is
the uh file, guys. You have to download okay. This is around uh 400 mb.
You can download. So for me, I already downloaded, I'll just try to cancel it. So once you have downloaded, guys, in the download folder, you will see this uh file, this uh uh PostgresQL okay.
Install it now. You just need to double click and install this uh software, okay, inside your system. So I think you know how to install any software.
Okay, the way you install any software, just try to double click and do next, next, next, okay.
Um, it will ask for uh like uh um a password. Okay, you just need to set the password and you can complete the installation process, okay?
So once you have done the installation, now simply you just need to search for pg admin
pg
admin on your search board. Now you'll be able to see this kinds of uh this kinds of application. Now let's open it up, okay? So this kinds of interface you will be able to see.
See, this is my pg admin. So for me, I already connected with the server, that's why it's coming like that.
But for you, it would be completely different. Okay, so maybe I can close this.
So for this, you will be getting this kinds of window screen, a welcome screen.
Okay, so now uh what I have to do, guys, I have to set up this uh
I have to set up this uh uh Postgres server on my render cloud, okay? Because I told you for this uh persistence memory, will be using post Postgres, right?
So, how to install this Postgres server on the render cloud? Let me show
you. So here I'll just visit the render.
Okay, make sure you have a account on render. If you don't have account, please try to create one account. For me, I already have the account, I'll just try to go to my dashboard.
Let me close these are the tab.
So
here uh to launch a Postgres server, guys. You just need to click on new,
and There you will see one option called PostgreS Postgres. Okay, PostgreSQL database. Let's try to click here.
So give the name of that uh PostgreSQL.
I'll give let's say
trip
trip agent.
let's say this is the name I have given. Now you can give the database name, so I'll give let's say
I'll give trip memory.
Or let's say agent memory.
Okay, now you have to give the user.
So I can give my user ID.
You can give your any unique user ID here. I have given ENT buck P, then everything just keep it default, no need to change anything.
Just here in the plan option, you just select the free instance. Okay, so uh render provides actually free instance.
You can use the free instance to launch this server, okay? And if you want to take this subscription, you can also do that. But in free instance, there is a limitation.
I think after uh 7 or 14 days, I think this instance would be deleted automatically, and here you are getting uh 256
mb RAM, 0.1 CPU, and 1 GB storage.
Okay, I think this is enough for our learning, but whenever you are creating any real-world application, my production grade application, whichever you will be using, right?
that time you can take their subscription plan. Okay, no need to take the free instance that time,
so yeah, everything just keep it default and simply just create the database,
okay. it's giving one error because previously I also created one Postgres server, right? So, first of all, I had to delete that one, so maybe I can delete that one.
So, this is the database I created, right? I'll just try to delete that.
So, if you're doing for the first time, right? you don't need to do that, it will create.
But for me, I created previously that's why it's coming like that.
So I'll just try to delete it
done now. Maybe I will be able to create that.
All the informations are fine.
Let's create a database.
Okay, now it is getting created. Okay, now let's wait. This starter should be active. Once it is active, then we can use this database.
Okay, guys, now you can see starters is available. That means my Postgres server is running successfully.
Okay, you can check there, you can go to the dashboard and you can see it is available, and this is running.
Okay, now I have to connect this Postgres server with my PG admin so that I can see all of the uh table inside that, all of the database inside that. Okay, whatever I'm going to create later on.
So, for this, what I can do, I can go below,
and there is a URL you have to copy. This is called external database URL.
Okay, so render tells you if you are connecting this server in an external service that that means right now I'm using PG Admin. This is the external service, okay.
This is running on my local machine.
So for this, I have to use external database URL.
Okay, but there is another one called internal database URL as you can see. This is the internal database URL. This is only required whenever you are deploying this project.
That means let's say I am deploying the same project in the render cloud, okay, and I'm using render Postgres server.
That time I will be using internal database, okay.
So if you are only running your application in the same render cloud, that time internal database should be used, okay. Database URL should be used.
But if you're running from the external one, you have to use call you uh you have to copy this external database URL.
Okay, now let's try to copy that and make sure you don't share this URL with anyone,
otherwise, they will be able to access your database. Okay, I'm going to remove, I'm going to delete the instance after this recording. That's why I'm showing you.
So I'll copy this, and uh, what I can do,
maybe I can save it somewhere.
Let's I will save save this inside my readme file.
Okay, so this is the information I have.
So
this information I need to connect with my PG admin.
So now let's open the PG admin. So there is an option called server. Just try to right click and there is an option called register. Okay, just click on register and there is a option called server.
Now here you just need to give the name of the server. So I'll give um
table agent
or let's say trip
tripmate server. I'll give my application name
tripmate.
So this is the name
Tripmate,
tripmate. Okay, I'll give tripmate and uh just keep it as it is, okay.
Then uh there is an option called connection, just click on the connection, and here you have to give the name, okay. Host name, and why will get get this host name? Hostname should be
uh this one.
This should be the host name. See after add direct, right?
Whatever you have, just try to copy till.com render.com. This is your host name. Just try to copy
and provide it here.
So this is the host name, okay. Now by default, uh this Postgres run runs on port number five uh five four three two. No need to change change this now.
You have to give the database name. Okay, so what is the database name?
So here is the database name
agent memory.
So let's try to copy this.
This is the name
you can also verify.
Simply go to the
server,
and here is the database. Okay, so this is the name actually it has taken for the database. So I have given agent memory, but it has added this uh 6 uh 8k5 because it should be unique name.
Okay, that's why this information is added. Okay, just try to copy this and add it here,
okay.
Now it has uh it is asking for the username.
So, what is the username?
I think you remember.
I given the username ENT Buck P.
Okay, you can also verify in the Postgres
server
here. So, username is ENTB. Let's copy
and paste it here.
Now I have to give the password, okay? Where you'll get the password?
Here is the password.
This is the password, okay. There's copy,
even it is also available on my URL.
So this is the URL, okay. This is the password.
Let's try to copy and paste it here,
okay.
Then just try to activate this one, save password on, and uh yeah, everything is fine.
Now, simply
let me check everything is required or not. No, I think everything is fine. Now I'll just try to save this information.
See, once you will do that, it will be connected to the uh render Postgres server. Okay, now you can expand it.
Now you can click on database.
Now see this agent memory uh 68 uh 68k5.
Agent memory
68k5. Okay, this database I can see because this is already connected. Now, whatever tables you will be creating inside that, it would it would be available inside pg admin.
Okay, I can see all the tables. So this is the table.
Now we can refresh and simply
uh see right now there is no table. Uh we haven't created, but once I will try to create the table, you will be able to see all the tables. Okay, all of the conversation will be available.
So, see, so far we have connected our uh Postgres server with my PG admin.
Now, right now you have the graphical user interface, and from there you can see all of the tables you will be creating going forward, okay. So that means my Postgres installation is completely done.
Postgres setup is completely done, and this is running on my render cloud.
Okay, I hope you get it.
So, guys, we have successfully uh set up our Postgres server on the render and we have connected with our PG admin, and this is running completely fine.
Now I need to set up some additional uh additional let's say keys which is required for this development.
So, first thing I need the
I need the aviation stack api key.
Okay.
Um aviation stack API key.
Then I need
Grok API key.
Okay, first of all, let's collect the Grok API key, okay?
Our LLM provider API key.
Because here I told you I'll be using a meta lama model, okay. Lama 3 model from the Grok Grok provider.
Then I need
tably API key.
Then I need my database URL.
Okay, that means my Postgres database URL. And we already copied the URL. I think you remember that external URL. I'll just try to copy this as it is.
Let's cut it, okay?
And I'll try to save inside this variable.
So this is the URL. Okay. So with this URL, my Python client will be able to connect with my Postgres server.
It will store all of the conversation there.
Okay, so make sure you copy this external URL.
The URL we just copied okay, external URL. This one and try to save here.
Okay.
Then I need
some other things like my
Langsmith
API key and tracing, these are the things I need.
Let me show you.
Because to monitor to trace the entire application, will be using Lang Smith.
So this is the Langsmith. Okay, Langsmith tracing, it should be true.
Lang Smith endpoint. So this is the URL you have to provide, and Lang Smith API key we have to collect. Okay, so let's delete this API and I will collect my own API and Langsmith project name.
So let's say I'll give uh
travel agent, okay. Or let's say I'll give
my project name, which is tripMet AI.
Let's say this is my project name, okay. Now let's collect all of the API key one by one. Okay, one more thing I have to add, which is the default origin data.
Default origin data means let's say here the things you have to do, you have to give the location A to B. Let's say you want to visit India to Thailand, right?
So India is your origin, right? And Thailand you want to visit.
So by default, if user is not providing origin, let's say user is giving the prompt like that.
I want to visit Nepal.
Okay, so you are not giving the origin here. So by default, uh you can set the origin here, okay. Let's say which your origin. So let's say I'm from Dhaka right now, so I'll give DXC.
Okay, that means Dhaka.
So from Dhaka, it will plan to the different country. Okay, that means Dhaka is the origin right now for me.
Okay, I I hope you get it, guys. Okay, so that's how we can add a default origin.
If user is missing their origin, it will automatically take the default origin.
Okay, you can change this origin as per your requirement. If you're in let's say Thailand, you can give Thailand. If you're in let's say USA, you can give USA.
Okay, it's up to you. You so yes, uh, this is how we have to add all of the API key. Now let's collect the Grok API key first of all.
So, what I will do, I'll just
go to the Grok platform.
So you can search for Grok
Grok API key. Okay, simply search for Grok API key and go to the first website
and you can create an API key here, okay.
So let's create an API key.
So what I can do, I can maybe
remove my previous API key.
I'll give the name. Let's say I'll give
my treatment agent.
Treatment.
No expiration, just try to keep it here. If you want expiration, you can also select.
Now let's submit.
Now, this is your API key. Just try to copy
and make sure you are adding inside your environment variable.
Okay.
Yeah. Now you can ask me, I have given double quotation here, but in the database URL, I've been given a document uh double quotation.
See, whenever you are adding the database URL, no need to give any double quotation.
Okay. Uh, because uh database URL is a sensitive information. If you are giving quotation, sometimes it will also consider as a quotation uh as this uh as this URL.
Okay, so that's why I'm not giving any kinds of quotation.
Perfect. So we have successfully copied the grok API key, and inside grok you will be able to see different different models are available. Let me show you if I go to the dashboard
I think playground, and here you have different different model. So here I'll be using meta llama model.
Okay,
you can also use any other model, it's completely up to you. Then the next thing, guys, I need my
aviation stack API key. Okay, so let's search for aviation stack API key.
You can simply search on Google Aviation Stack API key.
So this is the first website, just go to the website,
okay?
So this is the website, guys.
Now here you will see one option get free API key. But for this, you have to sign up, okay. Sign up in their account. So I already have the account, I'll just try to log in.
Let's give my email and password
and log in.
Okay, so I've done log I've logged in now. Here you have the API key. Okay, just try to copy this API key.
Um, this is the API key as you can see. Just try to copy and you paste it here.
Okay, this is my aviation stack API key. So we need this aviation stack API key to get the real-time flight information, okay.
Uh, so as you can see, this is the interface.
So free real-time flight status and global aviation data API.
Okay, this provides flight flight tracker airport
timetable data web service trusted by uh 5000 plus of smart test company.
Okay, fine.
Now the next thing I need, which is uh tably API key, okay. For real-time source operation, I think you saw the diagram, right?
So I have already collected my aviation stack API key and grok API key okay for the large language model provider.
Now for real-time source operation, I need tably API key.
Now let's collect this tably API key.
So for this on Google, just try to search for tably API key.
Go to the tably
and make sure you log in with your account.
Okay, now here you have the API key. Okay, so previously I already have some API key. Maybe I can collect or maybe I can create a new one. So let me delete some of the API key.
I'll create a new one.
I'm going to name it, name it as let's say
my project name.
Now simply create the API key.
Okay, now copy this one
and add inside your environment variable.
Now, last thing I need my Lang Smith API key for the tracing. So we'll be using Lang Smith platform.
So you can search for smith.langchain.com.
So this is the Lang Smith platform.
So if you don't have account, guys, please try to create one account.
so I already logged in with my account, okay.
But for you, it will look like that.
Okay, so once you have done that, uh you have to collect the API key.
So left hand side you will see one option called settings.
Now, here is the API key section. Okay, just create one API key.
So I'll create one API key here.
You can give the name.
Okay, just keep it as it is.
Now expiration date, you can give it as never and create the API key.
Now copy this API key
and mention it here.
Okay, and give the name of the Lang Speed project. I have given uh tripMet AI.
So it will create this project inside that you will perform all the tracing.
Okay, so yes, that's how we have collected all of the API key, whichever we need it here.
Now uh we what we'll do, guys, we'll just try to define the folder structure, then we'll try to implement the component one by one.
So, guys, now let's try to define our folder structure.
So, first of all, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to create a folder, I'm going to name it as tools.
So, inside that I'm going to create all of my tools I need for this development. So, I think you know I need some tools like these aviation stack tools.
So, this function I'll be writing separately, so it will get the real-time flight informations. Then for hotel agents, I need tabily, right?
So, tabily will do the real-time search operation, it will get the different different uh information that information for this. I will be creating another function.
Okay, so that's how I need separate separate tools, and this thing I will try to define inside my tools. So let's create some file inside that. So, first of all, I'm going to
define a constructor
underscore underscore init underscore dot pie.
Now inside that let's create a file. I'm going to name it as
flight tool
dot pi.
and I'm going to create another file.
I'm going to name it as stabilitool.py.
Okay.
Yeah.
Now uh I need another
another um
another files here.
I'm going to name it as
backend.py.
Then I'm going to create another file called app.py.
So this is going to be my endpoint, okay?
And I'm going to create another folder called templates.
So inside that I'll write try to write my front end codes that means HTML codes, right?
Templates.
Inside that I'm going to create a file called index.html.
So here we'll try to write all of the HTML code because I told you we'll be using HTML, CSS JavaScript with the fast API.
And fast API needs this template folder and this is HTML file and whatever CSS and
JavaScript file I'll be writing, it should be available inside static folder.
Okay, static folder inside that I'm going to create two more file.
One is style,
dot cs,
and there is
script.js.
Okay. and if you don't know about HTML, CSS, JavaScript, no need to worry.
simply you can take the help from chat gpt and you can create this at the user interface for you.
Okay, so yes, these are my folders and file I need for this development. Now let me close these are the one by one.
Now let me commit the changes on my GitHub. So simply I'll tell folder
structure
add it.
Now, if I go to my GitHub refresh,
see all of the folder structures are available.
Okay, so later on, I also need Docker file. Uh, I will use that whenever I'll do the deployment. Okay, as of now it's completely fine.
Now, first of all, uh, what I can do, guys, first of all, let's
say here
I'm going to define the tool. Okay, first of all, let's write this travelly tool.
So I already installed the uh environment, and the environment name is
travel, right? I think I created travel. I'll select this environment. Okay, now let's import some necessary package. I'll import tably
import
tabily client. Okay, then I need operating system,
then I need dot env. So from
dot env import
load env.
Then now I'll try to load my environment variable.
Then let's create a tabily client first of all. So client
is equal to
tabily client.
So first of all, inside that you have to pass the api key.
So why do you have the api key? API key is available inside my environment. So I'll just write os.get env.
Okay.
Get
uh
env
and what is the name of my key?
The key name is
tabily API key.
I'll copy this and paste it here.
So this is going to be this is going going to give me the client. Okay,
so after that, here we'll just try to write a function. So dev tabily search
search inside that it will take a query that means the search query,
okay,
and it will search over the internet. So for this, I'll just try to write response is equal to client
dot search. Okay, and inside search I will give my query
query is equal to my query,
and there is another parameter you have to give called max result. Okay, that means how many maximum search result you want. So I need five results. Okay, five search results. I need
then then whatever results I will try to get, guys. I'll try to I'll just try to do some refinement operation.
That means it will also give me some some kinds of metadata, but I don't need the beta data, I only need the content, right?
And to filter out, I have written this code.
Let me show you.
First of all, let's define the result,
so it is going to be an empty list, okay?
So this is the filter code I have written. So it will run a for loop, okay? So it will run the for loop on the response result and it will get the title URL snippet.
Snippet means the content, and it will lengthen the snippet if the snippet it is more than 300 words. So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to split it
and I'm going to append in my result uh result list. Okay, that means I'm only taking the content uh from my source result instead of some metadata.
Okay,
so yeah, I think um
it's done.
Uh, even you can also uh I mean remove this if you don't want. So this thing I have added just to keep only the first 300 character to avoid one of text. Okay, so that's why.
But if you want, you can take the entire snippet if you want, okay.
Uh, it's up to you, uh, because we are using uh free, large language model, and definitely some input output limitations are there, token limitation is there.
so that's why I have taken, like some um, some, like important fast character instead of, I mean, the last one,
but you can.
uh, you can ignore this line. okay? Maybe you can directly take the snippet and you can add inside the results.
Okay, this is completely up to you. So this is my uh tabily search function.
Okay, now let's test whether it's working or not. So, what I can do, maybe I can create another file here. I'm going to name it as test dot file.
Let's import this.
from
tools
dot tabily
import
tabily source
Now,
let's define an object I'm going to
call the tabily source Inside that, I'm going to give a query.
So, let's say I'll give
"best hotels
india"
and I'm going to print the response.
Now, let's execute:
so python test dot py
So you can see, this is the information we are getting: "best hotels in india ". So it is, uh Uh, see, it is referring different different website,
real time website.
Okay, that means tripadvisor.com,
and it is finding some best website, uh, hotels; okay, then some other youtube resources also. It has um referred some review, it has uh seen right, and it is giving you some best hotels in India.
Okay, so that's how we are getting.
Best out of all of the, uh, all of the, let's say, resources out there with the help of this Tably, instead of manually exporting. I have the tablet.
I can search, like, I need best things, it will automatically search over different different website hotels, okay? And it will give me those information, okay? For my agents, this is the idea.
See?
Okay, it is referring that you
—that means this function is working completely fine. There is no issue with this function now. Simply, I'll just try to
open up my code again.
Yeah, now next guys, I'll be writing my flight tools. Okay, this. Tools I have to write now. This will give you that yield time flight informations.
Okay, so for this, let's import some necessary library. So I need operating system.
I need regular expression.
I need
certify.
airports, data.
I need pie country.
Then I need dot enb. So from dot enb
import
load env.
Okay,
then I'll load the environment variable.
After that, see if you're using Windows operating system, you might get a path issue. So to prevent that, we add these two lines: SSL.
Cert files and request key bundles, okay? You have to give certified dot while.
So if you're uh getting the path issue, that time you can give, okay?
So I have given for the safest purpose.
Then first of all, I have to get my aviation API key. So I'll just write: api underscore key is equal to
os dot get env Okay, and what is the name of that?
And the name of that is Aviation API key, Aviation Stack API key.
I'll just try to get this API key.
So, once you get the API key, you also need to take the origin.
See, I'm taking the origin as well. Default origin.
We mentioned Dhaka here.
But if you want, you can also change it as per your requirement.
Okay. So here my default origin is Dhaka. If user is not giving any default origin, it will take the Dhaka.
Otherwise, uh, it will take the default, uh it will take the origin okay from the user query. Then uh, what is the base URL for aviation flights?
So this is the base URL.
You can visit the base URL.
So here you have to give an API key. If you give the API key, this will give you the this will return you the aviation.
Sorry, this will return you the flight information. Okay, so we are hitting this website API.
Okay, now uh first of all I will load the airports data.
So to load the airports data, you have to use airports data.load, then you have to give i what uh i a ta.
Okay, so it will give you all the airports.
Then I will also mention my country allies
because sometimes uh user may pass the allies information, right? Let's say user will give us us means USA.
Okay, that's how it has all the um allies name for all the country. Let's say Korea, K R Dhaka, D A K, right? I already told you.
So this is called allies, so we are defining the allies,
then country many airport.
So all the country many output I'll just try to mention here.
So these are the airport name okay.
So BD Dhaka in the
like that, then ct menu airput.
These are my ct menu outputs, okay.
We are defining.
Then we just write a function for cleaning the text.
So clean text, so it this will take the text and it will perform the cleaning operation, it will remove some stop words and all, okay, and it will return you return you that
then. I'll write another function. This will return you country name to code.
Okay, if you give any text that means the country name, it will return you the country code,
then airports
country matches.
So if you are um giving a give you give you if you're giving any airports and country code, it will give you the
uh airports, okay.
Then get best airports for the country.
For this, I have written another function,
okay.
So get best airport for the country. So you just need to give the country code, it will give you the best airport for that.
Then some other things I have also added here.
So this is like more robust code I have written.
Um
if you see over the uh internet, right? And if you see this aviation stack API key code, you will see different different codes are available over the internet.
People are using to get the real-time information, real-time flight information with respect to all the country.
Okay, so I utilize the internet resources and I prepared the entire functionality for you.
Okay, so this is giving you the location,
okay.
Then let me show you some other things I have added.
So
this is the entire code, guys.
Okay,
So, one thing I had to import, which is request.
Now, see, this is the entire code I have written to get the flight informations. Okay.
So, see, these are some dependency utility function I need to get the airport informations, flight informations.
See,
and some of the functionality I generated from chat GPT just to make it more robust.
See, here my main intention is to handle all of the country user is giving, right? So that's why these are the things are required.
So, see it will return uh these are the thing airlines, flight, starters, departure, okay, terminal gate, schedule.
So, these are the information it will return from the aviation stack API.
So, search flight.
See, we are getting these are the informations, okay.
Now let's test this whether it is working or not. So, what I can do, so this is the function SARS
search flight. This is my final function. This takes the query and the limit. So by default, limit I have given 10.
Okay, 10 information it will give you.
Okay, 10 flight information it will return you.
So let's let's test it. So what I can do, maybe I can copy this code.
I'll go to the test,
I'll comment this.
Let's import that. So from
tools
dot flight
flight tools import
search flights. Okay.
now let's mention the search flight,
and I'll get the result,
and I'll print that
salgive Nepal
trip from Bangladesh.
Now if I execute
now, see this is giving you all the flight information from Bangladesh to Nepal.
See all the flight information it is returning you,
okay.
And why this is happening? Because I have written this code.
This code, okay. This is like more robust code and it can handle almost all kinds of country, okay, all kinds of flight informations.
Okay, so I took the help from chat GPT, I prepared this entire functionality for you. Even we can also write a small function, but a small function has some limitation.
Only if you hit the aviation stack API key, that time sometimes if you are giving the wrong let's say location name, that times it will
return you none. Okay, so to handle this kinds of scenario because user can give any anything right in the chat interface.
They can sometimes uh let's say
give the wrong input okay, uh, of the country. That time it can also handle this kinds of scenario. Okay, that's why I have written this code.
Now you can ask me why I'm not using tools decorator here whenever I'm writing the tools.
Um, see here I'm not going to use it as a um
as a like custom tool. Instead of that, I'll be using it inside my agent. Okay, I'll tell you this part how to do that.
That's why I'm not using any kinds of tool functionality from Langchen.
Okay, I'll tell you. So, yes, uh, my tably and flight tools functionality are added, and this is completely working fine. We have already tested now. We'll start the agent workflow, okay.
But before that, let me commit the changes.
So here I'll just write flight
and
tabily
tools
added.
Now. Go to GitHub, refresh.
This is available, okay.
All right, now let's work on the um agent tick workflow part. That means right now my tools are ready. Okay, all the tools, whatever we'll be using, aviation stack and tabily, these are ready.
Okay, then now I'll be working on the agent part. Okay, we'll try to define all the agents one by one and we'll be creating the Langaroff workflow.
Once all of the agent implementation is complete, then we'll also
define the state, okay.
And the state will try to save inside my Postgres SQL database, okay?
So, yeah, this is the entire plan. Now let's try to work on the um
agent workflow. For this, I'm going to open up my backend.py
and here I'll just try to write all of my code.
So, first of all, here let's import all the necessary library.
I need operating system
again.
I need certify just to prevent that path issue, and I need dot enb as well.
Load enb.
Okay, so I'll load my environment variable,
and this is the code I need to
prevent that path issue.
Okay, then I need some other libraries as well. Let me show you.
these are the libraries I need,
so I need this typing type dict annotated, and why I need I think you know to define the state okay of the graph, then operator I need because here we'll be using the reducer
concept because all of the conversation uh we are doing right. Let's say I'm giving an input, my my uh agent is giving output, right? And this output I don't want to replace with the previous one.
I have to add uh add it like a list, okay. And for this, I I can use reducer concept. Okay, I think you know we have already started about this thing inside our course, right?
Inside my agent KI course, I already told you about that. If you haven't checked that, please try to check. Then UI ID I need just to define um
shone trade.
I think you know uh in persistence memory we have to give a trade, right? Trade ID. So every time uh we can generate new trades, okay, for the user.
Then uh this is for the Postgres okay database.
Uh, then uh we are also importing this uh row uh dict row okay for the Postgres database. Then uh from line graph, we are importing a state graph start and end, and this is the checkpointer.
So from Langgraph checkpoint postgase, we are importing Postgres server, okay. So we'll try to save my checkpoint in my Postgres server.
Apart from that, I also need to import these are the libraries like from Langchain uh messages. I need any message, human message, AI message, system message.
Then from Grok
Langchain Grok, I need chat grok because we are using Grok API provider to access the large language model and the tools we have created. So from tools
dot tabli
I'll import my
tably source
and from tools
dot
flight tools, I'll import the source flight.
Okay, these two things I'll try to import.
Okay, so yeah, these are my imports uh I need as of now.
Now, first of all, here what I'm going to do, I'm going to um
I'm going to
define a function. Okay, so this function what it returns, it returns the database URL.
That means I think you remember, let me show you.
So let me close these are the files.
So I think you remember in the.nb we have mentioned the database URL. Okay, so this is the database URL.
So this database URL I have to return, okay, just to connect with my Postgres SQL database server. Okay, so for this, I'll define a function.
So see, this is the function, only you just need to do a slight modification here, which is that at the last, okay. At the last of this URL, you will be adding this SSL mode is equal to required.
That means if you if this is your database, right?
So here we are adding this line,
we are adding this line, we are adding
this thing, okay, at the last.
This thing at the last we'll be adding okay. This is required. Why this is required? Because here we will be will be connecting with my remote Postgres server, right?
And for remote Postgres server, this is required, so that's why we are checking.
First of all, we are getting the database URL, then we are checking if not database URL, I'll raise the exception.
Database URL is missing, otherwise, I'll try to check if SSL mode not in database URL. I'll just try to add it and return the database URL.
Okay, now how this uh this will uh look like so. Let me show you. So maybe I can call this function
so URL is equal to database URL.
So I'll print the URL right now.
So I'll
come here python
app.py
okay. Okay, sorry, it's backend.py. Sorry, my mistake. So python
backend py
now. See, this is what we are getting. This is the entire URL, and the last see it is adding this this thing, okay.
It is it will give you this uh question mark, then this SSL mode is equal to required.
Okay, this thing it should add, then I will be able to connect with my post case remote server, okay, which is running on Brandat.
Okay, I hope you get it. That's why we are giving this function.
Yeah, so now let's delete this code, it's not required, okay. Now, guys, uh, we'll try to get some other things, like —my.
let me show you,
like, my Grok,
Grok, API, key.
So we are loading the grok API key, okay, from the environment variable.
Then here we'll just try to write a condition.
If not grok API key found, it will raise an exception.
Okay, now we'll try to define the large language model.
So here we are defining the large language model as you can see. We are using chat grok and model is equal to I'm using Lama 3.37 billion versatile model. Okay, this is available on the
um Grock.
See this one, okay. This model we are using.
Okay, now you can use any model, only you just need to give the model ID.
Okay, just try to check here. It has the model ID, just copy this model ID and paste it here.
It will use that model, and we are giving the
um API key. Then we have to define the state, okay?
My
graph state.
So this is the state I have prepared, guys.
And I think you know what is the state and how to define the state, each and everything I have completed in my course.
Please try to check, guys. Okay, so I named it as table state and uh inherited with the type dict.
First of all, the message that means you can match with here message, okay. Whatever message uh user is giving, I'll try to store here, but this should be reducer object, okay.
That means we are doing operation dot add that means every time it will add add that masses, okay, instead of replacing, then user query.
Whatever query user is passing, I'll write to save in the user query, then flight result, hotel result, uh then itinerary uh result, and one additional things I have provided here, which is llm calls.
That means I want to see how many times llm calls we are doing here. That means we'll do the llm count as well. This thing I also stored inside my state memory, okay.
That is my shared memory.
Now, first of all, I'll define my flight agent. Okay, the first agent. Let's define the first agent.
So, this is my first agent, flight agent.
Okay, so I named it as a flight agent. It will take this state okay as a shared memory.
Then first of all, I'm taking the user query from the state and we are doing the flight search operation with the help of this search flight function we have written inside my flight tools.
Okay, that is why I'm not using this function as a tool, custom tool.
Instead of that, I'm using inside my agent.
Okay, I think you remember, uh, I think you get it right why I'm not using custom function.
Yeah, so I'm using directly inside my agent, so it is doing the search operation, uh, it will get the flight information and I'm returning the flight information as a result
and AI message, okay. That flight result fetched, then I'm also doing the LLM count. That means initially my LLM uh calls would be zero, okay?
So I'm just uh getting that particular data and I'm uh doing the plus one add operation. That means if initially it was zero, it will add the plus one. That means one llm call I have done.
That's how many time LLM call I'll try to do. I'll just try to update this LLM calls, okay?
Done.
So this is my first agent we have prepared. Now let me define the second agent, which is nothing but hotel agent.
Okay, now let's define the hotel agent. Now, what hotel agent do it will use the tably search and it will get the hotel information.
See, this is my next agent, which is hotel agent. So again, it will take the state and this is the query best hotels for user query. That means if user is giving, let's say
I want to visit uh Japan from Bangladesh. So Japan best hotel it will try to find, right?
And for this, we're using tabily search functionality. So this is the tablet search functionality, it will found best hotels okay from the internet I will return it here.
Then I'm returning this hotel result as well as the AI message hotel information fetched and again we are updating the LLM calls with plus one, okay.
I think you get it. So this is my second agent. Now I'll try to define my third agent, which is itinerary agent, okay. So basically, this will uh do the plan, it will basically
create the places to visit activities, all of this thing, right?
So here what I'm going to do, I'm going to utilize the large language model here because without large language model, I can't generate the plan, right?
So that's why I have to use the large language model. So this is my
next agent,
okay. Inside backend.py have to write.
This is my
uh itinerary agent. Okay, as you can see, itinerary agents this is taking the state, and this is the prompt I am defining. So create a complete table itinerary, uh, user query.
This is the user query, this is the flight result, this is the hotel information. Okay, make the itinerary a practical budget hour and easy to follow.
Okay, now here we are invoking the llm. The llm we have defined, I think remember this is the llm.
We are invoking the llm with this prompt.
We are giving the system message your expert table planner, and this is the human message we are giving as a prompt.
Okay, then after that, we are returning the itinerary response message as well as the LLM call we are also updating.
Okay, I hope you get it. So that's how we are completing the third agent, which is itinerary agents. Now we'll be creating the final agents, which is final response agents.
That means it will take all of the results and it will combine everything and it will generate a final response for me.
Okay, so let's try to write it here.
Uh, so this is the agent
or final response.
So this is our final agent. It will take this state again, and this is the final prompt.
Generate a final tribal response for the user. This is the user query, flight information, hotel information, and this is the itinerary plan.
Format the final answer beautifully using these sections.
That means it will have the trip, summary, flight information, hotel suggestion, day by day, itinerary, estimated budget, final recommendation, and some important note as well.
Okay, so yeah, this is my entire prompt, and we are again booking the LLM. We are giving the system message.
You are a professional AI travel booking assistant, and this is the human prompt you are giving, and whatever response I'm getting, I'm returning as a response and I'm upgetting my LLM call.
Okay, that's how we have completed four agents implementation.
Okay, now we'll try to build the graph.
So in Line Graph, we have to define the graph.
Let's try to define the graph right now.
So we'll build the graph.
So to build the graph, first of all, I have defined my state graph.
I passed my state, and this is going to be my graph.
Now we'll try to add all of the nodes one by one. First of all, I will add my flight agent, then hotel agent, then itinerary agent, then final response agents.
All the agents I'll try to add one by one.
So these are my agents. Okay, I'm adding the nodes: flight agent, flight agent, hotel agent, hotel agent, itinerary agents, itinerary agents, flight agents, flight agents.
Sorry, final agent, final agents.
I have added all of the agent node.
Now I have to do the edge connection.
Okay, that means flight agents would be connected to the hotel agents, hotel agent would be connected to the itinerary agents, itinerary agents would be connected to the final response agents.
Okay, that means the connection we have to build right now.
So let me show you the connection.
So this is the connection. So you can see start,
start to flight agents, okay.
Then flight agents to hotel agents, flight agent to hotel agents,
then hotel agents to itinerary agents, hotel agents to itinerary agents, okay. Then itinerary agents to final response agent to final respond agents and final response agents to end.
Okay, so this is the connection we had we have done now. We have to define the Postgres
checkpointer.
So I think remember we already written a function called database URL.
So basically, this returns the database URL, okay, and we are store uh storing the URL inside a variable called database URL.
Now I'll try to do the connection.
So we are using uh psycobg.connect.
We are giving the database URL, then auto commit is equal to true and row factory is equal to dick row. Okay, these are the parameters we have to pass and it will give you the connection.
And this connection I have to pass inside my checkpointer.
So Postgres server, I think remember we imported from checkpointer here
from Langer checkpointer postgets postgets server.
Inside that we have to pass this connection, and this will return to the checkpoint, and I have to do the checkpointer uh checkpointer dot setup.
Once it is done, then I'll try to pass this checkpointer inside my graph. Okay, we'll try to compile.
So travel graph is equal to graph
graph.compile, and we are giving the checkpointer now. All of this state would be saved inside my memory.
Okay,
then uh once everything is done, now let me write the function
for my fast API.
So this is the function,
final function.
So run travel agent. So this takes the run user input and the trade ID. Okay, so first of all, if user is uh not given trade ID, so what I'm doing, I'm just uh generating a unique trade ID and
we are preparing the configuration, okay. Configurable inside trade ID, I'm passing my trade ID.
Then I'm invoking my travel graph. Okay, so here we're doing the invoking, so we are giving the human message user input, and initially my flight result, total result, itinerary,
lm cost would be empty. That's why I'm passing as a empty, then I'm passing the configuration.
Whatever result I'm getting, I'm just checking the content and I'm returning the response. That is my trade ID, answer, flight result, total result, itinerary, lm cost.
Each and everything I'm just returning on my front end.
Okay,
and in from here, I'll try to get the informations and what I can do, I'll just try to show in my front end.
Okay, the front end will try to create now. Let me test whether it's working or not. So, what I can do, I can maybe run this travel agent test.
I'll copy this and open my test.py.
Let me import here so from
backend
uh
import
run travel agent. Okay, and then again, I'll try to comment out
so
response is equal to
run the travel agent
and I'll print the response.
Even maybe what I can do, I can instead of writing like that, I can write a full loop.
Okay, let me show you.
I can write a full loop like that.
So here I'm taking a user input from the user, and
okay, instead of for loop, maybe I can directly run okay. Then I'm running the travel agent
this function and I'm passing the user input and trade ID just for testing purpose I've given test user and whatever response I'm getting, I'm just um
printing the response. Okay, now let me test.
So I'll just try to execute.
So
I'll just run python backend dot py.
Not backend.py, sorry.
It should be
um
it should be test.py
okay let's execute huh.
So python test dot py
now it is asking the user input. So let's give a input.
So this is my user input.
plan a complete seven days India trip from Bangladesh, including flights, hotel, sightseeing 102 lakhs.
Now let's see.
Now see this is the entire plan I'm getting. So final response, the summary, flight information,
hotel suggestions, day by day itinerary, then estimated budget, final recommendation.
Amazing, okay, it's working fine.
Now we have to add uh add this inside my user interface. Okay, right now my back end is ready. Okay, we are able to test it perfectly.
Now we'll be creating the
front end user interface with the help of fast API, and we'll be writing the fast API, fast API route, okay.
back end route, and so that my front end can communicate with my um like back end, okay. So for this we'll be using fast API service, and fast API is a production grade
web framework, okay, especially API creation framework you can use.
Okay, so let's try to implement my fast API code, guys, right now.
And one more thing I want to show you. I already executed my workflow and it has executed successfully. I think we have seen that.
Now let me see whether it is able to store the checkpoint in my database or not.
Now I'll open up my PG admin and now if I refresh on my table, right?
Now if I go inside the table, you will see that all of the checkpoint has created. Okay, now here is a checkpoint. Uh checkpointer table is there.
Now just try to right click and there is an option called view edit data. Now just click on all rows. Okay, if you do that, you'll be able to see that all of the checkpoints it has saved here.
See all of the checkpoint it has saved.
Okay, this is the state memory,
and it has also traced on my
Langsmith platform.
Let me open my Lang Smith
done. If I go to my Langsmith, so tap uh tripMate AI. If I go inside that now, see this is the Langsmith execution. Even you can see the trade device, okay.
The test user uh trade we have given initially, and this is the execution.
Okay, this is the execution it has done.
Okay, see,
amazing, right? Now let's try to add my fast API code.
So for this, I'll open up my app.py
and here let's define all of the code.
And I'm expecting, guys, you are already familiar with fast API here.
fast API knowledge is required.
So here, what I'm going to do, I'm going to import some necessary libraries.
Yeah, so I'm importing path from pathlib, traceback, UVcon from fast API. I'm importing fast API request, fast API.
I'm importing HTML response, JSON response, static file, ginger templates, and base model from Pydentic. So here I need Pydentic just to define my
data structure.
I think I already completed Pydentic videos as well on my um on my uh agentki course and why pydentic is required. I already told you. Please get to go through that session.
Then I need another functionality which is my
this function run travel agent from my back end.
Let me import it as well.
So from
backend,
import
run travel agent. Okay, first of all, let's create a base directory,
then I'll define my fast API app.
That's how we can define the fast API app. So I've named it as AI travel planning system, or maybe I can give this name
tripmate ai.
Okay, trip met AI.
So this is a language multi-agent travel planner with fast API front end. And this is the version we have given. Okay.
Now, first of all, you have to mount your static folder as well as the template folder.
So let's mount.
because inside static you have JavaScript and CSS and template, you have the HTML.
So we are doing the app.mount static, and this is my static file file directories. Okay, we are giving it.
And similar wise, we have to give the templates as well.
So you can see ginger templates. I am passing my directory, which is templates. Inside that I have my HTML content.
Now, what I have done, guys, I have already generated HTML CSS code from chat GPT for this project.
See if you don't know about HTML CSS design, it's completely fine. There is there would be a separate front-end developer for that.
Uh, they will be using some other front-end framework like next.js react.
Okay, with the help of that, they will be creating the front-end server for you, and then they will be connecting with your fast API backend, right?
So if you don't know about HTML CSS, completely fine, just try to go through Chat GPT and just tell I need this kinds of interface. Okay, just give me the HTML CSS and JavaScript code.
Chat GPT will give you, and you just need to copy paste here and you need to modify with respect to your requirement. So I have done the same thing. So this is my HTML code I generated from ChatGPT
uh for my user interface, and then I modified okay, as per my requirement.
So here, title wise, I can give
my name tripmeti.
So that's how you can modify the data data property with respect to your requirement, okay. Whatever data you have inside HTML content, just try to change.
So this is a simple code I have generated from chat apt and it needs a CSS, okay, just to load the design so CSS style.
So I'll again try to
give this CSS design here in my CSS file, static.css style.css file.
So this is the CSS code, CSS design.
Okay, I have added
okay. Again, I generated from chat GPT.
Then just to communicate with my front end uh
just to communicate with my fast API route, I need this script.js.
So again, I prepared with the help of
chat GPT.
So this is my JavaScript code and hit it hits my uh fast API route. Okay, I'll tell you what are the route it will hit just to get the data.
So, first of all, it will hit my API travel. Okay, API travel means it will hit that API travel route and it will get the uh it will get the entire plan.
Okay, that means whatever execution I showed you right now, these are the information it will try to get and it will try to show in my front end. Okay, this is what it is doing.
Now let me show you.
First of all, let me define all the routes one by one.
So, first of all, I'll try to define my
pydentic schema travel request.
I'm inheriting with the base model, and this has the message and trade ID.
Okay, and this is my default route.
This is my default route. If you visit my app, first of all, it will launch my HTML page,
and this is the final
API route.
This is my final API route as you can see. API slash travel. If you hit that, and again I'm using asynchronous, okay. Asynchronous functionality.
Why asynchronous? Because it will run my agent is asynchronous way, okay.
That means parallel execution it will do.
I think I already covered this asynchronous as well in my playlist. Just try to go through that. So asynchronous, I'm running.
You can see travel planner, it will take the uh information from the user. That means the user input, whatever user input will pass from the input box.
First of all, I'm checking if user is not available.
I'm returning masses, can cannot be empty.
Then, if available, I'm running my run travel agent. That means this function, okay. This function I have imported from back end.
So this function will return what result. Okay. And from the result, we're extracting these are the content and we're returning okay in my front end.
And if some exception is occurring, I'm handling the exception.
Okay.
And uh some other route I need
sometimes uh it will check the health condition of my first API server. So for this, it will hit this route slash held, and it will if everything is uh working fine, it will give uh strategies
okay, and this is running, and some icon to load some icon. Actually, you need this one, okay.
Now uh finally, I'm going to execute my server with the help of uvcon run so app clone app because this is app file and my object is
app,
my objective app okay.
Then uh host and port number and reload is equal to true.
So these are the things you have to provide. Okay, now in this uh JavaScript I'm calling this route.
If I show you, if I do just control F and paste, see this is what actually I'm executing. So whenever user is generating the response, it is hitting here, okay, and it is getting the information.
Let me show you. So I'll execute my app right now.
So python app.py
this is running on localhost port number 8000.
So I'll come here, search for localhost port number 8000. See, this is your application.
Okay, uh, you can see this is your application. Now, here you have to give the input. So let's say I'll give this input Dubai trip plan a five.
This Dubai trip from Dhaka with flights, hotels, and sites like uh site sinks.
Now, if I see click on generate plan, that time it will hit this route, okay.
Hit this route and it will get all of these uh information, it will generate all of the information, then it will get and show in the front end. Let me show you.
See,
uh okay. Uh it is terminating the okay, because my previous application is running. Okay, I already executed my uh this app previously just to show you. So let me first of all stop this execution.
Okay, now it will run.
It's running now.
Refresh again.
Now let me give this prompt and generate the plan.
Now see, this is the
entire plan we are getting okay, in a beautiful format.
Okay, and there is a download PDF button. And how this is coming because of the front-end design we have done.
Okay, so this work uh this work is completely uh responsible for front-end designer. So uh you just tell them okay what you need.
So if you need these kinds of download PDF or if you need let's say uh any um download any markdown file, you just tell them, okay, they will try to prepare for you,
and you can um you can just use that as it is, okay. And this is the trade it has created, okay.
Because we haven't passed any trades, that's why it has created uh um randomly generated trades, okay. So that's how we can give any kinds of prompt right now.
Let's say instead of Dubai, I'll give
maybe Thailand.
See, this is the plan for the Thailand.
So this is the summary, this is the flight information, this is the hotel suggestions, this is the day by day itinerary.
Uh, first day, second day, third day, fourth day, fifth day, sixth day, seven days, okay, an estimated budget you need.
then final recommendation. Okay, amazing, right? Now I can easily download this file and I can uh I can store in my mobile phone.
Okay, and I can use it anytime.
So, yes, guys, that's how we can implement this entire system. And if I show you my checkpoint right now, if I again do let's say refresh, see all of the checkpoint would be available,
all of the conversation memory would be available inside my Postgres.
See, okay. Now, see initially I executed test user. Now this is the current user, the current trade. Okay, current trade execution, and these are my messages.
Now you can also see the
Um
langsmith.
So if I go to the Langsmith, uh, if I again refresh,
now another trade should be created. See, this is the trade and two conversation. I have done now. This is the two conversation.
Now you can see all of the information. Okay, which tools it is using, each and everything is visible here.
Input and output, each and everything.
Okay, so amazing guys, we have successfully completed our implementation and it is working fine.
Now, what I want to do, guys, I want to deploy it over the render cloud. Okay, so I'll deploy this uh project on my render cloud, but before that, let me commit the changes.
So here I'll just try to
app,
add it, commit and send the changes.
Okay, now if I go to my GitHub, refresh
now, see it's updated. Okay, now it's ready for the deployment. Now let's do the deployment of this application,
okay? So, guys, for the deployment, uh, we'll be using Docker.
Um, so let's create a file here.
I'm going to name it as Docker file, and inside that you have to mention all of the Docker related command.
And if you don't know about Docker, guys,
Docker is a containerization service, and
this tutorial is already available on my YouTube channel. Let me show you. So, if I go to my YouTube right, DS with Bhappee.
So if you go to the video section, I already have a
full MLOPs course. Okay, here if you see here,
this is the MLOps course, you can open it up
and this course already covered
Docker, okay.
Yeah, so see Docker for MLOps. You can um at least go through this Docker part, okay, and try to master the Docker. And if you're interested, learning entire MLOps. This is already available.
This is around 12 hours of recording. You can go through that, okay. And if you like the content, please try to subscribe to my channel.
So Docker is required. I'm expecting you already familiar with Docker.
So simply I'll try to add all of the Docker related command here. So this is these are my Docker-related command, guys.
As you can see, first of all, I'm taking a beige image 3.11 creating working directory, adding some environment variable, then running some commands,
copying the requirement.txt file, then installing the requirement.txt file, copying all of my source code, then this thing I don't need. I'll just try to remove
this thing I not in. Then I have to expose the port. Okay, port should be uh port number
eight thousand I think. Right, we are using port number eight thousand. So I'll try to add port number eight thousand here,
and we are running the command hivicon app file localhost and port number 8000.
So this is my Docker file, okay. I need, and for this, I need to create another file which is dot
docker
ignore,
and here you have to mention all of the
uh files and folder you have you you want to ignore during Docker Dockerization. So these are the things I'll try to ignore okay during Dockerization.
So now let me push the changes again, and what I'm going to do, I'm going to also update the readme file. Okay, I already created the readme file update.
So I have added a beautiful README content.
Let me show you.
So this is the README, guys. I have added, so I have given the entire um project summary, features, take stack, project structure, prerequisite, environment,
installation, running the app, endpoint. Okay, so each and everything I have added. So your project should have one beautiful README file, guys.
Okay, this is super important.
So README just try to add.
Uh one more thing I want to add, which is I will give my project name as it is
now.
It looks good, I think.
Now it it looks it looks good. So yeah, I think we are done now. Let me commit the changes
docker
added.
Now if I go to my GitHub refresh,
now see beautifully I have added the readme and each and everything.
Okay, now it is ready for the deployment. Now what I'm going to do, guys, I'm going to open up my render cloud.
Go to the dashboard.
Now I'll create a new
web service.
Okay.
Select this public git repo and copy this GitHub repo. Okay,
copy this URL and paste it here.
And let's connect.
Okay, see automatically it has taken and it is using the Docker services.
Okay, for the deployment.
So everything just keep it as it is, no need to change anything. Simply just create uh select this free instance, okay?
So I'll select the free instance, but if you're doing like actual deployment, just try to take the subscription, okay?
Because free instance has having like very low configuration machine, and there is some limitation as well.
Okay, now once everything is fine, you have to add the environment variable.
Okay, so what I can do, maybe I can add it from my.nv file.
So simply I can copy
my dot env as it is
okay, and add the variables.
Now it has added my grok API key.
I can delete this one. grok API
key. This is my grok API key.
This is my aviation, this is my default origin, this is my tablet, this is my database URL. Now, this database URL you have to give the internal database URL.
Okay, so again, I will go to my render, go to my Postgres server,
and go below and copy this internal URL. Okay, this one copy this.
Okay, I'll copy this and
add it here.
So I've given my internal one, okay.
Then Lang Smith tracing endpoint,
Langsmith API K and Langsmith project name. Okay, so everything is fine now. Simply deploy the web service.
Now it should take some time. First of all, it will build a Docker image.
So i will wait guys okay. Once this this is complete, this is live, then we'll be able to access that.
On this playlist, you can see AWS CICD deployment. Okay, you can go through the CI CD deployment, you can learn how to deploy as a CICD. Even this project also have deployed as a CI C D on AWS.
Okay, you can refer it.
This is also CI CD. If you push your changes, uh it can upgrade your features okay automatically.
Again, I created another tutorial like this one
render deployment. You can go through that.
So, guys, as you can see, our application is live. Now let's copy this URL and paste it here.
And if I hit enter, so it should open your application. Now, see our trip ADI is live right now.
Now let's uh test it.
So I'll give this prompt.
Okay.
Seven days India trip from Bangladesh. Now let's generate the plan.
Now it's generating. Let's wait.
Now see, this is the entire plan we are getting.
Amazing, right? Now it is live. Now we can share this with your friends and family. They can also access that and you can tell them just use my multi agent right now just to prepare your trip.
So, yes, guys, this is all about from this implementation. I hope you liked it.
Okay, guys, we have successfully completed our uh agent KI course with the help of Langgraph. We have learned each and everything, whatever uh are required to implement these kinds of agentic system.
Now uh I have uh another plan, guys. Uh actually I have designed some more phases okay for the future, and this is available on my channel on DS with Bappi
YouTube channel. So this is my channel, guys, DS with Bappi. So here I only completed the Langgraph, right?
Langgraph Agentic AI orchestration framework, and we have implemented all of the AI agents with the help of Lang Graph. But what about the others' framework?
Okay, there are some other frameworks are also available on the market, uh, like crew AI is there, right?
Then Microsoft Autogen is there, N8N is there, right?
So if you want to learn these are the framework also, so you can subscribe to my channel because in my channel I'll try to publish all of the video related, these are the
framework like crew AI. We'll try to master the entire crew AI in depth. will also implement some end-to-end agentic AI application with help of crew AI.
will be also learning about the Microsoft Autogen. Already I have Microsoft Autogen playlist. Okay, uh, I will uh upload all of the recording related autogen.
Okay, we'll be also implementing some projects, end-to-end projects. Then I'll be covering the no-code platform as well, like N8N. Okay, this would be also available on my YouTube channel.
Then one very interesting and important concept, which is MCP.
So this MCP I didn't cover in this course, right? Uh in this my uh agent ki with uh Langgraph course because this is already like a very long course we have recorded so far.
It is around 25 hours of recording, okay. So that's why uh all of these uh concepts like MCP, autogen, crew AI, okay, these are the recording would be available on my YouTube channel.
Okay, these are the video would be available on my YouTube channel. So please try to refer my YouTube channel. You can subscribe to my YouTube channel.
So I think uh you'll be enjoying a lot the future phases as well. Okay, so we'll try to master the entire model context protocol
in my YouTube channel. Then phase 10. I will try to cover the AI safety and evaluation nowadays.
If you are creating any kinds of agent application, this is super important uh to know, like how we can add the AI safety evaluation pipeline inside your agents.
Uh, definitely we have to master the gut rails and safety.
We'll try to see prompt injection, security tools, restriction, AI safety patterns. Okay, these are the concepts we have to cover, and everything would be available on my YouTube channel.
Okay, that means these are the future uh phases would be available on my channel DS with Bhapti.
And if you want to understand, if you want to learn, these are the concept, you just need to subscribe to my channel, and all of the content would be available on my YouTube channel.
Okay, so yes, if you found my content useful, guys, please try to subscribe to my channel and support me.
If you're supporting me, definitely I can bring these kinds of content more in future, and yeah, I think you'll be learning a lot.
And if you want to connect me, so this is my LinkedIn profile, Boktier Hamet Bhappi. Simply you can follow me here, you can connect me here.
And if you have any kinds of query, you can ask me if you need any kinds of guidance.
You just ping me on my LinkedIn.
Definitely, I'll try to help you with that.
So, yes, guys, this is all about from this course. I hope you enjoyed a lot.
So, thank you so much for watching, and I will see you next time.